MATT: Hello, everyone.
(laughter)
MATT: And welcome to tonight's episode of Critical
Role, where a bunch of us nerdy-ass voice actors
sit around and play the first game of our new
campaign of Dungeons and Dragons.
(cheering)
MATT: Super excited to be back. I've missed this a
lot. Missed this-- oh, you guys will be fine. So
yes. Glad you guys can join us, apparently in some
crazy numbers. So welcome new viewers. Hope you
enjoy your stay. So, without further ado, let's
get this going so we can get through our
announcements. Since it is our first episode of
the year, of the campaign, I want to make sure
that we get our announcements out of the way.
We've got some cool stuff to talk about. First and
foremost, we have two sponsors tonight. Our first
sponsor-- and we're going into, for a time, a cool
partnership with the folks at DnD Beyond,
actually. They've been really awesome, and we've
been talking, and anybody who hasn't seen it, it's
an online digital tool where you can create your
own D&D character, they have options to purchase
any of the current D&D books out there, and then
carry over any of the character options and racial
options over into it, so you can basically use it
as a tool. We'll be using it to help us out in the
game as we go, 'cause it's actually got some pretty
cool stuff. So excited about that. It is D-N-D
Beyond, by the way, if you haven't seen, not the
ampersand. It's D-N-D.
LAURA: As in nnnn.
MATT: Nnnn. But yeah, so they're going to be a
long-term partner for the show, so working with us
through the start of this campaign. We're super
excited. But yeah. So we're excited. You can
currently activate-- it should be now-- some
Critical Role content on there. They should have
available the Blood Hunter class that I created a
couple of years ago, kind of refining. Should be
available for you guys to find on the DnD Beyond,
which I'm excited about, and there's a one-time
discount of $10 off any digital book in the
dndbeyond.com marketplace if you use the codeword
'beginnings' in there right now. So yeah, get a
chance to check it out.
TRAVIS: (vomiting noises) Would you like some?
MATT: So yeah. I'm super excited to have that,
guys. So you apply that code at checkout to make
that happen, in case you're confused and trying to
get it to work. There's a bunch of stuff to
explore on there, and a bunch of cool ways to
incorporate the existing breadth of D&D lore and
options in there, and now you have some of our stuff in
there as well, and hopefully more Critical Role
content and Tal'Dorei content and Exandria content
down the road to also be available on there as we
go. Super excited about that. I'd like to thank
you guys at DnD Beyond for being awesome. We also
have our second sponsor. Sam, if you want to take
it away.
SAM: I'm our second sponsor.
(laughter)
LAURA: Thanks, Sam!
SAM: No. Welcome, new viewers. Every week-- or
many weeks, I am charged with writing the ad for
the sponsor of that week. I did this one way back
in mid-December, so it'll feel a little stale.
(laughter)
SAM: Sorry. I didn't have time to write a new one.
Apologies to our sponsor. But our second sponsor
tonight is Backblaze. They offer unlimited cloud
backup for Macs and PCs. You can restore from the
web or via hard drive. They'll even overnight
FedEx a drive to you, and because it's Christmas
season, I wrote this. 'Twas the night before
Critmas when I clicked on my mouse, but the drive
wasn't whirring; it had said 'Adi-ouse'. When up
from the cloud there arose such a sight, I knew in
a flash that my shit was all right. As I spat out
my plate of cold chicken kiev, down my chimney
came a weird little elf named Lev. I said, "Whoa,
whoa, whoa, how'd you get in my place?" Lev gave
me a wink and punched me in the face. And suddenly
he fired up a pipe and started to restore my
computer from a backup he carted. My documents,
like slash fiction from My Little Pony. My photos,
like me naked, covered in bologna. He mumbled that
you can get backed up at once for a merry little
fee of $5 a month-s. You even get 15 days free if
you scroll over to backblaze.com/criticalrole. And
just like that, my computer was on. Lev greased up
his body, and bam, he was gone. But I heard him
exclaim, "Peace out, yo, whassup! Happy Backblaze
to all, don't forget to back up!"
(cheering)
SAM: I'll write another one for Easter, I
promise.
(laughter)
MATT: Thank you, Sam. So thank you, Backblaze.
Happy to have you for our sponsor tonight as well.
Also, as a heads-up, we've had our friends at
Wyrmwood for a while have been awesomely providing
Wyrmwood dice boxes and dice trays and dice towers
to give away to people in the community. They have
new boxes for all the players in the new campaign.
And they have been working on something for a
while for us to kick off the new campaign. They
made us a new table. If we can go to a camera view
of this table they made for the campaign.
(cheering)
MATT: It's made out of English brown oak, the
center Critical Role inlay is made of ash burl, is
the background, and then rosewood for the d20
outline, wenge for the Critical Role words
themselves, and silver stringing around the
border. It was built by hand in their
Massachusetts office and workshop, and it was
hand-rubbed oil on a wax finish. Over a hundred
hours were put into this table. They did an
incredible job, and we're super honored to have
that here, and thank you guys for showing such an
awesome appreciation for what we do.
SAM: It smells really nice.
LAURA: We have cubbies!
MARISHA: It smells like wood in the studio, like
fresh wood.
SAM: And, when we get canceled, this is going to
be a great dining room table.
MATT: This is true! Thank you guys, Wyrmwood. If
you aren't familiar with any of their stuff, go to
wyrmwoodgaming.com, that's W-Y-R-M-wood Gaming
dot com. They do awesome work. It's really super
high-quality, it's great. So thank you guys. All
right, so. Let's see. Updates we can get through.
Laura, do you have an update for merch stuff in
the new year?
LAURA: (yells) Okay. Yes, I do. It's a new
campaign, new us, new merch. I don't know which
camera I'm looking at.
SAM: That one.
LAURA: So we released our teaser on socials, and
everybody was like, "I want that as a poster!" So
we listened to you, and we made it a poster!
(cheering)
SAM: It's a real poster?
LAURA: It's a real poster!
SAM: Oh, wow!
LAURA: Look at this lameness that you could have
on your wall! So yeah. It's in the store right
now, you guys, and we printed a small amount, so
those ones will be shipped faster, and then after
that it'll just be pre-order, but I think it's all
listed as pre-order, so just so you know.
SAM: Can you photoshop out my crotch region?
LAURA: No.
TALIESIN: That would be a lot of photoshop, man.
MATT: None of us have that much talent in post,
Sam.
LAURA: But let's just talk about this Matthew
Mercer.
MATT: Let's not talk about what I-- when I put
that outfit on, I did not consider quite the
permeation in my life it would become. So there's
that.
LAURA: So we can be with you always. Matt can
stare at you while you sleep.
LIAM: That's actually how Purvon dressed.
MATT: God damn it.
TALIESIN: Hey, first throwback! Well done.
LAURA: Oh yeah. We've got to be careful, guys,
because we have a lot of people that haven't
watched the last campaign, or haven't finished the
last campaign, so no spoilers for last campaign.
SAM: I don't really remember it.
TRAVIS: Well, we all died, so.
MATT: That's true, yeah. Okay, next announcements:
the Critical Role podcast we have currently up to
date. All of Vox Machina's story, the whole first
campaign, is now on the podcast. You can find it
where the finest podcasts are downloaded. And do
we have an update as far as the release schedule
for this podcast?
MARISHA: Yes, we do. They will be releasing one
week after we are live. We'll be one week behind.
SAM: On a Thursday?
MARISHA: They will be releasing on Thursdays the
week after.
LAURA: Oh, so you can listen to it in the morning
and watch it live at night. If you have a lot of
free time. Or a really long drive, maybe.
SAM: An extra eight hours to spend every
Thursday.
MATT: To be fair, you guys would have about as
much free time on a Thursday as I would. Cool, so
look forward to that. Comic book, issue four of
Critical Role: Vox Machina Origins, Liam, when
does that come out?
LIAM: It is coming out on the 24th of this month.
TRAVIS: Oh, make it sooner!
LIAM: I've read it. It's so good, it's real good,
it's so good. You guys, Vox Machina's story ended
at this table, but it is going to live on and on
and on-- at least for three more issues.
MATT: Thank you very much.
TRAVIS: Check it out everywhere.
LIAM: Yeah, on Zune, on PalmPilot. Darkhorse app,
Comixology, Limewire, finally.
MARISHA: Napster.
LAURA: I'm going to throw up.
MATT: That's okay, guys, we've got a couple more
things left. Thank you for hanging in there. As
far as con appearances go, I actually fly tomorrow
to Miami, Florida for Paradise City Comic Con.
I'll be there tomorrow until Sunday. If you guys
are in the area, come say hi at the convention. It
should be fun. I have panels and signings and
stuff. Hopefully see you there. Also, I'll be at
Lexington Comic and Toy Con in Lexington,
Kentucky, March 9-11, Otafest in Calgary, May
18-20, and A-Kon in Texas, June 7-10.
ASHLEY: Jeez Louise, Matt.
LAURA: We have Emerald City Comic Con, me and
Travis.
TRAVIS: First weekend of March.
MATT: Badass. Cool. All right, so. Paring it down,
finishing it up here. Thank you for your patience.
With the new campaign, I want to renew our
appreciation for and make sure that we push to you
guys that we, from the very beginning, have been
supporting a really amazing charity called 826,
826LA being our local chapter. They have 826
groups all over the United States that they do
after-school creative writing, and a lot of great
creative classes for children who are either
underprivileged or don't have opportunities to go
to these types of classes. They do wonderful,
wonderful work, and we've been supporting them
from the very beginning, and we're just doubling
down on that for this new campaign. You guys as a
community have been fantastic in supporting them,
and all the charities that we've supported from
the very beginning. Critmas every year has been a
very prime example of that, so I just wanted to
continue to push that forward, share the love, and
a big thank-you to 826 for being such an amazing
source of creative drive for so many young kids
who normally wouldn't have that opportunity. So
you guys are amazing, and show them your
appreciation if you can.
(cheering)
MATT: Final shout-outs. One, thank you to Ian
Phillips of Iron Tusk Painting, who has painted
the miniatures for this campaign.
(cheering)
MATT: He actually painted me and Marisha's cake
toppers for our wedding, and whenever you manage
to see them in the campaign, you can know that
it's his handiwork. Soon enough.
ASHLEY: Also, fun fact about Ian Phillips: I grew
up with him. He was one of my brother's best
friends when we first moved out here to LA, and so
when that name was floating around, I was like,
wait a minute. And then we reconnected back on
Instagram. It's such a crazy story. You know,
Critical Role brings it all back around.
(laughter)
MATT: I love it. So you can follow him,
@PaintingTusk on Twitter.
LIAM: I've had him paint 20 to 30-- I'm kind of
addicted-- 20 to 30 miniatures. They're amazing.
He's amazing at what he does.
MATT: And final thank-yous to Warner Bros and
Monolith Entertainment for letting us incorporate
the Shadow of War soundtrack into our Critical
Role soundtrack here on the air, so those will be
coming into the new campaign. And, super excited,
CD Projekt Red has been nice enough to allow us
use of the Witcher series soundtrack to also
incorporate into the campaign, which, honestly,
when we started playing at home, the Witcher
soundtrack was most of my music, and I couldn't
use it when we started streaming, and so it's been
a cool full-circle to be able to bring it back in.
Plus it brings a unique flavor that works with the
new campaign setting, so.
With that, I believe our announcements are done.
Thank you for bearing with us.
LAURA: Wait, we're going to give-- oh, that's--
MARISHA: Afterwards.
SAM: There's one more announcement.
MARISHA: Our announcement is our brand-new opening
title sequence. Which I think we're ready for.
MATT: So, as we bring it down, guys, let's go
ahead and prepare to dive in to the new year and
the new campaign for this episode of Critical
Role.
(yelling)
[80s music]
(laughter)
MATT: And welcome back.
TRAVIS: That was a new level.
MATT: We've definitely returned to the table.
Thank you, Sam. So.
MARISHA: Wait, super fast. We've got to go through
credits. Right? Okay. So normally we don't do
this, and I did this once before when we released
our other opening title sequence. Yeah, 50th. So
we're going to do this again. These are just
people who do so much and who do not get enough
love. I'm going to shout them out. Sean Becker,
who's the unsung hero of Geek and Sundry, he's the
executive producer. T.J. Rotell, he's our
production manager around here, he makes sure that
we actually have cameras. Maxwell James, our
producer that makes this show go every week. Dani
Carr, our production coordinator, also huge
producer here. Steve Sprinkles, who directed that
amazing opening title sequence.
SAM: That's not a real name!
MARISHA: I know. I love it on the slate. It always
says 'Sprinkles'. Jan-Michael Losada, who is our
D.P., and is the same D.P. from last time. Tristan
Savage-Tate, our first A.C. Sean Delahunt, who is
our key grip. Tyler Hart, who is our gaffer, who
gaffs everything around here, he's amazing. Jenny
Newman, who did the amazing wardrobe. She sourced
all the wardrobe. Wren Witting, who's one of our
hair and makeup artists. Vanessa Marie, who is our
second hair and makeup artist. Jose Sosa, who was
our production assistant. Selina Ruthe--
LAURA: That's a lot of pieces of paper!
MARISHA: I know. Selina Ruthe, who did additional
photography, and she also does stuff every day.
LAURA: Why didn't you put them on the same piece
of paper?
MARISHA: Because I didn't know there was going to
be this many. Brandon Clark, who was our location
manager. Pamela Joy, who shot all the photos for
that, and Loretta Ritchert.
LAURA: Yeah, they're with Heirloom Photography,
and they did all of our thumbnails, too. They did
that poster.
ASHLEY: Go check them out on Instagram!
MARISHA: Jason Charles Miller, who does our
music.
LIAM: Party on, Garthok!
MARISHA: Sean Hudson, who does our
post-production. And Andy Inglat, who edited that
thing. Okay. I'm sweating a lot.
MATT: That's okay. So.
SAM: What a night. Well, guys...
TALIESIN: This has been great.
LIAM: Holy shit.
MATT: Everyone. Everyone.
SAM: Can we open our fricking books yet?
MARISHA: Not yet.
MATT: Welcome to Wildemount. The year is 835 P.D.,
or post-Divergence. This continent is divided both
by jagged terrain and political powers. The
Menagerie Coast, a collection of city-states
united under the Clovis Concord, monopolizes the
southwestern shores and ports of Wildemount,
thriving on open trade and cultural freedom.
Beyond the Cyrios Mountains lies the massive
region known as Wynandir, bisected by the
Ashkeeper Peaks. Eastern Wynandir houses the
expansive wastes and turbulent badlands of
Xhorhas, overrun with all manner of beasts and
terrors, relics from the final battles of the
Calamity that ruined that scarred landscape.
Northward, you would find the Greying Wildlands, a
lawless realm harboring a curse that has kept it
unconquered by human hands. However, this story
begins in the territory of Western Wynandir,
within the boundaries of the Dwendalian Empire.
Emerging 13 generations before, the Dwendalian
Empire has slowly spread to encompass the
surrounding societies of the region, absorbing the
peoples of the Zemni Fields and the Marrow Valley,
before finally conquering the Julous Dominion and
taking the whole of Western Wynandir for the
Empire.
SAM: There will be no test.
MATT: No. This is-- let me continue. Under the
rule of the current King Bertrand Dwendal, now in
his 68th year, most are left to their own devices.
You live as you did before. The crown only takes a
tithe of what you produce and earn. You follow its
laws, worship its gods, and bow to its installed
local leadership. In return, denizens of the
Empire are protected from the chaotic horrors and
shadowed evils that stalk the edges of the
civilized lands. This accord has led to a
prosperous century for the Empire, or at least the
political elite. Tensions brew beneath the
chafing watch of the Crown's Guard. Every temple
is government-owned and run, and worship outside
the approved idolatry is met with imprisonment.
Rumors of military clashes at the eastern border
near Xhorhas have many common folk on edge. Our
story, however, begins much smaller. Here in the
southern reaches of the Marrow Valley, beyond the
entry gates of the Wuyun Gorge, lies the small
rural town of Trostenwald. Bordering the blue
waters of the Ustaloch, this town came to
prominence near the turn of this recent century,
when the surrounding fertile farmlands were
discovered to produce a unique type of grain and
wheat, leading to a boom of breweries. When the
glut subsided, three large families stood
triumphant in the local business of fermented
delights. Now Trostenwald thrives on their exports
of fish, crops, and ale. Here in this sleepy trade
stop along the Amber Road, a handful of wandering
destinies slowly begin to intersect.
We begin in the early hours of the morning on the
day of Grissen in a messy room on the second floor
of the Nestled Nook Inn. A bleary-eyed, bruised
man in a tattered coat slowly wakens from his
lengthy sleep, catching his small, snoring ally
curled at the foot of the bed. Liam, if you would
like to describe your character, please.
(nervous laughter)
LAURA: Oh my god, no pressure!
SAM: Were we supposed to prepare this?
LIAM: I'm pretty filthy. I have a mess of
reddish-brown hair, and really filthy road
clothes. I wear a long coat that I slept in. I
slept about 20 hours last night. Jeez. Unshaven, a
bit of a mess.
SAM: So far you're just talking about current
Liam.
LAURA: What color are your eyes? I need visual.
LIAM: They're blue. That's it. It was a rough day
yesterday, and-- that's it.
MATT: And your name is?
LIAM: Oh. Caleb. Caleb Widogast.
MATT: All right. As your smaller friend curls
awake, Sam, would you like to describe your
character?
SAM: Yeah. Um. I am a little goblin girl.
(laughter)
SAM: I am a goblin. So, you know, the green skin,
the green hair, the yellow eyes. And she wears
not-great clothes, just like her traveling
companion there. She hides in the shadows a lot,
because she knows goblins aren't welcome in this
part, and that's about it. I mean, she's a little
skittish, and right now she's probably stirring
awake as well, right?
MATT: Well. What's your name?
SAM: Oh. Nott the Brave.
MATT: So Caleb, as you come to consciousness, you
glance over and can see, slowly snoring and
rousing at about the same time, Nott's eyes blink
open, her slowly groaning face looking over
towards you.
SAM: (high-pitched Cockney accent) Oh! You're finally awake,
I see. Oh yeah, motherfuckers. It's on. You were out for quite
some time, there. Rough day, eh?
LIAM: (light German accent) Not our best day, no.
SAM: No, I mean, usually you're so good at
everything, but yesterday you were just-- maybe
you needed the sleep, is what you needed.
LIAM: Thank you.
SAM: Well, don't thank me yet. I should probably
tell you what happened while you were asleep. I
mean, you were asleep for so long. I got bored,
frankly. I was going through my pack and
reorganizing.
LIAM: Has anybody seen you-- seen you seen you?
SAM: Well, I mean, many people? I got bored.
You've never slept that long, so I left, I went
downstairs, I thought I'd do a bit of
window-shopping, and you know how sometimes I get
the itch, you know?
LIAM: I do. Did you make it back here okay, at
night?
SAM: I'm here, aren't I?
LIAM: Yeah, you are.
SAM: Yeah, I did. But I might have been spotted by
a few of the Crown's Guard.
LIAM: Did you have the mask on?
SAM: No? No, I didn't. But they didn't catch me,
so. Listen, I'm sorry, sometimes I get the urge,
I've got to take something, you know? I was trying
to replentish what you lost yesterday, and I failed.
LIAM: Well, we-- (sighs)-- discussed coming to a
bigger town. It's going to be a little more
difficult now. You can't go-- it was easier on
outskirts, it was easier in farms, but we can't do
that here.
SAM: I know, I'm sorry. Yeah. I know. You're
right. Yep. I just got a little bit squiggly.
That's all.
LIAM: Okay. Well, I think today you should have
the mask on at all times.
SAM: Yeah, good idea, Caleb.
LIAM: It's better when we're working together. If
you need to steal something, do it with my help,
all right?
SAM: Yeah, yeah, of course. Yeah.
LIAM: Back up the conversation a minute. Thank
you. I would not be alive if you had not-- you
saved my life. So thank you.
SAM: Ah, no problem.
LIAM: Yesterday was really not great.
SAM: Yeah, well, we'll do better today, right?
LIAM: Sure. Sure we will. Are you hungry?
SAM: Yeah, I'm starving.
MATT: At this point, you notice the gentle smell
of cooked meats and promises of mediocre porridge
and eggs just barely begins to creep beneath the
subtle floor of your room, meet your nostrils.
LIAM: Well, Nott, what are we going to do today? I
can go down and get breakfast and bring it up
here. At least-- I don't know. I mean, I'm a
little wary of just splashing back into the town
right away.
SAM: Let's go down, get some food. I'll come with
you, 'cause as you said, we're better together.
And we'll take it from there. You need some books
and stuff, right?
LIAM: Always.
SAM: All right, well, that's on the to-do list.
LIAM: All right, well, let's get something to eat,
then.
MATT: All right, so you prepare yourself with your
mask set over?
SAM: Yes, yeah, so I have a half a mask that
covers my goblin face, and with the hood over,
kind of obscures. Maybe it's not a goblin, maybe
it's a little halfling person or something.
MATT: Which is helpful. The southern, more rural
region of the Empire, especially near Felderwin,
which is one of the largest tilling and farming
areas of the entire Empire, has a very heavy
halfling population. And so while this city is not
the core of it, you'd probably see a larger 20-25%
of the population here in Trostenwald is halfling.
So you pass off pretty decently as long as you
keep away from discerning, intent eyes. So the two
of you manage to gather your things for the time
being, wander down the stairs from the top floor
down to the base of the tavern, which, the air is
already bustling with townsfolk and all manner of
travelers preparing to take on the day's
responsibilities. Yorda, the 40-something woman
barkeep with shoulder-length blonde hair and
weathered skin that you previously rented your
room at the inn from, frantically darts behind the
bar while the red-headed barmaid rushes from table
to table. It seems that the clientele is a bit
more than they were expecting this morning. Yorda
yells from behind the bar to the barkeep,
"Adelaine, two more brats and a bit of mush at the
corner table." She looks up, "I'm working on it!"
And she runs over and heads back to the kitchen.
There's a faint bit of music as two
slovenly-looking musicians in the corner are
trying to work for tips with a small hat on the
floor that it looks like nobody's thrown any coin
into it. The tables are fairly busy, except for
maybe two that appear to be available between the
two of you guys, if you'd like to find a seat.
LIAM: Okay. Sure. Is that easy to do, find a
seat?
MATT: Yeah, you walk over to it, you sit down.
(laughter)
LIAM: Is this how D&D works?
SAM: What do we roll for?
(laughter)
MATT: You sit down, and due to the chaos that
ensues around you, it takes a little while for
Adelaine, the red-headed barmaid, to come by, and
she scoots by the table. "I'm terribly sorry. What
"can I get you?"
SAM: You know, meat if you have it, but if you
don't, that's okay, too. Potatoes, or bacon if
it's on the menu, but really anything--
MATT: "I can get you all three, it's fine. What
you want?"
LIAM: A Trost for each of us, please.
MATT: "For breakfast? I like you. All right, two
Trosts and a bunch of meats. Be right back." And
she rushes off, she pulls her hair back and ties it as
she goes into the kitchen, getting ready for the
midst of chaos. While you guys have a moment there
at the table, you can hear conversation muttering
around you, and you have a brief bit of privacy to
discuss.
LIAM: Yes, I need books, that's true, but did you
find drink yesterday?
SAM: I have a little left in my flask.
LIAM: How much?
SAM: Just a couple swigs.
LIAM: So that's also on the to-do list, then.
SAM: I mean, if you don't want me to get too
jittery, yeah.
LIAM: All right. Okay. So we'll do that first.
SAM: All right.
TRAVIS: I love her.
(laughter)
MATT: A short time passes before the two platters
are rushed over and scattered across the front of
your table with a clattering. Pile of meats there
set for you, a little bit placed on the side,
because you might need, especially with the look
on your face-- Adelaine gives you a glance and
goes, "Put something in your belly." Comes back
and slides two Trosts to you.
SAM: I remove my little mask, and then just go
(eating noises).
(laughter)
LIAM: I take the last piece.
MATT: As you guys are partway through your meal--
let's see, this would be Caleb. You notice out of
the corner of your eye a gentleman enter the door
looking kind of meek. Middle-age, looks
work-hardened. He has a heavy chin-beard that is
unkempt and a bit wild, but his eyes are warm.
He's holding his hat in his grip, and he scans the
room with an eager glance before his face
brightens, and he begins to push his way across
the room, in your direction, it looks like. He
scoots over towards your table, and as you're
about to turn and see what he's about--
LIAM: I'm putting my hand on my purse.
MATT: --he pivots to the table next to you
instead. He turns to you three.
(yelps)
LAURA: We've just been sitting here this whole
time!
MATT: Yeah. You've met this man the day before,
Rinaldo, the fisherman, who you had aided. And as
he approaches, he goes, "Might I sit, please?"
LAURA: Of course, take a seat.
SAM: What's that?
MATT: As he sits down in his chair, I would ask
each of you to please describe yourselves,
starting with you, Laura.
LAURA: (Slavic accent) Oh, well, okay. I'm just, you
know, a little blue tiefling, that's all, with blue hair.
And I'm wearing a pretty cute dress, that's all.
And I'm having a good time, you know? We're just
having a good time here at breakfast.
MATT: All right. And you?
MARISHA: Uh, yeah. Yeah. I'm, you know,
simple girl, simple needs. Just wearing nice, baggy
clothes, some monk vestiges. They're in nice blues
and greys. You notice I have a blue sash around my
belt. Got a nice shave going on, little undercut.
Looks like maybe I put on makeup two days ago, and
I'm like, yeah, it's still holding up. It's fine.
I can work with that.
SAM: What's your name?
MATT: We'll get to that. Thank you. And Travis, if
you'd like to describe yourself, please?
TRAVIS: (Texan drawl) Yeah, I'm here too.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: I'm a half-orc, sitting here in beat-up
leathers. Have a big scar across my face.
SAM: (sings 'Bad to the Bone')
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Green skin tone, and got some piecemeal
armor put together and stuff. My name's Fjord.
LAURA: You're very handsome. I just need to tell
you.
TRAVIS: Thank you. Appreciate that.
MATT: As Rinaldo sits down, clutching his hat
still in his hands, says, "I thank you for your
"time. Fjord. And, I apologize, I forget your
names."
MARISHA: Beauregard.
MATT: "Beauregard. And?"
LAURA: Jester.
MATT: "Jester, thank you. You all came when no one
else would yesterday, and because of you my
"daughter is still alive."
MARISHA: Oh yeah. Sorry for being a pessimistic
asshole, by the way, when we first came into town.
MATT: "Oh, that's okay."
MARISHA: I'm not used to things turning out good.
MATT: "You'll do well this side of the Empire.
Anyway. I won't keep you, but I-- we spoke
"yesterday, and I didn't have much to give you.
Sent you away with nothing but my gratitude. But
"I've been asking around the other fishermen,
lochsmen, and we've put together a little bit of
"coin for your troubles, so." And he turns his cap
over on the table, and this catches your
attention, you hear this clattering of coin. Your
eyes glance over, especially you, Nott, and watch
as he leaves this pile of what looks to be mostly
copper and silver pieces, with a couple of
glimmers of gold, and as soon as it clatters
across the hard wood table here in the center of
the tavern, other faces begin to turn, gather
attention as to what's happening over here in the
back edge, and he takes his cap back and pushes it
forward towards all of you, his dirty, you can see
cracked and very callused fingers shoving it in
your direction, before taking his hat and placing
it back over his head.
LAURA: So cool!
LIAM: Those coins went all over the floor?
MATT: All over the table. "I hope it's helpful.
But thank you."
MARISHA: Yeah, yeah. Oh wait.
TRAVIS: We can't accept this, right? I mean, it's
too much.
MARISHA: We're supposed to at least say that,
right? And then still accept it, right?
TRAVIS: I think you're supposed to do it if you
say it.
LAURA: Well, I mean, he did go around to a bunch
of people. That was a lot of work on his part. I
would hate to make him go back to all of those
people and give it back to each individual
person.
TRAVIS: Fine, fine.
MARISHA: If he didn't keep a ledger, you know. We
wouldn't want to do that. It's rude not to accept
a gift, right? It's rude not to accept a gift,
right?
MATT: "I would hope that is the case. Anyway.
Thank you very much. I am sorry for getting in
"your way." And he stands up and gives you all a
nod and rushes out of the tavern, a little
embarrassed by all the attention that's now placed
on him by the other patrons, and as he leaves,
everyone goes back to their business, a couple of
wandering eyes starting to count what coins are
there as you slowly mitt them in your direction.
LAURA: Divide it up.
MARISHA: Okay, okay.
MATT: There are four gold pieces amongst the pile,
22 silver, and 48 copper pieces.
TRAVIS: Can I clock the room, see who else is
watching her count?
MATT: Perception check. 48 copper.
TRAVIS: Is this the first roll?
MATT: First roll of the campaign.
TRAVIS: Natural 20.
(cheering)
MATT: And that's how you start it. All right.
LAURA: So I'm leaving it to you to do that
counting. Which is really hard for me, personally,
but there you go.
MARISHA: How do you split up four gold? We have
four gold and there's only three of us.
LAURA: Don't know.
TRAVIS: Well, I actually did pretty good at that
card game, so you can have mine.
MARISHA: Aw. I will. Okay.
LAURA: So two for each of us! That's great.
MARISHA: Oh, that's good. One for you, two for
me, two for-- oh wait, no, wait, math doesn't
make sense.
SAM: She's your treasurer?
MATT: This is going to go great.
LAURA: It's hard not being the treasurer.
MARISHA: I'll give two to Jester, one for you, one
for me. And then 22 silver, that's--
LAURA: Tell you what, you do that math.
MATT: While you're counting this out and figuring
out the division of your gains, Fjord, you glance
about, narrowing your orcish eyes across the room,
and you can see two other tables there are some
gentlemen who are peering over, and as soon as
they meet your gaze, they go right back to their
business and completely shrink away. There's a man
and a hooded figure at a table immediately
adjacent to you. The man looks rather filthy, his
hair a bit unkempt, and he's trying to finish his
drink. However, the smaller halfling-looking
figure is just glaring intently, and is slowly
leaning in the direction of the table.
TRAVIS: That's creepy. Fucking disgusting. I think
we have people watching us.
LAURA: Who is watching us?
TRAVIS: Well, just take a look right over there.
SAM: Don't arouse suspicion, but did you hear all
that coin hit that table, Caleb?
LIAM: I did. It's on the table, though, so I think
on the table it will stay.
SAM: Yes, but we could follow them out. We could
do the Moneypot. We could run Rat Food. We could
do Prince and the Pauper to get it from them. We
could try Spider Eyes. Any of those could work--
LAURA: Are you guys staying here?
MATT: This blue-skinned tiefling suddenly leans
over to you at the table.
SAM: Don't move. Don't move. Tieflings can only
see movement.
LIAM: I don't think that's true--
LAURA: It's very true, we have a hard time seeing
things that aren't moving, it's very true. But I
can hear you. You should take a bath. You know they
have showers here. It's possible.
LIAM: A what now?
LAURA: You bathe yourself in water.
LIAM: No, I've bathed before, yeah, I know what a
bath is.
LAURA: It's because you smell really bad, and it's
wafting over this direction. I'm just letting you
know. I would hate if I smelled that bad and
someone didn't tell me.
LIAM: I've only just met you.
LAURA: Hi! I'm Jester.
LIAM: Hi, I'm Caleb.
LAURA: Nice to meet you, Caleb. How much silver
did I just get?
MARISHA: Seven!
LAURA: Woo!
(laughter)
MARISHA: And 16 copper. Aren't you all jealous?
SAM: Morning.
MARISHA: Morning.
MATT: Make a perception check, Beauregard and
Jester.
LAURA: Whoa.
LIAM: Are you checking your DnD Beyond specs?
MARISHA: I am, I'm adding my--
LAURA: 22. I haven't even flipped over my
character sheet yet. This is crazy.
MARISHA: 19.
MATT: Okay. The somewhat meek female halfling
who's now suddenly very reserved, and not as
filthy as the human compatriot that she keeps,
seems less and less halfling the more you glance
in her direction. The ears are folded inward but
elongated, the tinges of green to the skin, and
with the little words that have poked through her
lips, you can see what appear to be teeth more jagged
than expected of the half-folk.
MARISHA: I just shout over and I say, good
morning, in Halfling.
SAM: I know Halfling, right? Yes. I'll shout back,
top of the morning to you.
(laughter)
MARISHA: Would you like a coffee? I'd love to buy
you a coffee.
SAM: We've got-- free coffee? Yeah, yeah, I'll
take it. Sure. Thank you.
TRAVIS: You're being mighty fucking friendly. They
were looking at our coin.
MARISHA: Why can't they have been looking at me?
Maybe they were looking at me.
TRAVIS: I didn't think of that.
MARISHA: Maybe they were looking at you. As Jester
said, you're handsome.
LIAM: Just--
LAURA: Yes?
LIAM: Nott.
SAM: He said "Jest".
LAURA: I just thought you said my name, is all.
MARISHA: Oh, I said your name. Oh, they might have
said your name, too.
LIAM: Never mind, never mind. Could I get another
Trost over here, please?
SAM: Two, please, right away.
MATT: Eventually Adelaine comes by and brings two
fresh Trosts to the table, glancing about at the
unique tension in the air right here. "Would you
like anything as well?"
LAURA: Oh, yes. Lots of baked goods if you have
them, please.
TRAVIS: Pork belly, if you have it.
MARISHA: I don't think I've seen you eat anything
other than pastries.
LAURA: I really like them.
MARISHA: I'm kind of concerned for your
well-being. It's fine, I'm not that concerned.
Eat whatever you want. I'll have bacon, some
ham, whatever.
MATT: "All right, pork it is. I'll be right back."
She rushes off to the kitchen. You guys continue
to awkwardly stare at each other.
LIAM: I'm going to put my hand up and say,
quietly, to Nott, the Moneypot is not for them.
It's not for them, it's for farmers. Okay?
SAM: Yeah, you're right, you're right.
MARISHA: Do we notice them whispering?
MATT: With your perception rolls earlier? Yes.
LIAM: But I said it really quietly.
(laughter)
MATT: She rolled a 22.
LIAM: But she can hear my little whisper?
MATT: No, you heard the whisper, you're not sure
what the words are. You can see that they're
whispering. Being mysterious.
LAURA: Okay, cool.
SAM: In Halfling, I'll say to Beau--
MARISHA: Beau for short works.
SAM: Are you in town for business or pleasure?
MARISHA: Can I insight check him, see what he's
hiding?
MATT: Make an insight check.
MARISHA: Okay. What's my insight, I can't
remember.
LAURA: What is he saying? I mean you, you're a
girl. What is she saying? Shit. That's really hard
to remember now.
SAM: You're asking me what I'm saying.
LAURA: Yeah, what did you just say?
MARISHA: 13.
MATT: 13? I mean, seems to be genuine. Hard to
read through all the wrappings, shadow, and the
hood still obscuring the face.
LAURA: Do you have the mask covering you?
SAM: I think I do.
MATT: Yeah, it's this porcelain covering that has
painted lips. It's a little unsettling.
LIAM: I mean, I'm sorry, not to be blunt, but, you
know. It's pretty obvious goblins are not welcome
strolling about.
LAURA: She's a goblin?!
SAM: Yeah, yeah, but you don't have to make a big
thing of it, all right? There could be people here
who don't know.
LIAM: That's right. She's my companion, she's my
friend. There's nothing to make a big deal about.
That's why she's wrapped up. Just leave it,
please.
LAURA: I didn't ask why she was wrapped up.
MARISHA: I know, we're not making a big deal out
it. You're making a big deal out of it.
LIAM: Somebody asked why she was wrapped up.
LAURA: No, nobody asked.
LIAM: Somebody said the words-- this is Liam--
"Why are you all wrapped up?"
MARISHA: Oh, I asked if she was cold.
(laughter)
SAM: That's concern.
MATT: As Caleb finishes oversharing.
LIAM: Vaxleth is over. It's so over!
MARISHA: Those are old times, man. That was a
different universe. Different life.
MATT: At this point, there is a bit of a commotion
towards the entrance of the tavern. Two shadows
step into the doorway of the nearish-noonday sun.
The figures, one eclipsing the other from behind,
begin to step in. You notice one of them begins to
step from table to table, glancing about with a
sort of grace to the movement, the other staying a
few feet behind. Taliesin, if you'd like to
describe your character, please.
LAURA: I didn't think we were going to meet you so
soon!
TALIESIN: Neither did I.
ASHLEY: I didn't either.
TALIESIN: But here we are. A lavender-- damn it,
Travis. A lavender tiefling with red eyes and very
pierced, extremely ostentatious horns that are
pierced with little gems and little baubles. He's
got a tattoo that seems to be running up the side
of his face, a peacock tattoo that goes off into
his very ostentatious, ridiculous, overblown robes
that he wears. His two swords and pouch dangling at
the side of his hips. He's very broad in his
dress.
LIAM: So a literal and figurative peacock.
TALIESIN: Oh yes.
TRAVIS: One of your characters? No.
TALIESIN: I know, mine. Who knew?
MATT: As this tiefling darts from table to table,
a few feet behind, you see--
ASHLEY: Wait, did you say your name?
TALIESIN: I didn't say my name.
ASHLEY: Okay. So there is a woman behind him. Taller
than your average... lass.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: She's very, very, very pale-skinned. Her
hair is black that starts to turn white as it gets
longer. It's matted, it's dreaded, it's braided.
Her clothes are a bit tattered, but just sort of--
she's a bit of a mess, and she has two different
color eyes. One of them is a light greenish-blue,
and the other is a violet color. And she's very
standoffish, hunch-y, arms folded.
MATT: You watch as these figures slowly move from
table to table, the tiefling engaging in some
distant conversation, leaving a slip of paper,
walking to the next table. Gauging the atmosphere,
not leaving a slip of paper, and quickly moving
on, and then eventually your eyes meet what looks
to be two tables with a very motley crew of
individuals that are both awkwardly avoiding their
own tension and currently trying to figure you
out.
TALIESIN: Can I tell if-- where are they in the
dispensement of the coin? Can I tell they have a
little coin on them? Did I catch any of that?
MATT: They've completed distributing, so you don't
see any coin, unfortunately.
TALIESIN: Well. I don't believe I've ever seen a
group of people more in need of a good time in my
entire life. Mollymauk Tealeaf of the Fletching
and Moondrop Traveling Carnival of Curiosities. If
there was ever a group of people that needed a
good time to go out, have a laugh, see things that
you have never seen before, and my god, take my
word for it, one month's time, people will be
buying your ale to hear the tale of what you saw
at the Traveling Carnival of Curiosities this night.
LAURA: We saw your tent going up! We did!
MARISHA: We were actually going to go without the
flyer, but now we also have a flyer.
TALIESIN: It's just five copper. A steal. At five
silver, it would be a steal, at five gold? Worth
every penny. But if you've got the five copper to
spend, we would happily have you all.
LAURA: Do you perform?
TALIESIN: Ah. I'm less of a performer and more of
an intermediary for these parts. I do on occasion
perform. I can read fortunes--
LAURA: (gasps) I was going to ask if you read
fortunes! Can you do one now?
TALIESIN: I knew you were going to ask that.
LAURA: (gasps) Oh my gosh, you're so smart. Look
at this guy, he knows everything!
TALIESIN: I'm going to sit down at the table.
MATT: Okay. He goes and sits down at this table,
finishing his presentation. One of the barmaids
comes up to you, and looks up. You're standing
almost a solid seven inches taller than her.
"Miss, can I get you a drink?"
ASHLEY: (deadpan) Yes could I have a drink,
please. Just some ale.
MATT: "Coming right up. Any preferences for the
family? Baumbauch?"
LAURA: Stay clear of Baumbauch. They're dicks.
MARISHA: That's kind of true.
ASHLEY: Just a big.
MATT: "Husseldorf, then. All right. Be right
back." And she wanders off.
TALIESIN: Well. Who has coin for a fortune?
LAURA: Do you know my name?
TALIESIN: What is your name?
LAURA: Jester.
TALIESIN: I know your name now!
LAURA and TALIESIN: (laugh)
LAURA: What is your name?
TALIESIN: Oh, my name is Molly to my friends, and
we're friends, now, aren't we? Pleasure.
LAURA: Molly. Look at this guy.
TALIESIN: Mollymauk. Molly for short. This is
Yasha, she's a charm.
ASHLEY: Hello.
MARISHA: Yasha. Yasha.
TALIESIN: Now. Would anyone like a fortune read?
LAURA: I would love one.
TALIESIN: Do you have coin?
LAURA: Yes. How much do you want?
TALIESIN: Two copper.
LAURA: Two copper, okay, I just got some copper.
Here you go.
MATT: Mark down your two copper. (laughs)
TALIESIN: I am taking this in. All right. (sighs)
I'm going to try and do this.
LAURA: Oh my gosh, really?
MATT: So, as he pulls out a small set of cards and
begins to shuffle them, go ahead and roll an
insight check.
ASHLEY: (deadpan) He's really quite good, you
all should line up and get your fortunes told.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Let's do a 16 there.
MATT: Okay, so you get a brief conversation here,
you get a pretty solid read: the excitability, the
eagerness, and the exuberant interest in just
getting in your face that this person wants-- any
fortune you tell will probably suffice. Go ahead
and roll a sleight-of-hand check as well.
SAM: Look at this fucking game!
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Also 16.
MATT: Yeah. And you feel pretty confident that her
eyes are locked onto your eyes at the moment and
not the deck, as you set up a proper reading. And
the cards are shuffled, set, you place them before
you, and you may give your fortune.
SAM: I'm going to just keep my eyes open for any
tricks of the hand, sleight-of-hand-y-type tricks.
MATT: Make a perception check.
SAM: Okay. Perception. 14.
MATT: 14. All right. Everything seems pretty
above-board.
TALIESIN: Your first card, the Silver Dragon. This
is good. You're pure, you're virtue, you are a
worthwhile and wonderful human being, obviously,
or creature of some repute.
LAURA: That's what everyone always tells me.
TALIESIN: It's true. And heading towards the
Anvil.
LAURA: What is that?
TALIESIN: That is a destiny forged.
ASHLEY: (deadpan) Ohh.
TALIESIN: There is something bright and
adventurous in your future.
LAURA: Wow! You know, we did just defeat a really
big snake? So maybe there's even bigger things
coming up, you know?
TALIESIN: Can I make another roll?
MATT: Sure.
SAM: Ashley confirmed worst hype-man ever.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: 19.
MATT: Yeah, easy enough. Even with discerning eyes
at the table, you are at the top of your game.
TALIESIN: The Serpent card appears. Of course you
did.
LAURA: (gasps) Oh my gosh! Look at that! How did
you even do that?
TALIESIN: That's all the cards. I'm simply a
vessel for higher powers.
LIAM: While everybody's watching this shit happen,
may I cast Detect Magic?
MATT: You may. You lean back and subtly begin a brief
muttering of an incantation, your fingers wash
through the air, a faint silver gleam across your
fingertips. Nothing magical shows up in the
immediate vicinity.
LAURA: Will you ask the cards if I'm going to find
him?
TALIESIN: If you're going to find her?
LAURA: Him.
TALIESIN: Give me a little bit more. Who's this
'him' that you're looking for?
LAURA: I'm looking for my dad.
TALIESIN: 14.
MATT: You fumble for a second, but the card still
finds its way through without issue.
TALIESIN: Pushing through, pushing through. The
Eye card pulls up. You've already found the clue
you're looking for. You just don't know what it is
yet.
LAURA: Really?
TALIESIN: Apparently. Well, it's what the cards
are saying. It's right in front of you.
LAURA: Wow. Does it say how long ago I found it?
Because that's--
TALIESIN: Sadly, I don't have that sort of
specifics. That's much more expensive.
LAURA: That's going to take a lot of thinking.
TALIESIN: Well, you find us at the show, you'll
find my tent and I'd be happy to give you a more
complicated reading.
LAURA: I can't wait! It's going to be so much
fun.
TALIESIN: So much fun.
MATT: Yasha, at this point, the barmaid, Adelaine,
comes up and hands you the ordered ale.
ASHLEY: Thank you, my lady.
MATT: "On the house."
TALIESIN: On the house!
ASHLEY: That's very kind of you.
MARISHA: Do you perform in the circus, too?
ASHLEY: No. I do not. I just-- I put it up.
MARISHA: Oh, cool.
TRAVIS: The tent.
LAURA: It's a big tent. It would take a lot of
work.
ASHLEY: I put up the stage, I move things around.
I'm very strong. But I don't do anything in the show.
TALIESIN: Some of our acts are a little
complicated, with performers who are not of the
traditional variety. Can make some of the locals
get a little shifty, if you know what I mean, and
it's good to have a few people around who are
capable of keeping issues contained.
MARISHA: Is that why it says 'No admittance to the
elderly'? You don't want to deal with those riley
elderly. Or the ill, yeah. Why no elderly, though?
Ill kind of makes sense, but elderly?
TALIESIN: We cannot be held responsible for
anything that may happen to someone who is ill or
infirm. It is such an exciting, impressive show.
ASHLEY: We've had people die watching it.
Yeah. It's just that exciting. Just from
excitement.
TRAVIS: Did they die in the show, or from watching
it?
ASHLEY: Yeah, just like heart attack. Just from
getting so excited, I guess.
MARISHA: We gotta get so wasted.
LAURA: When is it? How long is it? When is it?
MATT: It is actually the day of Grissen, and your
first show is today.
TALIESIN: First show is tonight.
LAURA: Well, we have plans tonight!
MARISHA: Yay!
LAURA: Do you stinky people want to come with us?
SAN: I-- Caleb, we don't have any plans tonight. I
guess we could go along. I wouldn't mind seeing it.
MARISHA: It'll be fun!
TALIESIN: Or you could stay here and buy beer for
the people who do see the shows, and you can hear
all about it and pay more.
LIAM: Yeah, we can go.
LAURA: It's going to be so much fun.
SAM: Yeah, yeah, it sounds like a good night.
Yeah.
LAURA: Look at all these friends we're making
here. This is a good city.
SAM: Yeah, it is.
MARISHA: Yeah, yeah.
TALIESIN: You are all the most charming people I've
met in-- yes. I finish my beer. (sighs) Well, we'd
better be getting on.
ASHLEY: Yep, nice to meet you all. You're so, uh,
wonderful.
TALIESIN: Charm. Pure charm. See you tonight!
MATT: And as they leave you, Yasha just downs her
entire ale, slams it on the table, and they both
walk out, passing a couple more flyers at off
tables, and then exit out to the rest of the day's
sun beyond your sight.
MARISHA: She was awesome.
TRAVIS: She didn't say much.
MARISHA: That's why I liked her.
LAURA: She was really, really cool. Did you see
that cool thing she had going on with her chin?
That's interesting. I wish I would have thought of
something like that.
MARISHA: Yeah, I mean, you could maybe do
something like that in time. Just wait until
maybe--
LAURA: So she doesn't know I copied. I can't do it
tonight.
MARISHA: No, no.
LAURA: Wow. Cool. What do you guys want to do
now?
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Was he using magic?
LAURA: I don't know.
MARISHA: Are you-- you're superstitious. Yeah?
LAURA: No.
MARISHA: Okay.
LAURA: No, I'm not superstitious at all.
MARISHA: You-- sure.
LAURA: Why?
MARISHA: I mean, what he was working in was-- he
was doing a little like-- he-- he's a smart guy.
He's a smart guy.
LAURA: By the way, did you open your Christmas
present from me?
TALIESIN: No, not yet, no.
LAURA: You should go open it! Yes! Go grab the
bag!
TALIESIN: On the break. On the break, I'll grab
it.
SAM: Hey, Matt. Dungeon master. They're wearing
what they described. They're not wearing any
cloaks or anything right now, are they?
MATT: Both of them have small cloaks over the
shoulders, Beau has a--
SAM: Do I recognize those cloaks?
MATT: No, you do not.
LAURA: What? Why would you recognize the cloaks?
SAM: Maybe I saw something. I don't know.
MATT: No, you do not.
SAM: I didn't see them last night?
MATT: No.
SAM: Okay. Interesting.
MARISHA: Mysteries.
LIAM: Also, for the record, there was nothing
magic about that. Maybe he's good at reading
people, but that was not magic.
SAM: Caleb knows everything about magic. He's been
even teaching me some. He's real good. You should
see him--
LIAM: Nott--
LAURA: Caleb, are you going to go the Academy?
LIAM: (strained laugh) That's silly.
SAM: He could if he wanted to. He's really good at
magic. He can make a cat appear and disappear
whenever he wants.
LAURA: Really? A cat?
LIAM: (snaps)
MATT: You watch as just beneath the table, this
orange patchy tabby leaps up.
MARISHA: Oh, shit! What's his name?
LAURA: Or her name!
LIAM: Well, it is a he. This is my cat Frumpkin.
Frumpkin, yes.
LAURA: Aw! Can I call him Lumpy?
LIAM: You can call him Frumpkin.
LAURA: Look at this Lumpy! Made in England.
(laughter)
LIAM: That was a little show gift from Marisha, so
this is Frumpkin.
LAURA: That's so great.
SAM: That's not all he can do. Caleb, tell them all
the stuff you can do. It's really impressive!
LIAM: You know, sometimes less is more.
LAURA: I can do things, too.
SAM: With magic?
LAURA: Yeah.
SAM: Like what?
LAURA: Like--
SAM: Not to me, not to me!
LAURA: Like-- oh, gosh. Okay. I'm going to use
Thaumaturgy and I'm going to make all the windows
in the place open up really fast, like crash
open.
MATT: Okay. You watch as four of the nearby
windows slam open with a sudden burst of wind, and
all the various bits of torchlight that light the
deeper and more shadowed corners of the room
suddenly darken and flicker. The music suddenly
comes to a stop. Everyone holds their position and
glances over at the table where you're all sitting.
TRAVIS: Jester, don't you remember us talking
about keeping a low profile?
LAURA: You're right. I'm sorry. I use Thaumaturgy
and I close all the windows.
(laughter)
MATT: They all slam shut a second time. The light
flickers and then brightens back to its normal place.
LAURA: Ta-da!
MARISHA: Yeah! Yeah!
LAURA: Come see me tonight at the carnival! I'm
really good!
MATT: One really crotchety-looking guy in his
early 50s with a super underbite, probably missing
most of his teeth, just goes--
(laughter)
LIAM: I telepathically tell Frumpkin to jump up
and sit in the lap of the woman in the monk's
robes who just made a big scene and hopefully keep
her occupied with being cute.
MATT: Okay. As soon as you sit down, Frumpkin
leaps into your lap and starts purring and rubbing
up against your hand.
MARISHA: Hey, buddy. Look at this kitty! I think
he likes me.
LIAM: Sure, right now he likes you.
MARISHA: Is this a real cat? Or is this a fake
cat?
LIAM: What do you mean, a fake cat?
MARISHA: Like a magic cat.
LIAM: He's both a real cat and a magic cat.
MARISHA: Is he an illusion cat?
LIAM: Do you feel him?
TRAVIS: Could you put him over there?
MARISHA: Are you allergic to Frumpkins? Oh no!
LAURA: But he's a magic cat. How can you be
allergic to magic cats?
TRAVIS: I'm pretty sure he's a real fucking cat.
MARISHA: He's one of those hypoallergenic magic
cats.
LIAM: I don't know what the Fifth Edition rules
are--
LAURA: --for cat dander?
MATT: As far as you know right now? Yeah, he's
having an actual allergic attack. A minor one.
MARISHA: I walk away a little bit from Fjord.
LIAM: Shit.
(laughter)
SAM: Well, you're both magic-users, then. And so
is the larger fellow?
TRAVIS: Well, I mean, a little.
LAURA: Yeah, I mean, he's learning. He's getting
really good at it.
TRAVIS: Trying to learn more.
LAURA: Yeah, you should have seen him. He
disguised himself the other day, and it was like,
(clicks tongue).
TRAVIS: Thanks, Jester. She's better at it than I
am. We're trying to make our way up to the Academy
to get a little bit more learning done.
LAURA: Well, he's going to learn. I'm not going to
go to the Academy.
MARISHA: Man, this Academy place keeps getting
brought up.
TRAVIS: Well yeah, it's the place to be.
MARISHA: Okay.
SAM: I'm sorry, what Academy are we talking
about?
TRAVIS: Solstryce Academy. You know.
MATT: Soltryce.
LAURA: Yeah, that one.
SAM: The Soul Train Academy.
LIAM: It's a very fancy place.
TRAVIS: You know it.
LIAM: I have heard of it.
TRAVIS: And you have arcane talents as well.
LIAM: Yeah.
LAURA: How long have you had yours?
LIAM: That's a tricky question. I studied when I
was younger, and then I gave it up for a while. I
picked it up again recently. It's all
book-learned.
LAURA: Wow, that's cool.
MARISHA: This was a good way to go for your
first.
LAURA: A frickin' cat!
MARISHA: This is kind of therapeutic. Making me
feel better, just about life in general.
TRAVIS: (sneezes)
MARISHA: All right.
SAM: He reads lots of books, Caleb does. He's very
smart. In fact, should we go looking for more
right now?
LIAM: Maybe in a little while.
LAURA: Can I see one of your books?
LIAM: Well-- and I pull apart the lapels of my
coat. I have books in what modern-day people like
to think of as holster-straps, but there's a book
hanging here.
SAM: I think ancient people would call it a
holster as well.
LIAM: Bap-bap-bap. The books are right here. I
have these, but these are heirlooms, family
heirlooms, so I don't share those, but-- no, I
like to read. That's all. And I'm a bit of a
self-starter, so I have to find-- I mean, good
luck at the Academy. That's rough, I hear.
TRAVIS: Do you know anything about it? We're just
going up. Beginner's luck.
LAURA: We know it's rich people that go there. We
have to find a way to get you in.
LIAM: All I know is how hard it is to get into.
SAM: You don't have a lot of money, then?
LAURA: Well.
TRAVIS: No.
LAURA: We had more.
MARISHA: But then we lost it, but then we got it
back.
TRAVIS: Somebody has a gambling problem.
SAM: Oh. Which one?
LAURA: What's the name of it again?
MATT: It is the Crick-Queen's Call.
LAURA: Have you played it?
SAM: No, I haven't.
LAURA: I'll teach you someday. It's so much fun.
SAM: It's a game?
LAURA: Yes.
SAM: Cards? All right. I might like to know that.
LAURA: I mean, I can teach you, if you want.
SAM: Yes, I would like to know that.
LAURA: Okay, I'll deal!
SAM: Oh, right now?
LAURA: Yes, sure, this will be fun.
SAM: Is this okay?
LIAM: Listen, I would not be sitting here if it
were not for you. Do whatever you like.
LAURA: Okay. You draw three cards. Well, I give
you three cards. So you use 3d6.
SAM: 3d6.
LAURA: Yeah.
SAM: Got one. I'm not you. I have one of each
dice.
(laughter)
LAURA: Okay. So hide your roll from me, because we
can't know. So first you have to ante up. How much
coin do you want to put in?
SAM: I'm out.
(laughter)
LIAM: It's all right. I will front some coin for
you to play this game.
LAURA: Oh, great! How much do you want to front
him?
LIAM: I will give you a silver piece.
LAURA: A silver. Okay, this is great.
SAM: Thank you, Caleb. Thank you.
LIAM: Wish I had more.
LAURA: Okay. Am I doing this right?
MATT: So far.
LAURA: Now I'm going to give us three cards, so we
both roll, but we can't see. That's good. Okay.
MARISHA: Don't say 'that's good'.
LAURA: Bluffing. How do you know I wasn't?
SAM: I'm going to try to change one of my cards.
LAURA: No, wait, there's rules!
SAM: Without you seeing.
MATT: Make a sleight-of-hand check.
SAM: 12 plus eight, so that's 20.
MATT: Make a perception check.
LAURA: No, he totally did it. She totally did it.
This is really hard, Sam.
LIAM: You're only an hour and a half in.
SAM: This is my only skill, guys.
LAURA: But, you know, that's my skill, too.
SAM: Oh, shit.
LAURA: So I'm going to try to do it as well,
'cause that's my skill as well.
MATT: Well, first, what'd you roll for--
LAURA: I did not notice him doing it.
MATT: Okay, yeah, so you only get to reroll one of
the dice.
LAURA: Okay, so I'm going to try to reroll one of
my three, too.
MATT: Go ahead. So make a sleight-of-hand check.
LAURA: Oh, right. Oh, shit.
SAM: Do I notice her?
MATT: Well, roll a perception check.
SAM: Nope.
LAURA: 13?
SAM: No, I rolled three.
LAURA: Okay. So the best hand you can get is three
of a kind. Then, after that, it's a straight. A
high straight. Then a low straight. Then it's if
you get all evens, or if you get all odds, then
it's two of a kind, then it's nothing, it's just
high card. Okay, but now we put in a second
amount, because you can up the ante, and you get
one more card.
SAM: I'm out.
LAURA: No, but wait, wait, wait. You can put in
more money, and then I deal you a different card.
You get to give a card back, and then I deal you
another card.
SAM: Should I? Caleb, do you have any more?
LIAM: Because you saved my life yesterday, you may
have one more silver piece.
LAURA: One more silver. Okay, I'll keep it low,
too, because you're only doing the one. So I only
put in one silver, too.
MATT: That's a four-silver pot.
LAURA: Yes. And now give one of your dice back,
whichever one you don't want, and roll it again.
MATT: So you get to reroll.
SAM: Okay, got it.
MATT: And you get to reroll one as well.
LAURA: I don't want to reroll any. Okay. Now you
show what you got and we'll see who wins.
SAM: I got a pair of fours.
LAURA: I got three fives.
SAM: I draw my shortsword.
(laughter)
MARISHA: I immediately grapple him.
MATT: Make an athletics check. You make an
acrobatics check.
SAM: Acrobatics? 24.
MARISHA: 14.
MATT: So the female goblin draws a shortsword. You
reach out to grab, and she slips out of your grasp
and is now holding the blade at the edge of the
table.
SAM: You're cheating. Somehow you're cheating.
LIAM: Nott, Nott, that's fine. That's fine. She
won my two silver pieces. We'll just leave it at that.
SAM: I'm sorry.
LIAM: That's okay. She's very jumpy sometimes. You
can understand; we've been living in the woods for
a long time. Every time we come near any place
like this, we're attacked, jumped, followed. So I
apologize on behalf of--
SAM: That was stupid. I'm sorry. I shouldn't have
done that. I'm sorry.
LAURA: No, it's okay. Just don't do it again. But
I'm sorry I took all this money from your friend.
LIAM: That's making it worse.
TRAVIS: Maybe you could give some of it back.
LAURA: Why, though? But I won it.
SAM: Your Laura is showing.
(laughter)
LAURA: Tell you what. I'll give you-- none of it
back, I can't! Okay, here's one silver back--
LIAM: No, I insist.
LAURA: Okay, but I insist, all the money back. All
right, fine, it's mine, thank you. Yay.
SAM: I need another drink.
LIAM: A round of Trosts for both our tables,
please.
LAURA: See? Isn't that the most fun?
SAM: It's fun.
MATT: Yorda looks over and goes, "Any preference
of family?"
LIAM: Not Baumbauch.
MATT: "Von Brandt it is."
MARISHA: I'm impressed that you stuck to taking a
guy's money in a training game.
LAURA: Right? Oh, wait, is that bad?
MARISHA: Meh.
LAURA: Well, I only learned last night, you guys.
LIAM: What is a training game?
MARISHA: Just meaning when she was teaching.
LAURA: People took my money when I was learning.
LIAM: It's fine. It's water under the bridge. It's
fine. It's all right.
MATT: Another round is brought to your table. You
guys can share a solemn post-game drink amongst
yourselves.
LIAM: If you feel slightly worse, there's a drink
on me.
LAURA: Oh jeez, now I'm definitely giving you your
two silver back. Don't worry about it, man.
(laughter)
SAM: She's just a couple of wild and crazy guys
over here.
(laughter)
LAURA: Have my baked goods come out yet?
MATT: They have. Your meal's been presented for a
while now. You've had the opportunity to eat most
of your meal.
SAM: That's real.
MATT: That is actually real. That's the power of
imagination, Sam. That wasn't there a second ago.
TALIESIN: Bangarang!
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Right there for you.
MATT: So you all finish your independent meals and
decide to continue your conversations or go about
your business for the day.
LAURA: I just want to go to the carnival.
LIAM: That's later tonight, though, isn't it?
MATT: If you have no other business, we can wait
until dusk.
SAM: Well, there's that board on the wall. Has
anything new been posted on the board?
MATT: You go ahead and take a look at it. There is
one sheet that pertains to somebody in the Hills
Ward looking for folks to go ahead and do an
extermination run near the southern portion of the
Ustaloch. It looks like there's what looks to be
a vole infestation.
TRAVIS: What the fuck is a vole?
MATT: It's a small rat.
LAURA: Should we do it?
MARISHA: I mean, we have to kill Rodents of
Unusual Size.
SAM: That doesn't sound interesting to me at all.
TRAVIS: What else is there?
MATT: Currently, it looks like there was another
sheet that looks like most has been torn off. The
rest of the board is pretty empty at the moment.
LIAM: DM, did I tear that? I can't remember.
MATT: You did, yes.
SAM: Wasn't it a delivery thing?
LIAM: That was what it was, yeah.
MATT: It was to help move and load crates at one
of the local breweries.
SAM: Fuck that.
LAURA: We've done that. It sucked so much.
SAM: You did that?
LAURA: Well, by mistake.
MARISHA: We played D&D and we moved crates for
eight hours.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: We did, yeah.
MATT: Welcome to level two.
SAM: We said no to that job, thank you.
TRAVIS: We get bored pretty easily.
MARISHA: We did, however, then gamble with the
other workers and then Jester-- yeah. Jester--
LAURA: Well, I lost it, but he made so much.
TRAVIS: Maybe not out loud say that. Just a
thought.
MARISHA: Oh, that's right. We probably shouldn't.
We didn't make any money.
LAURA: Do you guys want company? Do you want us to
come and hang out with you today?
SAM: I don't know about that. That sounds risky, I
don't know.
LIAM: Do you know something? I, shockingly, think
that's not a bad idea.
SAM: To have these weirdos with us?
LAURA: I can hear you.
LIAM: Yesterday was a very bad day.
SAM: Yes. Well, I suppose if we surrounded
ourselves with weirdos, then maybe it would take
some of heat off of me.
LIAM: Well, yes. Bottom line: can you hang with
the goblin?
LAURA: Bottom line-- and I touch Nott's shoulder,
and I cast Blessing of the Trickster.
SAM: Oh, Jesus, she's going to kill me right now.
(laughter)
SAM: Any magic kills a goblin instantly. Yeah,
instantly.
(laughter)
LAURA: That would be the worst character choice
ever.
(laughter)
LIAM: We will mourn her. Tschuss.
MATT: Okay, so there's a slight sense of warmth
that emanates from under her hand, and for a
moment, you look over and glance instinctively,
ready to almost draw your sword again. But it
seems to quicken your reflexes. You have this
surge of adrenaline that doesn't quite fade.
LAURA: You have advantage on all your stealth
checks.
MATT: For the next hour.
SAM: Thank you. That's very nice.
TRAVIS: I don't have a problem with goblins, but
you guys aren't in any trouble, are you? No one's
after you?
LAURA: Because she is all kinds of trouble.
SAM: No one is after me!
TRAVIS: Can I make an insight check?
MATT: You may.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: 13.
MATT: 13. If you want to go ahead and try and
lie.
SAM: That's a 14, except negative three to
performance.
TALIESIN: I've been waiting for this for so long.
SAM: So 11.
MATT: So, are you lying?
SAM: I am lying. I am definitely on the run from
someone.
TRAVIS: Good to know.
MARISHA: So. Mask. I'm just fascinated by the
mask. Looks well-made. Did you make it?
SAM: That's a good fucking question. Did I make
it?
(laughter)
SAM: I don't make things.
MATT: No, I presume-- and we discussed this a
little bit-- we presume it may have been scavenged
from a porcelain doll.
SAM: Oh, that's cool. Cool and gross, cool and
gross.
LAURA: What's her name? The creepy doll?
TRAVIS: Annabelle.
(laughter)
LAURA: No, don't say that. I don't want to see art
with you with Annabelle's face.
SAM: Too late.
MATT: The internet's running with that now.
SAM: Check your Twitter.
TRAVIS: It seems we have all day. What were your
plans?
LIAM: Not much. We were going to sample the
different Trosts, and I wanted to maybe do some
book browsing. Nothing major.
LAURA: What's a Trost?
MARISHA: Brewery tour!
SAM: It's ale.
LAURA: We just can't go by the Baumbauch ale.
SAM: What happened with the Baumbauchs?
LIAM: There are two others to choose from, here.
MARISHA: They're who we loaded crates for, and
then we kind of swindled their employee.
TRAVIS: Didn't leave on the best of terms.
LIAM: DM, which one is the one that everybody
knows has got the blessing of Fryda Langer?
MATT: No, that is actually the Baumbauch.
LIAM: Shit.
MATT: Yeah, the Starosta is kind of tied with the
Baumbauch family.
TALIESIN: We're imaginary beer snobs now.
LAURA: Is that the one you need?
LIAM: No, I'm just saying the one that you
swindled, it's got the blessing of the big cheese here.
LAURA: Oh. Well. Why do you need it?
LIAM: We don't need it. It's just pleasurable to
have a Trost, is what they say. She kind of needs it.
SAM: I need it a little bit.
LAURA: You need a beer?
SAM: Well, I prefer the harder stuff, but I'll
take what I can get at this point. Yeah, I'm
sticking with this fucking accent for the next two
years.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Laryngitis every Friday.
MARISHA: So beer tour, then circus?
LAURA: I've got to say, I miss those two people we
ran into at the carnival.
TRAVIS: I might just wait for the carnival,
actually.
MARISHA: Well, if we just montage through a beer
tour, we'll quickly get to the circus. To the
carnival!
MATT: You can totally do that.
LIAM: Can we just bring my book-browsing down to a
single roll to see if anything of use--
MATT: Yeah, we can do that. We'll say, if you guys
decide to go ahead and travel, the five of you,
you make your way through the town for the day,
you coast around the Husseldorf family brewery,
you meet Voss and June, who are the two very nice
ladies who run the facility. The Husseldorf
family. You avoid the Baumbauch, but can acquire
Baumbauch ale from other taverns in the town, of
course. And the von Brandt family brewery. All of them, as
soon as you say 'Trost', they correct you and say
the family name. They're very intent on getting
rid of the name 'Trost' as an overall, discussion
of Trost-brand brews, and trying to make it their
family name. There's an offense, to the point
where you're like, "Oh, Jesus. I didn't realize."
TALIESIN: Like Kleenex and tissue paper? All
right.
MATT: But you manage to get nice and sauced
throughout the day.
LIAM: I take it easy. I have one more in the first
half of the day, and one in the second half.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: I don't have very much either.
SAM: I'm going to have tons.
MARISHA: I get sauced.
MATT: All right, well, that being the case--
LIAM: --you are poisoned.
MATT: No, make a constitution saving throw.
SAM: Well, that was crazy. 12.
MATT: 12, okay. You get a little woozy for a
while, and as the sun begins to crawl towards the
distant horizon, you do not manage to allow your
meal to usurp your control.
LAURA: Aw, it's like Ren Faire.
MATT: Yeah. Don't remind me.
MARISHA: Good times, good times.
MATT: So as the day comes to a close, you're
fairly tipsy, you're not fully intoxicated. For
your trip, you wanted to head to the Hillsbrook
Parchment and Binding.
LIAM: Is that where I went the last time? Except
not as myself. So I'll go as myself.
MATT: Okay. Go ahead and make an investigation
check.
LIAM: All right. Don't fuck me, Vax. That is--
LAURA: That's Vax. That's Vax's dice.
LIAM: Yeah, the thing about even a light German
accent is that when you say "Vex" and "Vax", it's
the same shit.
(laughter)
LIAM: That is a 12.
MATT: 12. You take the better part of 30 minutes
or so, and you find there's a lot of books on
farming techniques. There's a lot of books about
how to grow, care for different types of
vegetation, plants, various beasts of burden. You
find books on the different seasons and what's
best for different types of grain and wheats. You
manage to pull through and find a couple of books
that deal with discussion of the Menagerie Coast
that talk about what's called the Clovis Concord.
It's more of a discussion of the political
structure that maintains all the city-states there.
LIAM: And the person who ran this place was an
older man, right? Just sipping tea.
MATT: Yeah, Sheenah, yeah.
LIAM: I'm sorry. You have a nice selection here.
Do you mind if I ask-- I haven't seen any other
booksellers of any kind in town. I'm not really
looking for anything on farming, so much. Is there
anywhere else I could look into?
MATT: "If you're looking for some sort of a
library, your best bet is to go to Zadash up north."
LIAM: Zadash.
MATT: "That's where the Library of the Cobalt Soul
resides. They have all the information you could
"hope for. A bit pricey to peruse their interior,
unless you have proper coverage, but unfortunately
"if what we have isn't what you're looking for, I
can't help you."
LIAM: No, it's a fine selection. Sorry. How much
for this book on hoe technique?
MATT: "Oh! Jamieson's Hoedown, yes, quite. That
will be two silver pieces."
LIAM: Oh. I'm very embarrassed, I'm sorry, I gave
away my last two silver pieces.
LAURA: No, I gave it back to you, remember?
LIAM: I gave away my last two silver pieces, so.
Maybe I can earn it back and come back later this week.
MATT: "Please do. Do you want me to hold it for
you?"
LIAM: Yes.
MATT: "What's your name?"
LIAM: My name is Caleb Widogast.
MATT: "All right. I will keep it here under the
shelf. Thank you so much."
LIAM: Okay, good day, thank you.
LAURA: Is this a big shop?
MATT: It's a boutique. It's designed almost like a
cross. There's two cross-sections of hallways that
have books across the walls, and there's a window
at the end of each and then a door at the far back.
LAURA: While he was talking to the shopkeeper, I'm
going to take out as many books as I can and move
them around on the shelves, and then take some of
them and turn them around to where their binding
is facing the inside.
MATT: Go ahead and make a sleight-of-hand check.
LAURA: Natural 20!
MATT: Over the period of him searching and
distracting this man, you have completely
rearranged the interior of this bookstore, to the
point where even in the far corner, you
Ghostbusters stack them in the center of the room,
floor-to-ceiling, with him not even noticing it.
LIAM: You little fucking poltergeist.
MATT: You feel confident and happy and a sensation
of approval washes over you. All right, so.
LAURA: I skip out the door.
MATT: Okay. You turn around from having this
conversation and notice the interior is not as you
last saw it, and a bit of nerves begin to brew up
under you.
LIAM: Frumpkin, come on.
MATT: (meows) Frumpkin follows behind.
LIAM: Oh yes! Matt's got to make cat sounds now!
MATT: I didn't even think about that until now.
God damn it. All right, so as you guys have
gathered at this point, the oranges and the pinks
of dusk begin to peek through the quite-cloudy
sky, the chilled air of the coming night sky
signalling the Crown's Guard to begin lighting the
hanging lanterns that line the streets of
Trostenwald. A renewed energy takes the streets as
the sound of a fiddle seems to creep through the
night air.
SAM: My god, Ashley's a master fiddler, isn't
she?
ASHLEY: Beedle-deedle.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: I love how your fiddle noises were
"beedle-deedle".
ASHLEY: That's the sound for all instruments,
right?
SAM: Drums.
LIAM: By the way, DM, can I ask-- sometime in the
entire day, when Nott was getting wasted, could I
have spent an hour using Arcane Recovery to gain
back that one spell slot I used this morning?
MATT: Sure, yeah. I'll allow that. All right.
Folks begin to prod their heads out into the open
air, curious about the source of this unusual din,
and you find your vision capturing a small
procession of flamboyantly dressed people parading
through the central road. A lanky man of some
obvious elven descent leads the pack, his long,
ashy-brown hair curling ever-so-slightly past his
mid-back, his long coat and tails knocking around
by his skipping step. Two halfling women in purple
and green bodysuits dance from side to side,
handing flowers to children and flyers to adults,
as a bald man in a neck-frilled frock coat of
bright red, his face adorned in vibrant orange
makeup to look like the setting sun behind him,
plays the violin that you heard earlier in an
upbeat, jovial manner. A tall half-orc masculine
man with a well-groomed handlebar mustache that
curves out to the side, billowing white silk shirt
and black trousers, follows behind with a big drum
slung over his shoulder, going (drumming) along with the
fiddle. The tiefling man of lavender skin that you
saw earlier walks along with a grin, juggling two
curved scimitars as he walks in place, almost
loses one and catches it, continues to go.
Families are beginning to gather out to see this
display. The two dancers part, and then a woman of
short, fiery red hair and dark skin walking
between them, lifting a small candle before--
fwoosh! A giant burst, a gout of flame emerges
from the front of her mouth, brightens the
vicinity, and everyone collectively gasps and
begins cheering and clapping as they continue the
walk. There, to the back of it, you see the rather
burly-looking pale woman, arms crossed, just
following behind and keeping an eye like a
security guard to ensure that no business gets out
of hand. The gasps and the cheers begin to follow,
and as the procession continues down its way, the
families and civilians begin to gather and follow
behind. As the last bit of the sun sets behind the
mountain range, the torches glowing, the
procession curves through the center of the Loch
Ward to the edge of the Ustaloch itself. Through
the fishing village, more folks begin to gather.
Do you all follow?
ALL: Yeah.
LAURA: And I cast Blessing of the Trickster on you
again, just in case.
SAM: Thank you.
MATT: People following the parade, you see faces,
eager for this fresh form of entertainment.
Children laugh and chatter excitedly, while the
Crown's Guard in their familiar bronze and
vermilion uniform try to maintain order between
themselves being quite curious or visibly
mistrusting of these hooligans that suddenly have
usurped the evening air. The procession continues
towards the eastern side, out along the southern
edge of this Loch Ward, to the Ustaloch's
southern place, towards the new, completely
constructed, large, dark blue tent. Lengthy
streamers of white and silver flap with the cold
winds from the top of the structure. As you guys
walk, you watch as the horned tiefling you had
approached earlier slowly saunters up to your
side, you recognizing these individuals you had
spoken with earlier.
MARISHA: I go, Molly! Molly, hey!
TALIESIN: Oh, it's my favorites. Hello.
LAURA: We came!
TALIESIN: I'm so glad you all came to see the
show. It's going to be great tonight.
ASHLEY: (deadpan) It's going to blow you away.
(laughter)
SAM: The hype continues.
ASHLEY: You're going to love it.
TALIESIN: First show of a round's always the best.
Without fail.
MARISHA: Where are the best seats?
TALIESIN: Well, I'm always partial to the front.
Then you're right in it, if something goes wrong,
it's nothing between you and whatever terrible,
bloody mess is going to happen. It's just the best.
MARISHA: What?
TALIESIN: Nothing, nothing, you're fine.
ASHLEY: It's going to be great, but before you go
in, I do have to give you guys a pat-down, 'cause
you can't go in with any weapons.
MATT: At this point, a voice rings out behind you,
you see as the carnival master Gustav glances over
your shoulder and goes, "You two, skip ahead,
quick. We need to go ahead and set up. Looks like
"we're already having quite a few people excited to
come here, so at the door, interior to set up.
"Meet us at the front. Actually, you know what?
You'll be on card duty. We need a little extra
"change on the side."
TALIESIN: Card duty it is.
MATT: "All right. Folks, excited for your
patronage." As he spins around and addresses the
whole crowd now and says, "Enjoy the night air.
Walk slowly. We need just a moment to set up." And
the half-elf man bows and tips his large-- it
looks almost like a top hat that gets floppy
towards the top and flops forward, and he puts it
back on top and begins sauntering, continuing the
music, but picking up their pace to get ahead of
the crowd as they draw you all slowly towards the
exterior tent. And that's where we're going to go
ahead and take our break.
(yelling)
TRAVIS: Face is on fire.
LAURA: Am I the only one going, do we really have
to give up our weapons? I don't feel okay with this.
SAM: Ashley, I'll do whatever you want, but if you
take my weapons I might kill you.
ASHLEY: I'd like to see you try.
(yelling)
MATT: All right, so. We'll be back here in a few
minutes. We're going to take a quick break. We
have our weekly giveaway from our friends at
Wyrmwood. We have a white oak complete dice tower
system that's a three-piece set. That's going to
be given away to one of you there in the chat. The
password, if I recall, is 'beginnings'. Yeah. This
one. If you're in the Twitch chat, if you want to
be part of this, when you're prompted there, go
ahead and enter the word 'beginnings' once. If you
enter it more than once, you'll get disqualified,
so be careful with that. Otherwise, it gets this
spamming spree of chaos. So the word is
'beginnings'. When prompted, go ahead and enter
that, and we'll come back from the break with the
winner of that. Regardless, guys, welcome to the
beginning of the new campaign.
(yelling)
MATT: We'll see you here in a few minutes.
LIAM: Magic!
LAURA: Magic!
[break]
MATT: Welcome back, ladies and gentlemen. Guys!
Wow!
LIAM: Grenade lobbed in by Foster at the last
second.
MATT: I know. Welcome back. So, first and
foremost, we have our winner of the white oak
complete dice tower from our friends at Wyrmwood.
The winner is GTDevoto. Congratulations. Denova
will reach out to you and get your contact
information. Everyone else, thank you for
entering. We'll have more with each future episode
of Critical Role, thanks to our friends at
Wyrmwood Gaming. Also, as a heads-up for those who
aren't familiar and for those who may be, we have
a Tuesday aftershow of this called Talks Machina
where our friend W. Brian Foster Esq., just mixing
up all of his names-- you guys know him, Brian W.
Foster, friend of the show, is the host of the
show, and he'll be there Tuesday talking about
this episode tonight with some of the cast. 7PM
Pacific time on Tuesday. So. Anyway.
(laughter)
MATT: Bringing us back.
TRAVIS: Bring that ass back.
SAM: Five dragons swoop down.
(laughter)
MATT: It's so hackneyed. As you guys begin to
approach the outside of this large, dark navy
tent, people are being inspected and ushered
through by the well-groomed half-orc on one side,
and the pale woman, Yasha, you met for a second
time approaching the outskirts of this carnival,
with entry fees being collected by both as people
begin to pass into this large structure. A few
feet off to the side, you see a small crowd
gathered around Mollymauk, who is sitting atop a
small blanket and has cards splayed before him, a
similar set that you saw Jester toying with
earlier, and a farmer sits across from him,
listening intently. "All right, so what can you
"tell me about this here cough?"
TALIESIN: How long have you had it?
MATT: "Oh, going on like three, four months."
(coughs)
TALIESIN: It looks like it's getting better. Oh
yes. Does it feel like it's getting better?
MATT: "Oh, right now? Yeah."
TALIESIN: Yeah, look at that. I would maybe
breathe a tincture or something. Let's-- yeah,
maybe you should get that looked at.
MATT: "From who? What do the cards tell me?"
TALIESIN: Some sort of physician, perhaps.
MATT: "Right! Of course! Oh, thank you so much."
And he places a--
TALIESIN: Platinum Dragon be with you. Thank you.
MATT: Stands up. "Dear, a physician!" And he walks
off.
(laughter)
MARISHA: What happened to 'no sick people'?
TALIESIN: This is outside the tent.
MATT: Yeah, he doesn't enter the tent. He goes off
to the side.
MARISHA: Fair.
TALIESIN: It's good to see you all here, though.
LAURA: Here's the thing. Some of us have weapons
that we don't want to pass away to other people,
so how much of a chance is it that we could get
through without having to do that, you know?
ASHLEY: Well, you can't see the show if you have a
weapon on you.
LAURA: Right. And we really want to see the show.
But, you know, we are really good at security,
like all of us are really strong, and we could
fight things that came up, too, so maybe it would
be best if you don't take our weapons, and then we
could help.
MARISHA: Actually, here's a deal. We'll make you a
good deal. You waive our entry fee and if anyone
needs to be kicked out, or any security needs to
happen, we'll help you out.
SAM: Like deputy bouncers?
MARISHA: Like deputy bouncers.
ASHLEY: Well, see, funny thing about that, though,
is that's my job. So.
LAURA: So do you want to hire us?
ASHLEY: No.
MARISHA: You would be like our boss. Have you ever
wanted to be a boss? Like, in charge?
ASHLEY: Well, I am.
LAURA: We could ask you for days off sometimes.
MATT: A heavy greenish-grey-skinned mitt slaps
onto Beau's shoulder, as you glance over to see
the large, well-groomed half-orc man standing
there. "I'm terribly sorry, but we've got it taken
"care of. If you wish to pay entry, you can, but
the rules are the rules. So sorry."
LIAM: Do they get stored in some sort of locker or
something?
ASHLEY: I hold them. And if you want, I can stand
right next to you guys. You can keep your eye on
me the whole time.
TALIESIN: She's very trustworthy.
LIAM: That seems fair-ish to me.
MATT: "Yasha, does that seem-- all right."
MARISHA: I look at him as I take his hand off.
What's your name, by the by?
MATT: "Bo."
MARISHA: Good name.
MATT: "Thank you."
LIAM: Well, that's funny, because your name is
also Beau.
MATT: "Really?"
MARISHA: You didn't have to-- maybe let me choose
when to tell people--
MATT: "No, no, I'm curious about this. How do you
spell your name?"
MARISHA: Well, it's short for Beauregard.
MATT: "Oh, mine's just B-O."
MARISHA: That's unfortunate. I mean, it's great.
Did kids make fun-- never mind.
MATT: "It's not inaccurate." And he flicks the
side of his mustache.
(laughter)
LAURA: Like, is his mustache especially B.O.-y?
Like, what? That's really gross.
MATT: Make a perception check.
LAURA: Ew. I don't want to perceive this. I'm glad
I didn't roll very well.
MARISHA: Can I make an insight check? Is he a
creep or is he just--
MATT: Make an insight check. Eight? Thankfully,
you're not in proximity enough to catch a whiff of
his mustache.
MARISHA: Natural 20.
MATT: Okay. Interestingly enough, he seems very
well put-together. And he seems like he's just
fucking with you. He's having fun, and he's
messing with you, and he's just casual and
competent and actually pretty well-groomed. He
doesn't smell. And he seems more just enjoying the
discourse.
MARISHA: It's funny, see, my name's Beau because
my parents wanted a son.
MATT: "Well. If it helps with any other confusion,
call me the Breaker. Well, if you see the rest of
"the show, perhaps you'll see why I got my name."
LAURA: Are you in the show, too?
MATT: And he cracks his arms. "I am. Towards the
end."
TRAVIS: Now I want to see the show.
MATT: "Well then. May I?" You can see now the
crowd's starting to queue up behind you pretty
heavily. "Besides, if you're going to enter, we've
got to get through the rest of this riff-raff. Do
"you wish to join in?"
LIAM: I pull-- all I have is a dagger, but I just
hand it to Yasha.
LAURA: Just one dagger?
ASHLEY: I promise you I will give it back.
LIAM: Yes, here you go.
ASHLEY: I promise you I will give you all of your
weapons back.
LAURA: Pinky-swear me, Yasha.
ASHLEY: Ugh. I don't like--
LAURA: Yeah! Now we're best friends. Here's my
sickle.
MARISHA: I have a staff, but I also use it as a
walking stick, so I like to keep it on me.
TALIESIN: Can you not walk around without it or
something?
LAURA: She has a really bad limp.
MARISHA: Sometimes I get a little twinge, a little
disc issue.
TALIESIN: Can you hand me your staff so I can
watch this? I want to see this limp of yours.
Purely for my own entertainment.
MARISHA: Are you patronizing me, Mollymauk?
TALIESIN: No, I'm hoping that you're going to
patronize us.
(laughter)
MARISHA: Can I keep my stick?
ASHLEY: How about this? I'll take it, and I can
just carry you to your seat.
MARISHA: Deal.
LAURA: How are you carrying all of these weapons?
ASHLEY: Because I'm really fucking strong.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: You. Can I give him a pat-down, because
you're--
MATT: Sure, roll an investigation check. I'll give
you advantage because you're really good at this.
LIAM: I open up the coat just so she can see the
books.
ASHLEY: I don't think I find anything. 12.
MATT: You find two books and a modicum of change
and nothing else on him. He's actually pretty
sparse as far as collectibles and keepsakes.
ASHLEY: I just thought your chest looked rather
square, so I wanted to see what was happening.
LIAM: I'm practically concave. Is it concave or
convex, I forget?
ALL: Concave.
MARISHA: Convex would be funny.
(laughter)
SAM: I'll hand her my shortsword, but not my
little crossbow.
MATT: Okay, make a sleight-of-hand check to try
and hide that.
SAM: Four. Oh, wait. 12.
MATT: You have advantage on that, technically,
right? Dexterity checks?
SAM: Well, did you give me dexterity or just
stealth? How does that work?
LAURA: I think it's just stealth checks with the
blessing.
MATT: Let me double-check that real fast.
ALL: Going to the book.
MATT: What the heck!
SAM: We're playing First Edition, right?
MATT: No, it is stealth. You're correct. Yeah.
LAURA: Sorry, I wish I wouldn't have said it and
then you could have had advantage just then, but
I'm not a cheater.
SAM: No, you're not.
LIAM: Out of game.
MATT: You see him slowly pocketing this crossbow.
ASHLEY: No, no, no. Little girl.
SAM: I'm just a little girl.
ASHLEY: Give me your other weapon.
SAM: This is a toy for little children. All right,
here. I'm sorry.
LAURA: Are you keeping track of what goes with
what person? Because it's a lot.
TALIESIN: She's very good at this.
ASHLEY: I'm very good.
LIAM: I just drag Nott five feet over. That is two
strikes against you. I think we should really just
sort of enjoy the show tonight.
SAM: All right. But what if someone attacks us?
LIAM: Well, I'll handle that for you, okay?
SAM: All right.
MARISHA: Also, little girls don't tend to tell
people they're little girls.
SAM: This is my first time.
(laughter)
LIAM: When someone is a goblin in the middle of a
town where people hate goblins--
LAURA: Stop saying the word 'goblin'. People are
going to hear you.
SAM: I mean, she's kind of right.
(laughter)
LIAM: Technically, I dragged her away, but you
know, D&D is funny with what is known and not.
TALIESIN: I heard you over the earring.
ALL: Aww.
LIAM: RIP.
ASHLEY: Wait, I didn't get your weapon.
TRAVIS: Hah.
ASHLEY: Do you want to stare at me all day, or do
you want to give me the weapon so you can go watch
the show?
TRAVIS: That's an interesting choice.
ASHLEY: It's not really a choice.
TRAVIS: Sure.
MATT: What do you pull out?
TRAVIS: My falchion.
SAM: Your what?
MATT: A falchion, a large, curved sword, emerges
from a sheath on his back.
SAM: What is that?
ALL: It's a large, curved sword.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: I twist it around a little. Play with it.
This is nice.
TALIESIN: Very nice.
ASHLEY: I like it.
SAM: It's a falchion!
LAURA: You're going to hang out with us the whole
night?
ASHLEY: I'll hang out beside you so you can
watch.
MATT: Make a perception check.
TRAVIS: 11.
MATT: 11, that's enough. As she spins the falchion
around, you notice that, affixed to her back, in
uncharacteristically clean leather towards the
rest of her outfit, what appears to be a
slung-over sheath and a very large bladed weapon,
larger than your falchion, affixed to her back.
MARISHA: I just like how everyone says
'falchion'.
LIAM: It's pronounced 'felching'.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: I'm going to pick up my cards in a very
specific order very quickly and start stacking the deck.
ASHLEY: All right, well. If you want to follow me,
I'll take you to your seats and I'll stand beside
you the whole time.
TRAVIS: Fucking lead the way.
TALIESIN: Hey, Jester. Before you go. Tiefling to
tiefling, and thank you for keeping this rabble in check.
LAURA: Of course, you know, they're a lot to
handle.
TALIESIN: One on the house. And I pull two cards.
LAURA: Yes? What are you telling me?
TALIESIN: I pull the Moon and I pull the Shadow.
Does this mean anything to you?
LAURA: Oh, yes.
TALIESIN: Well, think about it. Put it away.
ASHLEY: Beau.
MATT: Both her and the half-orc turn to you.
ASHLEY: Little one. I just go over and I
fireman-style over my shoulder. Since you can't walk.
MARISHA: Oh.
(laughter)
MATT: Just carries her right in. Perfect.
MARISHA: I turn back to the rest of them.
TALIESIN: Such grace! Such form! Such dignity!
TRAVIS: The birds are out already.
MATT: At which point, the other Bo, Bo the
Breaker, goes ahead and collects five copper from
each of you as you pass through, so mark off five
copper, except for the two of you, you guys are
part of it.
LAURA: If I skip around, will I be part of the
show and then I don't have to pay?
TALIESIN: Weirdly, being part of the show means
you strangely pay more. I'm not entirely sure how
that works.
LIAM: Nott, do you have five copper?
SAM: For you, Caleb, I do.
LIAM: No, I'm not asking. I was going to help you,
but if you have it, you're good.
SAM: No, you've been spotting me all day, I'll
take care of both of us.
ASHLEY: Mollymauk. That Jester's adorable.
TALIESIN: I know. Highly entertained.
ASHLEY: I like her.
TALIESIN: I do too.
MATT: So, stepping into the interior of the tent,
the rocky floor filled with grass and dirt and
various flattened groundscape on the outskirts of
the Ustaloch, you can see a thick, heavy
tarp-like material hitting the very edge where the
heavy dark blue cloth hangs from the sides of the
tent you're within. You can see where the seating is
guided across the floor, and there, already in a
very packed room, you see a few dozen townsfolk
that have begun to gather in a semicircle. There
is the entrance flap of the tent where you guys
are walking in. As soon as you walk in, you can
see a central pillar, a heavy column of wood, a
tree that has been completely rounded off on all
sides, held aloft to carry the top of the canopy
of the tent itself. And across the way, you can
see a larger flap tent that is currently closed
that appears to be probably the performers'
entrance. You can see above you four hanging
lanterns that glow with what seems like a flicker
of light, but the pattern to them is consistent,
meaning it's not probably natural flame. Children
and people are beginning to mash around the sides,
and the space along the edges of the interior of
this tent is starting to get a little cramped.
Where do you guide them, Yasha?
ASHLEY: Did you guys want to sit in the front
row?
SAM: That's what we were told is the best seat in
the house.
ASHLEY: We want to sit in the front row.
MATT: So there's-- if you consider a semicircle
pattern here, there's-- if you're entering, you
can go front to the right, front to the left,
front to the center, anywhere in between. Where
would you like to be currently sitting?
ASHLEY: Front and center? Or do you want to be on
the sides?
LAURA: Front and center!
ASHLEY: I take them to the front and center.
MATT: Front and center, okay.
LIAM: I'm going to keep my hand on my meager purse
for the evening.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: As soon as I sit down, I'm going to pull
out my sketchbook and draw the moon and the shadow
card that Molly showed me.
MARISHA: As we're walking over, I say, hey, Yasha,
'cause I was totally on your shoulder, heard you
talking about my friend, Jester.
ASHLEY: Ah, shit.
MARISHA: Yeah.
ASHLEY: I didn't mean anything by it. I just--
MARISHA: No, dude. No, she's never mentioned a
significant other, so, I mean.
ASHLEY: Oh, I'm not looking for anything, I
just--
MARISHA: Will you hold me through the show?
(laughter)
MARISHA: Like, cradle me?
ASHLEY: That's an extra charge. We do do that,
though.
MARISHA: How much?
ASHLEY: Well, it's an extra five gold pieces.
MARISHA: Five gold?
ASHLEY: These arms are worth a lot.
TALIESIN: It's a very swaddling hug. You've never
experienced anything like it.
ASHLEY: It's the best way to see the show, if
that's how you want it.
MARISHA: I'll give you five silver just to have
your shrug to sit on so my butt's not on the floor.
ASHLEY: I don't take off my shrug.
MARISHA: Oh, sorry.
ASHLEY: How about you just keep your money and
I'll put you in a chair and I'll just watch over
your weapons.
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: So she places you on the ground, as there
are no chairs.
ASHLEY: On the ground, I mean, because there's no
chairs.
LAURA: Oh, there's no chairs? Aw. I was picturing
benches. That's okay.
TRAVIS: There's no benches? Oh, fuck.
MATT: Where are they going to transport benches
from place to place?
ASHLEY: That's a good point.
TRAVIS: Carnival? I don't know.
(laughter)
MATT: Well, sorry, you have Fletching and Moondrop
to deal with.
TALIESIN: Bring a cushion from home like a regular
person.
MATT: So, as the music has died down and everyone
begins to crowd in and whisper to themselves,
eventually it begins to quiet a bit, everyone
having their seats. The familiar sound of the
fiddle begins to play, and everyone quickly gets
quiet, down to a hush. The music seems sourceless
in the interior of the tent. Everyone begins to
look around to see where it may come from. You
hear points of hushed "look"s, pointing off in
different areas, and at the top of the tent, you
see, seeming to stretch and fall, like a slow drop
of water, the man in red you saw earlier descends
from the top of the tent, but now dressed
head-to-toe in a matching deep blue outfit and
full makeup, to where he appears out of the canopy
of the tent. He hangs from a rope by one foot,
it's wrapped around and clutched as his foot
catches the edge. Playing his violin
ever-so-slowly as he carefully descends, and then
at the last moment releases the rope and lands on
his feet, continuing the music he's playing. He
slowly spins as the longer-haired elf leader of
the earlier parade that you saw, the one that had
marked back briefly to your two new friends over
here, enters the tent from the distant flaps, the
performers' entrance, his head now sporting that
same tall hat, flopping backwards at the apex. He
extends his arms, removing the hat, and takes a
deep bow as the crowd begins to clap.
(applause)
MATT: "Ladies and gentlemen of Trostenwald, I am
Carnival Master Gustav Fletching, and allow me to
"welcome you to the Fletching and Moondrop's
Traveling Carnival of Curiosities."
(applause)
MATT: "I ask you, each and every one of you--" You
hear some children giggle as he makes eye contact.
"--grant us your imaginations this eve but a
trifle bit of time, and allow us to reveal a realm
"of laughter, mystery, danger, and beauty. I see
you've already met Desmond." And he gestures
towards the man in all blue who's playing the
fiddle. "He'll be part of our story tonight, so
"keep a wily eye for the shifting fool. But first,
I tell you a tale of two sisters of the Fey." And
as Desmond slowly leaves the tent, you see two
armored guards by where he is now have entered,
two of the Crown's Guard are stepping by the
entrance where he walked in, watch him pass. "Lost
"without form into the mazes of the underworld.
There, where the body would break, they found a
"teacher in a mystical serpent, and the gift they
received was the ability to bend with this maze
"that captured them and slither their way back to
the surface to reclaim their place in the world.
"May I present to you Mona and Yuli, the Knot
Sisters." As he slowly backs through the
performers' entrance, the two halfling dancers you
saw earlier, in the full bodysuits, emerge from
behind the Carnival Master as he discreetly exits.
They sport serpentine makeup, scales affixed to
the sides of their face and arms. Approaching the
central spire, the pole that holds the tent up,
one immediately leaps onto the shoulders of the
other, bending her back a near-impossible amount,
creating this humanoid sculpture that you see the
front row cringe at the idea of the pain that
would cause an average individual. But these
halflings are very nimble and able to create
almost a single form out of two bodies. Their
rigid form becomes fluid to the eye as they move
and shift to the music, the violin now sourceless
once again, not seeing where this Desmond is
placed, but they seem to move as it picks up
speed.
LAURA: (whispers) It's like the serpent we fought,
you guys!
SAM: I was expecting more Ringling Brothers,
actually.
(laughter)
MATT: Suddenly, the top one folds over and slams
into the ground, tumbling across the center in a
wild display of physical control. The two of them
begin to tangle and wrap like two battling snakes,
their bodies seemingly disconnecting from the
rigid halfling forms you had seen, and you swear,
for a moment, becoming serpentine-like as they
intertwine around the base of this pole. It's
beautiful and violent at the same time. It's
off-putting. And watch as they curl around the
base of this pole, the lights above begin to
become a dull greenish-blue, and get darker and
darker, presenting this imagery of the underworld.
One by one, they silently tell a tale of struggle,
crawling across one, then the other, one at a
time, using their serpentine-like forms as an
extending ladder, folding over each other as they
use every muscle in their body to cling around
this pole and ladder-step up like a snake. It's a
very strange but alluring sight, and you can't
help but notice that you forget that these are two
halfling girls, and you find yourself pulled into
this wordless story they tell of climbing back to
their place, to the surface, towards the dark sky
of lightless blue cloth. As the baubles that
contain the interior light of the tent begin to
glow brighter and brighter, their climbing becomes
more fevered. The two of them, arm into arm, leg
into leg, rolling up and swirling, until
eventually at the apex they grab each other's arms
around the pole before spinning downward,
back-to-back, legs outward, with a rapid pace, the
music coming to a full crescendo. Like a Maypole,
they both curl and twirl and then tumble to the
ground before the audience with a flourish, arms
in the air, and the audience erupts in applause.
(applause)
MATT: As they both begin to back away, smiles on
their faces, nodding to each other, Gustav emerges
once more from the performers' flap. The fool
appears at the back entrance again, taking an
ominous tune with his violin this time, his outfit
no longer blue but deepset black. The hanging
lights darken once again as Gustav takes the
center stage. "In a flash, beyond the ash, the
"gods all went and gone. The darkness came to
grasp, reclaim, and suffocate the dawn." Suddenly,
out of the darkness behind him, a burst of flame
lights the room. "But from that night, a burning
"light doth keep back shadows' bane. The strength
to fight will set alight the morning sun again.
"Ladies and gentlemen, I present to you Ornna the
fire fairy." And Gustav leaves the tent once more.
As you watch, a pair of metallic fans, alight with
flame, now frame the beautiful woman of short red
hair you had seen before in the procession. Gustav
slinks into the darkness and vanishes as Ornna
spins in hypnotic twirl, her simple dress of golds
and reds almost glowing in the firelight around
her, the flickering of the flames giving her the
visage of a warrior-goddess battling the dark that
surrounds. The frenzied fiddle of the fool picks
up as she twirls the fans in her grasp, her face
stoic and graceful simultaneously. The hushed awe
of the audience fills the air, watching this
magnificent warrior strike at the shadows, the
lights above flickering brighter with each spin
and dive, banishing the shadows from the room. She
matches the pace of the music, drawing to a
crescendo, and leaps, and barrel-turns and
climaxes with her striking a powerful pose as the
lights rocket to a victorious luminescence. Once
again, the crowd goes crazy.
(applause)
LAURA: This is really different than most
carnivals that I've gone to.
SAM: It's very artistic, yeah.
MATT: Gustav enters as she exits with a bow, the
fans flickering out. He enters clapping at Ornna. A
low drumbeat begins to beat in the distance as the
fiddle grows tense once more. "Even as the sun
"would rise anew, bellowing roars will quake the
lands of Xhorhas and beyond. Terrible beasts, now
"freed from their dark masters, scattered into our
world." (roars) A terrible, guttural roar shakes
the room, followed by the sounds of grinding and
dragged chains. From behind the performers' flap,
the half-orc, Bo, who you'd met earlier, the
Breaker, and the fool, who is now still playing
the fiddle, yet the bow of it continues to go on
its own as he drags the other chain with his arm,
wrapped around his forearm. The two of them pull
something through the flap. It swells, and from
beneath it is revealed an enormous creature of
green scales, slimy-looking skin, and a corpulent
form, large toad-like legs frame a rotund torso,
and muscular arms that are manacled and pulling
him in. It fights and wrestles against the taut
chains as it's pulled further and further towards
the center of the tent, but is held in place by
the two men. It roars a second time. (roars) The
front row immediately pulling back and screaming.
You hear kids begin to cry. A handful of townsfolk
shoot to their feet, grasping the children in
fear, preparing to run.
LAURA: Have we ever seen anything like this
before?
MARISHA: Yeah, what's it look like?
LAURA: Well, he just described what it looked
like.
MARISHA: By name.
MATT: You have not seen this creature. Gustav
continues, seemingly unflinched by its approach.
"The devil-toad crawls hungrily--"
SAM: But what does it look like?
(laughter)
MATT: "--into the land of the free folk, lording
over nightmares as they say, and what truth lies
"behind the eyes of this beast? What would be
learned when the guiding heart of innocence
"pierces the hateful soul and brings it to see
beauty for the first time? I present to you the
"vivid voice of Toya." And as Gustav backs away,
the devil-toad struggling against the chains, a
soft, faint voice begins to slowly emanate from
the air--
(a voice appears in the background music)
(exclamations)
MATT: Eyes previously locked on the frightening
creature now seek a source and find, atop a
platform within the chamber, high up on a small
platform set against the apex of the pole, a young
dwarven girl, maybe 12 years of age, her braided
golden hair clasped and her hands at her side, a
white dress obscuring her feet. She sings with a
mystifying, mature voice that pierces your hearts
with joy, unexpectedly and uncontrollably. The
crowd audibly gasps as one, the entrancing song of
this girl bringing every person into this music.
The devil-toad stops struggling against the
chains, seemingly caught by the sound of her
voice. Its face drops into a soft smile as it
slowly walks towards the base of the pole and
sits. The half-orc and the fool drop the chains and
back away, leaving the beast free in its rapture.
Her voice almost begins to summon a chorus from
the ether, magical in nature, as there are no
others but her joining into this piece. Her smile
is infectious, and you can't tear your eyes away.
You only now realize the tears down your cheeks,
but you cannot break your gaze. From the front row
of the audience, on the left, a man stands up, his
arms outstretched towards her. His dirtied cloak
falls away, his face and skin wracked with age.
You see his legs shaking as he stands, his cheeks
wet with tears. He shouts (exclaims). His arms
drop and clutch his chest. Gurgles a burst of vocal pain
once more, and folks nearest to him begin to lean
away as he begins to shake. You glance over as the
old man yells out once more, as the skin on his
arms suddenly begins to tear, the bones splitting
from the flesh, writhing, cracking. Dust and blood
shake from his wounds as his form swells. Screams
begin to ring out from the audience around him,
people rising up and running for the exit. Chaos
breaks into the room around you. Toya's song
abruptly ends, the little girl looking down with
fright in her eyes, the devil-toad glancing about
worriedly, the half-orc and the fool rushing up
beside him to look at the transforming man. The
half-orc yells, escorting patrons to the exit,
"Everyone! Leave the tent now! Kylre--" As he
points to the devil-toad. "--get her to safety."
The devil-toad glances up and leaps with a sudden
gust of strength to the top and grabs the center
pole of the room as it begins to almost quiver to
his weight. He grabs the little girl safely under
his arm and leaps back down. What are you all doing?
LAURA: I invoke Duplicity.
MATT: You watch as her form suddenly dissipates
into multiple seemingly copies of her form as
Jester.
TRAVIS: Yasha? We're going to need those weapons
back.
MARISHA: I turn to Mollymauk and go, man, I
thought it was kind of lame at first, but this is
awesome!
TALIESIN: Everyone get out right now.
MARISHA: This isn't part of the show?
TRAVIS: Not part of the show.
SAM: It's too artsy.
MATT: The old man's body stops quaking, his flesh
now grey and mangled like an ancient tree trunk.
He turns, his eyes blood-red and bulging, his lips
curled into a horrifying grimace. The two Crown's
Guard begin to try and make their way through the
panicked crowd, but the people, like a wave of
chaos, are keeping them at bay. I need everyone to
roll initiative.
(yelling)
LIAM: The miniatures come out, guys!
TRAVIS: First map!
(yelling)
MARISHA: I rolled a natural one.
SAM: That bodes well.
MATT: So you guys, this guy is actually over here.
You guys are all up here in the front.
LAURA: Oh yeah, we were right in the fucking front
row. Look at us! We're so cute!
TALIESIN: Oh my god, it's so pretty.
SAM: We're all going to die.
LIAM: Probably. But then the third campaign
begins.
LAURA: Yay.
SAM: I like the tents and donkeys outside.
Amazing.
MARISHA: Look, Taliesin, it's a bardo. Oh my god!
TALIESIN: No, go for it. Oh boy.
MATT: All right, so. 20 to 15?
LAURA: 21.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: Oh, wait, 22.
MATT: Nice. 15 to ten?
TALIESIN: Ten.
SAM: Ten.
TRAVIS: 12.
ASHLEY: 13.
LIAM: 11.
MATT: So 13 and then ten and ten? Sorry, 12. So
Yasha got 13, then we have Fjord. And then 11. And
then we have Nott at ten. And what'd you get?
MARISHA: Five. Rolled terribly.
MATT: There we go. Okay, so. Top of the round, as
this creature turns and glares about in the area,
this swollen form over here to the side, that's
what remains of the old man who had stood up in
the center of the chamber. Jester, you're up
first.
LAURA: Okay. Well, I'm just going to go for it,
all right? I'm going to cast Guiding Bolt on the
monster that just appeared.
MATT: Okay, as it turns towards you. It's a saving
throw, correct?
LAURA: Let's find out. You make a ranged spell
attack.
MATT: Go ahead and roll on that.
LAURA: Okay, okay.
SAM: Magic, you're using magic.
LAURA: Well, it's cocked. It was 20 and then it
rolled.
SAM: You said cocked.
LIAM: You're a cock.
LAURA: That's 11 plus-- what do I add to my--
Guiding Bolt, plus five. So 16.
MATT: 16 hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
LAURA: Yay. 4d6.
MATT: Yasha, you're almost on deck.
LAURA: Ten, 16, 18, and then any attacks in the
future-- the next attack has advantage.
MATT: How much damage was that? 2d6, 18?
SAM: 4d6, you said.
LAURA: Yeah, it was 4d6 radiant damage. So yeah,
it was 18. And then I'm going to run the opposite
direction away from him, but I'm going to keep my
duplicate up there.
MATT: Okay, which, for your duplicate, I should
go ahead and grab something.
TALIESIN: Oh, you've got toys.
LAURA: That backpack's almost as big as my dice
bag.
MATT: Almost. I was like, that's right, you can do
this, so I need to pull out-- we'll say for the
purposes of this, you're-- we'll put you-- this
will be your duplicate, wherever you want to move
it from where you are, so she moves there.
LAURA: So she's going to stay here. I can't reach
that far, but. Oh, shit, sorry.
MATT: Just let me know where. There?
LAURA: Sorry, I didn't realize it was--
MATT: You can get there.
LAURA: Okay, sounds good.
MATT: Okay, so that ends your turn. At the top of
your turn, this creature closest to one of the
people nearby screaming, this young woman who's
trying to back away, it just turns toward her and
grabs and tries to tear into her with two strikes.
The first one, that is actually going to miss. She
ducks out of the way and begins crawling across
the ground as it goes for a second attack. That,
however, does hit, it's a 16. That'll do it. So
with eight points of bludgeoning damage, it
reaches down and slams its fist into her chest,
and as it does, she gives out this horrible yelp
as it rips into her and begins gnawing into her
flesh and pulls away with a mouthful of it and
stands up, its eyes scanning the room for the next
possible victim. It's going to begin to stalk
forward, coming up to that guy. All right, Yasha,
your turn.
ASHLEY: Okay. How close am I to them-- I want to
give them their weapons.
MATT: You're right there. You'd have to-- You're
pretty close to everybody. You could distribute--
you could use your action to toss the weapons out
to everybody this turn, I'll say.
ASHLEY: Okay. I'll pass my weapons out this turn.
MATT: Okay, so you'll spend your action throwing
them out to the individuals. So your shortsword
and crossbow clatter to the ground, and you
quickly scramble to grab them. Caleb's dagger
falls at his foot. Your staff gets tossed quickly
from behind you. Your falchion meets your arm.
SAM and MARISHA: Falchion.
MATT: All right. That ends Yasha's turn. Fjord,
you're up.
TRAVIS: Can I run up with the falchion within
melee?
MATT: You actually rush through Jester's form. You
watch the image dissipate as you charge through it
and meet up, face-to-face, with this large,
gnarled, horrible-looking creature. What are you doing?
TRAVIS: Ripping the falchion, can I swing it into
the creature?
MATT: You may.
LAURA: And you get advantage.
TRAVIS: I do? Thank god, because that was a one.
18.
MATT: 18 hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: Nice.
SAM: It's a real fight!
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: 11.
SAM: We've got like a dozen hit points, we'll be
okay.
MATT: All righty. That ends your turn? All right,
you're done. That brings us to Caleb.
LIAM: I would like to use my movement to push as
far into the crowd as I can.
MATT: Okay, going through the crowd is--
LIAM: Half-movement? That's fine, sure. I just
want people in front of me.
MATT: Push through to about there. You end up
pushing a kid out of the way.
LIAM: That's great. That's exactly fine with me
and I will pull out the diamond and cast Chromatic
Orb, and I will send a ball of cold at the
creature that Fee-ord-- Fjord--
MATT: All right, go ahead and make a spell
attack.
LIAM: Yes, here it comes.
SAM: Watch out for Fee-ord.
(laughter)
LIAM: My goodness. That is a 17.
MATT: 17 hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
LAURA: Isn't Chromatic Orb like a really strong
spell?
LIAM: No.
MATT: There's Prismatic Spray. Chromatic is the
starter version.
LIAM: That is nine.
ALL: Nein!
MATT: (German accent) All right, very well done,
Caleb.
LIAM: (thicker German accent) Now is the part
where we dance.
MATT: So as you push the child out of the way,
turn, putting your pocketed diamond out in front
of you, you focus and you watch as this beam of
light blue energy streaks past, just barely
coasting between a few heads. It slams into this
creature, as crystals form where the
wound and impact was. It cracks back into place
where it was. End of your turn? All right. Nott,
you're up.
SAM: Okay. Having seen the beautiful dwarven--
girl, was it? Who sang and soothed a monster
earlier in the show, I'm going to attempt to sing
and soothe this monster. So I step forward and I
open my mouth, and I sing, (singing badly) And I
will always soothe you!
LAURA: Can I shoot an arrow at Nott?
LIAM: He's killing the memory of Scanlan.
MARISHA: I know, can't let that go.
MATT: Make a performance check.
SAM: Performance check. Ooh, it's really good. 18,
minus three, so that's 15.
MATT: Okay. As you're singing out this discordant
sound, folks nearby are covering their ears and
glancing back and looking in surprise at this
strange creature giving off this--
SAM: Does it die?
MATT: No. However, it now, after taking a few hits
nearby, its red eyes-- or at least one red eye
slips over to look in your direction. That's as
much of an effect.
SAM: Fuck!
(laughter)
MATT: Do you want to move, or are you going to
stay there?
SAM: Yes, I'm going to move, and I'm going to dash
behind somebody in the crowd, some weak-looking
individual.
MATT: Okay. You can get behind there. Okay. All
right, that ends your turn?
LIAM: That's our M.O., baby!
MATT: Beau, you're up.
MARISHA: Oh shit, okay. To RP my tragic one on the
first fucking battle a little bit, I'll turn to
everybody and go, guys, no, it's part of the show.
Molly said that people die. She was just a claque.
Okay. And then I run and I'm going to tackle the
zombie guy. Can I see if I can grapple him?
MATT: You can certainly, on the first attack. Go
for it. Make an athletics check.
MARISHA: Just straight athletics. Oh god. Do I
keep that? It's not good.
(laughter)
MARISHA: Seven.
MATT: 17. You attempt with your first strike, and
the creature just breaks away. Its strength is far
more than you imagined it would be from what was
originally an elderly-looking frame.
MARISHA: I go, oh, fuck that. I don't know if
that's true, and I'm going to do a flurry of blows
and do two, pop-pop. That's unarmed, right?
Pop-pop.
MATT: That is correct.
MARISHA: I do two, right?
MATT: Yes, if you're using your ki point to do
that, yes.
MARISHA: Yes, I am. So first one, it's plus six?
Okay. First one is 19. No, 20. First one is 20
total, and then the second one is 15 total.
MATT: Both hit. Roll damage for each.
MARISHA: Okay. Not great.
SAM: What are those dice?
MARISHA: They're d4s, they're just fancy d4s.
Yeah. That is four, eight, 11 points of damage.
MATT: Between both? Great. So after the grapple
fails and it pushes you away, you go ahead and
pull back and then leap, kick it in the chest and
then uppercut it in the chin.
MARISHA: Yeah, that's cool.
MATT: Looks back towards you. So that would be
putting you up base-to-base with it there. All
righty. Ending your turn? Okay, at that point, the
crowd is now screaming and begins to swell and
push in this direction. These folks all begin to
run back and around this way. This crowd begins to
push, the guards are trying to push forward, and they
can only get a little ways forward to there and
there. Everyone just shifts out this direction.
LAURA: God, somebody's going to get trampled.
SAM: It's really a hazard. They should have had
more exits.
LAURA: I mean, it's a fire hazard, for sure.
MATT: Caleb and Nott, I need you both to make
dexterity saving throws.
SAM: 15.
LIAM: Oh, pretty good. That is 17 for me.
MATT: All right. You both manage to just bob and
weave through the crowd to prevent being trampled
and backing away from the chaos as people are
pushing through. The entrance is too small for
everyone to leave, and there's now a giant
bottleneck that's beginning to push up as people
are now screaming and trying to get out. They're
crying, and the chaos is just swelling into this
absolute cacophony. As soon as that finishes, the
devil-toad carrying the dwarven girl, who was
given a decree, exits out back with her to get her
to safety. These two begin to slowly back away,
seeing that things seem to be handled? And the
guards making their way in are looking scared at
each other, not really knowing what to make of the
current chaos. At that point, you watch as the
woman whose chest was torn into by this creature
suddenly--
(groaning)
MATT: --snaps up into place.
LAURA: Oh, shit. Okay, we have to keep them from
being dead.
MATT: Top of the round. Jester, you're up.
LAURA: Oh, god.
MATT: What was your initiative again?
TALIESIN: Ten.
MATT: Ten, oh, shit. That's right, you're with
Nott, that's what happened. So Molly, you go ahead
and go for your turn as well. My apologies.
TALIESIN: I'm going to yell to the back, open the
tent wide! And I'm going to pull-- how far away am I?
MATT: You're right there. You're in the middle of
the crowd as it's swarming around you and Yasha.
TALIESIN: (sighs) I'm going to run around and see
if I can flank that creature, if I can move
towards flanking that creature with the other
two.
MATT: You can't really flank it, but you can get
next to it.
TALIESIN: All right. Can I get close enough to
take a shot?
MATT: You can, yeah.
TRAVIS: Take a shot?
SAM: You have guns?
TALIESIN: Well, old habit.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: As a bonus, I'm flipping it out, and I'm
going to activate the first sword.
MATT: Okay, so you watch as Molly pulls the
scimitar out, and as he unsheathes it, draws it
across the side of his exposed chest, causing a
little bit of blood to spill out, and as it does,
he pulls the blade out, and you watch as the edge,
suddenly, ice crystals begin to build on the outside
of the blade.
TALIESIN: And I'm taking a shot at the creature.
SAM: Taking a shot?
TALIESIN: Taking a slice.
LAURA: Taking a stab.
SAM: But with bullets.
TALIESIN: That's 21 to hit.
MATT: That hits.
TALIESIN: That's not bad. That's eight points of
damage and one point of ice damage.
MATT: Okay, so nine points of damage on the first
strike.
TALIESIN: No, that was my bonus.
MATT: That was your bonus, that's all you've got.
Okay. So one strike, you cut across, and you watch
as you cut this wide wound open, exposing the
fleshy organs' interior, but they're frozen where
the wound cut through, and it's still holding it
together. It's looking like it's starting to hurt
a bit and fall apart slightly.
SAM: This is the bigger monster?
MARISHA: So it's the one I'm fighting?
MATT: Yes. So that ends your turn, Molly? Brings
us to the top. So Jester, sorry, back to you.
LAURA: Oh, now I'm worried. I'm worried about
the undead. I don't know. Well, I don't think I
would know this, so it's okay. I'm going to say to
the air and say, dude, are you here, because this
is like the coolest shit we've ever seen! And then I'm
going to cast Toll the Dead on the first zombie
creature guy. And there's a bell that tolls.
MATT: Toll the Dead.
MARISHA: Oh, that's fucking rad, dude.
LAURA: He has to make a wisdom saving throw or
take 1d12 necrotic damage.
MATT: Natural one. Go ahead and roll a d12.
LAURA: Oh, three. That's lame.
MATT: Three points of necrotic damage. So as this
deep temple bell rings out in the air above, you
watch as this creature who has turned and is
beginning to just whale upon the surrounding
allies that are curling at its sides, it seems to
retract from the sound and cover its ears briefly
before angrily lashing out.
LAURA: And I made that sound like it was coming
from my duplicate, and my duplicate's going to run
back a little bit and stand next to the pole.
Yeah.
MATT: Cool. Is that your turn? All right. The
standing creature that's now been sliced,
bludgeoned, and wounded by all three of you, is
going to go ahead and make two strikes at-- roll
randomly to see who it goes for. That's going to
be at Beauregard. It swings at you twice, both
with its giant massive clawed fists, just striking
out towards you. First one is 17 to hit?
MARISHA: My armor class is 17.
MATT: Nine points of bludgeoning damage as the
first one just slams you in the chest. You feel
the wind knocked out of you for a brief second.
The second swing's going to come at you. That's
going to be a 20 to hit.
MARISHA: Yup, yup, that hits.
TRAVIS: This thing's swinging hard. Holy shit.
MATT: And that's going to be six points of
bludgeoning damage to you.
LIAM: What are you at, girl?
MARISHA: Don't worry about it. I'm bad.
MATT: It slams into you once with the fist, and
the other one grabs into your stomach, abdomen
region, and the claws dig in, and its jaw unhinges
and drops like a snake's.
MARISHA: I turn to Fjord and I go, I'm not a
claque, this show's bullshit.
MATT: The other one is going to rush over towards
you, Mollymauk, as you're the closest one to it,
and is going to take one swing at you.
TALIESIN: Yeah, no. I'm going to use Blood
Maladict.
MATT: Okay, so you're using a reaction? You don't
have to roll anything for it. He just has
disadvantage on the strike.
TALIESIN: Oh, that's right, because I'm not
doubling it up.
MATT: That'll do it. He rolled a 16 and then a
four. So as it swings towards you, you watch as
suddenly the reddish burning eyes of the second
creature go black, and it goes way too wide and
misses you. You easily duck out of the way of its
first strike. As it runs past, towards you this
way, you get an attack of opportunity as it leaves
your attack range to attempt to swing around Molly
for a second strike. Go for it.
TRAVIS: That is 16.
MATT: 16 hits! Go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: Nice. That is 12 points of damage.
MATT: With this brief opening as it rushes past
Mollymauk, after its eyes go black, you watch as
it stumbles, its vision ruined. With that moment,
you swing out with your-- falchion, thank you.
Yeah, it's falchion, that's right-- and strike
across the back of its shoulder. You see what once
was this beautiful young woman is now this
swollen, horrible undead form lumbering past, and
you cut a heavy chunk of meat off of its shoulder.
It curves around and makes a second strike at you,
Mollymauk. This one without advantage. That's a
natural 19. Yeah, that's a 24 to hit. All right.
You take eight points of bludgeoning damage, as
the first one, you manage to move out of the way,
and as you spin your scimitar around, you glance
over just in time to have it clock you right
across the jaw. Your vision blurs and doubles for
a second. That's going to end their turn. Yasha,
you're up.
SAM: All right, Yasha!
ASHLEY: Can I get to the big beast? Beast number
one? Okay, so this is the first time I've done
this, so hopefully I won't do this wrong.
I would like to rage.
(cheering)
ASHLEY: I'm going to workshop it, I'll make
something later. For now, it's a placeholder.
Okay, I would like to rage, and reckless attack?
MATT: Yeah, you can reckless attack any of your
attacks.
SAM: Is that something you can do right away? That
sounds like a later thing.
ASHLEY: Is that something you do later? Okay. I
didn't get a practice shot at this. Okay. So I
just roll.
MATT: You roll at advantage.
ASHLEY: I don't know how to play D&D anymore! I
just forgot how to do it.
LAURA: Okay, but roll again, you have advantage.
ASHLEY: Oh, reckless. Okay. 17?
MATT: That hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
ASHLEY: I take out my beautiful greatsword.
MATT: Freshly purchased. In fact, this is the
first time it's seen battle.
ASHLEY: It is the first time it's seen battle.
SAM: Google reported a weird influx of 'falchion'
searches.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: 13.
MATT: On the one that's already been damaged?
ASHLEY: Yeah. The first guy.
MATT: Yeah, all right.
ASHLEY: Get the fuck out of my tent!
(laughter)
MATT: Yeah, no, it does not make the save-- it
rolled-- yeah. So as you come down with your blade
and carve through its body, you watch as it curls
back, trying to reform and hold itself, but your
blow was too strong, and its zombie-ish form
cannot maintain a cohesive hold on its form, and
you watch as it just crumbles to the ground, no
longer moving.
(cheering)
SAM: Yasha!
ASHLEY: Okay, okay, okay.
MATT: Okay, that ends your turn. As you're there,
growling animalistically towards the creature.
ASHLEY: Ooh, that feels fun.
MATT: You have about five more feet of movement,
if you wanted to move.
ASHLEY: Okay, so I'm going to go a little bit
closer to-- wait, how many more are left? Just
the other one? Yeah, so I'll get ready for the
other one. So a little bit closer to it.
MATT: All right. That ends your turn, Yasha.
Fjord, you're up.
TRAVIS: Shit. I'll turn and head towards
other tree-zombie fuck. I would like to use my
bonus action to cast Hex on it.
MATT: Okay. So you watch as Fjord lumbers towards
it, his large, armored half-orc form holding the
blade in his hand. Puts his hand out, and the
shadows suddenly swirl and gather around this
zombified woman's form and cling to it, like it's
holding it in place. So with it now hexed, what
would you like to do?
TRAVIS: I would like to use my falchion to open it
the fuck up.
MATT: All right, go for it.
TRAVIS: 21.
MATT: That definitely hits. Go ahead and roll
damage.
TRAVIS: That's 12 points of damage, plus five
points of necrotic damage.
MATT: 17 points of damage.
LIAM: Level two, that's major.
MATT: So, as you rush up, after the shadows gather
around it, it looks up to you, and it pulls back,
ready to strike, and you just shake your head, and
one large swipe of your falchion carves this giant
mark across its chest. Where the cloth and flesh
opens, you can see this blackened interior, where
the muscles are trying to move, almost like worms,
to regather and tighen. All right, that ends your
turn. That brings us to Caleb.
LIAM: All right, I know that it's restricted
movement, but I will push this way through the
crowd so that I have a clearer shot, as far as I
can, and then I will re-up with Chromatic Orb.
MATT: You can push right about there. You just
barely pull through the crowd to the front to get
a clear--
LAURA: Hi, Caleb.
LIAM: I certainly don't want to do that. I want to
stay in the crowd, behind people, and I will do
Chromatic Orb again, but this time, I'm going to set it
to acid, so see if it hit. Oh, that's not good,
it's 11.
MATT: 11 unfortunately does not hit. So as you
pull it out a second time, you're pushing through
the crowd and you pull up your diamond, and right
as you're about to release the spell, one of the
people in the crowd slams into you with her
shoulder and you get jarred off to the side. The
acid bolt of the Chromatic Orb flies off and
actually burns a hole through the distant tent and
then vanishes into the night sky.
LIAM: Hope that didn't hit anyone.
MATT: All right, that ends your turn, Caleb. Nott,
you're up.
SAM: Do I have eyes on the biggie? Is Fjord right
next to her?
MATT: Fjord and Mollymauk are both next to it,
yes.
SAM: All right. I'm going to peek out behind
whatever patron I'm next to, take out my little
crossbow and just shoot a little shot.
MATT: All right, go for it.
TRAVIS: Is it made of piano wire?
(laughter)
SAM: 16.
MATT: 16 hits.
LAURA: I like how every time you roll it comes
out.
SAM: It does. This is very bouncy. Okay, so 1d6,
that's a four, plus four is eight, plus I get
sneak attack damage, 'cause I'm a rogue. Another
four, so that's 12. Is the creature bigger than
me? I will use Fury of the Small.
(cheering)
SAM: To inflict another two points of damage, so
that's 14 points of damage.
MATT: Okay. As you pull around the corner and
release your one crossbow bolt, it hits the bottom
of the chin and pokes out one of the eyes. The eye
goes flying off into the distance as the bolt is
now jammed outside of the socket. The creature
turns, glancing your direction. It looks pretty
hurt, but it's still standing.
SAM: Can I use the rest of my
action-movement-whatever bonus to look at the
patron I'm next to. Do they have any baubles or
jewelry on them?
TRAVIS: In this moment?
MATT: I'll say you can use your bonus action to
just look. There's nothing you can do this turn,
but next turn, you could. So make a perception
check.
SAM: Oh, it's just nine.
MATT: Nine? It's hard to look. You see this what
looks to be late-30s woman dressed in some sort of
general workers' clothing with a loose apron, and
she's just running and scrambling to get towards
the exit. You don't see anything of worth on her,
unfortunately. Sorry. All right, Nott, that ends
your turn. Molly, you're up.
TALIESIN: I'm still engaged with it, right? Okay,
I'm going to take two swipes.
MATT: Okay, so you spin around. You pull your
second scimitar out, as part of the strike, one of
them encased in ice crystals. So the first
strike-- make sure you mark which one's which.
TALIESIN: Purple's the ice. That's-- the purple is
12 to hit?
MATT: 12 just barely hits.
TALIESIN: Ooh. So they both hit, so that's good.
So that's going to be-- or all three, then, because
the other one is 21 to hit.
MATT: That hits, yeah.
TALIESIN: The first one is four points of damage.
MATT: Four points of damage?
TALIESIN: I'm sorry, the magic one is six points
plus three ice, so nine points.
MATT: Nine points of damage, all right.
TALIESIN: The other one is four points of damage.
MATT: Okay. So the first strike hits, and as the
scimitar carves through, the body snaps and opens,
and it snaps back into place, the torso locking
back in. The second strike does how much damage?
TALIESIN: Four points of damage.
MATT: Yeah. The second one hits again, and you
watch as the torso spins off. It looks like only the
spinal column is holding it in place, but it's
managing to maintain its structure as it (snarls).
That ends your turn.
TALIESIN: Someone, anyone? Yep.
MATT: All right, ending Mollymauk's turn, that
brings us to Beau.
LAURA: Beau, you got this.
MARISHA: In response to him, I say, I thought you
said you didn't let in the sick!
TALIESIN: Just kill it!
MARISHA: I come up and I want to do a flying
Superman (impact).
MATT: Wham! Go for it.
MARISHA: First one. Okay. 16?
MATT: That'll hit. Damage.
MARISHA: I had my staff-- oh, I had my staff, but
I said--
LIAM: You said Superman punch, man.
MARISHA: It's fine, it's fine. Six damage.
MATT: Six points of damage. Natural 20. You watch
as you sock it in the face and the jaw breaks and
then snaps back into place. As you land, pulling
it back, you can see some of the teeth are
actually stuck in your fist as you pull back,
they've broken off into your knuckles.
MARISHA: I go, oh, come on. I'm going to use my
other ki point to do flurry of blows again, and
I'm going to try and punch him in the bridge with
the remainder of his teeth.
MATT: Her teeth, technically, this is the woman
that was killed originally.
MARISHA: Oh. I'll be like, you were so pretty,
too.
MATT: Go for it. Two more strikes.
MARISHA: 19 and 18. Natural. And then, okay.
LAURA: That's a really pretty dice.
MARISHA: Eight, 12, 13 damage.
MATT: Natural one, no. So the second punch, you
swing wide and hit the side of the head, and the neck
snaps, and it's now stuck in a sideways position.
As it turns, the jaw, it pulls back one of its
weirdly swollen clawed hands, ready to go for that
open wound in your gut, and as it does,
how do you want to do this?
(cheering)
TRAVIS: First one!
SAM: First blood.
MARISHA: I'll do the uppercut with the other one,
and the one that has its teeth in it, I want to go
right between the bridge of the nose and get the
teeth right in the eyes and break the nose bridge
into the brain. You know that thing? Yeah.
MATT: And as you do that, you slam into its face.
You watch as the skull caves in, the teeth
piercing both of the red, bulging eyes. And with
this horrible sucking, sighing sound, it falls
onto its back, no longer moving, the shadows
released.
MARISHA: I grab my gash and fucked-up ribs and
immediately turn over me. Can I do a perception
check or an insight check on any of the
ringleaders? On any of what was going on? The
ringleader or the jester?
MATT: That was your turn, unfortunately. That's
your turn. At this point, the current threats are
down, and the crowd is screaming and rushing. The
two members of the Crown's Guard are rushed to the
front, weapons ready, and they see both of these
creatures bloodied and ruined across the base of
this. In the midst of the chaos, one of them
points and goes, "You, you! Stay where you are!"
And you watch as the rest of the crowd slowly
pushes through, you see as Gustav
manages to make his way in. "Dear god, what's
happened here?" Looks over toward Bo the Breaker,
the half-orc who's now joined the rest of you.
"Sir, I don't know how he got in here." And
everyone looks around back at you. Bo looks at
you, Gustav looks to you, Molly. "What happened?"
TALIESIN: One of them turned. I don't know what
happened.
LAURA: There was a sick guy! There was an old sick
guy and he turned into a zombie! And I run over
and I cast Cure Wounds on Beau.
MARISHA: Oh, thank you, man. I'm really down.
LAURA: Are you sick too? Did you get hurt? Hold on
two seconds. I'm going to cure her and then I'll
cure you too.
TRAVIS: Yasha, have you ever seen anything like
this happen before?
ASHLEY: No. Never.
LAURA: Seven points, that's all I could cure.
MARISHA: That's amazing. That's great.
TALIESIN: I'm going to drop my sword.
LAURA: Oh, that's better for you, ten for you.
MATT: Okay. At this point, the two Crown's Guard
that are there are trying desperately to maintain
control. You can see they're visibly shaken, and
they glance at each other like they're a little
out of their depths at the moment. "Stay where you
are. Don't go anywhere."
TALIESIN: Oh, wherever will I go.
MATT: And he turns to the one who's in the front,
looks to the other one who just made his way
through, and goes, "Sivelmen, find someone. Bring
the rest of the guard. Please!" "Right now, sir."
And he pushes his way towards the back as the rest
of the crowd runs out. Now everyone in the crowd
has mostly pushed out of the tent, the last few
dregs pushing through. Children crying, people of
Trostenwald just exiting out the flaps as they
close, and you're all standing there, weapons in
your hands, wondering what to do.
TRAVIS: What are the corpses doing now that
they've fallen?
MATT: They're both unmoving, ruined, torn apart.
LAURA: Can I search the corpse of the woman?
MATT: You can. As you go to move to it, both of
your forms merge. The Crown's Guard goes like,
"Don't move."
LAURA: Which one?
MATT: "Both? Uh." He looks genuinely confused.
LAURA: When I'm going "which one?" I make my
second form just dart forward and start searching
the body.
MATT: Okay. It mimics searching a body. It's not
actually you. Begins rifling imaginary things out
of the pockets.
LAURA: Look at all the stuff that that one's
finding over there!
(laughter)
LAURA: Can he turn and look and I try to search
the other guy?
MATT: Make a deception check to try and deceive
him to glance over.
LAURA: Not bad. 19?
MATT: (laughs) He goes, "What, over there?" Looks
over as you jump over quickly and begin searching
through it, and you guys watch her do this, and
there's a clear line of sight. As soon as he turns
back, he's going to notice her rifling through the
other corpse.
ASHLEY: Is Gustav still in here?
MATT: Gustav is now walking up, and he's hands up
in the air. "I'm terribly sorry. I-- this has
"never happened. I don't know what happened. What
happened?!"
TALIESIN: We've never seen anything like it
before. He just-- he gripped his heart and fell
over and turned into that thing.
ASHLEY: It was when Toya started singing.
MARISHA: Yeah, what's with the dwarven girl?
Why--
TALIESIN: Nothing like this.
MATT: "She's been singing with us for over two
years, now."
MARISHA: How'd she come to you? She's a pretty
young girl.
MATT: "She had no family and she was singing in
the street for change. There was an opportunity.
"We seized it. We gave her a family she didn't
have."
TRAVIS: Put your hands down.
MATT: The Crown's Guard goes like (grunts). "It's
fine, just don't move."
LAURA: Did I find anything?
MATT: Make an investigation check.
SAM: She uses a different dice for everything,
Travis?
LAURA: Shut up.
SAM: Is that what I'm dealing with now?
TRAVIS: You're not even ready.
LAURA: 14?
MATT: You manage to rifle through the old man's
body, through the stringy bits of gore, and you do
find three pieces of silver that are just coated
in blood. A few moments pass. The rest of the
people are gone, and it's just this awkward quiet,
and at this point you watch as Ornna, the fire
fairy who had previously performed, walks in and
is like, "I'm sorry. What has happened here?"
LAURA: Your little dwarf girl was singing, and she
turns people into zombies.
TALIESIN: I feel that that was entirely
coincidental. I'm really not sure that the two
things were related. Something was wrong with this
man.
MARISHA: See, it's interesting, because I would
say the opposite. I would say it wasn't that
coincidental, because--
LIAM: I would agree, it seemed to happen with
this--
TALIESIN: We've seen her sing dozens, hundreds of
times. Nothing like this has ever happened. I've
seen people sit in the front row hundreds of
times. Nothing like this has ever happened.
LIAM: Have you had the elderly or the sick in
these tents before?
MARISHA: Yeah, you also happen to be very explicit
on your page that you don't want the sick, so.
TALIESIN: Gustav.
MATT: At this motion, Gustav goes, "It's generally
just because we want to promote a space of
"welcoming cleanliness. When we're working amongst
the outskirts of the Empire, we don't want to
"bring an element that reminds you of death and--"
SAM: You hate old people so much.
MATT: "Well, we're in entertainment. We have to be
cautious." The single Crown's Guard guy who's
sitting there with his weapon out, you can see him
shaking almost, he's never had to deal with
anyting like this before.
TALIESIN: Hold up. I've never seen that one
before. He looks really suspicious.
MATT: Towards him?
TALIESIN: No, the guy behind him.
LAURA: (gasps) He does look suspicious.
MATT: Make a deception check.
TALIESIN: Sure. Eight.
MATT: He goes, "Don't try that on me. I've been
doing this for over ten years."
ASHLEY: Oh wait, look at him!
LAURA: I cast Thaumaturgy and make it sound like
there's a sound coming from behind him, too.
MATT: Make a sleight-of-hand check to see if you
can cast this spell subtly enough or not.
SAM: This poor guard. Ooh!
(groaning)
LAURA: Natural one.
MATT: As you attempt to cast this spell, a little
bit of spittle gets caught in your windpipe, and
you begin to cough uncontrollably. Yeah, it just
falls away.
LAURA: (coughing) There was some popcorn that I
ate earlier.
TRAVIS: You should know that whatever happened to
that first man when he attacked the woman, she
caught whatever he had.
MATT: "And that is extremely worrying. Nobody
touch that body." And he looks back and sees you
coughing over the corpse, and the guy's like,
"Don't you touch that body! Are you sick?"
LAURA: (coughing) I have bloody fingers.
MATT: "Someone hold her down. If she's sick and
turns into one of these, I will not--"
ASHLEY: She's fine. Just calm down.
TALIESIN: Well, we've already killed two of them.
SAM: She's definitely sick.
MATT: Make a deception check.
LAURA: That was cocked, unfortunately. That was a
good one. Oh, well. 16?
MATT: 16? His face goes white and he goes, "Kill
the thing!" And rushes forward, blade held above.
ASHLEY: I take out my greatsword.
SAM: What, you're going to kill a guard?
ASHLEY: Stop, stop.
MATT: He holds back. He turns to you and sees you
standing a full four inches taller than him with a
much larger blade, with one hand, and he goes,
"Look, if she's going to become one of these
"things, we have to stop her now."
LAURA: Yasha will totally kill me. Don't worry,
you can leave.
MARISHA: Jester. Jokes are great until they get
you killed, man. She's joking.
LAURA: (weak laughter)
SAM: Poor guard.
MATT: Immediately rubs his eyes. You can see him,
now that he's closer to you, you can see he's
sweating, he's scared, he's generally trying the
best he can to use whatever training he's received
to deal with a scenario he was not trained for.
MARISHA: This is the King's Guard guy?
MATT: One of the Crown's Guard. The Crown's Guard
are all generally hired and trained militia that
are sent amongst all the cities to keep the
peace.
MARISHA: What's your name, man?
TALIESIN: Wow, he's really shook up.
SAM: Jamieson.
MATT: "Flynn."
MARISHA: Flynn. How long you been doing this, you
said ten years?
MATT: "Ten years two months ago."
MARISHA: Oh. Happy ten year-i-versary. Yeah,
congrats. Did you get a nice watch or like a
commemorative tankard?
TRAVIS: They don't have watches yet.
MARISHA: Shit. Did you get a commemorative
tankard? Forget the watch part.
MATT: "No. Don't move."
MARISHA: I'm not moving, man. Hey. Hey, Flynn.
Hey, man. How about first we put the swords down,
because we helped? Yeah.
SAM: Are any of us high charisma? 'Cause it don't
seem like it.
MATT: At this point, the flaps at the front of the
tent, the entranceway, fold in and you watch as
one, two, three, four, six, ten Crown's Guard
begin filtering into the chamber. You watch as one
man, the one who has his helmet off and under his
shoulder, he's maybe in his early 40s or so, short
brown hair with patches of grey. Somewhat
jaundiced skin. Molly, you've encountered this man
once before when you entered the city. He
approaches Gustav right now with a commanding
voice. "I had a gut feeling that you were nothing
but trouble when you came into our town." Gustav
turns around. "I guarantee to you, my friend, I
have no idea--" "What happened here?" The Crown's
Guard who's been shaken turns around and goes,
"Sir, Flynn. There was a creature. This carnival
"seemed to create some sort of terrible entity that
killed and then created a secondary beast. I
"watched it with my own eyes from the back row."
And the man turns back towards Gustav and the rest
of you. "And who else saw that?"
TRAVIS: We did.
LAURA: Well, we saw an old guy turn into a zombie.
But it's possible that he just died because he was
old, and then he had the zombie curse on him and
just turned, you know? Because that happens a lot.
TALIESIN: (deadpan) Gustav, it's no use, we've
been found out. Our terrible plot to make a zombie
rampage through our carnival has been discovered.
Whatever will we do now that we've been discovered
for our brilliant plot to make a zombie ruin our
circus. My god.
MATT: Flynn turns to you and goes, "Put your
weapons down or we'll arrest you immediately!"
TALIESIN: I'm literally holding nothing but my
hands.
LIAM: I mean, I'm sorry, but we're basically a
group of strangers. Most of us don't know each
other. We all have the same story. There was a
show, an old man became a thing, and we helped
destroy it. This one destroyed it. What more do
you want from us?
TALIESIN: It ruined our show.
MATT: Flynn turns back and says, "Watchmaster,
what should we do?" And the man with the helmet
under his arm walks forward, walks to Gustav,
gives him one look over, still a few inches
shorter than him. Looks at him with a sense of
purpose and social status that has a sense of
disinterest and disrespect. "You, sir, and your
orc, and your circus, are considered currently
"under arrest. Who else belongs to your merry
band?" He looks about the rest and Gustav goes,
"The orc." Glances back at the two of you and
goes, "The rest of them are just purveyors of our
"performances. He was just joking earlier, right?"
Make a deception check.
SAM: Oh boy.
TALIESIN: Nope.
MATT: "And you are also under arrest. The rest of
you, what are your names?"
LAURA: Shirley.
SAM: Temple.
(muffled laughter)
LIAM: Caleb Widogast.
MARISHA: Beau, same as him.
TRAVIS: Bo.
(laughter)
SAM: I am Bo!
TRAVIS: You pointed at me.
MARISHA: I meant the NPC Bo! But it works!
ASHLEY: Here's the thing. Oh, it's Mary by the
way, but I think I know who might know what has
happened here.
MATT: "Do you? Tell me."
ASHLEY: I'll have to go get her.
MATT: "Who is this?"
ASHLEY: She is the singer that made this all
happen.
MATT: "Flynn, escort this woman to retrieve this
individual she speaks of." Flynn nods and walks
over towards you.
LAURA: She's really shy, though, and I hear she
only talks to tieflings, so you should probably send--
MATT: "Stay where you are."
LAURA: --my brother along, because he's really good
with that stuff.
TALIESIN: Try not to stab any random people on
your way there, Flynn. You're doing good.
MATT: "My men tell me that the rest of you helped
destroy these fiends. Is that correct?"
ALL: Yeah.
MATT: "Then on behalf of the Starosta, I
appreciate your aid. But until this investigation
"is complete, you are all under investigation from
us. Where are you staying?"
TRAVIS: The Nestled Nook Inn.
SAM: Nested Nook.
MATT: Nestled. He got it right.
SAM: Oh, shit. One letter. God damn it.
TRAVIS: I have an intelligence of 14. I know what
I'm doing.
MATT: "Do not leave this city unless you are told
otherwise. Should you do so, I have your names,
"and I can have the full might of the Cerberus
Assembly track you down. You. Flynn. Free this
"girl." While you all stand in the tent, Flynn
approaches you and walks a little bit behind you,
weapon drawn but at the side. Do you lead him out
of the tent? Okay. So you walk through the
performer's flap, and as you walk out, you can see
backed up into the number of tents that are set
up, and some of the carts, other members of the
circus are hiding, and as soon as you exit out
the front and they see you before the Crown's
Guard, they all immediately scatter and vanish to
the nearby shadows, out of sight. The two of you
walk out into the center, the fire crackling in a
small pit off to the side. "All right, where is
this girl you speak of?"
ASHLEY: She's in the back in the tents.
MATT: "Show me."
ASHLEY: Follow me.
MATT: He follows you. Which tent do you lead him
to? Over here? Okay, there's a larger tent, as he
walks by your side, there's the flap that's
slightly open.
SAM: God, you could seduce him.
ASHLEY: Go get her. She won't talk to me. She's
too scared of me.
MATT: "All right." Gets his weapon ready and walks
into the tent.
ASHLEY: I close the tent and I take off.
MATT: Okay. There's a few moments before, in the
distance, you hear a voice say, "The tent is
"empty. What are you talking about? Hello?
Helloooo?"
(laughter)
MATT: And you don't look back, and you just run
into the darkness of night, into the Marrow Fields
and disappear.
SAM: But that's so mysterious.
LIAM: While that was happening, I'm close to the
edge of the tent, and at some point I just (snap)
and summoned Frumpkin. I have a 30-feet outside
the tent, so Frumpkin's out there.
MATT: Okay. Frumpkin keeps watch. The Watchmaster,
as you heard him notified earlier, turns to the
rest of you. "So. The investigation will begin. If
any information comes to light that could
"alleviate you of the charges brought to this
carnival, come to me and let me know. If you have
"no answers before we complete this investigation,
then I believe you all will fall into the judgment."
LAURA: Next time we don't help. That's what it
comes down to.
MARISHA: I know, we got paid the first time we
helped, and then we got arrested the second time.
I don't know what lesson to learn here.
SAM: Just say okay and let's leave.
LIAM: Yeah, yeah.
MATT: So the guards escort you out of the tent.
Molly, you're stuck behind with Gustav and Bo the
Breaker, with a guard of five Crown's Guards set
to keep watch. As the rest of you are sent to the
city, the Watchmaster turns once more and says,
"Remember, you flee, I'll find you."
And that's where we'll end tonight's session.
SAM: No way! What? No! I want to keep playing.
TALIESIN: I'm so excited, this is great.
LIAM: It's a good spot.
ASHLEY: We did it, we did it.
TRAVIS: Holy shit.
LAURA: We have to get Molly out!
SAM: (sighs) Everything's better with Molly.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Truer words were never spoken.
MATT: Well, guys, welcome to the new campaign.
Season two, I guess.
LIAM: Oh my goodness.
MARISHA: It feels so weird.
SAM: Look at these cool Wyrmwood cases that we
have!
MATT: Fucking Sam. I swear to god.
MARISHA: I used 100% new dice. No repeats from
Keyleth.
TRAVIS: Yeah, totally new dice.
TALIESIN: I kept the Gil die.
LAURA: I used some new dice.
TRAVIS: What are you talking about?
LAURA: Some new dice.
MATT: I used this beautiful little--
TALIESIN: Fuck you.
MATT: The Snitch is mine now.
LIAM: Look at all the 20s Taliesin rolled
tonight.
MATT: I know. Oh man. I'm excited.
SAM: Such cool characters, guys!
MATT: I'm excited to see where this goes.
SAM: I still don't know what half of you guys are.
What's Travis?
MATT: Everyone did something that revealed them
tonight.
SAM: I don't know nothing, I don't know how to
play D&D.
MARISHA: Should we all say in case you're Sam and
you don't know?
TRAVIS: I'm a ballerina.
MARISHA: He's a prima.
MATT: Well, guys. Happy New Year. Welcome back,
Happy New Year to you guys. Thank you for coming
along with us on this first episode of a new
journey. Thank you, Backblaze and DnD Beyond, for
being awesome sponsors partnered with us going
forward. Thank you, Wyrmwood, for this amazing
table. Thank you guys for coming along with us
this evening for our first dive into this new
venture. Hope you enjoyed it. We did.
MARISHA: Thank you to our amazing crew.
SAM: Thank you, Matt Mercer, for this amazing new
campaign! Welcome to Wildemount.
MATT: I'm excited.
SAM: Thanks, Yev.
MATT: Guys, have a wonderful evening. We'll see
you next week. See where this next stage in the
story takes us. Ashley, I'm glad you could make it
for this first episode.
ASHLEY: Yeah, me too.
MATT: Until then, have a wonderful night, sleep
well, and is it Thursday yet? Good night!
(cheering)
[music]