MATT: Hello, everyone, and welcome to tonight's
episode of Critical Role, where a bunch of us
nerdy-ass voice actors sit around and play
Dungeons &amp; Dragons.
(cheering)
MATT: Welcome. Thank you for joining us. Before we
jump in to tonight's episode, we're going to go ahead
and do some quick announcements. First and
foremost, our returning sponsor and long-time
partner for this campaign's beginning, on into the
foreseeable future, hopefully: D&amp;D Beyond. They've
been awesome. Sam, do you have a few words you
want to say?
SAM: Guys, hi! Sam Riegel, here. It's award
season, so tonight I'm going to announce the D&amp;D
Beyond Awards. The envelope, please!
TRAVIS: Paper cut.
SAM: Okay, nervous, really nervous. There's
nothing in here. Best discount codes for books in
the D&amp;D Beyond store? The winner is: beginnings.
"Beginnings" is the discount code! Best URL on the
entire internet? The winner is: DNDBeyond.com!
Best picture--
LAURA: This is so stupid.
SAM: La La Land. It's Moonlight.
(cheering)
MARISHA: Old jokes.
SAM: Best way to build a Blood Hunter? Activate
Critical Role content on DNDBeyond.com! Best
supporting actor? Sam Riegel. Best job opening at
a D&amp;D-related internet company? Front-End
Developer. I guess they're looking for a front-end
developer. Someone will put a URL somewhere on here.
MATT: At careers.com is where you can go to the
Careers tab.
SAM: Thank you, D&amp;D Beyond, for being our
official-- What are they calling it?
LAURA: Sponsor?
SAM: No, not sponsor. They're the official tool
set of Critical Role.
LAURA: Oh, that's cool.
TRAVIS: Well done! Is that the first annual--
SAM: The first annual awards show. What should we
call them? Not the Oscars. The Critters. No. The Sponsees.
LAURA: Ooh, The Sponsees. That's fancy.
LIAM: That was strangely manic and desperate.
MARISHA: Isn't every awards show, though?
LIAM: Did you literally write that in the bathroom
six minutes ago?
SAM: For sure.
MATT: I feel like Kendrick Lamar should've won
at least two of those, but...
Thank you, Sam. Thank you, D&amp;D Beyond. You
can find them on DNDbeyond.com. That's
DNDbeyond.com. Next up, based on tonight's
episode, we'll have next Tuesday, at 7:00PM
Pacific Time, here on Twitch and Alpha, Talks
Machina, where members of the cast will come, with
our fantastic Brian W. Foster, to discuss what
transpires tonight. You get to ask questions and
submit them, so do so. Asinine Wisdom, next week
on Geek &amp; Sundry Twitch, has a special guest. I
believe our very own Sam Riegel will be there.
SAM: Oh, god.
LAURA: You're actually doing something else on the
internet?
SAM: I always do shows on Geek &amp; Sundry, and this
is no change. What's the show called again?
MATT: Asinine Wisdom. It's at 9:00PM on Tuesday,
Pacific Time, after Talks Machina. A double-dose
of Sam Riegel, which is a lot. We have a new show
coming up here, featuring the Weave RPG, from The
Monocle Society, called Weave. That'll be showing
next Wednesday night at 9:30 Pacific Standard
Time, here on the Twitch Channel. Check it out
then. It has a great cast of Amy Dallen, Gina
DeVivo, Whitney Moore, Becca Scott, and Stef
Woodward, so check it out! I hope you like it.
Weave is really awesome. I'm really excited to see
that. The podcast of episode three last week
released today, so if you missed the last episode,
or have friends who have been trying to keep up with the
podcast, last week's episode is available for
download. Once again, we have issue number four of
Critical Role: Vox Machina Origins. It's
available for download digitally, on Comixology,
the Dark Horse app, and all other places where
fine digital comic books are sold.
TRAVIS: Go get it, rate it, love it. Show us that
you're reading it.
LIAM: Burn it. Not the book, Laura's die.
SAM: I've got to help her choose her dice.
MATT: No! Why would you do that? You know better!
SAM: I've already cursed two of them.
LAURA: They're out. All the ones that got selected
tonight are shades of pinks, purples and blues and
I think it's lovely.
MATT: It's like watching a video of guys putting
their hands in alligator mouths. Like, why would
you do that? It's entertaining for us, but why
would you do that? Once again, our fantastic
charity, 826LA. If you get the opportunity to
either give and help out or donate your time to
help teach any of their fantastic classes to help
children learn creative writing in environments
where it's hard to find that type of tutelage.
It's a great program. Check it out at your local
826 chapter and see if you can help out.
MARISHA: Tell them you want to run a D&amp;D game for
them.
MATT: I think that's it.
LAURA: That was so fast, though!
MATT: I know.
SAM: The comic book is out.
LAURA: What about our appearances coming up?
LIAM: I'm going to be at BAK-Anime this weekend.
Two days only in Bakersfield, California. I will
talk and I will go out in public.
LAURA: Me and Travis--
TRAVIS: Travis and I--
LAURA: Travis and I are going to be at Emerald
City Comic Con the first weekend in March.
MATT: I'll be at Lexington Comic and Toy Con in
Lexington, Kentucky. That's March 9th to the 11th.
I'll be at Otafest in Calgary, up north, May 18th
to the 20th.
TRAVIS: Keep it within a few months, for the love of--
MATT: And A-Kon in Texas, June 7th to the 10th. If
you are anywhere near those regions. I've said
before, I'm going to take this off the sheet for
the future. We've said that a lot now. Hey, it's
not my job to update that sheet. Anyway guys, I'll
remember this.
MARISHA: You should go check out Good Fortnight
Kevin on Alpha because it's a morning show and
it's funny. It's dumb and it's super meta.
MATT: Super meta funny dumb show. All right. It
appears that the dice have been culled.
LAURA: We're on the last one, so we're solid.
MATT: Then let's go ahead and dive into tonight's
episode of Critical Role.
[click, TV static]
[groovy Critical Role theme]
MATT: Welcome back. Last we left off, our group of
adventurers had found their various individual
fates come together here in the city of
Trostenwald, where they had attended a carnival
that had blown into town, had watched a horrible
occurrence happen where one of the older attendees
transformed into this terrifying zombie creature.
Upon defeating it, you were all put under
investigation as possible culprits for the reason
that it occurred. In trying to wander the city to
investigate and try and clear your name, you
eventually found that there was a fiend hiding
amongst these carnival workers. This large
devil-like toad creature, which through some
research you had found to actually be called a
nergaliid, had killed two more of the guards,
leaving you to fend with their transformed forms,
and then fled deep into the center of the Ustaloch Lake.
(clattering off-camera)
MATT: Thank you for the punctuation. Upon
gathering your supplies after a night's rest, you
managed to, through the trade of a bottle of wine, get
passage across the lake onto the central island,
which at one time housed the abode of a witch that
had long collapsed. Waiting for nightfall, you
approached the center of the grove that existed there on the
island and found near this ruin this same fiendish
nergaliid, as well as Toya, the 12-year-old dwarf
girl who had been affixed to him for the
performances in the carnival. You did battle with
this large fiendish entity who summoned a cluster
of imps and managed to knock a few of you pretty
heavily to the ground before you finished it off.
We left off as you all were finishing licking your
wounds, catching your breath, and now as the
moonlit night gets its darkest in the sky, you
figure out what the next step is in gathering means
of absolving yourselves of suspicion. As you've
all now taken a moment to yourselves, you can hear
the sound of the nearby crickets getting more and
more deafening as the silence crawls over the
center of the lake. Toya, the young girl, still
lies unconscious. The remains of the devil toad,
still partially burnt from the final blow
delivered by Fjord, are mostly intact above its
shoulders, head, and its legs. What would you like
to do?
TRAVIS: Ow. We're all fucked up.
LAURA: Does anybody need any healing?
SAM: Oh, are you alive right now?
TRAVIS: We're up. Just barely.
LAURA: You need some?
LIAM: I'm really shabby at the moment.
LAURA: Oh, that's too bad because I don't have any
spells left.
LIAM: That's good. Let's go back and talk to the
cops.
LAURA: Should we do something with this body?
TALIESIN: I think we need to bring it. I think we're
going to need a trophy.
LIAM: What about just its head?
TALIESIN: That'll do.
TRAVIS: It's a big head. It might be all we can
take.
LAURA: I don't know if it'll fit on the boat.
Would it fit on the boat that we came out on?
MATT: How much of the body?
LAURA: The whole body.
MATT: The whole body with all of you could
probably fit. It doesn't have the usual-- you
could probably fit it.
SAM: How about just the head?
MATT: The head it would probably do, but the full
body, I'd have to make a few rolls.
TALIESIN: I'm going to give the body a quick
search to see if there's anything.
MATT: You already did.
LAURA: Yeah, I got a bunch of rings. See?
TALIESIN: Do I recognize any of these rings?
MATT: No, you do not.
TALIESIN: All right. That's disturbing.
SAM: I got one, too.
TRAVIS: Has the head been damaged at all, or is it
mostly intact?
MATT: It's mostly intact. There are a few gashes
on it from the general fray, but for the most part
it's still a solid head.
TRAVIS: Molly, you've got them impressive swords.
You want to do some hacking?
TALIESIN: Suppose I should.
MARISHA: I'd say you have a pretty impressive
sword, too.
TALIESIN: I'm going to try and carve off the head.
MATT: Okay. It's a tough form. Not only is the
exterior of its flesh blubbery and a heavy
rubber-like substance that is glistening with
whatever mucus-like liquid it naturally produces,
but then beneath it, the muscle sinew is extremely
tough. It takes you the better part of 20 minutes
to finally get the head entirely off the rest of
the torso. It weighs enough to the point where
you're going to need one or two other hands to get
it anywhere.
TRAVIS: That's an artiste at work right there.
TALIESIN: This is as far as I go one this one.
That's way too heavy for me.
LIAM: It's all you, blue.
MARISHA: I'll help you out.
TALIESIN: I'm going to grab Toya.
LAURA and MARISHA: (groaning)
LAURA: Is Toya waking up at all?
MATT: Toya is passed out. You'd have to try and
rouse her.
LAURA: It's probably best not to wake her up while
we're carrying this head around.
TALIESIN: I think that's a very good idea.
MARISHA: Yeah, this is frightening.
LIAM: The imps burned away?
MATT: Yes, they turned to ash.
LAURA: Does he have hair? What are we carrying him
by?
MARISHA: Yeah, what are we carrying him by?
MATT: Along the brow line there are these small
holes that could be breathing holes. You'd have to
carry it from there, under the socket, or under
the jaw.
LIAM: Because that's what you want to stick your
finger in.
TRAVIS: Yeah, totally. The mucus hole.
MARISHA: I grab the jaw and I say: "Hey, Jester."
TALIESIN: I did share meals with this person for
two straight years. Never mind. I'm walking away.
TRAVIS: We are fucking with his old co-worker.
TALIESIN: I'm already walking away. I took the kid
and am walking to the boat.
LAURA, MARISHA and TRAVIS: Sorry!
LIAM: Caleb just retched into the grass from
watching that.
LAURA: All right, let's carry him.
TALIESIN: You're the worst. You're all the worst.
LAURA: Fjord, I gave you the bag of skin. Don't
forget you have that.
TRAVIS: I have it?
LAURA: You have the bag of slimy skin.
TRAVIS: I'm going to salt it and hang it out to
dry.
LIAM: If it will help tomorrow or today-- what
time is it? It's the middle of the night, isn't it?
MATT: You approached just after dusk, so between
the slow moving in there, the combat, and the rest
afterward it's probably close to 10:00PM.
LIAM: I know exactly what time it is, don't I?
Yeah.
TRAVIS: You know exactly what time it is?
LIAM: It's something I've always been able to--
why is everybody looking at me like-- (vomiting sound)
LAURA: Where's Frumpkin?
LIAM: (fwoosh)
LAURA: Oh, good.
MATT: At this point, Molly, as you're ahead of the
group and you're making your way through the
trees, Toya begins to stir in your grasp. Her eyes
open a bit as you're holding her and she looks up
at you, confused, eyes lolling around in the
sockets for a moment before they see you and
clarify. "Molly?"
TALIESIN: I know, dear. You've been through a bit.
There's been some bad business.
MATT: "What happened?"
TALIESIN: (sighs) A friend turned on us, but it's
going to be all right. I'm going to get you home,
all right?
MATT: "Wait, where's Kylre?" She starts trying to
fight your grasp.
TALIESIN: I'll explain it later.
MATT: She's going to try and break free of your
grasp. Are you going to attempt to hold onto her?
TALIESIN: Oh, yeah.
LIAM: How far away are they from the rest of us?
MATT: While you guys have been doing all this,
he's gone on ahead. He's probably a good 40 to 50
feet ahead. Go ahead and roll an athletics check.
TALIESIN: You're a monster.
LAURA: Oh, no!
TRAVIS: Tell me you did it.
TALIESIN: No, it's not that bad.
LAURA: Oh, it looked like a one from this angle.
Still pretty terrible.
TRAVIS and MARISHA: (chanting) Level two.
LAURA: You were rolling bad on this the last game.
You need to stop rolling that one.
MATT: Yeah, that dice needs to go away.
TALIESIN: I've got some new stuff coming in.
LAURA: All right.
MARISHA: It's coming across the border. It's real
good.
TALIESIN: Coming in from the Feywild.
MATT: You can choose athletics or acrobatics.
TALIESIN: Oh. Can I reroll?
MATT: No.
TALIESIN: Then that's nine.
MATT: That still beats her. She rolled a five. All
right, wanted to double-check. She's scrambling
and as you pull her back she tries to fight for a
second and then goes limp in your grasp and goes,
"I'm scared."
TALIESIN: I know. It's going to be a bit rough,
but it was for the best. I'm so sorry. Some people
just turn, I'm so sorry.
MATT: "What happened?"
TALIESIN: He got sick. There was something inside
him. There was something that made him
do some bad things, but it had to be taken care
of. You're going to be all right.
MATT: She gets really quiet for a second. You get
to the boat and the gentleman earlier that you had
passed the wine off to is sitting there waiting.
He has a small pouch that's opened with some dried
meat that he's chewing on as he's waiting. As you guys
walk up, he says: "Oh, I see you've finished."
LAURA and MARISHA: (groaning)
MATT: (shouting) "What in the hell is that?!"
MARISHA: Move!
LAURA: We told you we were having a party, man!
LIAM: I was just about to suggest covering that
up, but you know, all cards on the table.
MATT: He grabs his bag of dried meat, pulls it up,
and backs up. "I didn't know-- What is that? What
"did you do? What is that?"
MARISHA: I said we were going to be doing some
frog digging.
TALIESIN: Biggest frog you've ever seen.
MATT: There's a pause before this tiny screeching
sound begins to emit from Toya. This high pitched
and barely audible squeak as Toya begins to
scream.
LAURA: I take off my cloak and I cover the head
with it.
TALIESIN: I was trying to keep her away from
that.
MATT: It's hard to keep her away from that.
TRAVIS: We literally cut the head off Barney and
shoved it in her face. (singsong) I love you.
TALIESIN: The Barney that been raising her, yes.
Really take that in. Off to a great start.
MATT: After Jester throws her cloak over Toya--
LAURA: No, not Toya. Over the head.
TALIESIN: I'm trying to keep her quiet.
MATT: She's sobbing into your arms at this point.
You feel her body shaking against your grasp.
LAURA: I feel so bad.
TALIESIN: You should.
SAM: Poor girl.
TALIESIN: I'm going to take her to the front of
the boat and keep her far away from all that.
LIAM: I pull Fjord away for a moment, about ten or
15 feet away. This man in the boat has seen all of
you who are supposed to be under house arrest. We
cannot have him talking to the authorities.
SAM: Should we kill him?
LIAM: Jeez! Come here.
TRAVIS: I have a good feeling that this guy is a
man of upstanding nature. I'm sure he'll keep it
to himself.
LIAM: Oh, that's very trusting.
TRAVIS: Yeah, of course.
SAM: We gave him one bottle of wine. That's not
very much.
TRAVIS: We have another bottle. Don't we?
MARISHA: Yes?
LIAM: Oh, you're here too, now. Great, it's a party.
MARISHA: We could also toss him a bit of gold if
we think it would make him forget the night.
TRAVIS: After all, we came to him, right? I would
prefer not to use any violence.
LIAM: I'm not suggesting that, but it's either
violence or giving him a little something.
MARISHA: What makes you think he's going to go
talk to the authorities?
LIAM: You want to leave it to chance?
MARISHA: Who cares?
SAM: This is a small town, Beau. Everyone talks to
everyone. You taught us that.
MARISHA: I did, but everyone also hated the
circus.
LIAM: Molly, do you want to join this
conversation?
TALIESIN: I've been listening. I pull out a gold
coin. Give him this.
LAURA: Maybe one more. Or two more.
MARISHA: I pull two out as well.
LAURA: I'll pull three out.
MATT: He's recessed to the very back of his boat,
wide-eyed as you approach.
TRAVIS: You're right. Coin is a good idea.
LAURA: Go charm him, Fjord. You're very charming.
MARISHA: You've got fisherman vibes.
TRAVIS: Oh, shit. Wait a minute. How long did that
fight take?
MATT: You've returned to your normal half-orc
form.
TRAVIS: Oh, cool. Okay. There was an old man who
was with us before.
TALIESIN: And now there's a little girl. It's all
coming full circle.
TRAVIS: Maybe we give him the extra bottle of wine
and you go talk to him.
LIAM: Walking up to the boat--
MARISHA: Here. (clink)
LIAM: Collecting it as I go. The thing of it is,
we've just done Trostenwald-- what was that?
Never mind. --a great service. There was an unsavory element--
did you know the circus was in town?
Doesn't matter. There was a bad fellow-- that's his head--
with them. It's no fault of theirs. You pick weird folk up on the
road in the circus. Isn't that right, Mollymauk?
TALIESIN: I'll let that go.
MATT: He reaches over, grabs the oar from the
side, and lifts the cloak off the face.
LIAM: That's going to rile you up. That's a bad
idea.
MATT: "It doesn't look like a savory creature."
LAURA: It wasn't. Trust us.
TALIESIN: Took a lot out of us.
LIAM: But the situation in town is a little
political. We're going to take this thing out of
here and I'm going to report it to the
authorities. We don't really want to create a stir
and frighten people here. I hope you will take--
LAURA: We like to be unsung heroes. You know, like
superheroes with secret identities.
MARISHA: Yeah, we're an underground anonymous
activist group.
LAURA: Yeah, that helps people. But if everyone
knows who we are, it'll be much harder to fight
all the crime.
LIAM: Try to focus on the gold.
MATT: He slowly reaches out and takes it from your
hand. "All right. I trust it was a bad thing. So
"I'm going to take you back, and then you promise
I'll never see you again?"
LAURA: We'll try really hard to not let you see
us.
TALIESIN: If you see us, we won't make eye
contact.
LAURA: We'll pretend we don't know you.
MATT: "That includes the goblin."
SAM: I was never here. We never had this
conversation.
LAURA: She's a halfling.
MATT: He glances over and takes a closer look.
SAM: I'm very ugly for a halfling.
MATT: "Let's just get back to shore." He grabs the
oar, takes the bottle of wine that he had mostly
drunk by himself before, and polishes it off in
one series of gulps.
LAURA: Don't boat drunk.
MATT: As you all gather up onto the ship, he
begins to paddle you back towards the western
shore of the Ustaloch to the outskirts of
Trostenwald.
MARISHA: When we get to the shore, we should
probably split up.
LAURA: How are we going to get this giant head to
the authorities?
MARISHA: That's a good question.
LAURA: Oh, I got an idea! Why don't you go get a
wagon as soon as we get to shore, and we'll help
you load it onto the wagon, and then you just take
it on in yourself.
TALIESIN: It's a shame we didn't just get rid of a
wagon not more than one night ago.
SAM: Why do we need to take it with us? Us
traipsing through town with a giant head seems
like it would draw focus. Why don't we just put it
somewhere and send the authorities out here to
find it later?
TALIESIN: Someone else may get to it, or something
might happen.
SAM: What are they going to do with it? It's a big
head!
MARISHA: We could leave someone with it, and we
can just--
TRAVIS: I could stand guard as a crownsguard next
to it.
TALIESIN: What could people do with the head of a
creature like this?
MATT: What could people do with the head of a
creature like this? Who knows.
TALIESIN: Would I know?
LAURA: They could make a lot of soup.
MATT: They could turn it in for-- there's a lot of
poor folk here. If they had a large looking odd
creature, that's worth some gold.
SAM: We can hide it. Maybe some of us have skills
to hide things.
LIAM: I think Fjord had a good idea, which is if
you can disguise yourself as a crownsguard again,
you wait with it. You guys get back to the tavern,
yeah?
MARISHA: You can go and alert the authorities.
LIAM: Now, here's the thing. I may be speaking out
of turn-- I know I don't know you very well, but
it feels like the thing that we all share in
common here is that we don't wish to make-- maybe
not you-- make a big splash here.
TRAVIS: Agreed. The less attention, the better.
LAURA: Well, you know, whatever.
TRAVIS: The less attention, the better.
TALIESIN: For the moment.
LIAM: Okay, so maybe I'm 70 to 80 percent correct,
but we're all in this together.
MARISHA: And gold. I like getting paid.
TALIESIN: We need to get this one back to the
circus, too. You might be helpful for that.
LIAM: I don't want to make a big thing. I'm going
to go the authorities, to-- my keen mind tells me
that woman's name was--?
MATT: Oh, the-- sorry.
LIAM: Yeah, the one who wanted to go eat.
MATT: Yes, you're talking about--
TRAVIS: Norda?
MATT: Yes, Lawmaster Norda.
LIAM: Norda? I want to go to her and citizen's
arrest kind of thing. Keep it quiet, don't need
big accolades, will take gold, and then I'll bring
that back and we can divvy that up. That's no problem.
TRAVIS: I like it. As soon as other crownsguard
arrive with Norda and the rest of whoever you
bring to the scene, maybe I can go with you and
help return Toya.
LAURA: You disappear quickly, because if you get
drawn into that investigation, it would be bad.
LIAM: Right, and if nobody recognizes you-- Do you
remember any of the guards that were in town that
you could make yourself look like specifically?
LAURA: Oh!
MARISHA: What was that guy's name?
LAURA: What were the two guards that keep coming
to the tavern?
MARISHA: Oh, wait!
LAURA: We wrote their names down.
MARISHA: Jonas and Lucas.
LAURA: That's right!
SAM and MARISHA: The Jonas Brothers.
MATT: They're not related at all.
LIAM: DM, question. The two zombified back at the
circus tents, were they burnt to a crisp beyond
recognition?
MATT: One of them was, and they have been
discovered.
LIAM: Yeah, but was he recognizable? Did we leave
him looking like that dude at the end of The Last
Crusade after he drank from the wrong cup?
MATT: With some time, he could be identified.
LIAM: Okay. Well, the Jonas Brothers it is,
friends.
SAM: Just to game this out. You, Caleb, someone
who is not suspected of a crime, is going to bring
the severed head of a member of the circus to the
police--
LAURA: No, he's going to go to the police and
bring them to the head.
SAM: Either way. You, Caleb, someone who is not
suspected of a crime, is going to point the police
to the severed head of a member of the circus with
no evidence showing what that thing was or that it
was evil, and that will somehow not implicate
other people who were not with us at the time. How
is this going to prove their innocence, just
showing a head?
LIAM: They already believe that the circus is
terrible. I think they were just going to confirm
their own suspicions.
MARISHA: Also, Toya. If she would speak honestly,
she would absolve all of us.
TRAVIS: I think Beau makes a very good point.
Without Toya's testimony we're in trouble.
TALIESIN: I'm hoping Toya will--
LIAM: Well, that's a sticky situation. Because
what if she talks about my friends who were there
with me?
TALIESIN: She knows what to say when guards are
asking questions.
LIAM: It looks like she knows how to go off like a
siren.
TALIESIN: She's had a bad night.
LIAM: I'm at one hit point, I understand.
TALIESIN: We'll have a talk. We'll get her to some
people who can calm her down and make sure she
remembers how we take care of each other.
MATT: "If there's something you want to ask me,
I'm right here." You're all in this boat as it
makes its way across the Ustaloch.
TALIESIN: Sorry, dear. I was hoping that we didn't
have to have this conversation in front of strangers.
MATT: "Can someone please explain to me what's
going on?"
LIAM: Can you explain to us, maybe, your
relationship with Kylre? If that was his name.
MATT: "I mean, that's the name I've ever known."
LIAM: Let's talk about the killing part, though.
MATT: "I don't know anything about that. When we
did the show the other night, the horrible man--"
TALIESIN: It turns out that that was-- Kylre did
that.
MATT: "Why?"
TALIESIN: I don't know why. Something snapped.
He's hurt and killed a lot of people. We think
that maybe he's been making you sick too.
LAURA: Have you ever heard him say nergaliid?
MATT: "No. Where's Gustav?"
TALIESIN: Gustav is having trouble with the
authorities. We're going to need to all work
together to save him.
TRAVIS: Unfortunately, the authorities think that
Gustav and the circus are responsible for what
happened. Actually, it's just Kylre. He wasn't
what you thought he was, I'm afraid.
TALIESIN: The twins are being the twins, Ornna's
being Ornna. But I think we can save everybody. We
just need to take care of each other.
MATT: "He was my friend, though."
LIAM: Child, how did you grow so close to him?
MATT: "Gustav put us together for our act and he
protected me. I felt safe around him. He didn't
"let anybody get too close I didn't want to."
LIAM: Did he communicate with you in some way?
MATT: "He talked."
LIAM: What did you talk about?
MATT: "Well, we talked about everybody else in the
family. We talked about how I missed not having a
"family. He didn't talk about himself much, but it
was mainly just little games."
LAURA: Did he teach you how to sing to affect
people's minds?
MATT: "No. That was how I got by before I met
these guys."
LIAM: I am sure this is painful for you. You are
young. Sometimes people we feel we know can be
someone else. Regrettably, this is one of those
instances. He was a dangerous thing. It is very
important that this is buried here. You want to
travel on with the circus and with Mollymauk and
your friends. That thing tried to kill us. It did
kill things in Trostenwald. Who knows what it
would have done to you, child?
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
LIAM: Oof.
SAM: It's good.
LIAM: No, it's not good.
TALIESIN: I felt it.
TRAVIS: It's Sam good.
LIAM: It is only a six. Rolled very low.
MATT: As you're talking to her, her eyes keep
flickering off of your face and over towards Beau.
You watch her curl back into herself and get
quiet.
TRAVIS: It might do for you to apologize.
MARISHA: Sorry.
LAURA: Sorry for what, Beau?
MARISHA: Really, Jester?
LAURA: Really.
TALIESIN: No, I want to hear this too.
MARISHA: Sorry for choking you with my stick.
TALIESIN: Somehow that was better than what I was
hoping for.
LIAM: Rated T for Teen.
SAM: And I'll never do it again?
(laughter)
MARISHA: And I'll never do it again. As long as
you don't try that again, of course, I guess.
LAURA: It was only because Kylre was trying to
kill us and she was afraid that you were helping him.
MARISHA: Yeah, I wasn't trying to hurt you. I was
just trying to get you to stop singing. But it was
so abrasive.
TALIESIN: You know how people outside can be. The
mean girl was just afraid of you and we're going
to let her go on this one.
MATT: "I'm tired."
TALIESIN: Yeah, I know. Let's get you home, okay?
MATT: She leans into you, Molly. After a few
minutes, she falls asleep against you.
LAURA: That went well, I think.
TALIESIN: Choked you with my stick?!
MARISHA: I did.
LAURA: She apologized for exactly what she did.
TALIESIN: That was certainly memorable.
MATT: "All right, we're here." The boat hits the
edge of the dock. He hops off and pulls the rope
up. Slowly manages the boat over to the side of the
dock, ties it up.
LAURA: How many people are around the dock right
now?
MATT: There's no boats at the dock that are being
manned currently. There are a few boats out on the
water that you saw in the distance. There are some
night fishermen. There's nobody immediately in the
vicinity.
TRAVIS: Okay, I'm going to hop off the boat and
break eye contact with the captain of the boat so
that I can Disguise Self into a crownsguard.
LIAM: I talk to him while you do that. You have
your wine, you have your gold. Thank you very
much, it is much appreciated. It was a lovely
trip.
MATT: "Yes that's fine. Just, please, get out of
my boat."
TRAVIS: (English accent) Who goes there? What is
this, what have you brought?
LIAM: Oh, I have felled a beast.
MATT: "They got in my boat. I-- they--"
TRAVIS: Are you responsible for this?
MATT: "No. They took over my boat and forced me to
take them to the middle island there."
LIAM: You will not take credit for my kill. I have
killed this thing and I want it to be watched. I
am going to the authorities. We will bring them
back and get this sorted.
TRAVIS: It's a horrifying-looking creature. You
are to be commended for your bravery. Lawmaster
Norda will want to know about this immediately.
LAURA: You weren't here.
MATT: Make a deception check with advantage.
TALIESIN: This is so weird.
LAURA: I'm just holding a bowling ball.
TRAVIS: 21. No, 20.
MATT: He goes, "I want nothing to do with this.
Good night." He helps each of you quickly get off
the boat. Ties and locks it up and makes a
beeline--
SAM: (shouting) We'll come to your house with your
share of the reward.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: All right, we can't waste any time.
LAURA: Can I lob the head up over the side of the
boat?
MATT: Make a strength check.
LIAM: Monster calves.
LAURA: Oh no.
SAM: You're strong, though.
TALIESIN: Are you?
LIAM: Yeah, but at level two you need to roll
higher than a three.
LAURA: Eight!
MATT: You get it partway up and it begins sliding
back into the boat and plops into the boat and
goes (bouncing) and you have to catch yourself.
TRAVIS: Tongue and mouth just (lolling).
MATT: It's terrifying.
LAURA: All right, I need help. It's still covered,
don't worry. She can't see what we're doing, it's
covered with my cloak.
SAM: I'll help you.
LAURA: By the way, it's a little tiny cloak. It's
like a half cape so it's like--
TALIESIN: It's like a napkin on a buffalo.
MATT: A doily on a couch.
SAM: I'll help you.
LAURA: It's going to squish you.
SAM: That's all right, I'm strong. One, two,
three!
MATT: Eventually you guys get it up onto the
dock.
LAURA: Oh, that's good.
TRAVIS: Molly, do you intend to keep Toya here or
do you need to take her back?
TALIESIN: Take her right back. No one can know
that she's been anywhere.
LIAM: That is correct. Take her and sequester her
with the family so not a peep gets out.
TALIESIN: We'll explain to her what needs to be
done.
MARISHA: How do we trust you all won't skip town in
the middle of the night?
TALIESIN: We still have people in the lockup.
LAURA: Gustav's in jail still.
MARISHA: So?
LAURA: Some people are loyal.
TALIESIN: I'll be back and I have to show back up
with you people anyway. I'm going to get her as
quickly as possible.
MATT: The rest of you guys are doing?
LAURA: Who is not very stealthy here?
TRAVIS: I'm keeping watch over the toad head.
MARISHA: I have a plus six to my stealth.
TALIESIN: I wouldn't say no to it before I take
off.
LAURA: Oh that's true, you're sneaking back to the
carnival. I give you a nice little blessing.
LIAM: You're going to stay with your new friend.
You can't come to--
SAM: I'm not coming with you?
LIAM: Not this time. It's not-- you know why.
SAM: What if you're in trouble? You're very hurt.
You've had a terrible night.
LIAM: If any problem should arise, I'll send
Frumpkin straight away to you.
SAM: Unless you're dead. No one's going to be
around to save you if you get into trouble.
LIAM: I'm almost dead already.
SAM: Yeah, that's not good.
LAURA: That's not comforting, Caleb.
LIAM: Nott, this is what I talked to you about the
other night. These are our friends and we're going
to sort this out and figure out what we do next.
It has been you and me, now it is you and me and
them. Okay? You're with your blue friend here.
LAURA: You can hold my hand.
LIAM: I'll be back. I'm just going to have a
conversation. We have gotten out of prisons
before, you and I. I'm not worried about that.
SAM: Her hands are very warm.
LAURA: I'm warm blooded.
LIAM: Well, she was just holding the throbbing head.
SAM: Oh god.
LAURA: Nott, you were too.
SAM: That's true. But I didn't have my fingers in
the holes.
LAURA: Should I leave my cloak here over the head,
sir, good sir, guard man?
TRAVIS: It's fucking me, right? We know it's still
me. I'm right here.
MARIASHA: We're not RPing still?
TRAVIS: No.
MARISHA: Sorry.
TRAVIS: You can do what you want.
LAURA: Should I leave my cloak here or should I
take it with me?
TRAVIS: Sure, I'll make a dramatic flourish of
it.
LAURA: Just make sure you bring it back home.
MARISHA: I feel like the cloak is identifying to
you.
TRAVIS: Take it with you, scratch that. Good
idea.
MARISHA: Like where did this really pretty pink
and lavender cloak come from?
LAURA: It's green.
MARISHA: I'm sorry, green. I haven't looked at the
art.
SAM: It's nighttime, the moonlight makes
everything sort of look purple.
TALIESIN: That's canon.
TRAVIS: All right, go quickly.
LAURA: Okay, we stealth away.
TALIESIN: What is my stealth bonus now?
LAURA: You just get advantage.
MATT: We'll get to you in just a second. The rest
of you guys make a stealth check, please.
LIAM: I don't need to cause I'm just taking a
stroll.
MATT: Nope. For those of you who are--
MARISHA: Ten total.
MATT: That's ten.
LAURA: Seven.
SAM: 26.
LIAM: Yep, that's my girl.
MATT: Okay, before we get to you. As you guys make
your way back to the Nestled Nook Inn, you come to
the intersection where the alleyway leads you back
to where the rope you had originally let down was
placed. The rope is still there, in the darkness.
As you make your way into the alley a voice goes,
"Excuse me." The three of you glance over and you
see a crownsguard at the end of the alley that's
currently there with his arms crossed. "Can I help
you?"
LAURA: Is our back to him still?
MATT: He's to the side. You guys are all looking
up at the rope now and he's to the right of you.
LAURA: Is it still dark out?
MATT: Yes. It's close to midnight at this time.
LAURA: Oh my god. Has anybody seen my shoe that I
dropped earlier around here?
MARISHA: I immediately drop to my knees and start
looking for a shoe.
TRAVIS: What, what?
SAM: Did you say a shoe?
MATT: I would like for you to make a-- (laughs)
TRAVIS: You turned into Mr. Rogers?
SAM: A shoe!?
MATT: I would like for you to make a deception
check, with disadvantage please.
SAM: My shoe!
LAURA: Eight.
MATT: As Beau's on the ground frantically
searching for a shoe and Nott's there in the
darkness, the guard with his arms crossed goes
(whistles). He begins to walk and approach you as
two more guards close off the other side of the
alley and they begin to come up to you guys.
TRAVIS: How far away are they from me? Too far?
MATT: Too far.
MARISHA: Drop one of those rings, drop a ring!
LAURA: It's not a shoe! I drop a ring. Wait, did
we take a short rest when we were on the boat? We
did. It was a short rest on the boat.
MATT: To get across, I would say I'd allow a short
rest.
LAURA: Okay, I'm going to cast Invoke Duplicity.
Behind the guard.
MATT: Make a sleight of hand check to see if they
notice you suddenly casting a spell, or a
spell-like effect.
LAURA: Please please please. Natural 20!
(cheering)
MATT: Okay, so you Invoke Duplicity. Another
version of you appears behind one of three guards.
What are you doing?
LAURA: Oh God. Oh, she doesn't make a sound, does
she?
MATT: Let's double-check this new ability that I'm
getting used to.
LAURA: I don't think she makes any noise.
MARISHA: Can she tap?
LAURA: But if she can cast through her, then I can
imagine she can make contact because she casts on touch.
MATT: You create an illusory duplicate of
yourself. It is an illusion, it cannot make
actually physical contact with anything.
LAURA: Well, if she's behind one of the guards
then two of the other guards can see her.
MATT: Sure.
SAM: We took a short rest on the thing?
MATT: I'll say on the boat across the river,
sure.
SAM: If you want to hit dice it up.
TRAVIS: You can roll one hit die. He's rolling
commando. He don't want it.
MATT: Anyway, you Invoke Duplicity and you appear
behind him.
LAURA: Yeah. My duplicate is going to jump up and
down and start flailing her arms and then run down
the alley around the building.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: We have to kill these fucking guards, don't
we?
MARISHA: No.
MATT: The guard sees something quickly dart into
the shadows and continues walking towards you.
LAURA: Oh, come on!
MARISHA: Just go with it, go with it.
LAURA: Did you see that behind you?
MATT: The guard approaches and goes, "It seems
that you have been out and about when you were
"supposed to be within the inn."
MARISHA: Found it! The ring.
LAURA: That's my ring. I dropped it out the
window.
SAM: She calls it a shoe, it's a shoe ring.
LAURA: I like to wear them on my toes.
MATT: Three more guards have now approached from
the front of the building and they approach and
begin pulling out manacles and chains and say,
"We're going to have to take you to the stockade."
LAURA: Oh, please don't. Really, we just left the
building because we wanted to go--
MATT: You're being locked up right now, as we
speak.
LAURA: This is the stupidest thing!
MARISHA: So stupid!
TALIESIN: Level two!
SAM: Do I have to go, too?
MATT: Oh yeah.
SAM: But I was just a bystander! I was walking
down here and I saw these two ruffians and
I was going to go get help.
MATT: Make a deception check.
LAURA: It's actually true, she wasn't with us.
SAM: Zero.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: You rolled a zero?
LIAM: Look at him!
TRAVIS: What's your modifier, negative two?
SAM: Three minus three is zero.
MATT: That went into my nose.
TRAVIS: Brave new world.
MATT: As you're telling him this, your mask goes
(creak). He goes, "Arrest that creature!"
TALIESIN: We're going to die from bad paperwork.
MARISHA: Yeah, we really are.
TALIESIN: Literally, we're going to die from bad
paperwork.
MATT: You both are put in chains. You're put in
chains both arms and legs.
LAURA: Oh, that's just mean.
SAM: Racism!
MATT: They bring you over to the stockade.
Mollymauk. I need you to make a stealth check with
advantage.
TALIESIN: 13.
MATT: You guys slowly make your way through the
low grass over towards where the outside of the
carnival is. As you approach, you can see there's
about five crownsguard that are making rounds
around the outside. It looks like where previously
they had been keeping watch over the people that
were there, since the murder of two of their own,
it has heightened the intensity of the watch. It
looks like it's fairly well watched. You get the
sense, at a distance, that you would have a hard
time getting in there. You can try and sneak her
in and sneak out, but it seems dangerous.
TALIESIN: Oh, shite. Not even a good push to get
her underneath, just back into one of the tents,
or no?
MATT: You can try.
TALIESIN: Yeah, I don't know they're caught, do
I?
MATT: No, you have no idea.
MARISHA: Let's all get caught.
TALIESIN: I'm going to try and wait for an
advantageous moment.
MATT: Which I'm going to allow you to do. You stay
outside of the outskirts of the torchlight at the
very front of the tent and the back of the tent.
The fire of the actual encampment has gone out
because you don't see any other carnival members.
The sisters ran. They fled. You don't see any sign
of Desmond or Ornna. Make one more stealth check,
for the two of you, with advantage because you still
have the ability. You're at the cusp end of it
though.
TALIESIN: Ooh. 22.
MATT: You manage to pace yourself, just carefully
wait for the right moment, dart out of the grass
having her under your arm and she's like, "What?
Why? What is going on?"
TALIESIN: You remember. Nothing happened. Find
Ornna. You didn't see me. You just hid and waited
and you didn't know that anything was wrong. If
people ask, unless you hear from me, you don't
know anything.
MATT: "Okay." You slip her into the tent and back
out, none the wiser.
TALIESIN: I'm going to start heading back to the
inn.
MATT: Okay. You go back to the inn. You two.
You're just waiting?
LIAM: No, I'm not waiting. I'm going to see Norda,
so I'll see you shortly. Be ready.
TRAVIS: You will.
MATT: Okay. You make your way to the stockade. As
you approach and make your way into the interior,
the two crownsguard at the front say, "Hold. What's
your business?"
LIAM: Excuse me, and I lurch and prop myself up
against a wall and push back. Excuse me. I just
had a very harrowing night.
MATT: "Have you been drinking?"
LIAM: You get me Norda this very minute and I will
tell you what has happened with this circus and in
this town and don't keep me waiting another
minute. I'm bleeding out here. Arschloch.
MATT: Make an intimidation check.
TALIESIN: Nice.
LIAM: Oh, come on.
MATT: Just keep it in the--
LIAM: I wish I had gone with that because it was
great there but it's not great here. That is a nine!
MATT: It is indeed. He sits there and glares down
at you for a second, your posturing, this
filthy, scruffy man in a coat that wandered up out
of nowhere covered in a little bit of his own
blood. He just looks down at you for a second,
"Sorry. She's done for the night."
SAM: They keep regular hours here.
LIAM: Excuse me. There are very good people being
held under house arrest in a tavern right now.
They are innocent. I have evidence that I can show
her. This whole thing can be solved now.
MATT: "This whole thing can be solved first thing
in the morning. I'll let you sleep it off. Have
"some water. Come back when you're feeling a little
more yourself."
SAM: Kill them all.
TRAVIS: I draw back, and flames burst forth!
LIAM: Okay. I look him in the eye. I will go away.
Get the message to her that the head of the circus
frog is at the docks, waiting for her inspection.
MATT: At this point, you hear a voice on the
inside, just like, "Good night, good night" and a
cloaked figure exits the front doorway, roughly
about four and a half foot tall.
LIAM: I remember the height.
MATT: Norda is off the clock and is currently
leaving for the evening to return to her home.
LIAM: (shouting) There is a circus toad's remains
at the docks! I would like to put this town's
fears to rest. I am looking for-- What's her name?
Yorda.
ALL: Norda.
LIAM: Norda. Yorda's at the inn. Right?
MATT: There's Norda and then Yorda because I like
to make it as confusing as possible.
LIAM: Liam's memory is really spotty, but Caleb's
is rock-solid.
MATT: It's funny. When you spell things on paper,
they seem so much different and when you say them
out loud they're like, "Ah, they're very similar."
The figure stops and turns and you hear this
audible (heavy sigh). The figure waddles over
towards you and pulls the hood back and it's
Norda. "All right, what's this about a frog
head?"
LIAM: Thank goodness. Thank you, gentlemen.
Forgive me, I can see that you're trying to get
yourself home to bed.
MATT: "That would be preferable, aye." You see
bags under her eyes. She's had a long day, her
hair's a bit frazzled, and she looks like she's
waiting for you to finish.
LIAM: You are very aware that there are people at the
Nestled Nook under house arrest by your order?
They are innocent and I can prove it, and I would
like to end things as quickly as possible. I have
killed one of the circus folk this evening.
MATT: "Now this'll be real interesting." She looks
past you, and you follow her eyeline, and there
you hear the sound of chains as a handful of
crownsguard with Jester, Beau, and Nott, in
manacles, approach from behind. "These ones,
you're talking about, right?"
MARISHA: Help. Help. Help.
(laughter)
LIAM: Funny story. Yes, these are the people I was
talking about. Nothing has changed, however, and I
am only asking to take another ten minutes of your
time to walk to the dock. One of the performers
has been killed this evening, and I have done it.
I staked out the circus because my friends were in
trouble, and wrongly accused, and I knew this. So
I staked out the circus this evening, and watched
as this toad thing left the grounds there. It did
this to me, and I, in a rage, followed it and
destroyed it, and I will show you the remains of
my work. We'll put it to bed. I'm either a clown
or I'm a toad-killer. Let's see what it is.
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
LIAM: Come on, you fucker.
LAURA: Oh, goddamn.
LIAM: 11.
MATT: She goes, (sighs) "Hold onto them for just a
moment." She walks back inside. A moment passes,
and she returns with four other guards.
LAURA: I keep doing this so I can make a jingling
sound with my chains.
LIAM: You know, that's probably agitating the
issue. Let's go to the docks.
MATT: She comes up. "All right. Drag them along
with us. Show us what this thing is, and if what
"you say is not true, you'll join them. How's that
sound?"
LIAM: I'm good with these terms. Follow me
please.
MATT: "All right."
LAURA: You know, the only reason we were out of
the inn is because we were looking for you, Caleb.
We didn't know where you went.
LIAM: I am not going to answer her. I'm just
walking very firmly, with purpose, to the docks.
MATT: It has been close to an hour at this point.
TRAVIS: If I can clock that, I would like to leave
the head, move off into the shadows, and assume my
older man form.
MATT: Using your second slot.
TRAVIS: No, I can just drop--
MATT: Oh no, you can do this whenever, that's
right.
TRAVIS: I'll drop the crownsguard, and make the
old man and sit so I can keep an eye on it, but
away from it.
MATT: Eventually, you guys are led up to the
docks, where you guide them.
LIAM: Moment of confusion-- here it is, right
here, where I left it. Nobody has tampered with
it. I turn around and I pull back my clothing and
show a huge slash across my body, and say: You see
this? It was done by this thing. (whoosh)
MATT: As soon as you pull back and reveal the
face, its jaw is relaxed now, its muscles have sat
now that it's been left in the dock, and it's
pooled at its base. This old pumpkin look. Its
tongue's lolling out and unraveled on the ground,
what remained within its salivary glands has
soaked the remaining wood around its base. One of
the eyes has rolled back, but it's a horrible
display. The guards take a step back immediately
at the reveal, and Norda immediately gets
interested, gets close, takes a look at it, and
begins prodding a bit with her finger.
LIAM: It is as bad as it looks, and if you have
any holy people in this city, they will confirm
that this thing is fiendish.
MATT: (sighs) "You say it's a fiend? Because what
this looks like is you just murdered one of our
"possible witnesses and/or other members of this
investigation, so I'm hoping this is a fiend. I
"don't know fiends."
LIAM: I hope you don't believe that I slashed open
my own body and then went to the police.
MATT: "Honey, I've been doing this for a long
time. I've seen stranger. Hold on just a second."
She calls one of the guards over, whispers to him
for a second. He rushes off. "Just so happens we have
"someone in town who might be able to confirm this
for us, might help your case."
LAURA: Who is it?
MATT: "Oh, they will be here shortly."
LIAM: I sit down on a crate and I stop talking.
MATT: Okay, and this awkward period of time with
the guards all just standing there, holding you
as you wait patiently. Some of them are tapping
their fingers. You start rattling your chains and
two guards pull the chains taut so you can't do it
anymore. Mollymauk, as you begin to make your way
back into town, because you're making your way
through the dock district along the lakeside and
you look up ahead, and you can see there's a
couple of torches being held by crownsguard right
where the head was left, and you can see Caleb,
and then three of your allies in chains.
TALIESIN: Hmm. (sighs)
LAURA: Oh no! What are you going to do?
TALIESIN: I'm going to get a little closer.
MATT: All right, make a stealth check, please. You
do not have advantage anymore, that has passed.
It's been more than a hour.
TALIESIN: Just to take a look at what is actually
going on.
LAURA: Not to get too close.
TALIESIN: Not too close.
MATT: Yeah, it's not a high DC.
TALIESIN: 19!
MATT: You get a little closer, you are still maybe
a good 100 feet or so away from them, keeping to
the shadows along a building, keeping low.
Thankfully it's nighttime, it's pushing midnight
at this point. Because you're ostentatiously
dressed, but there isn't a lot of light in your
colors. As far as you know right now, no one can
see you, you're too far away to hear much, but you
can keep an eye on them.
TALIESIN: Oh, what's the play? What's the play?
Ah! I'm going to--
Yeah, fuck it. I'm going to walk up.
MATT: All right.
TALIESIN: With briskly. There I find you!
I've been looking everywhere.
You're not supposed to leave
the bloody inn you-- oh.
(sighs) They're already in trouble, apparently.
MATT: "I love when they do this! Chain him up."
You are shackled as well.
TALIESIN: All right. Less questions to answer.
MATT: At this point, Norda is starting to smile a
bit. She's like "Man, if we could have more
criminals like you lot, my job would be far
easier. I would get home a lot earlier."
SAM: We're not criminals! We're not! Me and Caleb
were just travelling ever since we broke out of that--
Nothing!
TALIESIN: Dance number.
LIAM: No, it's good that you try so hard to
protect the rights of giant frog creatures. I'm
very impressed.
LAURA: Fiend creatures specifically.
MATT: At this point the guard that had left
earlier, who has been gone for about 15 to 20
minutes or so, comes back with a brisk jog.
There's another figure walking up behind him, also
jogging. You can see light gray hood and cloak
around and as the figure approaches into the torch
light, pulls back the hood, and you see this long
shoulder length curled blond hair. A very very
delicate looking elven male, who approaches. "I
believe I've been summoned, Norda?" "Yes sorry,
this is Archivist Zeenoth. He's been in town for a
few days and he comes from the library that knows
a lot about a lot of things. I hope that he can
help us in this. Zeenoth, they're calling this
thing a fiend. What do you know about this?" He
steps closer, kneels down next to the head.
TALIESIN: Xhorhas.
MATT: Hmm?
TALIESIN: I just whisper Xhorhas.
MATT: "Yes, these creatures do frequent Xhorhas."
He gives some look over, pulls a small book out of
his side pouch. Begins to thumb through it,
compares a few things. "I'm not a specialist,
unfortunately. This creature is very much a very
dangerous entity from the far east. I'm surprised
it made it this far into civilization before being
destroyed. It's a good thing it has been." He now
gets to look at everyone, over the crew and goes,
"Are you the ones who slew it?"
LAURA: Oh well technically it was Caleb,
technically.
LIAM: Just me.
MATT: As the figure looks over and stops on Beau
and kind of smiles.
SAM: What's going on over there?
MARISHA: Oh sorry, I just have back issues. I'm
just stretching.
LIAM: Yes it was difficult, but I prevailed in the
end. The city is safe. What library was that that
you mentioned?
MATT: "Oh I'm an archivist. I'm the archivist of
the Cobalt Soul."
LIAM: Here in town?
MATT: "No, I'm from Zadash. I'm a bit out of my
depth at the moment."
LAURA: What brings you this far?
MATT: "Well, I have business." At this point Norda
goes, "All right you know what? This is some
serious bullshite. We're all just chilling here at
the docks, we have confirmed that's a fiend."
LAURA: The nergaliid!
MATT: "A nergaliid! Bring them back to the
stockade. Let's have a trial." They begin to pull
you guys back to the stockade. Two of the guards
grab the nergaliid head and they begin dragging it
along, and you guys are all being pulled.
LIAM: Oh sorry, one last thing, Watchmaster. I
pull out the book that I read about the nergaliid.
Here this is a gift, for you. This is folklore.
You will find I have marked a page in there. It
will describe this thing.
MATT: As you guys are walking, she thumbs through
and finds the page, begins to read, passes it to
the archivist. He begins to read it. He passes it
back. You guys all make your way into the
stockade. You're not brought to her chambers,
you're brought to a much larger room. This room
has much more of a stark, barren, stone interior.
There are benches built. There is a central kind
of a pit. There's about four or five steps down
into this pit. Then above that is a desk where
Norda takes as the law master. As you step in you
realize, oh this is a room of judgement. What are
you doing?
TRAVIS: I would like to try, once they start
making their way back to that facility, to quickly
make my way to the inn, if I can as the old man,
enter, make my way into the restroom, drop my
disguise, come back out as Fjord. Oh the water
closet, what have you.
MATT: There is a shared water closet.
LIAM: It's just a pot.
TRAVIS: Yeah, the room with the pot in it. Then
make my way back to the front door, stick my head
out where the guards are.
MATT: Yeah, there's two guards still posted there.
Most of them have already left because they're
carting off the rest of your friends.
TRAVIS: Please, I can't seem to find any of my
comrades. Have you seen where they have gone?
MATT: They look at each other. "Yeah, they've been
arrested."
TRAVIS: I was afraid as much. Could I make my way
down to where they are being held? I would like to
be present, if it would be prudent.
MATT: "You leave our watch, we cut you." They both
flank you side to side and push you ahead a little
bit. They are glued to your right and left.
TRAVIS: Very kind of you.
MATT: They lead you to the stockade. As you guys
are brought into this chamber, Norda sets up.
SAM: Who is going to go get the little girl?
LIAM: You're the little girl here. You're
confused. It's been a night.
MATT: Norda, up there at the top, takes her cloak
off, puts on her ceremonial armor bits. There's a
whole element to the presentation of this. You can
see her tiredly putting them on. Sets her hands on
the top, "I would like you to present what
evidence you have to absolve you of these charges
against you and then based on what you present,
I'll decide whether or not you're innocent or
guilty or require further investigation. Who would
like to present evidence first? You! You brought
the head of a creature! You're not in chains.
We'll start with you." They drag the creature's
head forward. She takes the book from the
archivist. "And speaking with Zeenoth here, it
appears what you said is true. This creature is a
dangerous, terrible fiend. And looking at it's
apparent ability to feast on the essence of
creatures, this explains both the transformation
of the old man. This also explains destruction of
our two guards, who were recently discovered. Rest
their soul. So, that explains that. Convince me as
to why you were not working with this entity,
especially those of the carnival." She snaps her
finger again and you watch as Gustav and Bosun are
brought into the chamber, as well as a third
figure who you see step out of the shadows. Her
hair dark and fading to white, last seen fleeing
into the distant fields, you see, in chains as
well, Yasha being pulled into the courtroom.
(cheering)
TRAVIS: Showing up just to get arrested!
MARISHA: Welcome to the club!
LIAM: (singing) Breaking the law, breaking the
law!
TALIESIN: Lot of help you were!
MARISHA: Welcome to the chain gang.
ASHLEY: Hey. Yeah.
MATT: "That one was caught fleeing from the
scene."
ASHLEY: No, that's completely a misunderstanding
of things. That's not what happened.
MATT: "I'm certain. You have a trustworthy face.
What's the next bit of evidence you want to
present, please? Anyone?"
LIAM: Well, first a question. Are you familiar
with Occam's Razor?
MATT: "What?"
LIAM: I figured. Okay. That one works for the
circus. Do I look like I work for the circus?
MATT: "Strangely, not well dressed enough."
LIAM: No. I'm a dirty hobo and I reek like
yesterday's garbage.
MATT: "I wasn't going to go that far, but I'll
admiss it."
LIAM: Yeah. This one, does he look like a circus
performer? Is he filthy like me?
LAURA: He's not here.
MATT: "Which one?" Fjord has not arrived yet.
LIAM: But he's right here! Look, I can touch him.
MATT: We'll say for the purposes of that, as you
say that and reveal your hand, Fjord enters
through the door like it was a planned arrival.
SAM: Weirdly, he's dripping wet.
TRAVIS: Baby oil.
LIAM: The sardonic one, right? With the
shit-eating grin. Does she look like she works for
the circus?
MATT: "I don't know what she works for, but I
don't trust her."
MARISHA: That's smart.
LIAM: I am injured within a centimeter of my life.
This one is a nincompoop.
LAURA: Wait, which one were you pointing at?
LIAM: That's you. I pull the mask away. This is my
good friend. She's a goblin.
SAM: A little halfling girl!
MATT: At this point, you watch her pull back.
LIAM: I step in front of her. She is my friend and
colleague and you will not lay a hand on her while
I am standing here.
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
LIAM: Fucking right I will.
That is an 11.
(chanting) Level two!
MARISHA: (chanting) Shitty dice!
MATT: Her eyes are chained onto this goblin.
LIAM: She's looking into my chest because Nott is
behind me. I'm sorry, I'm confused why you're
going to such lengths to defend the rights of this
large, oversized frog skull.
MATT: "I defend no rights of this creature! I've
been in this office long enough to know that there
aren't usually solo workers on something like
this. I know these folk. They all protect each
other. Who's to say this wasn't their whole
reasoning for coming anyway, and something went
wrong, and they're letting him take the fall?"
LIAM: There's a big conspiracy to make undead
crownsguard here in the city?
MATT: "I don't fucking know! Don't tell me how I
do my business! Sit the fuck down! Who's next?"
TALIESIN: You're right. We do protect our own.
That's absolutely true.
MATT: "Let him up." They loosen the chains and you
get to stand and approach a bit.
TALIESIN: It's a common tactic. It's a good way to
make your way through this world. Normally it
works. We assumed, the circus, anyway, that we
were being framed. We were protecting our own. Is
the head in here?
LAURA: Yes.
TALIESIN: This one showed his true colors, and
then we took care of it. I'm going to throw one of
my swords down on the ground that is filthy with
its blood.
MATT: "All right. Why did this one run?"
ASHLEY: Well--
SAM: (high-pitched) I mean--
ASHLEY: I feel like I didn't need to be in there
anymore. You know. I don't-- ugh.
MATT: I would like you both to make persuasion
checks.
ASHLEY: I feel like--
TALIESIN: Oh, shit. 12.
ASHLEY: 11.
TALIESIN: We needed someone on the outside. We
knew we were innocent. We knew you didn't think
so. We just assumed you were going to have us all
executed and we didn't do anything. What would you
have done?
MATT: "Is that goblin pissing in my court?"
(laughter)
SAM: I'm sorry! I'm really nervous!
TALIESIN: In his defense, it's a wonderful
vintage. Her defense.
SAM: I'm very nervous. I'm sorry, it's just your
guards shackled both my wrists and my ankles and I
can't move to get into a good position.
LIAM: You know, when she's nervous she aerates her
bladder, all right?
SAM: Look, I have some evidence to submit. Look at
my hands and also the hands of Jester. We're
covered in the thing's blood. We were there too.
We helped the killing of the creature.
MATT: The dwarf woman, Norda, leans forward and
looks you dead in the eyes. "I've known friends I
grew up with who were carved down by your kin.
Convince me why I shouldn't hang you tomorrow."
SAM: I'm sorry for your loss. Where are your
people from?
MATT: "Grimgolir."
SAM: That's not where my clan's from. I had
nothing to do with it. My clan operates far, far
away and--
MATT: "Where does your clan operate from?"
SAM: I'm looking on the map. Near the Felderwin
Tillage.
MATT: "That's not too far. Maybe we'll send some
folks to pay a visit to your clan."
SAM: You can. Feel free. I'll even tell you where
they are. I'm no longer associated with them and I
can help you hunt them down if you'd like.
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
MARISHA: Wow.
LAURA: What is it?
SAM: One.
LAURA: No, but you didn't roll a one. He rolled a
four.
SAM: It's not a natural one.
LAURA and TALIESIN: Not a natural one.
LIAM: Still sucks.
MATT: (sigh)
LAURA: God, why are we rolling so bad?
MATT: She leans back. "I want to sleep. I think
you're telling the truth. Most of you. Archivist,
does this resonate with you as well? Does this
check out, lore-wise? I don't know what the fuck
you do." The Archivist is like, "I believe based
on what they've stated, at least it's consistent
though I'm a bit confused as to the demeanor of
the goblin. It's not unheard of to have goblin kin
turn against their own. There have been a number
of historic individuals of various monstrous races
who have been beneficial members of society."
LIAM: I invite Nott up to my piggy-back position
on my shoulders.
LAURA: You can't, she's chained up.
LIAM: I scoop her up.
SAM: This is even more awkward. Just put me back
down. Put me back down.
LIAM: Just let it happen.
SAM: No! The chains are pulling me one way and
you're pulling me the other way. Just come down to
my level! Come down here!
MATT: "Bring the two others forward." They bring
forward Gustav and Bosun. "This is your circus,
right?" He goes, "It is my circus and I take full
responsibility for what's happened. Sincerely.
They have done nothing wrong. They are completely
innocent. I brought this creature into our fold
and that is on me. Whatever judgement you have,
bring onto my head, not theirs. Please. I implore
you." "Fine. I'll consider the investigation
closed. You're all freed of charges against you.
Including the goblin."
SAM: Oh! Thank you! I would kiss you if I could.
MATT: "I would not recommend trying. Okay. Gustav,
what's-- I can't read your last name. You've been
given quite a debt for Trostenwald so you shall
remain here until you've worked off the debt to
the city. To the number of 2,645 gold pieces. To
make up for the deaths of our two crownsguard, of
the two civilians who have died, and the general
cost of this entire investigation. We'll consider
what your work is to the city tomorrow. However,
the rest of you: you're free to go. I'm going to
go get myself some sleep."
LIAM: Can I have my book back, please?
MATT: Takes her armor off. "(sigh) All right. I'm
going to get a drink." She puts her cloak on and
then hops off. With the imposing sight of her on
top of a large pedestal and desk, she hops down to
her natural dwarven height and it's almost
adorable to watch her just skitter the hell out of
there. She's done.
LAURA: Where are you getting a drink at?
MATT: There's no response.
LAURA: Do you want company?
TRAVIS: I just turn to the nearest crownsguard
and--
MATT: The chains are removed. They free everybody,
including Gustav, but two guards are assigned to
him to keep an eye over him.
MARISHA: As soon as Beau gets out of her chains, I
grab my stuff and I leave.
MATT: Okay. As you are exiting the stockade, in
the archway of the doors right outside, you see
another figure standing hood up-- like a short
hood with a mantle that stops about midway. Bare
arms and dark skin, baggy gray pants and is there,
waiting.
MARISHA: What's the mantle?
MATT: You don't recognize any details about it.
You see a cloaked figure there, waiting, looking
right at you.
MARISHA: Is he blocking the doorway?
MATT: Is just beyond the doorway. It's not
blocked.
MARISHA: Is there another way out?
MATT: I mean, you can exit. They're just on the
other side of the door. Every other way in, you
don't know the stockade well and all of it just
leads further into the stockade. There are other
crownsguard inside.
MARISHA: Okay, I'm just going to try and just bolt
through.
MATT: You're just going to bolt? Full run?
MARISHA: Not run, just you know, Irish goodbye.
MATT: Okay. All right. As you briskly exit and
turn to the left, the figure intervenes and side
steps right in front of you.
MARISHA: Do I recognize him?
MATT: No. You don't see much of the face. The hood
is up and a little bit of the moonlight is coming,
you can see the edge of features. The body is
muscular, but thin. Looks not terribly masculine
or feminine, but it looks able and it moved at a
very quick speed to intercept your positioning.
MARISHA: I just go: Oh, fuck! Turn around and walk
back in.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: I'll join everyone else. I flick off the
guy on my way back in.
MATT: Okay. As you guys are being escorted out of the
stockade, Beau comes back in and joins you.
LAURA: I thought you left.
MARISHA: Just had to pee.
LAURA: Oh.
TALIESIN: Shame.
LAURA: Hey, you guys, we're town heroes! What's it
feel like?
MARISHA and LAURA: Yeah!
LAURA: Yasha, it's very good to see you again.
ASHLEY: It's good to see you guys, too.
SAM: Where did you go? Were you on the lam for a
long time?
ASHLEY: I have a little bit of a problem with
authority and I didn't want to be caught in a
small and confined space and then that ended up
happening.
LAURA: How long have you been in there?
ASHLEY: Immediately after I ran away. They sent
out horses. I'm not that fast, but I did fuck up a
few of the guards. "By accident. "
MATT: As you say that, you hear a couple (clears
throat) and two of the crownsguard visibly bruised
that are escorting you guys out into the night air
before they eventually leave you to your own devices.
TRAVIS: Molly, what do you think this means for
the carnival?
TALIESIN: I don't know. That is a question.
LAURA: I mean, if Gustav has to stay here then
who's going to run it?
MARISHA: That's a lot of gold. That's like a life
sentence worth of gold.
LAURA: Well, I mean--
TALIESIN: Gold comes, gold goes.
LIAM: How much do you think the circus has?
TALIESIN: I don't know how much the circus has and,
honestly, I think Ornna would lie about it if we asked.
MATT: The crownsguard have pulled away and now
it's just you guys and Bosun and Gustav now, out
in the air and Gustav is rubbing his wrists.
"Well, thank you everyone for helping. That could
"have been a lot worse. And, you know, it's fine. I
know it's a lot of money, but shouldn't take me
"more than a few years. It's a nice town!
Trostenwald is a nice town!"
TRAVIS: It's not that nice.
MATT: "No, it's not, but you know, it's better than
prison."
LAURA: There's a lot of beer here.
MATT: "That there is. I may have to start a small
fund for that on its own."
LIAM: What happens to the circus, because, you know,
you can't do the same show for the same people for
a year?
MATT: "Where's Ornna? Where's the twins?
Where's--"
TALIESIN: Well, the twins buggered. Ornna? God
only knows.
ASHLEY: Where's Toya?
TALIESIN: Toya is back at the circus, but shaken.
Very shaken.
MATT: At which point, Gustav just begins making a
beeline for the circus. Bosun goes, "Oh." (sighs)
TALIESIN: How hard can it be to make 2,000 gold?
MATT: "I don't know how much he saved. Nowhere
near that much, probably."
TALIESIN: How hard can it be to steal 2,000 gold?
LAURA: I don't know how many people around here
have that much. Although, the breweries might.
TALIESIN: Maybe be best to find that gold
elsewhere.
ASHLEY: Wait, so who killed him?
MATT: Gustav has spun around and comes back and is
like, "Sincerely. I appreciate the aid, but don't.
"This is on me. I'll take care of it. This is not
your responsibility. It's not your responsibility.
"You guys have already done so much. It's fine.
I'll take care of it."
TALIESIN: Suppose we should take a look at what's
left of the circus.
MARISHA: Can I go take a look around? Do I see
Zeenoth anywhere?
MATT: Make a perception check.
MARISHA: Oh, god damn it, it was almost better. It
was almost good. Ten.
MATT: Ten? You don't see anybody immediately
around.
LAURA: Was that Archivist Zeenoth that was outside?
MARISHA: Archivist.
LAURA: That's what I said. Was that who it was
that was like--
MATT: No, Zeenoth was still inside the courtroom when
you were leaving.
MARISHA: Yeah. Different guy.
LAURA: Oh, who was it that was outside?
LIAM: We don't know, we didn't see him.
TRAVIS: It's very late, right?
MATT: Yeah, it's post-midnight now.
LAURA: I'm so tired.
TRAVIS: Don't suppose you want to retire for the
evening? Share a drink together now that this is
somewhat behind us?
TALIESIN: I will definitely drink. I think we
should probably drink at our camp then. I'm fine
inviting them.
MATT: "Tell you what. As a thanks, we'll grab
Toya. We'll meet you guys-- where are you all staying?"
MARISHA and LIAM: The Nestled Nook.
MATT: "We'll come meet you at the Nestled Nook and
I'll get a round for you all. As a thank you."
TALIESIN: Is this a human thing to-- never mind
LIAM: Yeah, we're just like tieflings, we're all
alike.
TALIESIN: I know.
MATT: "All right. Bosun, come on." They make their
way off to the carnival camp.
ASHLEY: It was him?
TALIESIN: Kylre went bad. Maybe he'd already
always been bad, I don't know.
LAURA: I mean, he attacked us. A lot of guards,
too.
SAM: He was an evil fiend. When he joined the
circus, who brought him in?
TALIESIN: Let's not be throwing words around.
SAM: No, he was literally an evil fiend.
LAURA: He summoned imps.
TALIESIN: He did summon--
LAURA: He summoned imps, Yasha!
SAM: He controlled the girl!
TALIESIN: He was fine for years. Something set him
off.
LIAM : Ah, he said it himself, you people in the
circus are weird, right? So, every once in a
while, a glitch.
MARISHA: A glitch? What?
TALIESIN: He was fine for so long. There was
nothing for so long. Why? Things don't just...
MARISHA: I still think there's something creepy
about this lake, man.
TALIESIN: Maybe?
MARISHA: It gives me the heebie jeebies.
TALIESIN: Everything gives me the heebie jeebies.
LIAM: Well, if it is this thing that we've read
about in the book, then perhaps he needed to feed
more or was impatient for some reason?
ASHLEY: What's happened with Toya?
TALIESIN: Shite.
ASHLEY: How is she?
TALIESIN: She is not good. She is taking it as you
would expect.
SAM: Also Beau crushed her windpipe.
TALIESIN: That's true. With her stick.
LIAM: And, I'm sorry, are we also taking the
bouncer into our little coven of weirdos. Is that
a thing that's happening?
ASHLEY: Oh, well--
TALIESIN: Always.
ASHLEY: I mean, I kind of go on my own, but--
MARISHA: Yeah, she's one of us.
TALIESIN: She's the charm, she has to come!
LIAM: I'm too tired to argue. Let's get that
drink.
TALIESIN: See, charm. Drink.
MATT: As you make your way back to the Nestled
Nook Inn, within the tavern, and within the next
hour or so, Gustav and Bosun, Toya and Ornna all
come in and join you. You guys crowd a few tables
together, and under what is generally a pretty
empty tavern this night, you guys, for the most
part, dominate the center space.
TRAVIS: I'm sorry, Yasha, for new patrons, you're
going to have to surrender your sword.
ASHLEY: (laughs) You're very funny.
TALIESIN: He is very funny.
LIAM: That is a very sick burn.
MARISHA: Speaking of swords--
LAURA: Careful Fjord, we haven't been healed yet,
you know. She could take you down.
ASHLEY: You could always try to take it.
TALIESIN: Arm wrestle.
TRAVIS: I could, couldn't I?
ASHLEY: Yeah.
MARISHA: Arm wrestle!
ASHLEY: You do look pretty strong. I mean, you're
just a little bit bigger than me, but I still
think I could probably take you.
TRAVIS: Looks could be deceiving.
MARISHA: Arm wrestle! Bets on Yasha.
LAURA: Do it! Arm wrestle!
TRAVIS: I just thought it would be a nice
gesture.
LAURA: To arm wrestle?
TRAVIS: No, to give up her sword.
ASHLEY: What about your sword?
TRAVIS: Oh, I'm a paying patron here. They know me
quite well.
TALIESIN: So? You've got to be putting something
on the table, though. Well, if you want to
surrender the sword or not surrender the sword.
TRAVIS: Did you want to stay in that room any
longer, Molly?
TALIESIN: (laughs) Never.
MARISHA: I don't know what we're talking about
anymore.
LAURA: I don't either.
TRAVIS: Let's get a drink.
MARISHA: Are you guys going to arm wrestle?
TRAVIS: No.
MARISHA: Okay. How about "Boulder, Paper, Shears"?
Wait, what is it? "Boulder, Parchment, Shears"!
TALIESIN: That's a stupid game.
SAM: I never heard of that game.
ASHLEY: I think it's something that kids play. I
have a better version of that game. We can play it
later.
MATT: The rest of the carnival in presence, Gustav
goes and orders a round of drinks to all of you
and then sits down. Toya still looks a bit shaken,
but seems to be comforted with the rest of the
family around her, that still remain at least.
Desmond's come and joined as well. As you're all
sitting together for a bit, there's a moment of
quiet as you're all sipping, and just tiredly
thinking over the events of the evening. Toya
breaks the silence, "Is the family going away? Am
I going to be alone again?" Ornna looks over at
her and goes, "Not if I can help it. It's you and
me, kid, against the world." Bosun pats Ornna on
the shoulder and says, "Well, if you'd have me,
you can probably use a strong arm." Ornna looks
back at him. Ornna and him have had this
rivalry tension for a while. She goes, "You know
what? Sure. The trio makes for a strong pack of
performers. Desmond, are you in?" And Desmond is
just sitting there, staring into his cup and goes,
"I see a new family before me. And one I fear
that's a story I could only spoil. No, I thank
you, but I'll find my own path." And he just sits
there kind of quietly in this somewhat sad space.
He gives a brief pat and side hug to Bosun before
standing up and leaving. Gustav stands up and
looks around. "I'm sorry for everything. For all
the pain this has caused you, for all the pain
it's caused you." Looks at Toya, "For all the pain
it's caused you, little one."
TRAVIS: We had quite the adventure, actually. I
know people were hurt, but that was really
something.
MARISHA: And apparently, nobody really cared about
Enon, so that's, you know, good for your
conscience.
MATT: "Everyone's conscience is heavy with its own
reasoning."
TALIESIN: Get no blame from me.
MATT: "I appreciate that. We are our own worst
enemy, are we not?"
TALIESIN: Ah, cheers to that!
LIAM: I catch Nott's eye and silently mouth the
word 'lunatics'.
SAM: Yeah, yeah.
MATT: "Well, I think that's the end of my
carnival." (laughs)
LAURA: It was such a good carnival.
MATT: "It was a good run! It was a really good
run."
MARISHA: Man, we caught the last show, you guys!
TALIESIN: Not our best show.
LAURA: I liked it.
SAM: The tickets are probably worth something!
MARISHA: They might!
TRAVIS: Closed it down.
MARISHA: I'm gonna keep this flyer.
TALIESIN: You have plans?
ASHLEY: No, I'm just going to float around like I
usually do.
TALIESIN: I don't know, I'm thinking about it. I
don't know where I'm going to end up now.
MATT: "You can go with Bosun and Ornna, if you
like. You guys are still carrying on. I mean, I'm
not going to keep the tent, I'm not going to keep
the supplies. I might hock some of it to try and
pay off my debt, but-- take what you want. Start
anew. It's my gift to you." They all kind of,
"Thank you very much. We'll start small, I don't
think we need too much of the ensemble. How we
began, back up in Shady Creek."
LAURA: I mean, I could use a really large tent.
Like the biggest one? I would take that off your
hands.
TALIESIN: The biggest one's a bit--
TRAVIS: What would you do with a really large
tent?
LAURA: I don't know, I could open up a hotel? Or I
could make a bunch of dresses. Or--
SAM: Out of the tent?
LAURA: Yeah!
TALIESIN: You could make a lot of dresses out of
that tent. That's fair.
LAURA: Yeah, right? It's really pretty fabric.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
LAURA: (gasps) A hot air balloon!
TALIESIN: I don't--
LIAM: A what?
SAM: Those aren't invented.
LAURA: Haven't you seen airships?
SAM: No!
LIAM: They generally run from crystals. I've seen
that kind before.
LAURA: Yeah!
LIAM: Yeah, there's no balloons, though. What's a
balloon?
MATT: They have simple dirigibles, but they're not
very functional.
LAURA: Yeah, it just involves fire you guys. We
can figure this shit out.
LIAM: Oh, a dirigible? Dirigible I've heard of,
but a balloon? I don't know what that is.
MARISHA: Have the airships made it to this
continent yet?
LIAM: You don't know.
SAM: I think, Jester--
LAURA: I've seen airships, okay? I've seen them.
SAM: Jester, I think it's safe to say that this
first case is closed!
LAURA: (gasps)
SAM: So we could open some sort of private
investigation service.
LAURA: That's what we should do!
SAM: Out of a tent.
LAURA: Let's not open it here, though. This town
sucks!
TRAVIS: Yeah, we were still planning on moving on
after this.
MATT: "Bosun and Ornna, you guys can use that
tent, right?" "Yeah, I think we'll take the tent."
"All right."
SAM: Aw, they took the tent.
LAURA: Aw. We waited too long!
SAM: You got to jump on the tent when it becomes
available.
LIAM: You know, just out of curiosity, what's
everybody plan to do now?
SAM: Well do we have to leave? I mean I'm not
wanted anymore.
LIAM: You were never wanted. Back to my
question--
LAURA: Fjord and I are going to try and get him
into the Academy.
TRAVIS: Well, I wanted to find out more about the
Soltrice Academy, yes. I didn't know what
direction you were heading. I never even asked
what you were doing here in the first place.
MARISHA: Oh, you know, I'm just doing a walking
tour? Through the continent, just kind of--
TRAVIS: A walking tour?
MARISHA: Yeah, just like a backpack vacation, you
know? Just stretch my legs a little bit. Meeting
some fine people. Discovering myself.
TRAVIS: Are you on a vacation?
MARISHA: Yes.
TRAVIS: Bring a lot of money with you for that
vacation, did you?
MARISHA: What's it matter to you?
TRAVIS: I don't believe you're on vacation. Where
are you going?
MARISHA: (laughs) That's your problem. So, you
guys going to take off or do you guys want company
or-- ?
MATT: Gustav finishes the drink and goes, "Well,
I'm going to go get some sleep and try and figure
out how to put my life together. I bid you all a
wonderful night--"
LAURA: Gustav, wait! Here. And I take off one of
my rings. This is an old family heirloom, and I
hope it can help you pay some of your debt.
TALIESIN: I want to spy the rings on her hand, by
the way, really quickly.
MATT: "Looks just like the one I lost off my
pinky."
LAURA: Well, that's so weird that you and my
family have the same looking ones.
MATT: "That's wonderful, thank you so much."
LAURA: You're welcome.
MATT: "That's very sweet."
TALIESIN: I want to look at the other rings she
picked up, not that she's wearing right now.
LAURA: They're right here. You can get a look at
them!
MATT: They're all over her fingers.
TALIESIN: They are obviously rings from random
dead people, aren't they?
MATT: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Okay. I'm just putting that together.
LAURA: I play dinosaur fights.
MATT: Gustav puts his hat on. "Yasha, be safe, and
punch anyone who gets in your way."
ASHLEY: I will.
MATT: "Mollymauk, I hope you find what you're
looking for."
TALIESIN: I think I will.
MATT: "To the new family, don't make the same
mistakes your forefathers did. The rest of you,
thank you."
LAURA: (whispers) He said forefathers.
SAM: (whispers) That's progressive.
(laughter)
MATT: "I bid you all adieu," and he exits.
LAURA: What are you looking for, Molly?
TALIESIN: Hmm, I'm not quite done with this one.
We'll see.
ASHLEY: Toya.
MATT: Bosun and Ornna stood up and Toya is there,
"Yeah?"
ASHLEY: What are your plans? What do you want to
do?
MATT: "I figure I'll just move on with Bo and
Ornna and make a new show. Something with a little
less death. That's what I'd like."
LAURA: You should make your way to the Menagerie
Coast. I think you guys would have a lot of
success in Nicodranas.
MATT: "I haven't been to Nicodranas."
LAURA: It's beautiful.
MATT: She looks up and tugs on the side of Bosun's
sleeve. "You know, I actually haven't been there
either."
LAURA: They're always looking for good performers.
You would do well.
MATT: "Hmm. Let's go ahead and make our way. That
sounds like a nice change of pace, and this empire
is getting a little stuffy for me anyway."
MARISHA: I've bend down to Toya, and I take off
one of the little jade bangles around my wrist,
and I say, "Here. This will keep you safe from
assholes named Beau. Except for that asshole,
named Bo. He's a good Bo, but all other assholes
named Beau."
MATT: You watch as Ornna elbows him and is like,
"Oh, no, he's an asshole too. It's fine."
TALIESIN: It's true.
MARISHA: Sorry. Sorry again about that.
MATT: She takes it and goes, "It's okay. I know
you did what you had to. But when I'm older, I'm
going to get you back."
MARISHA: You better.
LAURA: Your first nemesis!
MARISHA: My first nemesis!
MATT: Is a twelve year old girl!
(laughter)
MARISHA: I give her a little chin (weak punch
sound).
TRAVIS: She goes unconscious.
(laughter)
MARISHA: Aw, why? No!
MATT: The three of them stand up and give a nod,
wordlessly look over the rest of you with a smile
of thanks, and Bosun looks to you and makes eye
contact and goes, "Take care, brother. It gets
tougher for us up north."
TRAVIS: I'll keep that in mind.
MATT: And they all leave the inn.
ASHLEY: I mean, I'll say it. I don't know if you
will, but I think that little girl is creepy.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Oh no, she's had a thing the entire
time. There was a little while I thought she was
in on it completely.
ASHLEY: Yeah.
LAURA: I mean, she might have been.
TALIESIN: I've known her for years. I just assumed
that she was in on it.
LAURA: She could've been in on it, and just got
right away with it.
TALIESIN: Yeah. That would be great.
LAURA: She's good.
MARISHA: For her, yeah, I mean I got to give it to
her, yeah.
TALIESIN: You know, no matter what you pick,
you're always welcome, right?
ASHLEY: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Wherever you end up.
ASHLEY: Maybe for a little bit, but I've got some
things I need do, so.
LAURA: Do you guys want to travel with me and
Fjord?
ASHLEY: Where are you going, again?
TRAVIS: Up north. Northeast to the Solstryce
Academy.
LIAM: Straight there.
TALIESIN: Northeast. I've always wanted to go
there.
ASHLEY: Where's... where northeast?
LAURA: Um...
(chuckles)
SAM: We're here.
(laughter)
MATT: Well technically, you don't have a map.
SAM: Oh, no.
LAURA: We should really get a map, you guys. I
haven't spent a lot of time in this area and I
don't really know where we're going.
TRAVIS: We're kind of going from town to town and
asking as we go. Afraid we don't know too much.
LAURA: I wonder if there's a place-- maybe at the
general store? They would have a map? Or do you
have to go to a map maker?
TALIESIN: Traditionally, you have to go to a map
maker.
MATT: Traditionally but it can depend.
TALIESIN: We might have a bit of something at the
circus, I don't know.
ASHLEY: I would love a map.
LAURA: We'll go looking for things tomorrow. We
can go shopping.
ASHLEY: Okay. We'll go shopping with you.
LAURA: Yeah.
MARISHA: Where are you guys heading off to? Seems
like people are making pretty big plans.
TRAVIS: There's safety in numbers, you know?
LIAM: Yeah. Took the words out of my mouth.
LAURA: Nott, don't you want to travel with us,
too?
SAM: Um, is she coming?
LAURA: Yeah, she just said she was.
ASHLEY: Oh, are you scared of me?
SAM: A little bit. You're very big.
ASHLEY: Well, I thought you were Nott, the Brave?
SAM: Oh. No, there's no comma.
LAURA: (laughs)
SAM: I'm just Nott the Brave.
(laughter)
LIAM: I don't know. You know, Nott and I have been
travelling together for a while and two is better
than one, although still very difficult.
MARISHA: How long ago was it that you guys broke
out of prison?
LIAM: Uh... you know, it was six months ago,
about. Five, six months ago.
MARISHA: Damn, you guys are doing good.
TALIESIN: Insight check.
MATT: Against--
TALIESIN: Five or six months ago.
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: Oh, that was so close.
TALIESIN: 14.
SAM: You have to roll, don't you?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: Roll either persuasion or deception. You can
choose. Don't--
LIAM: I'll do persuasion.
MATT: I mean, you don't have to say but you did.
That's fine.
LIAM: That's uh, I don't know where on my
character sheet is. That's also a 14.
LAURA: Oh.
MATT: All right, so seems on the level.
TALIESIN: All right.
LAURA: (laughs)
TRAVIS: Broke out of prison? That's very
impressive.
SAM: Well, it was mainly Caleb. We had to get out.
I mean, it was a bad place.
LAURA: Were they going to kill you?
SAM: We would have died, for sure.
ASHLEY: But you guys were there together? Because
you knew each other before?
LIAM: Well, first of all, she's being modest. It
was not just me at all, I could not have gotten
out of there without you. I don't think you could
have gotten out of there without me either but you
know.
SAM: That's true, for sure.
LIAM: That's why I said two. Better than one. One
is the loneliest number.
LAURA: That you'll ever see.
LIAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: There's nothing wrong with being alone.
LIAM: You know, normally I wouldn't feel
comfortable talking about shit like this but you
are all very shifty.
LAURA: I'm very trustworthy.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
LIAM: No, no, no, you're shifty as well. Yeah.
TALIESIN: It's true.
TRAVIS: In the short time we've spent with you,
you seem to be very upstanding folks. I'm sure it
wasn't for anything too serious.
LIAM: No, nothing serious at all, really. I was
too curious. She was maybe a little thirsty. You
know, petty stuff.
SAM: But they treated us very badly and we needed
to get out of there.
LIAM: We all know how this country works.
MARISHA: And where was 'there'?
TRAVIS: Yeah, is there anywhere we should stay
away from on our travels?
LIAM: (clears throat)
SAM: Any place is-- I mean, we've been travelling
around a bit but--
LIAM: You know, I wouldn't go west, maybe.
TALIESIN: Northwest.
SAM: I'm told east is bad too. There's monsters.
LIAM: Yeah and they're pretty terrible in the
north. That's no secret.
LAURA: So we go south?
SAM: Oh no, not south.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: It just depends where in the south,
actually.
TALIESIN: I'd be happy keeping a bit of a low-key
existence.
LAURA: Well, I mean we are vigilantes so it's best
if we, you know, have our secrets.
TALIESIN: Some of us are a bit sketchy with the
law.
MARISHA: Yeah.
LIAM: Mollymauk, you're comfortable leaving the
circus? You are very-- you have a lot of flair.
TALIESIN: Well, I figured if you're going to live
your life, you're going to live your life.
LAURA: (jingling)
TALIESIN: Does do that. There's nothing wrong with
living your life. You only get one of them, or
mostly. And your days are going to be the days
that you're going to have and I'd like to keep
living my life the way I'd like to and keep off of
certain radars.
MARISHA: Cheers to that.
LAURA: Yeah. Life does need things to live.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Stupid phrase.
LIAM: That doesn't make any sense at all.
TALIESIN: Really stupid.
TRAVIS: Who said that?
LIAM: I mean, it does but it blatantly obvious and
simplistic.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: That's just ridiculous.
TALIESIN: That felt so good. That's catharsis.
TRAVIS: Yasha, anywhere that we should avoid for
you?
ASHLEY: You know. I'm just-- I'll make my way
wherever we go and maybe I'll not stay with you
the whole time but I don't like, you know--
TRAVIS: Being confined.
ASHLEY: Yeah. I don't-- groups and things--
MARISHA: Are you claustrophobic?
ASHLEY: Uh, no.
MARISHA: You mentioned the smaller cl--cramped space
in the cell. Just curious.
LAURA: Clamp space?
MARISHA: Clamps-- clampy space.
TALIESIN: Clam space.
ASHLEY: I like to have my freedom.
LIAM: I mean, technically this is a group. You
mean groups bigger than this group or is this
group too claustrophobic for you or-- ?
ASHLEY: No. I don't mean it like that. I just want
to make my own way sometimes.
MARISHA: Not tied down to anything but that cloak,
am I right?
ASHLEY: (chuckles) Yeah, that's right.
LAURA: Speaking of cloaks, mine smells really
bad.
SAM: It was on top of a head. Ugh, that's really
gross.
LAURA: I'm going to go try to find somewhere to
wash it.
MATT: Upstairs at the end of the hallway is a
communal washroom. You can find space there.
LAURA: Hey Caleb!
LIAM: Yeah?
LAURA: You know what's upstairs?
(laughter)
LAURA: This place where I'm going to go wash some
stuff. You could use it.
TALIESIN: You smell fine.
LAURA and MARISHA: (chuckles)
SAM: I like you just the way you are.
LAURA: You're bloody now, too, in addition to
being stinky.
TALIESIN: You should probably get that patched up,
actually, though. That is fair.
LIAM: (clears throat)
MARISHA: Yeah, I actually feel like you're
starting to get a rash.
(laughter)
LIAM: Yeah, I'm good, thank you.
TRAVIS: Damn right.
(laughter)
MATT: All right.
SAM: Well, I suppose we should all go to sleep and
then if any of us are here in the morning, we'll
set off together?
TRAVIS: That seems fair.
TALIESIN: I'm all right with that. Collect our
things from-- my things, anyway, from the circus.
There should be some spares.
LIAM: Do we have time to-- look at this, we're
making plans with friends, that's amazing. Do we
have for errands in the morning? I have a couple
stops. Nothing major.
TALIESIN: Take me a while to pack.
LIAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: You guys want me to tag along with you?
TRAVIS: If you weren't too anxious to run off
anywhere.
MARISHA: (chuckles, clears throat) No. I'm free on
my backpack tour. No plans.
TRAVIS: Right. Any sightseeing we should schedule
along our way?
MARISHA: Maybe avoid Zadash just because I just
came there, you know. Don't want to hit the same
place twice.
TRAVIS: Zadash?
MARISHA: Yup.
TRAVIS: Keep that in mind.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Note, note, note.
MATT: As you guys are all finishing your drinks
and standing up to leave the table, a familiar
voice pipes in from the center of the tavern.
"Beauregard?"
MARISHA: (groans)
MATT: And the Archivist who was there earlier
during the trial in the stockade. "It's been
difficult to find you. Do you mind if we speak?"
MARISHA: Hey, Zeenoth! Hey. It's been all of about
twenty minutes since I've seen you last.
MATT: "Yes, um, would you walk with me? I believe
we have much to discuss."
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: "Don't worry. She'll be returned to you.
Just--"
TRAVIS: You all right with this?
MARISHA: It's cool. I've got it.
TALIESIN: We don't care. We're not that attached
yet.
LAURA: (laughs)
MATT: "All right then. This way please,
Beauregard."
MARISHA: (sighs)
MATT: The elvish man gives a bow and he seems
jovial.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: More mine, more mine!
MATT: Beau leaves and you guys are able to go
about the rest of your evening to rest however you
see fit.
LIAM: Way up after Nott has gone, I go over to
Norda. Is Norda down there?
SAM: Yorda.
LIAM: No, there's two people with rhyming names.
MARISHA: Yorda is the bartender.
MATT: Yorda is the bartender.
LIAM: This is revenge for Vex and Vax.
MATT: Yeah, and Purvon.
LIAM: I find the purveyor of the establishment.
MATT: Yorda.
LIAM: Mork from Ork, that's what I said.
MATT: "Right, what can I help you with?"
LIAM: Excuse me, is there-- I know you have a bath
here, but is there a hot bath place like a
bathhouse? I'm bruised over every inch of my body
and I'm in a lot of pain.
MATT: "Right, that'll probably be in the
Hillsward. It's a bit pricey, but I don't know if
it's open this late."
LIAM: I know, but how much are we talking about?
MATT: "Oh, I'd put it maybe somewhere in the
neighborhood of five silver for a bath."
LIAM: That's expensive.
MATT: "But you get bathed like proper, multiple
people bathing you."
LIAM: Northward, you say?
MATT: "No, Hillsward."
LIAM: Okay, good.
MATT: "I mean, no offense to you. Their clientele
is a bit, upper class."
LIAM: I'm not worried.
MATT: "Alright, fair enough."
LIAM: Danke. And I head up there.
MATT: Okay. Beau, as you exit with Zeenoth. As
soon as you step into the night air, a second
figure flanks your other side. The hooded figure
from earlier that had caught you.
MARISHA: I just look at Zeenoth and go really? Is
this really necessary?
MATT: "It is only because it's been so difficult
to find you. I had to call in a favor. Please,
come with us. We have a warehouse."
MARISHA: Do we have to with this guy? He fucking--
look at him. He looks shifty.
MATT: The head turns to you in the hood and you
see dark elvish features. A bald head as the hood
comes back. What looks to be a female elf of very
lithe form who turns to you and goes, "Actually,
it is a woman, but I'll ignore that."
MARISHA: Sorry, you're super covered-- literally
saw no features until right now.
MATT: "It is fine."
MARISHA: You're very attractive though.
(laughter)
MATT: And she walks ahead of you and the two of
you begin to make your way there. They're guiding
you towards the Northward and as you step into the
dark following their lead, we're going to take a
break.
(cheering)
MARISHA: I smell bad y'all.
TRAVIS: Do you?
MARISHA: Don't. You were like, oh my cape smells
bad and I was like RPing and I like, ooh.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Everybody at home, grab your ticket you
got in the mail. Scratch off number three.
(laughter)
MATT: We'll be back here in a few minutes. For
those of you who want to enter the Wyrmwood
giveaway, tonight it's a special Valentine's Day
promotion from our friends at Wyrmwood. They have
four types of dice vaults to choose from where
they translate your Valentine Day's message in
Elvish.
(gasping)
TRAVIS: Damn that shit glows!
MATT: So you have some golden Evish stuff there.
LAURA: It's pretty and you can choose the wood.
LIAM: The writing only shows up if you throw it in
fire.
(laughter)
MATT: Don't listen to Liam. To whoever is the
winner of this or any of these, they'll go ahead
and get you the contact information for Wyrmwood
so they can customize your phrase. If you want to
be part of this giveaway over the break, make sure
to use the keyword toad. T-O-A-D in the chatroom.
There's also apparently an anti-Valentine's Day
Drow vault they do as well. It's pretty cool.
Check them out at wyrmwoodgaming.com but if you
want to enter that, the codeword is toad. Only
enter once please in the Twitch chat because if
you do more than once, you'll be disqualified.
Wait for them to notify you over the break and
we'll come back with the winner when we return.
MARISHA: They gave us an amazing matching set with
the Elvis-- Elvish for our wedding. It was super
sweet. Thanks Wyrmwood. Elvis from Memphis.
MATT: (Elvis impression) "Oh that was a natural
20." We'll see you guys in a little bit.
(cheering)
[break]
MATT: Hello, everyone, and welcome back. Before we
jump back in, we have our winner from the chat.
The winner is Piamo_Feddie! If I am reading this
correctly, Piamo_Feddie. Congratulations! Danoba
will get your contact information, we'll get that
sent out to you. Well done, and happy Valentine's
Day. Now jumping back into the game, I would like
to ask everyone but Marisha to leave the table,
please.
MARISHA: See you, guys.
TRAVIS: Don't die!
MARISHA: This is so scary! So nerve wracking.
MATT: Beauregard.
MARISHA: Mm-hmm.
MATT: Quietly, they walk you through the night
air, through the Northward, to a familiar place:
the outskirts of the Baumbauch Family Brewery.
There's a slight opening on the side warehouse
doors where you had previously worked when you
first arrived at Trostenwald, and Archivist
Zeenoth gestures for you to enter. "Please. If you
don't mind, my dear."
MARISHA: Really? Is this what got me caught,
working for these fucking assholes? Ugh. I walk in.
MATT: There is a single glowing lantern that is
currently hanging from a rope that is strewn
across the ceiling of the warehouse that gives a
central source of light to the room. It causes the
shadows to stretch out very long across the
sides.
MARISHA: What is this?
MATT: As you walk in and turn around, the door is
closed. The two figures approach. The female elf
goes and takes a chair and sets it in the center
beneath the lantern. "Please, have a seat."
MARISHA: I'd prefer to stand.
MATT: She just sits back, about 20 or so feet, and
leans against one of the large stacks of crates as
Zeenoth approaches you. "Now, Beauregard. You have
been what the Archive would call a problematic
student."
MARISHA: (laughter)
MATT: "I've had to pull in quite a bit of a
favor--"
MARISHA: Sorry. (laughter) Keep going. I'm
listening.
MATT: "Since I have been assigned to your
tutelage, overseeing your progress and training,
you've shown great promise, in many ways. You're a
seeker of truth, and you have a keen sense for
manipulations and falsehoods. Correct?"
MARISHA: Thanks?
MATT: "When the Archive took you in at the behest
of your family, you agreed to undergo our
discipline. Our lifestyle."
MARISHA: No, I didn't agree to shit. You took me
in because I'm assuming my father paid you a
pretty nice sum of coin to make sure that you took
me in. I'm assuming that coin is no longer coming
to the Reserve, so, why do you care?
MATT: "Believe it or not, not everyone does what
they do in this world for coin. We see possibility
in you. We, wish to prevent you from blowing out
your own flame. Your tendencies clash with our
teachings, your dislike for authority."
MARISHA: Yeah, I thought you guys hated me.
Thought I was doing you a favor by leaving.
MATT: At which point, the woman from behind says,
"Your dislike for authority is not a bad thing. It
can keep you alive. Authority should always be
questioned. Those with more power than you should
be held to a higher standard."
MARISHA: Thank you, authoritative figure who I am
unaware of your name?
MATT: At which point, Zeenoth picks up, again,
says, "But the way of the Knowing Mistress has an
order of learning. Your patience is essential to
adhering to this path. I know it may not be
stimulating at times, but we must prepare your
mind if we are ever to prepare your soul."
MARISHA: Yeah, I'd say that sorting books and
punching brick walls repeatedly can definitely not
be stimulating at all times.
MATT: "Look, I just wish to--" At which point, the
elven woman goes, "Enough. I've heard enough,
Zeenoth. You are removed of your responsibility to
oversee Beauregard." Zeenoth's eyes go wide. "This
is not a student you can help. Return to Zadash."
Zeenoth goes, "Expositor, I do not think that I
have been given a fair shot. Please--" "I know
this girl, because I see much of myself in her.
You cannot reach her. Go." Zeenoth looks hurt. "I
apologize that I failed you." He turns around and
heads back towards the warehouse doors, which
shift open, and close.
MARISHA: The fuck was that?
MATT: The woman now steps forward.
MARISHA: I feel like he made me look like an
asshole, feel like an asshole. Fuck, maybe I'm an
asshole.
MATT: "Maybe you're an asshole. You probably are
an asshole. That's all right, because so am I.
Because sometimes you need someone to be an
asshole to get shit done."
MARISHA: Being nice never did. What are we
talking, stranger?
MATT: "I am Expositor Dairon, of the Cobalt
Soul."
MARISHA: Dairon?
MATT: D-A-I-R-O-N. "I take it you have heard of
our station through whispers."
MARISHA: Some people like to call you boogie men.
I figured it was always real. In my opinion, the
best way to hide in a secret organization is by
having a boogie man.
MATT: "We are the hidden strength of the library,
you are not wrong. We wade in the filth of
society. We weed out the corrupt. We pursue the
secret evils of the world, and expose them to the
light."
MARISHA: Wow.
MATT: "We twist the arm of the unjust, until they
spill their mysteries. We are the spies. We are
the hunters. We are the watchmen to those who
rule. We are not kind. We are forthright. We are
truth. Do you, Beauregard, want to see the truths
of the world?"
MARISHA: Oh god, I'm sorry. I have this burn in my
butt from all the smoke you just blew up my ass.
It's just, oh god. Is that a magical talent?
MATT: What's your armor class?
MARISHA: 17.
MATT: You suffer ten points of bludgeoning damage
as, out of nowhere, her fist hits you right across
the side of your face.
MARISHA: It takes me to the ground. That takes me
to the ground.
MATT: You're unconscious?
MARISHA: No, just takes me to the ground.
MATT: Okay. "Are you listening now?"
MARISHA: Do I have a choice?
MATT: "Let me be your teacher."
MARISHA: Oh, boy. Is that what I have to look
forward to?
MATT: "No. What do you want to do now, that that's
happened?"
MARISHA: I kind of want to fucking punch you
back.
MATT: "Then do it."
"What's stopping you?"
MARISHA: Now you have my attention. And I fucking
punch her in the face!
MATT: Go for it. Roll for an attack.
MARISHA: Just a straight unarmed, right?
MATT: Yep.
MARISHA: 12 total, not good.
MATT: She dodges out of the way, and as you move
past, plucks you in the back of the head with a
knuckle. That hits. You take one point of
bludgeoning damage. It's a very light tap.
MARISHA: Ow! What the fuck, my dad used to do that
type of shit.
MATT: With that, she rushes around with a rapid
pace to the front of you, feints with an upper
cut, and then goes to elbow you in the side of the
head. That is a 16. What's your armor class?
MARISHA: That misses. 17.
MATT: Misses. You manage to duck out of the way of
it. She goes, "Good. Good."
MARISHA: I got to add some points here.
MATT: Okay. She's going to go ahead and use her
bonus action to go into a defensive stance.
"Come on."
MARISHA: (yells) I'm going to spend a ki point,
and go into Flurry of Blows, and do a blind
haymaker, a second blind haymaker, and then try
and backhand with the third. Wildly, recklessly.
Okay, first one. Natural 20!
MATT: Oh, shit!
MARISHA: Second one. Natural 20!
MATT: Two natural 20s in a row!
MARISHA: I don't have anyone sitting next to me to
confirm this, but I swear it's a natural 20!
MATT: No, I can see it!
MARISHA: I'll take a picture if I have to! A
natural 17.
MATT: Roll damage on those first two!
MARISHA: Okay. You double the dice, right?
MATT: Yeah. Roll the dice, double it.
MARISHA: Okay. That was a three, a two, so five,
ten plus eight. 18.
MATT: 18 points of damage. Then the third strike
that hit?
MARISHA: One, so another five points. God
fucking-- Thinking of my dad, after she just went
"boop," something just popping the back of my
head.
MATT: You watch as her defensive stance, she's
prepared for it, and as you go to swing, she lets
it down at the last second, and lets you get some
hits in. Wham, wham! But much stronger than she
expected. The first one clocks her across the
chin. The other one hits her across the temple.
The last one--
MARISHA: Just a wild backhand.
MATT: Just hits her in the back of the head. She
stumbles for a second, then spins around. You can
see a bit of blood trickling out of the corner of
her mouth, and there's a little bit of a scrape of
dirt on the side her head where you hit. She turns
around. "Very good. You have learned some things
in your time." She quickly advances on you. Hits.
18, hits. Okay. You take three points of
bludgeoning damage, one per hit. Pop! Pop pop! She
is basically going full in with the strike, and is
just prodding you with these gentle little hits,
showing control, showing that she's entirely able
to overwhelm you, and she's hitting different
places on your body, strategically. Because with
each hit, you feel this burst of numbness in those
vicinities. I need you to make a constitution
saving throw.
MARISHA: Not great. That's a natural seven, so ten
total.
MATT: Okay. After each hit, you gather yourself
for a second, she stops and goes, "You are quick,
and there is intelligence lying in there. You are
also quite nimble at dodging blows. Do you see,
with but a few simple strikes, I'm able to extract
from you everything I need to know about you."
MARISHA: What the fuck, why can't I feel my hand?
What did you do?
MATT: "You see, brute force has its place. But
precision, and intent. That can take down the
greatest of mountains, by poking the weakest
point. Now, I know where your weak points are."
MARISHA: You don't know shit about me, bitch. I'm
going to take another attack.
MATT: Go for it.
MARISHA: That's a three. That's a nine.
MATT: Nope. With each miss, or, the first miss,
she's going to use a reaction to attack you.
That's going to be-- She can do that. Ducks out of
the way, and immediately uses a reaction to smack
you in the head for one point of damage, another
bludgeoning point. She's going to spend another ki
point to do another reaction. She can also do
that.
MARISHA: Roll. I rolled a 15 to attack. Second
attack. These are two attacks, right?
MATT: For your second one, yeah.
MARISHA: 15, so, 21.
MATT: Yeah, the second one does hit. She does not
get the second attack. Roll damage on that second
strike.
MARISHA: Okay. Attacking her with the first one,
and then I'm just going to duck down a little and
jab her right in the ribs.
MATT: All right. What was the damage on that?
MARISHA: Eight.
MATT: Eight damage, nice. You crack her in the
ribs, and the impact actually does catch her off
guard. She ends up tumbling five feet backward
across the ground, catching herself in a
three-point landing.
MARISHA: I back up. I'm going to spend another ki
point to do my defensive stance. Patient defense.
MATT: Okay. Patient defense. You go into that
stance that she was in earlier, but holding it for
the entirety of this. Her eyes narrow for a
second. You see her looking at all the different
points that she struck on you earlier, like she's
reading some sort of a docket on what your
physicality is. With that, she doesn't run at you,
she runs around you in a circle and begins to jump
off the sides of the boxes, some of the crates
that are stacked up nearby. You watch them wiggle
as she puts her weight up against them, leaps
off--
MARISHA: Instead of getting distracted by her, I
just listen to her and look at her out of my
periphery.
MATT: Okay. Eventually, she uses her momentum to
climb to the top with her feet and leap off, then
come downward with the knee towards you.
MARISHA: Right as she comes down and I'm going to
use-- Oh, wait, dodge? Go first?
MATT: You're already in your defensive stance, so
her attack's at disadvantage against you. The
first strike. 19, 20 to hit?
MARISHA: Miss. It says patient defense, spend one
ki point to take the dodge action as a bonus
action on my turn.
MATT: Correct, what the dodge action does is it
means any attacks against you have disadvantage.
MARISHA: Oh. Cool.
MATT: The first one did hit. Second one does not.
The third one does. Two hits still get you. Both
one point of bludgeoning damage. The knee comes
down, and right as it cracks into your head, she
shifts to the side and glides off, and as soon as
her body glides off, her back is to yours, and her
spinning elbow goes and cracks you in the side of
the head, but it stops short, just barely hitting
you. She's toying with you at this point.
MARISHA: You said two more points?
MATT: Yes, two more points of bludgeoning damage.
Make another constitution saving throw, please.
MARISHA: 11. No, sorry, 12.
MATT: This time, opposed to the pressure points
being hit, there is the one smack on the side of
your head.
MARISHA: Yeah?
MATT: This pain surges through the side of your
temple, and travels through your spine, to all the
points she had hit earlier, and your whole body
tenses and seizes for a second. Your vision blurs,
and your mouth stammers, and you're stunned for
the next round. As she lands behind you, and walks
around to the front of you, you're unable to, you
can't move, you can't speak. "I can start you on
this path. You can return to your wanderlust, your
allies. Our kind learns more in the world than in
a library. Agree to my instruction, to use the
skills I teach you, as you return throughout your
journeys. One day, you too, can become an
expositor." You begin to regain control of your
senses, and your speech begins to slowly return to
you.
MARISHA: Okay. I got to hand it to you, that was
awesome, and I want to know how to do that. You
beat me.
MATT: "Very well. Your first lesson begins now."
MARISHA: Okay. (groan)
MATT: She snaps her fingers, and you watch as
Zeenoth steps back in, sheepishly. "Is it over, my
dear? Is it done?" "I need you to stand here for a
second, Zeenoth. I need a body. Let me show you
the proper pressure points." Zeenoth's eyes go
wide for a second. "I don't believe--" "You owe me
a favor. I found her for you, did I not?" Zeenoth
sighs, sags his head, and takes his cloak off.
MARISHA: I grab that stool, and I drag it over.
MATT: "Now, depending on what you wish to learn,
there are different places where you can pull the
information from the body." Over the next few
hours, working with you, and over time--
MARISHA: Does she beat the shit out of Zeenoth?
MATT: You both do.
MARISHA: Sorry, Zeenoth. Sorry. God, we're such
assholes.
MATT: "Assholes that the world needs, from time to
time."
MARISHA: Yeah. The world does need an asshole.
We'll work on that one together. We'll work on
that. That's good, that's good.
MATT: "I'll return to Zadash in the morning. Take
what I have taught you. "When you feel it's time
for more tutelage, return to me. Do not worry. I
have an eye on you."
MARISHA: What do I do until then, do I just
continue--
MATT: "Do what you must. Travel the world. Use
what I've taught you. Learn about injustice. Those
you don't trust, follow them. Bend them. Make them
tell the truth and admit their guilt. Find where
ever corruption is. Root it out and let the system
do its job. If the system isn't doing its job,
destroy the system."
MARISHA: Why are you doing this? Why me?
MATT: "Because a long time ago, I was a wayward
girl with no direction, was angry, and fighting at
the world. And someone did this for me."
MARISHA: I don't really believe in systems or
being a part of them, let alone a system that
takes down other systems. Seems almost
hypocritical.
MATT: "Perhaps. Who knows. Maybe one day you'll
find the corruption inside our own."
MARISHA: Touche.
MATT: "Go. Get some rest. Clean up a bit, I think
you could use it."
MARISHA: You might have broke my wrist.
MATT: "It'll heal. Zeenoth." She slaps him awake.
His unconscious body on the ground.
MARISHA: Bye, Zeenoth! Zeenoth!
MATT: (coughing)
MARISHA: Zeenoth!
MATT: "Oh dear."
MARISHA: Bye.
MATT: "Goodbye. I have such great pleasure in
saying goodbye, and good riddance."
MARISHA: I leave.
MATT: You make your way back to the tavern, go
back into the room, and, exhaustedly, pass out.
Let's bring everyone else back in.
MARISHA: Hi, friends. How's it going?
TRAVIS: Are you alive?
LIAM: I'm sure everything went according to plan.
TALIESIN: Quiet dignity and grace.
MATT: As you all come to consciousness in the
morning, little sore, but recovered--mostly--from
the battle that wrecked you the evening before.
The fresh smells of cooked meats, and the sounds
of various patrons below in the inn tavern floor,
rouse you to the morning. What do you wish to do?
LIAM: Ah--
MARISHA: Hi, guys. Sorry I snuck in last night.
TRAVIS: How does she look?
MATT: She's beat to shit.
TRAVIS: Oh, fuck! Did you get horse kicked?
MARISHA: Several times.
TRAVIS: Damn. How's the horse look?
MARISHA: Horse is fucking dead. I ate it.
TRAVIS: That's a bit excessive.
MARISHA: Horse is fucking fine. Hey, Jester, do
you have a bandage? Do you have a thing?
LAURA: Oh, yes! Of course I do. I have a lot of
bandages because I am the cleric.
TRAVIS: I don't know if that bone's supposed to be
sticking out of that part.
LAURA: Yes, I'm going to open the medical kit and
rummage around. Pull out some stuff. Give me your
wrist! I can definitely heal this.
TRAVIS: I bet Yasha can pop it back into place.
MARISHA: Yeah, crack.
MATT: Make a medicine check.
TRAVIS: You just made a bow.
TALIESIN: It was string and mime.
MARISHA: Oh, you made it worse!
LIAM: (blood gushing)
LAURA: 20.
MATT: Okay. It's actually fairly well made; it
gives some nice support to it. I mean, it's more
of a sprain than a break. But it helps offer some
support to it. It'll heal.
MARISHA: I've had some sprains that feel like
breaks.
MATT: Yeah, no, it hurts like a bitch, or it did
last night. Or it feels a little better today, but
that's definitely going to help give it some
support. Good job.
MARISHA: Thank you.
ASHLEY: What happened to you?
LAURA: I've been practicing.
TRAVIS: Not you, her. What happened to her?
LAURA: Oh. Sorry.
MARISHA: Man, it was a great night. I had a great
night! I haven't had a great night in a long time,
you guys. That was a great night.
TRAVIS: With the guy you--
LAURA: You came in really late.
TALIESIN: I'd like to see the other guy.
MARISHA: I might have been accepted into, like, a
secret society. It's kind of secret society
business. It's hard to talk about.
LAURA: Are you allowed to talk about it? Tell us
about it!
MARISHA: Okay! No, I can't. It's fine. There are
these monks. I thought they hated me. It turns out
they like me. Turns out they want me to become a
part of their gang. But it's not really real, and
they're like, "Just keep doing your thing! But
you're against injustice and seek out truth and
break systems!"
LAURA: You are a hero!
LIAM: Is this one of those dreams where nobody has
their clothes on?
TALIESIN: You know, if the monks beat you up to
make them join your gang, they're not really your
friends.
MARISHA: You know, I said something like that to
her. It wasn't as black and white as that.
TALIESIN: Is that why they did that to your face
there? Oh, no, they didn't. Apparently they were
pretty--
MARISHA: I wouldn't say this woman was my friend.
I would say she's definitely a badass. I wouldn't
say she's my friend.
TRAVIS: This woman, was she with the fellow that
you left with last night?
MARISHA: She was. His name was Zeenoth. He's an
archivist of the Cobalt Reserve. Lot of books
there. Lot of books.
TRAVIS: Cobalt Reserve. He was in the court.
ASHLEY: Was this a test of some sort?
MARISHA: I think so.
LAURA: Did you pass? I mean, they made you a hero,
so obviously you did.
MARISHA: I'm not a hero. That's not what they did.
It's more like a vigilante! Like what we said!
Yeah!
LAURA: This is so great. Can they let us into the
secret society too?
MARISHA: No.
LIAM: Well, you know, this is very fascinating,
but I have some errands to run. Nott, would you
like to run errands with me? We are totally coming
back and not leaving on our own undercover.
TRAVIS, LAURA, and TALIESIN: Insight check.
LIAM: Bring it on.
MARISHA: Do you need an insight check to know that
that was shady as fuck?
TALIESIN: Fuck all.
LAURA: 15.
TRAVIS: 11.
LIAM: Persuasion?
TALIESIN: 11.
MATT: You don't have to tell me what you're
rolling!
LIAM: I rolled a natural 20! Whatever. I'm being
very honest! We're not going anywhere. But I do
have errands to run. So, we're going to leave
soon. Have some breakfast. I grab some bacon from
Ford/Fjord's plate, and grab Nott and head out the
door.
TALIESIN: Meet us at the circus.
LAURA: I'm going to draw in my sketchbook a
drawing of the devil toad head rolling along the
ground like a bowling ball.
SAM and TALIESIN: She really did.
LAURA: Well, kind of. I put the little bowling
ball things on there. And he's going to run into
all of us, in chains, being knocked down like
pins.
MATT: Okay. Roll a dexterity check. Why not?
LAURA: Eight-- No, 15.
MATT: It's very well done. There's, like, hatch
mark shading.
LAURA: Well, I did get really good training, so
it's good that I know how to do shading.
MATT: All right, what are you guys doing? The rest
of you, while they rush off to go about their
errands.
TRAVIS: Apparently eating less of my bacon,
motherfucker.
TALIESIN: I'm going to pack up and head back to
the circus. Start getting things together.
ASHLEY: Yeah. I think I'll join you.
MATT: Molly and Yasha are heading back to the
carnival grounds.
LAURA: I want to go try to buy a map.
MARISHA: That's a good idea.
LAURA: Yeah!
ASHLEY: Oh, I did actually want to see that map.
TALIESIN: I'll meet you there. Actually, you know
what? I want to see you see that map.
ASHLEY: I think that's a great idea. Seeing me see
a map is something pretty special.
TALIESIN: It's gorgeous. It's fabulous.
MATT: You guys, where are you heading off to?
LIAM: I have two places to go. The first, we're
going to the Burnished Bibelots. The second is a
surprise. But I know that I whisked you away in a
hurry the other day and you weren't done
browsing.
SAM: That sounds lovely and I would like to browse
there again, but, honestly, Caleb, I am very
worried about you. You have passed out twice in
the last few days, and unless we get you a healing
potion, there is no promise that you will still be
alive tomorrow. I think we should go to Natural
Remedies. You distract the owner while I go in the
back and I steal a healing potion. It's the only
way to guarantee your safety.
LIAM: Maybe that's the third place that we go. I
will point out your point, which was that these
crazy bastards are very distracting and strange,
yeah?
SAM: Yes!
LIAM: So they could be my healing potion, you
know? We'll talk about it. Third place. So, drag
her off to the Burnished Bibelots. Boom, in the
door.
MATT: You head inside. It looks as chaotic as you
left it. You see what looks to be a small bowl of
heated porridge that's gathered on the counter,
and cross-legged on top is the fantastic gnomish
purveyor of the interior, Oglen. "Hello?"
LIAM: Good day to you, sir!
MATT: "Good day to you as well."
LIAM: I give Nott a little shove over towards the
shelves and walk up to him, right up to the
counter. What are you eating there? That looks
good.
MATT: "Breakfast."
LIAM: All right, yeah. That's what that is. You
know, I wanted to thank you for the book. I don't
know if you read it yourself, but I read it cover
to cover quickly. It was fascinating and very
useful.
[aside, quietly] I hope you're doing stuff over there.
MATT: "All sales are final!"
LIAM: Well, here's the thing. I have read this
book and loved it, and if you would like to
purchase it for the low, low price of one gold,
you can sell it again. You sold it to me for
three. You have it back for one. You can turn a
profit.
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
LIAM: Natural 20.
MATT: You watch as some of the porridge is
spilling out the side of his mouth, and he rubs it
off. "All right." And he pulls a gold coin out of
his pouch.
LIAM: That is a good decision, and it was a good
book. I am grateful for the knowledge you have
imparted upon me.
MATT: "Might I have the book?"
LIAM: Oh, of course! It's right here on the table.
Sorry, grandfather.
MATT: "All sales are final."
LIAM: Right. You will not sell that back to me,
for sure.
MATT: "Do you want it? I can sell it to you for
three gold."
LIAM: That's a good price. Nott, how are you
doing?
SAM: (chewing) Bacon's really good!
LIAM: All done for the day?
SAM: I'm looking around for something to swipe.
MATT: Make an investigation check. You guys keep
just shaking down this poor gnome guy.
SAM: Ten.
MATT: Looking around, I mean, a lot of this is
knick-knacks and inane garbage, and things that
just aren't quite worth what you'd be looking for.
You do find one art piece that looks like it's a
pretty good art piece with a decent frame, might
be worth a little bit, but that's the best you can
find. Everything else here looks like it's the
dingy side of the Salvation Army.
SAM: Anything small? Ooh! Can I find my old flask
that I left here?
MATT: Yes, I'll let you do that. It has not moved
from where you placed it.
SAM: I'm going to steal back my old flask.
MATT: Make a sleight of hand check, please.
LIAM: What is that little dancer toy? Between the
three red mushrooms on the shelf behind you, is
that a music box there?
MATT: "It is a music box."
He takes it and cranks it.
SAM: 24.
MATT: "It was a music box."
LIAM: It's lost the magic.
MATT: "I can fix it."
LIAM: How long would that take?
MATT: He breaks it open, looks inside. "Three
days."
LIAM: Okay. Well, I'll come back and see your work
in three days. Work on that and your breakfast.
Hey Nott, are you ready?
SAM: Mm-hmm!
LIAM: All right. Good day to you. Happy sales.
MATT: "Happy sales, as well."
LIAM: Sure. Out the door.
SAM: I rolled a 24.
MATT: Yeah, he did not notice at all.
LIAM: I'm going to head in the direction, dragging
my goblin friend with me, to that fancy bathhouse
that was described to me last night at the Nestled
Nook.
MATT: You guys make your way southward. Go ahead
and make a general charisma check.
LIAM: Charisma check? Well, something I wanted to
do before we got there, was going to do it maybe
in an alley, but you tell me, is I would like to
cast Disguise Self on myself. Presumably gone into
an alleyway so no one sees me doing this in the
middle of the road. I take the form of a man in
very fancy green robes, beautiful blond hair, very
handsome man, with a vomit stain down the front of
my clothes.
MATT: Okay. Specific and easily done.
LIAM: I drag my little friend along with me. You
are going to like this, this is something very special.
SAM: I'm excited.
LIAM: Oh, charisma check. Straight charisma?
MATT: Straight charisma. Add your modifier.
LIAM: Yeah, it's 11.
MATT: 11, okay. With your Disguise Self form, it's
easy enough for you to ask a few questions, and
eventually you are given directions to what is
called the Warm Dew Bathhouse. Warm Dew.
LAURA: Warm Doo, D-O-O.
MATT: D-E-W.
LIAM: Dew, dew. There's a liquid u in that.
TRAVIS: Warm doo. Thank you.
MATT: It'll be one before you bathe there and the
other when you leave.
(laughter)
LIAM: All right, let's enter this establishment.
MATT: For as far south as this is, it's pretty
decent compared to the other areas. Most of the
Hillsward-- you get the sense that a lot of the
rural farming community that fills out most of
Trostenwald, a lot of the money that gets made
goes directly to the central portion of this ward,
where this bathhouse is. It's small, but it's
really well put together. As you walk inside, you
can see there are marble busts set on the sides of the
entrance way, each side. You can see nice
tapestries that are pulled back over the windows,
and as both of you walk in, you see this young
man, maybe his mid-twenties or so. Human, but he
looks very thin and sickly, like he had a rough
upbringing, and his general constitution has
suffered for it. He has a warm smile, and he's
wearing these long white robes with what looks to
be a yellowish scarf that's wrapped around as he
approaches. "Hello and good morning. Can I help
you?"
LIAM: Yes, one moment. (quietly) Stay close to me
and let me do the talking. (louder) Hello, please,
don't focus-- my daughter is shy.
MATT: "I'm very sorry."
LIAM: I've had a terrible day. Some disgusting
derelict has vomited all over me, I smell like
filth, and I would like to spend a couple of hours
in your finest bath. Maybe not your finest. A good
bath, for a couple of hours. My daughter and I. I
will need adjoining baths, if you have that. For
modesty's sake, my daughter and I.
MATT: "That can be done. Of course." Make a
persuasion check.
LIAM: (humming) There's a 12.
MATT: "For two hours, that will run-- for two
baths adjoining, we'll put it at eight silver pieces."
LIAM: That's fine. I definitely have that. I take
out the eight silver, I slap it down.
MATT: "Wonderful. We'll show you to your
bathroom."
LIAM: Okay. Come along, dear.
SAM: Yes, Vater.
MATT: You guys are escorted to what-- It's really
off-putting for the two of you. Not only is the
smell clean inside here, but there's the scent of
lavender in the hallway, and you hear soft music
in the distance. As you walk past, you do see that
there is a resident violinist that plays, and you
guys are led to these two--
SAM: This is really nice!
LIAM: Yes, it is.
SAM: They got a violinist over there! I'm sorry,
zey got a violinist over zere, Vater.
LIAM: That's meine Liebchen. I'm hoping for a hot
bath for the both of us. It has been a long bit of travel.
MATT: "Right this way." Leads you into the
chambers. There is a glass, fogged window, so the
sunlight comes through, but no one can see
through. There are some linens set out, a towel,
and two basins that are freshly filled with
steaming water. You are left into the chamber.
LIAM: Are they separate, though?
MATT: They're separated by a small wall that's eye
length, but you can still talk to each other over it.
LIAM: Excellent. This is called a bath.
SAM: I've heard of them.
LIAM: A hot bath. We have been pretty dinged up
for the past several months, and we might not get
back into something like this for a while, so I
want you to enjoy it. Go over to your side, and I
will be here. Nott, I'm going to do a bit of
reading.
SAM: While you bathe?
LIAM: Yes.
SAM: You'll still be the same Caleb when you're
done, right?
LIAM: Yes, I will be the same Caleb.
SAM: I've just gotten used to you, and now you're going
to change a bit.
LIAM: Trust me, I will not.
SAM: All right.
LIAM: Once she is clear of the wall, I'm going to
start actually disrobing, although I guess the
illusion stays.
MATT: The illusion stays. Strangely, clothes start
apparating out of you. (slurping)
MARISHA: It's like a bad video game glitch. Bad
texture glitch.
LIAM: Nott, I'm probably going to go quiet for a
little while.
SAM: No problem. I'll just be over here, you know,
bathing.
LIAM: Enjoy it. I find the second book and examine
it. Am I able to read this?
MATT: You are, actually. There is one incomplete
arcane inscription in there. Unfortunately, it's
been too burned, beyond recognition. You can see
this was a spellbook. Mostly destroyed, but there
are two complete spells in there that, if you wish
to, you could transcribe over into your book.
Those would be Arcane Lock and Unseen Servant.
ALL: Ooh!
LIAM: So. All my actual clothes are off. I'm going to
take the book and set it on the edge of the basin.
MATT: Because you paid for it, there is a hinged,
small desk piece where food can be eaten, or
drinks could be served while people are taking a
bath.
LIAM: I set it down. I sit with just my legs in
the bath for a moment, and I look at the book.
[exhales]
SAM: I'm going to find the pitcher of cucumber
water, dump it on the floor, and eat all the cucumbers.
(laughter)
MATT: As you hear over the wall (gobbling).
SAM: Look around for anything in the room that can
be stolen?
MATT: Plenty of things, actually. No one's
watching. There's a vase that's really nice. The
doorknob itself is a brass, gold-like material.
SAM: I'll start working on that.
MATT: Using your thieves' tools, you can get that
free, if you want.
SAM: After a while, I put a toe into the water,
feel it, and I'm like: Nah. I'll use my empty
flask and fill it up with water.
MATT: Okay. You get a water flask.
SAM: Then work on the doorknob.
MATT: Okay. Go ahead and make a thieves' tools
check, adding your dexterity.
SAM: 12.
MATT: Add the dexterity and your proficiency.
SAM: Oh. 14.
MATT: There you go. With very little sound, the
doorknob comes off, and you have now a solid brass
doorknob. There is the vase.
SAM: Is it a big vase?
MATT: It's like that big. It's more of a
decorative flower holder over by the window.
SAM: Sure. I'll try to get that too.
MATT: Easy. You get it. There's nobody watching
you!
SAM: I'll also save the flowers in a separate
pouch.
MATT: Okay. There you go.
SAM: Any towels. Ooh, you know what?
MATT: Yeah, the linens can be taken.
SAM: I'm going to take one towel and tear it into
shreds, and use it to replace any of my bandages
that have worn or fallen off.
MATT: Easy enough. There's some nice clean
bandages. Good.
SAM: I'm good.
LIAM: On my side, while all of that is happening,
two things. One is that when I finally get into
the tub I dip my whole body almost entirely in,
but not my head or hair. Letting the bruises soak
in the hot water, which feels wonderful. The
second thing is, while flipping the pages of this
book, very still, I can hear all of this, and it
is extremely endearing, but I go completely still.
Completely quiet. And read in peace.
MATT: While you guys are taking a bath, the rest
of you are going off on a shopping trip. Except
for you, you're going to--
TALIESIN: No, I'm going map hunting.
MATT: That's right. You're going. Who's all going
together?
LAURA: All of us.
MATT: Where are you going?
LAURA: Okay, I'm going to ask Yorda if there's a
map maker in town.
TALIESIN: Or if she can draw us a map of how to
get there.
MATT: "There's not much of a specific cartographer
in place. Most of the cartography guilds are up
"north in either Zadash or Rexxentrum. There might
be one in Alfield? We're a bit small over here.
"You could ask the general store, or you could
maybe go to the stockade. They have maps there but
"they use those. You might be able to pay enough
for them."
LAURA: I don't want to go back to the stockade.
MATT: "Then maybe check the general store or any
of the strange book places might have something
"old and lying in the back."
LAURA: Ooh, what strange book places?
MATT: "Well, let's see. There's the Hillsbrook
Parchment and Binding. There's the Burnished
"Bibelots, that I think one of your friends has
already been to. Those are the two strange book
"places. I'm not much of a reader myself, so I
couldn't tell you."
LAURA: Can you draw me a map of how to get to
those places?
MARISHA: We've already been to the general store.
LAURA: Yes, you're right. I guess we can try that
place.
MARISHA: You can still make her draw a map. I
don't want to rain on your parade. I'm sorry.
TRAVIS: You just shit all over her.
MARISHA: I totally did.
MATT: She gives you directions.
LAURA: Let's go on a trip!
MATT: Where are you guys going first?
MARISHA: (singing) General store!
LAURA: We've been there before.
MARISHA: (singing) I want to buy another health
pack!
SAM: Health pack?
MARISHA: I meant a healer's kit.
LAURA: The general store doesn't like us very
much. Oh wait. That healer's kit, is that the one
you bought when we were together?
MARISHA: Yeah.
LAURA: You spent way too much money on it because
I changed the tag?
MARISHA: Yeah. That one.
LAURA: That was great. Now I have it. Cool.
MARISHA: You won twice.
MATT: Everything's coming up Jester.
LAURA: All right, let's go back there. They don't
like me, but let's go back there.
MARISHA: I can just pop in if you want to wait
outside.
LAURA: They don't like you either.
MARISHA, Yeah, but they like money. Let's go.
MATT: All right, so you guys make your way to
Lochward General in the Lochward District. As you
enter, the older woman, Harper Mince, is there in
the general store. It's the large, almost wooden
barn exterior. The front door opens two ways, and
the inside is wall-to-wall lined with tools for
farming and farming equipment for building.
There's lumber. There's all sorts of iron nails.
It's by all accounts a rural general store.
You see on far end is Harper, the older
woman there, standing and looking out at the rest
of you. "Hi, can I help you? What are you looking
for?"
LAURA: We are looking for pickles, did you get any
yet?
MATT: "No, we don't sell pickles here, sorry."
LAURA: Most general stores have pickles, this is
the only thing.
MARISHA: You're not wrong, generally, yeah.
MATT: "We can order some pickles, if you like."
LAURA: Yeah, you probably should. I think you
would do well if you sold pickles. Do you have
maps for sale of the area?
MATT: "The area? Let me check. I'll be right
back."
LAURA: Does she leave the room?
MATT: Yeah, she does. She leaves the room.
TRAVIS: Don't-- put your hands in your pockets.
LAURA: Don't put my hands in my pockets, got it! I
start running around and just moving everything on
the shelves again the same way as before.
MATT: Make a sleight of hand check.
SAM: You're just moving things?
LAURA: Yeah, just like moving--
TRAVIS: Please be Laura when she was five and
break shit.
LAURA: Oh yes! 18 plus five.
TALIESIN: This is beautiful.
MATT: With nary a squeak you completely rearrange
in a period of about two and a half minutes most
of the price cards that are dangling from a number
of the tools, their placement. You guys all sit
back and watch as this glorious display-- you can
almost hear the William Tell Overture begin to
play in the back of your head as she rummages back
and forth throughout the interior of the chamber,
turning things around and sticking them in the
ground. It has been completely rearranged.
LIAM: [old man voice] Why
is this crowbar seven gold?
MATT: Eventually you hear some rummaging from the
back room and some footsteps coming nearby and you
quickly stop and return to your original point
there and Harper Mince returns from the back room.
She has a few papers in her arms. She goes, "I'm
sorry, we don't have any maps of the local area
for detail. I have a map of the Dwendalian Empire
as a whole, I hope that's enough."
LAURA: I mean, that could work, I suppose. It's
not what we need, but if that's what you have
that's what we can buy from you.
MATT: "All right, let me look at the date here.
This will run about seven silver."
LAURA: Okay, that sounds like a good price, yeah.
MARISHA: Can I also get another healer's kit? If
you have one.
MATT: "Right, yes, let me go ahead and get that
for you here." The healer's kit. Looking up the
pricing in the equipment section.That is five gold
pieces for the healer's kit.
(groaning)
MARISHA: Five gold.
MATT: All right, mark it off. You get yourself a
secondary healer's kit.
MARISHA: Well, one healer's kit. She's got the
other one.
MATT: You hand over the seven silver?
LAURA: Yes, I do.
MATT: She takes it and put the ribbon back on it.
Finally get to give that to you guys.
LIAM: Shut the front door!
LAURA: And I have a pretty ribbon out of it.
TALIESIN: We're going to Goonies this really
quickly here. Ready?
LAURA: What the fuck?!
SAM: That's beautiful! Who made this? Did you make
this?
MATT: I designed the layout, but the map is made
by a wonderful woman named Deven Rue, who does
incredible handcrafted maps.
SAM: You got to get a camera on this shit.
TRAVIS: Hold it up!
MARISHA: Put it in the middle.
TALIESIN: Take a look, it's amazing!
TRAVIS: Oh my god!
MARISHA: Wait, where are we?
MATT: You guys are in Trostenwald, right there.
This is north, this is south.
SAM: Angle it to that camera.
LAURA: What camera?
ALL: Wow.
MATT: This is the Dwendalian Empire. This is not
all of Wildemount, this is just a portion. Deven
did an incredible job with this. You should follow
her on Patreon or Twitter, she does amazing work.
She does incredible work.
LAURA: Oh my god, you guys, let's go all of these
places.
ASHLEY: Maybe not all of them.
LAURA: Okay, we are definitely going to visit this
place called Hupperdook.
SAM: I think I had one of those this morning.
[laughter]
LAURA: Then we'll make our way up to Nogvuror. Oh
man, this is awesome. Hey look, look over here!
This is where I live!
SAM: There be dragons there.
TALIESIN: You live in a serpent?
LAURA: Mm-hmm.
MATT: By the way, Deven, who did the map, it is
her birthday today.
MARISHA: Happy birthday, Deven!
LAURA: Damn, this is amazing! Okay, I'll leave it
up here.
TALIESIN: If you pull out a real medi-kit now I'm
going to be really excited. 50 bandages come
flying in...
ASHLEY: That is so beautiful.
MATT: She did an incredible job. The exchange is
done, you have your map. Anything else you guys
want to handle?
TALIESIN: Medi-kit?
MARISHA: I got it.
LAURA: Can I just look around and see if there's
anything interesting to buy in here, like--
MATT: There's plenty of tools. There are various
packs of supplies.
LAURA: I guess if I bought the painter's kit then
it just stays and I don't run out of that.
MATT: Over time you would run out of it.
LAURA: But I'm good on paint?
MATT: Good for a while.
TRAVIS: Can I actually approach the storekeep and
say: do you know of any stores that have arcane
items, things with magical properties, healing
potions?
MATT: "I'm sorry, we're a bit out of the center of
the country for arcane items. You'd want to go
further north for that."
TRAVIS: Further north? I appreciate your time,
thank you.
MATT: "Of course."
MARISHA: This town blows.
TRAVIS: She's right fucking there.
MARISHA: I don't care.
[laughter]
TRAVIS: Shall we depart?
LAURA: Sure. Thank you so much for this beautiful
map. You did a really good job drawing it.
MATT: Take your map.
ASHLEY: I also really like what you've done with
the place.
MATT: "Thank you very much--"
MARISHA: Let's go, bye! Thank you!
MATT: "I-- um..."
TRAVIS: Gotta go!
MARISHA: [bell dangling noises]
MATT: As you guys all exit, she begins to come
around the counter.
TALIESIN: I like the idea of you just
standing there going, [bell dangling noises]
LAURA: Wherever we go, I'm going to bury my head
in the map and walk behind everybody like a total
tourist.
TALIESIN: Well, that's the question: are we going
to be able to grab a cart or two from the circus?
MATT: You can probably get a cart.
TALIESIN: Like one of the little vardos? Can we
snag a vardo?
MATT: Technically it's a vardo and the three of
them took it. There's a vardo and then there's
some carts. You weren't rolling with a pretty
heavy-- honestly, most of the room in the carts
was either for carrying you guys, whatever small
bags you had with you, and the poles you would
assemble to make the tent. Are you guys done with
your business? Anything else you want to do while
you're out and about?
TRAVIS: That's it for me.
LAURA: There's nowhere we can buy healing potions
in this city?
MATT: There's Natural Remedies, which you've
passed before, but not entered. It's an herbal
healers establishment.
LAURA: Let's try that.
TALIESIN: I'm very wary of this, but fine.
TRAVIS: It's going to smell like "Sephoria," I
know it.
LAURA: Sephora.
TRAVIS: That's the fancy version.
MATT: Now, you guys had left earlier, so as you
guys head toward Natural Remedies, you guys finish
your bath.
LIAM: I pack up. I said we're staying for an
hour, so I cast Disguise Self again to
keep the illusion going. I'm done, you look--
SAM: I splashed some water on my face.
LIAM: --refreshed.
SAM: Oh, it was such a good bath. I'm ready to go
now, I feel refreshed.
LIAM: Did you like it, though?
SAM: It was a once-in-a-lifetime experience.
LIAM: I wanted to repay you for all you've done
for me for the past couple of days.
SAM: Consider it paid! You look the same. Does he
look the same?
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: The brief moment that I was in my own guise
nothing changed up here, so I look exactly the way
I did this morning.
LAURA: What's the purpose of that?
LIAM: Who said that? You wanted to do something,
right?
SAM: I wanted to go to Herbal Remedies and see if
we could get you a healing potion.
LIAM: Let's do that, then. You lead the way. Well
wait, you lead the way outside. Let's keep our
little schtick going here and then off we go.
MATT: All right. As you guys exit--
SAM: Auf Wiedersehen!
MATT: "I trust you enjoyed your time at the bath,
thank you."
LIAM: Yes, but we have to go. Sorry, I'm late for
a very important appointment. I drag Nott right
out of here because I saw no doorknob on the
door.
MATT: Yeah, amongst other things. You guys make
your way out and beeline it towards the Lochward
to where you would find Natural Remedies. The rest
of you guys, as you approach the exterior, amongst the
rest of the buildings in the central city, Natural
Remedies is, for lack of a better term, humble.
It's a small shack, but as soon as you approach it
has very strong, pungent smells of funguses.
TRAVIS: Instant headache.
MATT: Yep. On the outside you can see, right where
the doorway is open, there are strings of herbs
that are tied up and left to dry out. On the
inside, you can already see that there are shelves
of various flora and fauna that are being
cultivated for various remedies and means of
selling to anybody who wants to come by and
procure herbal medicines. Let's see who's
handling this one, because you guys have not been
here yet. As you enter the main chamber--
LIAM: Sorry, I will say that on the way there
that I dropped the disguise, somewhere.
MATT: Okay, easily enough, so you guys haven't
arrived yet. You guys have arrived. As you enter the interior,
it's a very musty smell on the inside, too.
There's a lot of fungus being grown on the inside
here, and you can see that elements of it may have
expanded into the corners of the actual room and
it's not necessarily the nicest space to be
wandering in. It seems natural. Across the way,
you see a gentleman of relatively tanned skin,
with darker hair that's ratty and clustered. He's
in his late twenties or so, looks to be upon
closer inspection partial elven blood, partial
human blood, and he's in the process of carefully
carving a large stalk of what looks like a fungus
off of a small pot that he pulled off one of the
shelves. As you enter, he doesn't even make eye
contact. He goes, "Hello, please, just wait a
moment. There we are. Hi, can I help you?"
LAURA: Yeah, my friends keep dying. Do you have any
health potions?
MATT: "We have a handful, that is correct. How
many are you looking to purchase?"
LAURA: How many do you have?
MATT: "Four."
LAURA: Ooh. That will last us probably, like, a
day.
MATT: "What do you do for a living?"
LAURA: We're superheroes.
TALIESIN: Sword jugglers.
MATT: "Why would-- Fine, who am I to ask?"
MARISHA: Look at this bruise.
MATT: "I cut fungus for a living."
MARISHA: Look, it's in the shape of a dick.
MATT: "I'm not going to ask. Four? Did you want
them?"
LAURA: Sure, yes. How much for four healing
potions?
MATT: "For four healing potions," and he pulls
them out and plops them on the table, "240 gold pieces."
TALIESIN: Level two.
LAURA: Okay, hold on. I open up my pack and I pour
out all my money. I start counting it.
ASHLEY: Do you have a deal, you know, if we got
all of them? That seems pretty high. Right? That
seems pretty high for a healing potion.
MATT: Make a persuasion check with disadvantage.
Yasha: the wheeler and dealer.
ASHLEY: Three.
MATT: "No, actually, I think it's rather standard
in these parts. But I can put them back."
TALIESIN: Healing potions aside, you are doing
something really interesting and exciting here.
You're not a healing potion dealer. What are you
doing here? Like this is fascinating.
MATT: "Oh, I create all sorts of means of tending
to wounds and loss of stamina. To be honest, a lot
"of people come around here for
performance-enhancing fungus."
TALIESIN: I don't know, I feel like you can excite
me. I feel like there's something that you have to
show that's really exciting. I'm not entirely sure
it's all about stamina, I think you've got
something-- you did that on purpose. Talk to me
like I'm a child, show me something I've never
seen before.
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
TALIESIN: Not with advantage, because I don't have
it, but I was so excited.
MATT: Nope.
TALIESIN: Persuasion check. 19. I'm fishing for
drugs, I'm not going to lie. I've been on the road
a long time, I don't remember how to do this.
MATT: He leans in close to you. "Mind closing the
door?"
TALIESIN: I skip over to the door and gingerly
close it.
MATT: "Keep curious company, that's true."
TALIESIN: Yes, I do. And we're leaving town
today.
MATT: "Those are magical words for a man of my
business. Are you a fan of skein?"
TALIESIN: I don't actually know what that is.
MATT: "Well," and he goes back into the back
chamber, comes back with a small satchel. There's
a finely dried, dusted material on the inside, it
has a grayish-blue color to it. He goes, "This is
"a dried and ground fungus called skein. It's
called skein because when you eat it you can see
"the weave of time."
MARISHA: Is that what skein means?
MATT: "It's a woven skein, it's a joke on fate--
never mind."
TALIESIN: I thought it was very clever.
MATT: "Thank you very much. It's effective, it's
popular on the outskirts where it's not so heavily
"controlled and carries a huge jail-time if caught.
How much are you looking to purchase?"
TALIESIN: I've got to be honest, I'm not made of
money, but I'm always curious for a new experience.
MARISHA: Can I do an insight check on this guy?
MATT: Sure, go for it.
MARISHA: See if he's trying to scam us.
MATT: Go for it.
MARISHA: Can I use my criminal background?
MATT: Sure.
LIAM: All right, Marisha said that, not
Beauregard.
MARISHA: To know if he's actually giving what he's
giving?
MATT: You know what? Make your insight check.
MARISHA: Just straight insight.
MATT: Straight insight.
MARISHA: It's not as good as I would've hoped.
18.
MATT: Not as good as I hoped: 18.
LIAM: That's a slam dunk at level two.
MATT: Seems on the level, seems excited that
somebody's asking about it. You get the sense
that maybe he makes a lot of this either for
himself or in hopes that somebody asks about it
and is seemingly excited that somebody in this
bumfuck town, in his opinion, would even have
interest. You have once encountered this substance
before, and it does seem legit.
MARISHA: Okay.
ASHLEY: How do we know if it's good quality,
though? Can I give it a sample?
TALIESIN: Well, this might be complicated, I think
that just-- What would--
TRAVIS: How about a few experiences?
TALIESIN: A few experiences' worth. What would that
run me?
MATT: Hey guys, we're dealing D&amp;D drugs.
TALIESIN: I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry for dragging
the entire audience into this. Hopefully your
children are already asleep, I do apologize.
SAM: D&amp;D Beyond, everybody. Our sponsor for the
evening.
TALIESIN: Thank you for really bringing that to
earth for me. You started this.
MATT: "I'll put you in at a gold an experience,
how about that?"
TALIESIN: All right. Yeah, put me in for one. I'll
try anything once.
MATT: He takes a small little batch of this dried,
powdered fungus, and puts it into a small glass
vial, corks it, and hands it over.
ASHLEY: Well, you might as well make another one.
I'm not going to let my friend experience it alone.
TALIESIN: What's it called? Skein?
MATT: Skein. S-K-E-I-N. I believe that's how it's
spelled.
LAURA: Yasha, you should take it with them. Right
now. It'll be fun.
TALIESIN: No, this is not how this works. This is
not how this works. We bank our moments for those
moments when life is disappointing.
TRAVIS: I know a unique substance when I see it,
I'll take one as well.
TALIESIN: Oh my god.
MARISHA: One for me too.
TALIESIN: This can come in handy in all sorts of
ways.
MATT: God damn it, guys.
TALIESIN: The fact that you had this ready means
that there is no shame here. You were ready for this.
MATT: You're right, I am not making any of this up
on the spot at all.
TALIESIN: I know, I can tell!
LIAM: This guy went from the Simpson's Safeway
clerk to the shadiest motherfucker in a snap of
time, because of your question.
TALIESIN: A big, purple, pierced demon walked into
the room and was like, hello.
LIAM: Yes, can I help you, good sir? Yes, I can
help you.
TRAVIS: I'll tell you what, because you are such a
purveyor of such interesting items, I will take
one of those health potions, but for 50 gold.
That's the running price I've seen in neighboring
towns, and I don't mean to be swindled.
MARISHA: I assume you'd want to go ahead and give
it to us for that so that we keep this a secret.
MATT: Make a persuasion check, with advantage.
TRAVIS: 21.
MATT: "50 gold," and he pulls his hair back a bit,
"Seems fair." Takes a potion and hands it over. He
scoops a little vial and says, "And for fun." He
throws it over.
LIAM: You fucking badass.
SAM: Cut to an hour later, and someone's jamming
an adrenaline needle.
MATT: TPK by misuse?
TALIESIN: Somewhere around level eight, this is
going to be hilarious. Somewhere around level
eight somebody's going to go shopping and the rest
of us are going to be like: this is now, this is
happening now.
MATT: This has become the longest afterschool
special I think we've ever experienced.
TALIESIN: Years in the making.
MATT: He immediately gets nervous at her mention
of--
TALIESIN: She's fine, she's just awful, you're a
gentleman, I hope to see you again. I'm looking
forward to this.
MATT: "I'll be here."
TALIESIN: Of course, we never met you, you never
met us.
MATT: "Of course not. I don't know who you are."
TALIESIN: I am already out the door, with a
flourish.
MATT: At which point, you run outside just as
Caleb and Nott are approaching.
MARISHA: Before I go out I say, nice to meet you,
mister--?
MATT: "Davies."
TRAVIS: The decision was still happening by the
time you got to the last letter.
MARISHA: I go: Okay, Davies.
LAURA: I guess I'll scoop my money back into
my pouch and leave.
MARISHA: Do you want anything?
LAURA: No.
MATT: You bump into Caleb and Nott on the way
out.
LIAM: What's the matter, do you have a cold?
LAURA: You don't smell bad, what did you do?
MATT: Actually, ironically, his clothes do still
smell pretty bad, and he still looks awful.
LAURA: You don't smell as bad.
MATT: That's true, on a gradient scale, he does
smell a little better.
LIAM: I will take that as a compliment, thank you.
What are you guys doing here, are you shopping?
What do they have in there?
LAURA: They bought drugs.
TRAVIS: That is an over-exaggeration.
TALIESIN: That is an extreme over-exaggeration. We
got a health potion.
SAM: All of you?
MARISHA: Well, it was kind of a ploy to get a
cheaper health potion.
TALIESIN: It worked.
MARISHA: And we got drugs on top of it. It was a
win-win, am I right?
LAURA: If you guys go in there and you buy a
health potion, don't spend as much as he says,
because apparently he was lying.
LIAM: How much do they run for?
TRAVIS: Health potions were quoted at 70, but he
was kind enough to understand that 50 was enough.
LIAM: 70?
TRAVIS: Gold pieces.
SAM: North we go.
TALIESIN: North, to the horses.
LIAM: We have a plan for the day?
LAURA: Yes, and I show them the map that we just
got. We're heading that way. Can I take the ribbon
that was wrapped around the map and tie it around
one of my horns?
MATT: Easily enough.
MARISHA: That's cute.
LAURA: Thank you.
SAM: We could rob the store.
LIAM: Do you have a strategy for that?
SAM: I mean, we could use one of our pre-planned
strategies.
LIAM: Which one would that be? Because I was
thinking about it on the walk here and I can't
think which one applies.
TALIESIN: I was going to say, robbing shady people
is usually a bad idea.
MARISHA: Do we hear them doing these plans? Do we
hear you guys making this plan?
LIAM: No, I wouldn't be saying this out loud if
you're close.
SAM: We could just do the simplest: the Prince and
the Pauper.
LIAM: Here's the thing, I have died almost twice
in two days. We have our friends and I think
that's a good way to start.
SAM: All right.
LIAM: I mean, you know, we almost all got pinched
yesterday.
SAM: You're right, we should leave town with our
wits about us and full of health. Let's just go
while we're ahead. Besides, I got plenty of stuff
today.
LIAM: You and me?
SAM: Yeah, let's go.
LIAM: All right. Okay, where are we going first?
LAURA: We're heading north to--
LIAM: Is it this big?
MATT: That's the size of the map.
LAURA: I mean, we can stop through Alfield first
and see if there's anything cool there, or-- what
city was it that the academy was in?
MARISHA: "Solstryce?"
MATT and TRAVIS: Soltryce.
MARISHA: Is that the name of the town?
TALIESIN: No, I don't think it's the name of the
town.
LAURA: I mean, the ultimate goal, you guys, is to
get to Hupperdook, but--
TALIESIN: What about Yogurt?
LAURA: That's an afterthought.
TALIESIN: It usually is.
LIAM: How far off does Hupperdook look?
LAURA: Well, we have to pass through Felderwin and
the Felderwin Village first.
SAM: Let's skip that one, please.
LAURA: Oh, is that the one you don't like? Okay,
then we'll go up through Alfield, and then Zadash,
and then we'll cut across and go to Hupperdook.
MARISHA: Is that where your clan is from?
SAM: They roam about.
ASHLEY: You don't want to go to Zadash, is that
right?
MARISHA: Nah, it's cool. We can go back.
TRAVIS: It's cool now?
MARISHA: Yeah, I mean, there's a few places that I
didn't get to see in my sight-seeing roundabout,
didn't get to hit everything. Now that I've slept
on it, I've had a change of heart. It's a nice town.
LAURA: How long of a travel would it be to get to
Zadash from where we are now?
MATT: Following the road is longer, but it's
safest. That'll probably be close to 200 miles to Zadash.
SAM: Jesus. We're on foot.
TALIESIN: No, we've got a cart.
SAM: A cart.
MATT: You do have a cart. A single cart.
LAURA: A horse? Let's go back to the inn and ask
Yorda if she knows if Alfield is a big city.
LIAM: Do I have any knowledge of Alfield?
TALIESIN: I came though Alfield, didn't I?
MATT: No, you guys traveled around. You went from
Felderwin, and curved around to the Ustaloch.
TALIESIN: That's right.
MATT: Alfield is actually slightly smaller than
Trostenwald, it's a stop on the way to Zadash.
Zadash is the second-largest city in the kingdom.
MARISHA: What do I know about Zadash that I could
tell them? Can I tell them anything?
MATT: It was the last conquered bastion of the
previous government before the empire entirely
took the valley.
MARISHA: That's right. Zadash is on the edge of
the empire too, right?
MATT: It was, but now it's more central. It
expanded past and took over Trostenwald, Alfield,
it expanded all the way into the valley.
LIAM: Will you share your map with me for just
one minute?
LAURA: Of course.
SAM: This is a good trick he does. He can look at
it once and it will stay with him forever.
LAURA: Really?
SAM: Yes, it's amazing, you can quiz him on it later.
While he's memorizing it, Yasha, is that your name again?
ASHLEY: Yasha.
SAM; It's like Ash, with an -ay.
ASHLEY: Not really, but close enough.
SAM: I got you these flowers.
ASHLEY: Oh.
SAM: Thought that they might gussy you up a bit.
It's a lot of drab colors. Also, maybe you won't
kill me now.
ASHLEY: I'm not going to kill you.
SAM: I know, I gave you the flowers.
ASHLEY: All right, well.
SAM: Girls like flowers.
LAURA: I love flowers, did you get me any?
SAM: I didn't, because you're less of a threat.
LAURA: You don't know that.
ASHLEY: That was very nice of you, thank you.
SAM: Sure!
MARISHA: Didn't peg you for a flowers type of
girl.
SAM: All girls like flowers.
ASHLEY: I take out a book that I have and in
between some of the pages is a four-leaf clover.
I'll take the flowers and I'll put them in between
the other pages, and I'll put it away.
SAM: You see?
(laughter)
SAM: It doesn't hurt to be nice sometimes.
MARISHA: I mean, it can, though.
SAM: Well it hurts you.
LIAM: It looks like somebody was very nice to you
the night before, over and over again.
MARISHA: Oh, she was.
LAURA: You guys, we are going to Zadash. Is that
what we're saying, we're going to go to Zadash?
LIAM: Sure, let's do that. What's our goal in
Zadash?
LAURA: I don't know, I just need to know where
we're going, okay?
MARISHA: That's on the way to the "Solstryce"
Academy?
MATT: The Soltryce. Solstice, I can see you mixing
it up. The Soltryce is technically in Rexxentrum,
which is the capital of the empire.
LAURA: Which is a lot farther.
MATT: Which is a lot farther. Zadash does have the
only other subsidiary of the academy there, but
the main Soltryce academy is in Rexxentrum, the
capital. But Zadash has some connection to it.
TRAVIS: I'll take it.
LIAM: Unless you're a foreigner, everyone knows
about Rexxentrum.
MATT: Yes, it's huge. For player comparison, it's
twice the size of Emon. It's a massive city.
LAURA: Zadash?
MATT: No, not Zadash, Rexxentrum.
LIAM: Zadash is medium, or smaller.
LAURA: Okay. Yeah.
LIAM: How far did that map say, when I looked
at it? 200 miles you said to Zadash?
MATT: To Zadash, roughly 200 miles or so, if
you're taking the road, quicker if you take a
straight line, but you're not as safe.
LIAM: Well, I think it's good.
SAM: Are we going to walk there? Should we get
horses?
TALIESIN: We have a horse.
LIAM: How many horses?
MARISHA: A horse and a carriage. I'm assuming it
can't fit all of us.
TRAVIS: Yeah, like a wagon.
TALIESIN: We have a wagon.
MATT: It'll be about the same pace as on foot. At
a fast pace on foot, you guys can traverse about
30 miles a day. That also means you're moving at a
fast pace, so you're not being completely aware of
your surroundings, you have a penalty to passively
seeing things around you. But you get there quicker.
TRAVIS: I like it.
TALIESIN: Why be fast? What are we in a rush for?
LAURA: We can sightsee.
TALIESIN: I find careful is always best.
LIAM: A couple of weeks on the road to a city
bigger than this one.
MARISHA: Are we all going to get along for a
couple of weeks?
SAM: We'll find out, I suppose.
LAURA: I get along with everyone, Beau.
MARISHA: That's true, that's true.
TALIESIN: I don't get along with anybody.
MARISHA: That's also true.
LIAM: Two weeks is not a bad test run for
companions. If we don't like it, we part ways in Zadash.
TRAVIS: Yeah, free to go at any time. As long as
it serves everyone, we'll stay this way.
ASHLEY: I think I need to stay here just a little
bit longer. But I will meet you guys there at some point?
SAM: Why?! What're you doing?
LIAM: You have something else to do?
ASHLEY: I just don't think I can leave here until
I'm told I can.
SAM: By the authorities?
ASHLEY: No, I just--
SAM: You're so mysterious
ASHLEY: I have things that I need to do--
SAM: Name one.
TALIESIN: You know where we're headed.
MATT: Blindspot.
MARISHA: Poor Ashley, we make her come up with
excuses every time.
ASHLEY: I have reasons, I can stay, I just need to
converse with somebody to see where my next step leads.
MARISHA: You know you're not beholden to Gustav
anymore, right?
ASHLEY: No, yes, no. It's not him.
MARISHA: Is it Bo? The other Bo? Is it Desmond?
ASHLEY: No.
MARISHA: Is it Ornna?
SAM: Please, Beau, let the detectives figure this
out. Is it Desmond?
LAURA: Is it Ornna?
SAM: It's Ornna, isn't it? It's Ornna, I knew it.
LAURA: Will you hold this?
SAM: Yes, of course. See? Another case cracked. It
was Ornna.
LAURA: Before we leave, is there anywhere in town
that there would be a courier service where I could
send a message?
MATT: There are messenger services, yeah.
LAURA: Can I go find one?
MATT: Yeah, okay. For the purposes of brevity,
we'll say that you find a courier service that
runs fast horseback all along the roads from the
Empire, and then with approval, outside of it,
to the south and west.
LAURA: I'm going to write a letter to my mother
that says, "Dear Mom, all of the money's gone. I
"don't know what happened, but I am very broke and
I need more. Please help me. I am going to Zadash.
"That's where you can send it. Just send it to the
inn that is the biggest one and I'll find it
"there. Just address it to me. Your loving
daughter, Jester. Please, thank you, I need help,
"thank you."
MATT: All right. For delivery to Nicodranas, the
cost of the courier service will run you about
five gold.
LAURA: This is really fucking-- She better send
money, because this is eating into it.
MATT: That's hundreds and hundreds of miles on
horseback.
LAURA: Okay, I'll give the five gold for that.
TALIESIN: It is such a different world.
MATT: Yeah. Welcome to level... three, after
tonight.
SAM: Oh! If we live.
MARISHA: While we're stopping by the post office,
can I talk to the courier person?
MATT: Sure. It's a young girl with short-ish
brushed hair, she's boyish and freckled, and a
bit dirty in the edges of her chin, she's in the
process of loading up the packs on the horse, and
she's wearing simple leather armor, and looks back
at you. "Can I help you?"
MARISHA: Yeah, I was just wondering if you had any
incoming mail for the Baumbauchs? I said that I
would pick it up on the way home, heading over
there.
MATT: Make a deception check.
TALIESIN: Wow.
SAM: Mail fraud on the way out of town.
MARISHA: That's good! 20. No. Deception? 19
total.
MATT: "Let me check. Yeah, actually, we've got three
small parcels on the way to the Baumbauchs there."
MARISHA: Thank you so much. He's going to be so
happy to not have to run this errand. Thank you,
bye. Oh, sorry, here you go. I give her a gold.
MATT: "That's very kind, thank you."
MARISHA: Have a good day.
MATT: Hops onto the horse and takes off
southward.
TALIESIN: Mail fraud.
MARISHA: Let's go.
TALIESIN: That is actually the worst crime we've
committed today.
MARISHA: You said how many? Three parcels?
MATT: Three parcels.
ASHLEY: When you get to Zadash, maybe send me a
note, or maybe I'll be there. I just have to do a
couple things.
LAURA: We'll send you a note on the way to Zadash.
Then maybe you can meet us there.
ASHLEY: Okay. That sounds like a plan.
TRAVIS: Do we have our fucking wagon ready?
TALIESIN: Wagon's ready. I've even attempted to hide
some of the contraband and otherwise. I packed well.
LIAM: While everyone is getting ready, I wait for
a moment when Fjord is on his own and everyone is
busy, walk over. This group seems rough around the
edges, but you seem clever. Hopefully we can make
this work.
TRAVIS: I think we should be able to, yeah. I
mean, a little guidance goes a long way. You seem
to be good at looking out for Nott.
LIAM: I mean, full disclosure, I'm a little rough
around the edges, but you catch my drift.
TRAVIS: I do. You can trust us. You're safe here.
I'm concerned with what happens with Jester and
Beau. I think, amongst all of us, we should be
fine.
LIAM: Let's make it work.
TRAVIS: We'll make it work.
SAM: Fjord, something in me says that, for some
reason, you should be the one who tells the horses
and wagon to go.
(laughter)
SAM: It just seems-- you're the biggest, maybe?
TRAVIS: That is mighty considerate of you, Nott.
Are you sure you don't want to take a crack at it?
SAM: I could take a crack at it. The wagons be
hitched, hee-haw.
TRAVIS: Use your diaphragm. Really get a yee-haw,
get in there.
SAM: Saddle up your doggies, hee-haw.
TRAVIS: One more time, on the count of three. One,
two, three. On three, I push his chest in.
SAM: Yee-haw!
MATT: All right. With that, her vocal expulsion is
majestic and sudden. Make an animal handling check
with advantage, please.
SAM: With advantage? Six. I'm still a scary
goblin.
MATT: The sound that comes out is less of a
"Yee-haw," and more of a screech sound. The horse
immediately rises up and goes into a very heavy
gallop, and the cart takes off ahead of you, and
you all struggle to catch up for a bit. With that,
you guys quickly try and saunter up, heading
northward along the road towards the direction of
Alfield, and eventually Zadash, as you head
further into the Dwendalian Empire, and whatever
fate has in store for you the next leg of your
journey. We'll stop tonight's session there.
SAM: Ashley Johnson, ladies and gentlemen.
LIAM: Yee-haw.
ALL: Yee-haw.
TRAVIS: Well, we committed felonies and mail
fraud. That's good.
TALIESIN: Quite a few. Got into a bar fight.
LAURA: We skipped town without paying our inn
fees.
SAM: We bought drugs.
TRAVIS: We bought a little bit of mold.
MATT: You paid your inn fee.
LAURA: We did pay on the way in. I did pay for a
few days when we got in. I guess that is probably enough.
LIAM: Oh my gosh, and Sneaky McSneakerson over
here. Oh boy.
SAM: Oh, yeah. Who knows what Marisha did while we
were out there?
TRAVIS: Yeah, we got to go back and not watch that
later.
MARISHA: Like the three rules of Fight Club.
MATT: You guys are all level three when you come
back next week.
(cheering)
TRAVIS: Oh god, we got to shop. We got to book
shop.
LAURA: Oh man, this is fun.
MATT: Yeah, thank you guys for sticking around for
a less intense, more character-driven episode,
these early days of figuring each other out and
forming a fellowship. This is fun, I love it.
LIAM: Bunch of assholes.
MATT: I know.
TALIESIN: Bunch of assholes!
LIAM: That's the name.
MATT: Thank you guys for watching. Thank you
again, Deven, for being an incredible artist, and
an incredible mapmaker for working with me on
that. Her Twitter-- I should've had this prepared
in advance! You can follow Deven on Twitter
@devenrue, Mistress of Maps. Her work is
incredible. She has a Patreon, which I'm a patron
for, you should be too. It's her birthday, so say
happy birthday to her.
ALL: Happy Birthday!
MATT: All right, guys, have a wonderful week.
Ashley, come back.
ASHLEY: Hopefully soon, I never know. I'll try.
LAURA: So glad you were here.
MATT: If anybody from Blindspot is watching right
now, kill off her character. I mean, don't do
that, but we want her back.
ASHLEY: I don't think any of them are watching.
MATT: It's fine. We just miss her a lot. We'll see
you guys back next week. Much love to you, much
love to you, and is it Thursday yet?