MATT: Hello everyone, and welcome to tonight's
episode of Critical Role, where a bunch of us
nerdy-ass voice actors sit around and play
Dungeons &amp; Dragons. Some of us are mentally
lagging a little, but that's okay. It's been a
long day. Welcome, guys. Before we jump into
tonight's session, we're going to do some quick
announcements. First and foremost, thank you to
our returning sponsor and partner at the start of
this campaign, and for the foreseeable, amorphous
future of which they wish to come along with us on
this journey, D&amp;D Beyond. They've been awesome and
I actually just learned today of a really helpful
functionality that I probably should have known
about, where you can create your own campaign in
there and then send out a link to all your players
and their characters get added to your campaign.
Now I have access to all of your character sheets
at all times, which alleviates me having to text
you all, "What's your maximum hit points now?" and
all that shit.
LAURA: Did you just have them? Or do we need to
send you our characters?
MATT: Well no, I sent out the link earlier today
and you're one of the only ones who hasn't
responded yet, but you will, later, that's okay.
LAURA: I didn't see it, I was recording.
MATT: That's okay, so were we.
(laughter)
LAURA: I didn't look at my phone.
TRAVIS: What a dick.
(laughter)
MATT: It's all good.
LAURA: That means all of you guys were texting in
your sessions.
TALIESIN: This is true.
LIAM: We're that good.
(laughter)
MATT: Sam, do you have any words you wanted to say
about our sponsor?
SAM: I do. Here, give this to Matt, he'll need it.
MATT: Oh no.
SAM: Our partner this week is once again D&amp;D
Beyond, that's dndbeyond.com. The big news is that
D&amp;D's newest book, Mordenkainen's Tome of Foes, is
available for pre-order now on the site. If you
preorder, you'll get exclusive character portrait
frames, sheet backdrops, and themed colors that you
can use with upcoming character sheet updates! I
don't know what that means but it sounds awesome.
The $10 off code "beginnings" can be applied to
your preorder. To celebrate, I'm going to
personally be giving away one copy of this book to
either Travis, Liam, or Marisha, but they have to
compete for it. Here's the rules: I'm going to
give you a race, class, and character description,
just like you can do on D&amp;D Beyond, and all you
guys have to do is come up with the name of that
character. Laura, Taliesin, and Matt will be the
judges. Best out of three wins, all right? You
just have to come up with a name for this
character, ready? A male stout halfling swamp
druid who only wears a diaper made out of kelp and
loves to Wild Shape into manatees. Liam, what is
the name of that character?
LIAM: Twill Pillikins.
SAM: Marisha, what is the name of that character?
MARISHA: Squall Squatlock.
SAM: And Travis?
TRAVIS: Merkin Dullbringer.
SAM: Judges, who wins? Oh, Travis, easy win for
Travis.
MATT: Adding Merkin to a swamp druid was too
easy.
LAURA: It was you, Liam, until he brought up the
Merkin.
SAM: Remember, these characters can all be made on
D&amp;D Beyond. The next one is a male tabaxi bard
with an electric guitar who constantly plays K-pop
songs and has a runny nose. What is his name? Liam O'Brien.
LIAM: Bathtub Stealthcat.
SAM: Marisha Ray. Oh yeah, sorry, three names.
MARISHA: Mollysquawk the J-pop Hadockhop.
SAM: Yep, okay. Travis?
TRAVIS: Pubert Pimplepop.
SAM: Ooh! Judges.
TALIESIN: I got bribed.
SAM: Travis again.
TALIESIN: I'm purchasable, putting that out
there.
SAM: One more, this one is worth two points. A
female kenku paladin with no arms or legs.
LAURA: What's a kenku?
LIAM: Kenku's a bird.
LAURA: Yeah, I know. Shut up!
SAM: Who worships the lobster-headed god
Blibdoolpoolp, and it is a real god, and is
dragged around by a pack of reindeer. Liam, what
is the name of that character?
LIAM: Dagon Henry Kissinger.
MARISHA: Madame Mannequin Ba-Deece.
TRAVIS: Filma Kraken.
SAM: Judges, Liam, Liam, Marisha, Liam gets two
points! Travis gets two points! Marisha wins!
MARISHA: Yay, golf rules!
SAM: I will personally buy you one of those books,
Marisha, hold me to it. D&amp;D Beyond, everyone, make
your character today.
MATT: Thank you Sam, thank you very much.
LAURA: That was good.
TALIESIN: That got weird.
MATT: Isn't it always, though?
LAURA: That was close, I'm not going to count it.
This is the one Sam gave me, so we'll see.
MATT: Finishing up from that, we have Talks Machina
next Tuesday at 7:00pm Pacific here on Twitch and
Project Alpha to discuss tonight's episode of
Critical Role hosted by our fantastic Brian W.
Foster, so check that out on Tuesday next week. We
have a new show called Weave coming up, Marisha, do
you want to explain this a little bit?
TALIESIN: We're one episode in.
MATT: One episode in? That's right, that launched this
week.
MARISHA: Yeah, it happened... last night?
TALIESIN: Wednesday night.
MARISHA: Wednesday night, it happens after
Wednesday Club. It's being GMed by Amy Dallen and
it's an interactive storytelling RPG game. It's
got all the ladies of Geek &amp; Sundry, so check it out.
MATT: That's awesome.
TRAVIS: That's a dope jacket, by the way.
MARISHA: Thanks, man.
TRAVIS: Yeah, jealous.
MATT: We'll get you one, same size. Last week's
episode of Critical Role is available in podcast
form wherever you can find the greatest podcasts to
download. So if you have friends who are listening
to the audio, they can do so now and be caught up
with you up until after tonight. Also, comic book
issue four of Critical Role: Vox Machina Origins
is available for digital download anywhere where you can
find digital comics for the most part: ComiXology,
the Dark Horse app, and other great places.
TRAVIS: It's so good, Minxie's in there killing things.
MATT: We've got a new one creeping up on the
horizon.
LIAM: I've read the whole thing, I've seen the
pictures.
MATT: I was supposed to see the art today! I can't
wait! Anyway, enough of that. Of course, our
fantastic 826LA and the 826 group that does
fantastic after-school programs for kids to get
into creative writing. Check it out if you haven't
already, and if you can't give to help out with
this charity, you can donate your time as well to
help teach some of these kids and help expand
their imaginations, so check it out. They're
awesome people and we continue to support and push
them forward. Any new appearances you want to
announce? Or just rinse and repeat the ones-- if
you want to know what conventions we're going to
be at in the near future, watch last week's
episode. Otherwise it gets monotonous for us.
Anyway, any other announcements that I've missed?
SAM: Apparently my breath stinks, so if anyone has
any gum, I'll take it.
MATT: Send your gum to Geek &amp; Sundry.
TALIESIN: Don't send your gum.
LAURA: I have something. The Shadow of War
expansion pack, The Blade of Galadriel, came out
and you can play and be me, so get it and play.
SAM: Just you, Laura Bailey?
LAURA: Yeah, basically just me, running around
Mordor.
LIAM: Donut hole! Donut hole! Donut
hole!
TRAVIS: You've got a ring of power and shit.
LAURA: Yeah, so check it out.
LIAM: She has a ring of power?
LAURA: Shut up! What? No. What?
MATT: On that note, let's go ahead and dive in to
tonight's episode of Critical Role.
(cast singing)
[click, TV static]
[groovy Critical Role theme]
MATT: And welcome back.
LAURA: He just tunes it out now.
MATT: I have to.
LIAM: Except when he doesn't.
MATT: Except when I don't, which makes it a
challenge for you guys, which does not help me.
Anyway, last we left off, the group of adventurers
whose fates are slowly entwining found themselves
meeting in the city of Trostenwald on the southern
reaches of the Dwendalian Empire on the continent
of Wildemount. Through a mishap in a circus
passing through town, you began to give chase to
the investigation that has caught you up in this legal
issue and you found yourselves locked under house
arrest and being considered possible murderers.
You sought the answer to this endeavor, you found
the devil toad, or the nergaliid, as you
discovered, was responsible. You hunted it down,
slew it, brought its head back, and after arguing
with a very tired and wanting to get it over with
lawmaster in Trostenwald, managed to convince her
enough to let you off the hook and leave most of
the standing legal issues with Gustav, thus
disbanding the circus and setting you and Yasha
free. Yasha went on her own path while the rest of
you, the six of you, decided strength in numbers,
and at the time being, you all seem to enjoy each
other's company. Purchasing a fresh
map, looking at your future prospects and your
dwindling funds, you decided to head northward,
towards the city of Zadash by way of the Golden
Road, past the city of Alfield. And that is where
we left off, as you had smacked the rear end of
the single horse and cart, and sent it spooked
into the northern field.
LAURA: We chased after it, right?
MATT: You do. You chase after it to keep up.
LAURA: We don't just lose it.
MATT: Being relatively before noon at this point
in time, you're heading northward along the Amber
Road. The well-packed dirt of the ten-foot roadway
gives you a clear path towards your next
destination. The gentle creak of the cart mingles
with the clomping of the horse hooves as you push
forward. The midday air is warmer than you
expected. The sky's common gray presence is broken
into smaller cloud patches, the victorious blue
peeking through. You guys continue for a few hours,
talking amongst yourselves a bit. If there are any
questions you wish to ask each other, now is
the time.
SAM: Any questions?
MATT: Meaning if there is anything coming out of
the city you wanted to talk about, otherwise I'm
going to continue to push forward with your
journey. So stop me at any point.
TRAVIS: Is Beau-- is her face all jibbity-jacked,
or is it pretty normal-looking at this point?
MATT: Make a perception check.
TRAVIS: Not that I watched anything from last week,
because I didn't! 16.
MATT: You can see there is some faint bruising
starting to show on the left side of the face.
TRAVIS: I bet she doesn't want to talk about that.
That's a good shiner.
MARISHA: Thanks.
TRAVIS: Did you give as good as you got?
MARISHA: I wouldn't say I won, because I lost.
But I did pretty good. What color is it right now?
Is it in that orange-ish purple--
TRAVIS: It's got the green-yellow sunset
happening, things are starting to spread. Tomorrow
will be--
MARISHA: Right. Got that little orangey. Mm-hmm.
LAURA: It's really pretty.
MARISHA: Thanks.
TALIESIN: Significant improvement.
TRAVIS: That trouble going to follow you as we go
on our way, or do you think you're free and clear?
MARISHA: Oh no, that was just a little bar fight.
Nothing. Just a little friendly sparring. Nothing crazy.
TRAVIS: Nice.
LAURA: Does anyone want a donut from my bag?
TALIESIN: Yes, I'll have a donut, thank you,
please.
LIAM: I would also like a donut, please.
LAURA: Okay, here you go. I don't have them in
real life, just this one in real life. But in the
game, you guys are having delicious donuts.
TRAVIS: How old are those donuts?
LIAM: Do you actually have donuts? I don't
understand.
LAURA: Yeah, here you go.
LIAM: Oh, there it is.
MATT: Imagination!
LAURA: You're doing it, Peter, you're doing it!
TALIESIN: I was just going there, damn it!
Bangarang!
LAURA: These donuts are not that old.
TALIESIN: What does "not that old" mean, does it
mean they're young?
LIAM: Are they pretty new?
LAURA: They're pretty new, yes.
LIAM: Three days new? Or-- Forget it, I don't
actually want to know the answer.
LAURA: Just eat it, it's good.
TALIESIN: Is it good and do we gain or lose hit
points?
MATT: No hit point transition, no constitution
saves. They're a bit stale, but still tasty enough.
TRAVIS: Any lint from the bag that they were being
held in?
MATT: You can chose to remove it if you'd like,
but it may be part of the texture. It adds color.
LAURA: That's right. It's like sprinkles.
LIAM: Mollymauk, is this weird for you to not be
traveling with your performing family?
TALIESIN: It's change, but travel is travel, so.
LAURA: Did you travel in a wagon when you were
with your family?
TALIESIN: Oh yes, we traveled forever. It was
constantly on the road. Once we left home, we
stayed moving.
MATT: Ironically, traveled in the exact wagon that
you're in right now.
LAURA: Oh, nice.
LIAM: Some things don't change. We didn't have
much of a chance to see you perform. I saw you do
a card reading for Jester, but things got waylaid
at the circus. What do you normally do?
TALIESIN: Oh, things. I'm not really much of a
performer, I'm more of-- Help set up. Help run the
shows, help make illusions, that sort of thing.
SAM: Like a techie?
TALIESIN: I guess you could say a techie. I show
off a little bit of the sword juggling.
SAM: Oh!
TALIESIN: I've got some things I was working on.
Like this.
TRAVIS: You juggling those big motherfucking
swords?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: You watch as he balances one on the edge of
the hand and then tosses it up and catches it as
it falls, and takes the other one and glides it
across, spins it up, catches it on his chin. On
his nose; he makes it hop around. It's pretty
decent.
TALIESIN: Little roll.
LAURA: Can you swallow it?
MATT: Make an acrobatics check if you want to
try.
TALIESIN: Well, it's a curved sword. So not the
curved ones. But I could probably do a straight
sword. I'm not going to swallow a curved sword!
That would be very complicated to pull off.
LIAM: If anybody can do it, it's you.
SAM: That tiefling anatomy is very strange, you
know.
TALIESIN: I'm flexible, but not that flexible. I'm
pretty flexible. Yeah, I never nailed anything
down for a really good act.
MATT: A few hours into travel along the road, you
catch ahead the sight of another caravan heading
southward in your direction. They begin to crest
over one of the hills. As you look forward, too,
the central portion of the Marrow Valley isn't
just a smooth, constant grade. It's a series of
rolling hills and high grasses and wheats and
grains, and a lot of wild weeds that have taken
over the areas between bastions of civilization.
LIAM: How far away are they?
MATT: You can see up there about maybe a half mile
or so, as they crest over one of the hills in the distance.
LIAM: Yeah, I send Frumpkin ahead and see it, and
go blind and deaf here, so I can get a closer look
at them.
SAM: Which is Frumpkin now?
LIAM: Frumpkin's a sparrow at the moment. I don't
have the components to put him back to the shape
he prefers, which is a cat.
LAURA: What are the components?
LIAM: Charcoal and some incense, a kind of incense
you have to use. I'm all out. I used it all.
TALIESIN: Not my incense.
LIAM: No.
TRAVIS: Is there money involved?
LIAM: Money? Well, you have to pay money to get
the things to do it.
TRAVIS: Right, I'm sorry.
LIAM: He's been a couple of things before. He can
last. Anyway. Off you go.
LAURA: Have you ever made him a turtle?
MATT: He can't hear you right now, unfortunately.
LAURA: Have you ever made him a snake? Have you
ever made him a roach?
SAM: He's gone to the other place. He won't be
able to respond.
LAURA: Have you ever made him a unicorn?
TRAVIS: Oh my god.
SAM: A unicorn would be really cool.
MARISHA: That would be really cool.
TALIESIN: I'd like to see that.
LAURA: They exist, you know.
TALIESIN: I didn't know that.
LAURA: They do.
MATT: As your vision crests up with the flight of
Frumpkin, make a perception check for Frumpkin.
LIAM: Don't fuck me, Scanlan. Oh, that's not
Scanlan, that's Percy, but you did fuck me, Percy.
TALIESIN: I try.
LIAM: That is very low. We'll just say it fails,
because it's a two.
MATT: It's a two?
LIAM: Yeah, I rolled a two.
MATT: Okay. I mean, at a safe enough distance to
look down, there are shapes. The most that
Frumpkin makes out is that it looks to be six
heavy wagons.
MARISHA and LAURA: Six?
MATT: Six heavy wagons, each being pulled by a
trio of horses.
SAM: We can rob them.
LIAM: 18 horses.
TRAVIS: We should what?
SAM: Well, we could rob them, or we could go off
the road and hide and wait for them to pass.
LAURA: Is Frumpkin back? Do we know all these
things yet?
SAM: Oh, we don't.
MATT: We'll say for the purposes of this--
SAM: Pleasant day!
LIAM: I started muttering as soon as I could see
that. What they were, what I saw.
LAURA: Do they look like they're in armor? Do they
look like they're soldiers?
SAM: He can't hear you.
LAURA: Do they look like they're mean?
TALIESIN: Do they look like they're unicorns?
MARISHA: Do they look like they're traders? Like
traders, not traitors.
SAM: He can't hear you.
LAURA: Do you see, are they carrying money? Are
they carrying people?
SAM: He won't be able to talk to you for a while.
You see, he's not really there.
MATT: Coming closer down the road now, the gap
between your traveling troupe and this caravan
grows smaller and smaller. All the rest of you,
I'd like to make a perception check, please. I
think at this point, Frumpkin has--
LIAM: I would've released it, yeah. He's not back,
but I released the sight.
TRAVIS: 17.
LIAM: Perception check?
SAM: Nine!
TALIESIN: 20.
MARISHA: 17.
LAURA: Five!
LIAM: Zwölf.
MATT: Amongst all of you guys keeping an eye out,
you look ahead and you can see the wagons are
covered, some of them are bundled; some of them
are taller; some of them are smaller. What you do
notice is at the front of each of the wagons,
there's a figure with the reins that is in the
process of sitting there and occasionally making
sure the pace is kept relatively steady forward.
You do see by the long robes and ornate silk
mantles of the highwaymen that are holding these
reins, you get the impression that they probably
are from the Menagerie Coast. You two in
particular recognize, it's not well-off mercantile
clothing, but it looks like it's not rags for a
person that makes this trek up and down the Amber
Road. Looks like they're heading southward,
probably returning after completing some sort of a
trade run up to either Zadash or Rexxentrum and
spaces nearby. As the gap begins to close, there's
a brief moment of chicken to see who's going to
avert the path as it's only about ten foot wide.
It would be a pretty tight fit to get both your
troupe and their wagons past. Do you guys yield or
do you continue to push forward?
TRAVIS: I would just like to suggest we might give
way. There are six of them.
TALIESIN: I'm fine with that.
MARISHA: Yes, agreed.
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: You guys skirt your single horse-- poor
thing is pulling this cart on its own.
TRAVIS: We're going to kill it.
MATT: It's not going any faster, really, than you
guys walking, necessarily.
(laughter)
LAURA: But we get to be lazy.
TRAVIS: But we're not walking.
(laughter)
MATT: Because it is not a riding horse, it is a
beast of burden, so it's about the same pace that
you're going. As you guys pull slightly off into
the grass, the cart bumps as it hits some rocks
and patches of dirt and thick grass. They continue
to pass, and as they do, you see the individuals.
The one in the front has what looks to be a thick
scarf tossed over the shoulder obscuring part of
the face, and she gives a hand salute up to you as
it passes and a bit of a head nod. As you wave your
hand frantically, a bit of eye contact is made and
continues past.
LAURA: Are you going to Nicodranas?
MATT: No response. The first cart continues past.
LAURA: Hi. Hi, are you going to Nicodranas?
MATT: The next one looks over to you for a second,
the head cocked a little bit. "No, we are on our
"way to Port Zoon."
LAURA: Oh.
MATT: "By way of Nicodranas."
LAURA: Oh! Did you come from Zadash?
MATT: "We briefly did, yes, but we are returning.
We have finished our wares and we have things to
"bring back to sell."
LAURA: How far is it to Zadash?
MATT: "Uh..." At this point he's passed by you and
his voice gets a bit louder over his shoulder and
he's like, "From this point, it's probably around
150 miles."
LAURA: Thank you!
MATT: The next one continues, one after another.
You get a better look, too. The ones at the front
that were pretty heavily covered, as opposed to
the ones in the back which are a little taller,
and as you look into the back, there's little
flaps and openings on the inside, you can see
there's families traveling.
MARISHA: Does it look like they have any wares
that they're traveling to trade?
MATT: Make a perception check.
MARISHA: That's a 16, I think. Yeah. 19.
MATT: Glancing through, you can see the three
wagons towards the back seem to be more for
transport of people. It seems like either these
merchants are bringing their family with them for
long treks, so they're not apart from them for so
long, or their family is just a family of traders
or transport. Looking past them, you can see there
are a lot of supplies behind them, but you're not sure
if they're wares or just their personal goods.
TRAVIS: Molly, feel like making some coin, doing a
little bit of a show?
TALIESIN: Hmm.
MATT: The fifth cart's now passed. You're moving
on to the sixth cart.
TALIESIN: Do these people look like they're in the
mood to stop?
MARISHA: Yeah, do they look sad?
MATT: Make an insight check.
SAM: Do they look sad.
TALIESIN: What's insight?
LAURA: Plus five.
TALIESIN: Oh, where do you see that? Oh! There it
is. Thank you. 19.
MATT: They don't look sad necessarily. They're on
the road, just kind of looking out and keeping
eyes on the vicinity and probably lost in thought.
You do see a pair of children, hard to gauge their
age at this distance, but they're under the age of
ten at least, and they seem to look relatively bored.
TALIESIN: I'll balance one of the swords on my
head and flash the cards and see if anybody bites.
LAURA: As you drop them all over the ground.
LIAM: Wakka wakka.
MATT: You watch as the young boy, he has tangled
black hair that poofs out a bit on the sides, he
has a deeper brown skin, and he looks up at you
with his bright blue eyes. As soon as you begin
balancing the sword, he smiles a little bit and
jabs his elbow into his sister who's a little bit
older than him, who glances over and points. They
both point towards you. You don't hear anything.
They just point and smile as their cart pulls
away, the sixth cart making distance from you.
LAURA: He can tell your fortune!
TALIESIN: They didn't poke the parents.
LAURA: They're stupid.
MATT: The caravan continues without you.
LAURA: Yeah!
TALIESIN: Ah, it's very good.
LAURA: Is it?
TALIESIN: Yes.
LAURA: What does it mean?
TALIESIN: It means that you're on a cart.
LAURA: It was the chariot.
TRAVIS: Would you normally, you know, hijack a
caravan like that?
SAM: I mean, we have in the past. If we are
confident we can get away with it, we would. We could--
TALIESIN: Can you get away with something like
that?
SAM: There's a lot of people in that caravan
though, it seems like a risky maneuver.
LIAM: That's a pretty big matzo ball there.
TALIESIN: And stealing is wrong. But if you did
it, could you get away with it?
SAM: We could probably get away with it. Why? You
want to follow them and rob their shit?
TRAVIS: Just going off what you said earlier. I
don't want to change your behavior just because
you're with us all of a sudden.
SAM: I mean, sure. Let's go do it.
LAURA: He's just trying to get you in trouble.
SAM: Oh, okay.
TRAVIS: I am not. Merely asking a question.
MARISHA: Would you join in in the stand off?
TRAVIS: Wait, what does that--
MARISHA: Would you join the stagecoach robbery?
TRAVIS: If we're pointing them down, reach for the
sky!
TALIESIN: Careful, those fingers are loaded.
LIAM: Yeah, but I would ask. Are you asking
because that is something that you have no
experience with or are you wondering maybe is that
something that we could join you in?
TRAVIS: Only because I have no experience in it, I
was just curious what it was that you might have
done, you know, previously.
LAURA: Did you hijack a cart?
SAM: No, we were more small-time thieves. We
wouldn't typically hijack moving caravans. Usually
we'd wait until they parked somewhere and then
just go sneak on and steal something out of the back.
LIAM: Mostly whatever we can walk away with.
MARISHA: The things with moving carts of that big
a family is they tend to prep. You don't know what
kind of people or weapons they have with them.
LIAM: Always go for a sure thing.
MARISHA: You know how we're pretty sure that
everyone on this road's going to kill us? Yeah,
everyone else thinks that, too.
TRAVIS: Fair enough.
SAM: But if you need me to teach you how to steal,
you can tag along sometime.
TRAVIS: I might take you up on that, yeah.
SAM: All right.
TALIESIN: Interesting.
MATT: Continuing on your path, I want to ask which
two of you are taking point in keeping an eye on
the road and the landscape around you as you
progress?
TRAVIS: (fake cough) Beau.
MARISHA: Yeah, I'll take watch.
TRAVIS: Oh, sorry.
MATT: Okay. Beau and who else?
TRAVIS: So generous of you.
LAURA: You want to do it?
TALIESIN: I was going to say, yeah. I'll take a
round. I'm used to keeping an eye out on the road.
MATT: So the two of you are taking point up until
you guys decide to change it when it comes to
travel along the road.
MARISHA: It's just general perception?
MATT: Yes. I would like you both, currently about
an hour's journey past that intersection with the
other caravan, to make a perception check.
LAURA: Ooh! I bet someone's going to try to hijack
our shit on the road just like we were talking
about then.
MARISHA: Not too bad. 18.
TRAVIS: Yeah! Smash.
MATT: 18 and eight. Actually, both of you don't
really notice anything.
MARISHA: Oh. Take that back. Take it back.
MATT: Both of you keeping an eye out, the hills
continue to roll. You see patches of trees and
small wooded areas. Grass field is tall but it's
beautiful and the light breeze that blows through,
you can see the waves of wind as they come across.
You can hear the faint sound of it moving the
fields across.
MARISHA: Is there a tree that looks climbable that
I could get a vantage point?
MATT: There is. It's maybe about 600 feet off the
road, but you can try and head over there if you
want to.
TRAVIS: Plus we've been traveling for what? About
hour and a half, two hours now?
MATT: I'd say total right now, you've been
probably on the road for about four hours.
MARISHA: Oh.
TRAVIS: We should probably rest the horse for
just a bit.
(laughter)
MARISHA: Sure. Anyone want to take a quick pee
break?
LAURA: Yes.
SAM: Yes, please.
MARISHA: All right. Let's go over to the bushes.
MATT: All right. So you guys leave the cart on the
road or do you take it off to the side?
SAM: Should leave a guard with the--
LAURA: We should lead it off the road.
MARISHA: Can we take it with us fairly easily?
MATT: I mean, you can. The progress will slow a
bit because you're now taking it through the hills
and the field and having to push the cart through
the grass.
LIAM: No, we should take it off the road.
LAURA: Just off the road a little bit.
MARISHA: Just off the road but we don't have to go
all the way to the tree, I can--
TALIESIN: I'll sit with the cart for the first
roll.
TRAVIS: I'll stay with you.
LIAM: Where are you going to do?
MARISHA: I'm just going to go check out this tree
over here. See if I can get a little better
vantage.
LIAM: Okay. I have a bird that can go probably
higher than the tree, if you want.
MARISHA: Yeah, kind of forgot about that.
LIAM: Would you like me to do that?
LAURA: Maybe she likes climbing trees.
LIAM: Or you could. I don't want to rob you of the
joy of climbing a good tree.
TRAVIS: Or falling out of it, which we would
really enjoy.
TALIESIN: That would be actually extremely--
MARISHA: Both are very pleasant, but I do not
necessarily need that to feel fulfilled.
LIAM: Okay. Well, I will sit in the field then and
give him a little chuck under the chin and-- oh,
wait. Before I go away, am I looking for anything
specific?
MARISHA: Just people coming.
LIAM: People coming.
MATT: As the rest of you take a moment to step off
to the side of the road, pull out some of your
travel supplies to feed the horse, give it a
rest.
LAURA: Pick some flowers.
MATT: Pick some flowers, which you can find.
They're wildflowers. They're bright white,
scattered and simple, but they're beautiful in their own
right. You all take a bit to relieve yourselves a
little ways off the road. You make your way
towards the nearest tree and it's a cluster of
about five or six that are nearby, this pocket
where it seems like some seeds long ago got
dropped by a bird, probably, over the sky, and
then proceeded to grow and sprout. The lowest
branch is about ten feet up, so you're going to
have to take a quick leap and try and climb some
of it.
MARISHA: I wanted to wait for Caleb.
MATT: Oh, that's right, you're waiting there.
Never mind. You see that tree and you go, "I'll
"get to that later."
MARISHA: It's a damn good tree. I do miss climbing
trees.
LAURA: Do you need me to lift you up to the
branch?
MATT: Your eyes cloud over.
LIAM: They do. As the bird is flying, just for a
second, I say: You know, ordinarily-- I can't hear
you, but he's a cat almost all the time, so this
is a rarity. You'll be able to climb many trees,
many other times, but we should take advantage of
him. Well, okay.
LAURA: None of us were nearby when he was saying
all of that.
MATT: No, you guys were quite a ways off. No one
was in earshot.
TRAVIS: We were shitting in the bushes.
MATT: A ladybug lands on his nose and goes in his
nostril, but he can't feel it.
LIAM: Feel it?! I can feel stuff!
MATT: Maybe not this. You're too focused.
LIAM: We worked out that he could-- okay, great.
There's bugs in my nose.
MATT: It tickles a little bit.
LIAM: Shove it all in, everybody!
MATT: To be fair, your face itches in general from
the sheer amount of filth that's on it. It's hard
to really differentiate.
LIAM: In the middle of the field you hear: Ooh,
look at that! What do I see?
MATT: Make a perception check for your birdie.
LIAM: That's a nine.
MATT: Glancing over and doing a wide pass around
as everyone begins to gather their things and head
towards the cart, the road's pretty open. At this
point, the previous caravan is invisible from that
height, the hills close that distance. You don't
see anything coming your way. It seems pretty open
and safe.
LIAM: Okay. I keep flying for a little bit
longer.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: I lift Beau up to the branch just because.
MARISHA: Okay. Feels like childhood. Do you want
up here?
LAURA: Yeah, I'll jump!
MARISHA: All right, I lift her up.
LAURA: We sit up in the branches.
MATT: Okay, cool. It's a nice view.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: It's impossible to believe him.
MARISHA: Is there anything carved in the
branches, in the tree trunk?
MATT: Make an investigation check.
LIAM: The treant eats you.
MATT: Shh, don't spoil it!
MARISHA: 18.
MATT: No carvings of names or letters, but you do
see a few knots in the tree that have currently
been carved out and made a home to a number of
woodland creatures.
LAURA: I've never climbed a tree before.
MARISHA: Really?
LAURA: Yeah. This is really pretty.
MARISHA: What do you think lives in that hole?
LAURA: Probably very small unicorns.
MARISHA: Have you ever seen an unicorn?
LAURA: Yes, I've seen many. The little ones can be
as small as hamsters.
MARISHA: Pocket unicorns?
LAURA: Yeah.
MARISHA: Where do you find such things?
LAURA: All over. You just have to know where to look.
SAM: And believe.
TALIESIN: She's starting to believe.
MARISHA: What is it like being in your head?
LAURA: It's pretty great!
MATT: Eventually, you all gather yourselves again
back at the wagon, cart it back onto the road, and
head northward. Another few hours pass before the
sun begins to set. As the sky grows darker, the
clouds from the north-northeast begin to filter in
with a colder wind. You get the sense that the
warm day that you had is coming to a close and who
knows how long the current cold weather will keep.
The light begins to fade, darker and darker, until
you get the sense that you have about 30 minutes
before this field goes pitch black.
LIAM: How cold is it out?
MATT: You can see your breath.
LAURA: Oh, that's pretty cold.
MATT: Not super thick, but when you exhale you see
a bit of the breath before you.
TRAVIS: Should we pull off on the side of the road
and get a campfire going?
TALIESIN: I'd say let's get a bit off the road, if
possible.
MARISHA: Does it look like there's any trees or
any base of mountains or any place that would be a
good sheltered campsite?
MATT: There are no mountains anywhere in the
vicinity. You're in the center of the rolling
hills. There is a cluster of trees you could go to
that's about 300 feet or so off the road. It's
three trees, so it's not a lot of cover, but
unfortunately you're in the middle of a valley.
TALIESIN: It'll do.
LAURA: Can we get the horse over to them?
MATT: It takes you a little bit. You spend about
45 minutes in pitch dark keeping an eye in that
direction before you come upon the tree. You can
faintly see the outline of the tree against the
faint bit of light making it through the cloud cover.
You guys stop there, get the horse a little bit of
water and feed, and the site's yours.
TALIESIN: Set a tent. Start a fire.
LAURA: This is why we should've taken one of the
circus tents.
TALIESIN: They take an awful lot of time to put
up. You do know this. There's a process.
LAURA: Yeah, but think about how cool it would be
to camp in one.
TALIESIN: Oh, it would be amazing. I've done it.
It's great, but this is nice, too.
TRAVIS: Shall we collect some wood and start a
fire?
SAM: Sounds good.
MATT: Who's starting the fire?
TRAVIS: Anybody want to come with me to find some
kindling?
MARISHA: I have an adventurer's kit. Does that
have a tinder in it?
MATT: You can do that.
TRAVIS: Shall we?
MARISHA: Sure.
TRAVIS: All right. Go look for some dead-ish
branches.
MARISHA: I'm a little-- you be my eyes. It's super
dark.
SAM: Maybe you shouldn't go.
MARISHA: You know what, I'll start digging a
little pit.
LIAM: Now, hold on. I pull a rag out, and I (poof)
one of the Dancing Lights, and make that hooded
lantern again so that you can see.
MATT: With that light, it's easy enough to find
some small kindling. There's not a whole lot in
the vicinity, mainly being that it's an open
field. But you find a few pieces of fallen tree
and general dead plant life in the vicinity that
can get something going.
TALIESIN: We can chop it up.
MATT: Eventually you get a fire going. It's a
little beacon of light here in the darkness,
orange-ish flickering against the interior
of the three trees as you guys are situated there.
You figure you've made it a little under halfway
to Alfield, which is the small city on the way to
Zadash. It'll take you a little over a day's
travel, or if you push it ahead you could probably
make it in a day, but you can run the risk of
getting tired. But for resting this evening, who
wants to take watch?
TRAVIS: Nobody. We're all going to sleep.
LIAM: While they decide that, I'm going to pull
out my silver thread and I'm going to start
winding a 20-foot circle around the fire.
MARISHA: Oh, nice.
LAURA: I get my little bouquet of wildflowers and
I give it to Nott.
SAM: Oh, that's very nice of you.
LAURA: Well, you said all girls like flowers.
SAM: We do. That's very nice of you, thank you.
What did I do to deserve this?
LAURA: I don't know, you are my friend.
TALIESIN: A single tear pours down a porcelain
cheek.
LAURA: I'll take first watch.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: Everybody hears a little (ting) as I hit a
little bell that I have that's part of it.
And that's it.
SAM: I'll sit up with you, Jester, and take first
watch, 1B.
LAURA: I like it.
MATT: All right. We'll say for the purposes of
expediency on this, I'll take three perception
rolls from three different people that are keeping
watch throughout the evening. So with the setup of
your spell, you go to rest. Jester, you first.
LAURA: Oh, god damn it!
SAM: No, it's pretty good.
LAURA: Yeah, one. So pretty good.
MATT: All right, natural one. About ten minutes--
LAURA: Sorry, guys.
MATT: About ten minutes into your watch, the
inspiration hits for you to start drawing
interesting faces and weird trees. You start
sketching--
LAURA: Little tiny hamster unicorns!
MATT: There you go. As you begin to sketch, you
are not paying attention at all to the area around you.
LAURA: It's really cute! All wrapped up in a
little swaddling blanket!
MARISHA: Little hamster tails! Oh man!
MATT: Giant miniatures space unicorns. However,
even though you rolled really poorly, your watch
goes through unabated. Second watch, who's taking
that?
LAURA: I'm so tired! (snores)
LIAM: I will stay up for a little bit, yeah.
MATT: All right. Go ahead and roll a perception
check, please.
LAURA, MARISHA, and TRAVIS: (chanting) Caleb!
LIAM: Oh, that's pretty good. That's a 19.
MATT: Okay. Keeping an eye out, you see a little
ways off-- it's hard to make out any shapes
because of your human eyes and, with the firelight
that's near you, your eyes can't adjust to the
darkness as well, but there are bits and pieces
where the clouds do break, the moonlight comes
down and you can see a distant shape that's moving
through the field maybe about 400 feet off. You
can see it pushing through the height of the
grass, moving slowly.
LIAM: Am I the only one awake at this moment?
MATT: Yep.
LIAM: I slowly jiggle Nott awake. (whispers) Get
up.
SAM: It was violin class! What?
LIAM: I put a hand over her mouth.
SAM: What's going on?
LIAM: There is a thing out around our fire a ways
off.
SAM: Why did we leave you on watch? You can't see
in the dark!
LIAM: No, I saw the shape. It's not dark, there's
a fire here.
SAM: Okay, let me sneak around and look. Right? We
don't want to wake everyone because--
LIAM: Because we want them to die? I think we
should probably wake everyone.
SAM: What if it's nothing? Then they'll be upset
with us. There's nothing more dangerous than--
LIAM: I shake Beau awake.
SAM: No, she's the most irritable!
MARISHA: I'm what?
SAM: Sorry.
MARISHA: Did you say I'm fucking irritable?
LIAM: She said "most beautiful." There's a thing
out there in the field. Something is moving.
LAURA: She can't see! She's human, too!
(laughter)
SAM: I'm going to go look! I can see in the dark.
LIAM: No, wait here!
SAM: I'm going to dart off in a flanking maneuver.
MATT: Make a stealth check.
SAM: 18 plus stuff.
LIAM: As soon as I see her do that, I start
swatting Fjord on the back to wake him up.
SAM: 26.
MARISHA: What do I see?
MATT: You vaguely see the shape moving, but it's
hard to see, and only because of the moonlight.
Nott, as you stealth up and quickly move through
the grass, eventually you hear this (soft grunting).
You glance up and see there is not one,
but three large buffalo-type creatures that are
lumbering through the fields.
SAM: Buffalo-type creatures, or buffalo?
MATT: You're not sure. You're not close enough to
see. You see they're bipedal, they're thick and
muscular, and they have these large horns that
curl off to the side and out.
TRAVIS: Bipedal?
MATT: Sorry, quadruped, not bipedal.
SAM: How far am I from the camp?
MATT: You're about, maybe, 80 to 100 feet from it.
SAM: Cool. I'm going to pull out a piece of copper
wire and, remembering the motions that Caleb
taught me, I'm going to twirl it around in my hand
and hold it up to my mouth and whisper a Message
just to Caleb.
TRAVIS: Oh shit, what?!
SAM: I'm going to say: it's three buffalo, or
buffalo-type objects. Creatures. What do you want
me to do? (fwoosh)
LIAM: I'm so proud! I don't know that spell, so I
cannot talk back.
SAM: Yes, you can!
LIAM: What? Who said that? If you can can hear
me-- I don't think you can-- come back with the group.
SAM: All right.
LAURA: Can you hear him?
LIAM: Is that how Message works?
SAM: Yes, I can hear you.
LAURA: That is awesome!
MATT: The whispers continue back and forth.
SAM: It's just one back and forth. I can talk to
him, he can reply once. That's it.
MATT: For one round.
LIAM: For one round, so six seconds.
LAURA: Sick.
MATT: It's a cantrip.
LAURA: Oh my gosh, I love it.
LIAM: Oh, if it's a cantrip, you can do it over
and over again.
LAURA: It's a cantrip?
SAM: Is it? Oh, it is! Ooh, this is exciting! I've
never had magic before.
LIAM: It's two soup cans with a string.
MATT: Essentially.
LAURA: How far does it go?
SAM: You don't know!
TRAVIS: Yeah, there you go.
SAM: You're drawing hamsters.
LAURA: Oh, the cutest unicorn hamsters.
MATT: So Nott, what are you doing?
SAM: He said to come back, so I'm coming back. On
the way back, I'm going to see if they're eating
or sleeping. What are they doing?
MATT: They're just moving. As you head back to the
camp, you can see they pass and continue heading
in the southwestern direction in the field, not
taking notice of your fire or the encampment.
SAM: They could be good for meat. We could go kill
them and eat them for meat.
LIAM: Is she back?
MATT: Yes.
LIAM: I scoop her up. Look at you! You cast a
spell, you spoke to me!
SAM: You said to do the hand movements and the
whispery thing. And I did it and it worked!
LIAM: It's as simple as that, isn't it?
SAM: Yes!
LIAM: Oh, I'm so proud of you! We need to calm
down and go back to bed.
SAM: Oh, but we could've eaten those buffalo-type
creatures.
TRAVIS: Hey, what the fuck did you wake us up for,
anyway?
LIAM: (laughs nervously) Got you.
TRAVIS: That's a joke?
LIAM: No. I thought we were all going to die, but
it was just-- what was it?
SAM: Three large beasts of burden. Wait, we could
use them to pull the cart!
TRAVIS: Yeah! Where are they?
SAM: They went that way! In the dark!
MARISHA: You sure they were just cows? Or donkeys?
Or buffalo-type things?
SAM: I don't know! I don't know what they were,
but they looked big and able to pull the cart.
TRAVIS: Let's go look at one.
SAM: You want to go cow-tipping, don't you?
TRAVIS: Fuck yeah! Take me cow-tipping, son! Woo!
LIAM: Echoes in the field. (echoing sounds)
SAM: What happened?
TRAVIS: I don't know. Back in college.
SAM: Are we going to go after them or are we going
to go back to sleep?
TRAVIS: Yeah, let's go look at one.
LIAM: Well, shit. I guess we're going to look
at a buffalo.
SAM: Let's go!
LAURA and TALIESIN: I'm still sleeping.
MATT: While Molly and Jester continue to enjoy
their continued long rest, you all interrupt it to
get up, and head in the direction of these
creatures. I would like you all to make a stealth
check, please.
SAM: 12.
TRAVIS and MARISHA: 11.
LIAM: 16.
MATT: All right. The four of you, shoulder to
shoulder, keeping low, making your way through the
field, stepping ever so carefully. And there's
this (croaking) as one of you accidentally goes
completely foot down on to some sort of field frog
that had been there. As the croak hits, you watch
as one of the creatures (startled grunting), and
they all start running away, spooked by the sound.
TRAVIS: Shit.
MARISHA: Can we tell what they are? Now that we're
closer?
MATT: Make a perception check, if you want to.
TRAVIS: I'd like to, with my darkvision.
MATT: At disadvantage on you, unfortunately, at
this distance.
TALIESIN: Welcome to human.
MARISHA: Six.
MATT: They look like buffalo-like creatures.
TRAVIS: 13?
MATT: They look like buffalo.
SAM: You'll never know what they were.
TRAVIS: Well, that was worth a look.
MATT: You aren't too familiar with a lot of the
indigenous animals that live or have been brought
to this region if they haven't been near the port
towns that you grew up in. You haven't seen these
types of creatures before, but you vaguely know
they're in the ballpark of what a buffalo, you
imagine, looks like.
TRAVIS: It's vaguely what I imagine a buffalo
would look like.
MARISHA: Yeah.
SAM: Sorry.
MARISHA: That was fun, let's go.
TRAVIS: Back to sleep.
LIAM: Silently ruffle Nott's hair on the way back
to camp.
SAM: Stop it.
LAURA: (singing) Who's got the third watch?
TALIESIN: I'll take it.
LIAM: Turd watch.
MATT: All right. Molly has the third watch.
TALIESIN: Turd watch.
MATT: Perception check, please.
LAURA: Oh no!
TALIESIN: Six.
MATT: Okay. As you keep an eye out, everyone else
sleeps throughout the evening. Eventually, you nod
off, and fall asleep with the rest of them. I
would like to ask all of you to leave the table
for a moment, except for Fjord.
TRAVIS: For me?!
MATT: Yeah.
MARISHA: It's your turn now!
TRAVIS: Why? (shouting) Why didn't you roll a
higher perception?
TALIESIN: I literally don't know. That's actually
the problem.
MARISHA: Just don't get a lich phylactery
installed in you again.
TALIESIN: Travis, it's been nice playing with
you.
TRAVIS: Oh god. Oh no!
TALIESIN: I thoroughly enjoyed your accent.
TRAVIS: Oh shit!
MATT: Fjord, as darkness takes your mind,
dreamless like most, you await the emptiness of
sleep to carry you to the day. Your sense of body
fades, but your mind and the dark linger. Minutes,
hours, days. Time loses real sense and meaning,
but you're conscious for it and that is almost
maddening, in that split second or endless stretch
of experience that you're currently unable to
express. As the time passes, the air grows colder
around you. The faint shimmer of shifting midnight
blue, muted and distant, now showing endless depth
before you, rippling. You begin to flail about,
your senses returning with the dropping
temperature, but there is resistance to your limbs
as you push in the space around you. You're
sluggish. There's force. It's not air, it's water.
You suddenly feel the burning pain in your lungs
as your breath fights to escape you, but you hold
tight. You seize and swim in desperation, choosing
any direction, but the shimmering blue is
directionless. There is no up, there is no down.
It's just depth. Movement. The universal shadows
dance as one, right to left. With a speed that
pulls you along with the current, you feel
yourself being jostled. As it shifts again to the
left to right, around behind you, you find
yourself toppling, head over end, eventually
coming to rest again. You spiral over and over
again, the darkness swallowing you, tightening
around you as this dance, this shape, this endless
coil, this spiral around you. As the current tugs
at you, battering you, you cannot fight any more
as the increased power of the current pulls on
your form. You cough, and the freezing waters rush
into your body, the briny taste of salt water
stinging your insides. Your wincing eyes open with
the pain that clutches the interior of your chest,
only to see a gargantuan mass moving through the
water around you, like a massive noose closing in.
The pain in your chest vanishes. As your breathing
normalizes-- thicker than air, but breathable all
the same-- it feels strange yet weirdly familiar.
In that moment, yellow light bursts before you in
the shape of an enormous yellow eye. An
impossibly low tone rumbles through the waters
around you, shaking you to your core, like an
organic war horn the size of a canyon. The eye
narrows as the tone grows stronger. A thought
enters your mind, a jumble of emotions that your
brain attempts to make sense of until a word
congeals into the center of your consciousness:
"Watching." The eye just looks at you, waiting expectantly.
TRAVIS: (English accent) What are you?
MATT: "Watching."
TRAVIS: Watching me?
MATT: The eye opens a bit and leans closer towards
you. "Potential."
TRAVIS: My potential? What are you asking of me?
MATT: "Learn."
TRAVIS: Learn. What would you have me learn?
MATT: "Learn. Grow. Provoke. Consume."
TRAVIS: Learn, grow, provoke, consume. I don't
understand.
MATT: "Reward."
TRAVIS: A reward for this? I'm listening.
MATT: "Patience." The eye closes, and the light is
gone. You feel the darkness and the cold
completely suffuse your entire world as the panic
and solitude, the true quiet of your
unconsciousness, begins to take hold. At that
moment, you gasp for breath, and your eyes open,
coughing and sputtering in the morning air. If we
could have everybody else come back to the table,
please! Call them back in.
TRAVIS: Fuck. Fuck you! What were those words?!
MATT: Watching, potential, learn, grow, provoke,
consume. We'll go over the rest later. Come on in!
SAM: Are we supposed to come back?
MATT: Yes, you're supposed to come back in.
LAURA: We're supposed to come in!
MATT: You are.
TRAVIS: Sorry, I found a patch of strawberries.
TALIESIN: Everybody back?
MATT: Everybody back.
LIAM: Are you okay? We're fine? Everything's
good?
TRAVIS: Yeah! We're fine. We're great. Just
doing dandy. Yep.
LIAM: You would tell us if something was wrong?
TRAVIS: Of course.
SAM: That was fast. You really fought five guys in
an alleyway that fast?
TRAVIS: Sometimes it doesn't take that long, you
know what I mean?
LAURA: What does he look like? What are we doing?
MATT: As the rest of you have already come to
consciousness in the morning air, begun to situate
your belongings and put out the embers of the fire
that lasted-- pardon-- throughout the night. Your
morning belches getting out. Fjord has slept in,
and has been ever so still in his sleep. Suddenly,
without warning, he suddenly shoots up from his
sleep, his eyes wide, and as he opens his mouth,
begins coughing and spitting water up.
TRAVIS: (coughing)
SAM: Oh no, he's injured!
LAURA: Fjord! Have I ever seen this happen to him
before?
MATT: No.
LIAM: Can you speak?
TRAVIS: Yeah. No, I'm fine.
TALIESIN: Yeah, you look it.
LIAM: You just spit a lot of water out and you
were sleeping.
TALIESIN: Was it a lot of water?
MATT: It was a sizeable glass filled with water.
TALIESIN: I'm going to do something very weird.
I'm going to walk over and dampen my hand on the
water on his chest really quickly and (sniffing).
MATT: It's briny and salty.
TALIESIN: Huh.
SAM: Why are you drinking salt water?
TALIESIN: You don't know that.
SAM: Oh. (in Sam's voice) Why are you drinking
salt water?
(laughter)
LAURA: Jeez, Fjord. That's a lot of drool.
MARISHA: Does it taste like stomach acid? Because
that's gross, man.
TALIESIN: Only one way to find out!
TRAVIS: Like a momma bird. Everybody have some of
what I puked up. It's all good.
LIAM: I don't, I want to make an insight check.
He's talking about acid reflux but he just spit a
bunch of water out.
MATT: Yeah, make an insight check.
LIAM: Yeah, okay. That's 22.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I don't think it was acid reflux.
MARISHA: You taste like a seaman.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: I don't know. I want to shake your hand,
but at the same time, I want to smash it.
MATT: I've never been more proud of my wife.
TAIESIN: That's not normal.
LAURA: What happened, Fjord?
LIAM: Does he seem full of shit to me?
MATT: Seems like he's covering some confusion or
at least trying to deflect.
TRAVIS: I had a dream, I'm sorry. A vivid one.
Just shook me to my core a little. I'll be fine,
really. It's not a common thing.
LAURA: Why the water, though?
TRAVIS: I don't know.
MARISHA: You never told me where you got that
sword. I mean, because I saw it get a little soggy,
a little drippy, when we were fighting the frog
thing, so, you know.
MATT: As you glance down at your sheath on the
ground, it is empty. There is no falchion.
TRAVIS: Yeah. That sword is a pickle.
MARISHA: It's a pickled sword? Are there benefits
to pickling your weapons?
TRAVIS: It's a mystery.
MARISHA: Oh, right.
TALIESIN: He's not wrong, though. It actually is a
pickle. You can taste it.
MARISHA: Yeah. It is very salty.
LAURA: I do like pickles.
TALIESIN: Yeah, it's not bad.
LIAM: Is our group going to be all about puns and
that stuff?
SAM: It's the lowest form of humor.
LAURA: Is it really the lowest?
TALIESIN: Level three.
MARISHA: Okay, there are some pun competitions
that get serious.
SAM: Are you all right, Fjord?
TRAVIS: Yeah. I feel funny. Caleb, you remember me
asking you about your arcane prowess?
LIAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: My small experience with the arcane came
to me around the same time that sword did.
LIAM: How long ago was that?
TRAVIS: Not too long ago. Very recent. Right
before I met up with Jester.
SAM: Were you in the ocean?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I was. Did a lot of merchant
sailing, previously. Had one trip that didn't go
so well. Suffice it to say, after it was done, I
found that sword.
MARISHA: What happened on the trip? Rough waters?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
SAM: Did anyone die?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'm not real comfortable talking
about it.
LIAM: What about the sword? You said you found it
on the ocean, you found on the boat you were on?
You were on an island? What do you mean?
TRAVIS: I found it on the shore. When I got back
to land, it was just there. I'm not super familiar
with a ton of weaponry-- the sword I know, I had
some training in it, but this seemed like a unique
sword. I felt like it almost called to me. I know
how that sounds, but when I picked it up, seemed
like everything changed. Ever since, I've been
able to do more things. Been able to reach out
with some of the stuff I've seen you do. That's
why I'm trying to make it up to the Academy. I'm
trying to figure out what it is that I have.
LIAM: DM, when I cast Detect Magic in the first
game, in the tavern, did that sword light up?
MATT: No.
TRAVIS: I don't mean to alarm any of you, really.
I'm trying to be as forthright as I can.
TALIESIN: Where is the sword right now?
TRAVIS: Can I make it appear?
MATT: You look down, and it's not in the sheath.
You glance around, it's nowhere near you.
TRAVIS: I focus. Reach down.
MATT: He looks down at his open palm, and there is
a flash of greenish-blue, teal energy out of his
grip. There, clutched within his grasp, you see
the falchion, coated in the remnants of sea floor
life. You see the barnacles encrusted around the
edge and up the back of the blade, as it begins to
drip water. The same kind that was coughed up by
Fjord this morning.
TRAVIS: You can see why I'm a little curious about
this item.
TALIESIN: That's a great trick.
LIAM: I don't even need to touch it, but would you
trust me to study it for a moment?
TRAVIS: Do you have any experience with items like
this?
LIAM: I'm good at figuring things out. I'm
clever.
MARISHA: I might be able help you with that. I was
obsessed with underwater life and mermaids, so
I've read a few books.
TRAVIS: Could we revisit that idea, perhaps? I'm
sorry, the night has left me a bit shaken, and I
feel like I need a moment to get my bearings, if
that's all right.
LIAM: Ja, you can understand that we would be
curious, but I don't want to push anybody. I mean,
we've just met.
TRAVIS: Of course not, and I don't want to make anyone
feel uneasy. Again, trying to be as transparent as
I can. I don't quite understand, and I appreciate
your patience in advance. And I make it vanish.
MATT: You watch as it just disappears out of your
grip.
LIAM: When he says he doesn't quite understand, is
he telling the truth? Is that the same insight check?
MATT: You have to make a new one.
LIAM: 11.
TALIESIN: 23.
MATT: 23.
TALIESIN: This whole story, I've been watching.
MATT: As far as you can tell, as forthright and
honest as you've heard him be.
TALIESIN: That's so disappointing. All right.
LAURA: Fjord, do you think you're slowly turning
into water?
TRAVIS: (sighs) No. I hadn't considered that
terrifying thought, but thanks. I'll just add that
to the fucking list.
LAURA: If you feel like it's happening, let us
know and we'll try to catch you in a jar.
TRAVIS: In a jar?
TALIESIN: Unless he runs away.
SAM: We're not going to let you run into the
dirt.
LAURA: Maybe something can happen.
TRAVIS: Tell you what, I start sweating real hard,
I'll let you know, okay?
TALIESIN: He's fine.
MARISHA: Has that happened to you before, by the
way? The whole, "waking up coughing salt water" thing?
TRAVIS: I don't really remember.
LIAM: You wouldn't have to remember that far back.
You said that this all started just a few weeks
ago, when you met this one.
TRAVIS: I don't really remember my dreams all that
well. They leave me quickly.
TALIESIN: I remember all of mine, I don't know.
LAURA: I've never seen him wake up with water all
over him.
MARISHA: Well, excited to see what unfolds. Shall
we?
TALIESIN: If you're going to vomit something, salt
water's pretty decent. It could have been way worse.
LAURA: Of all things, it's way better than vomit.
TALIESIN: Oh, it's far superior. Already, you're
proving to be an asset.
LAURA: If we get really thirsty, we'll just come
to you in the morning.
TALIESIN: You can't drink-- the salt water makes
you thirstier.
LAURA: Oh, really?
TALIESIN: It feels like you should be able to, but
you can't.
SAM: Should we get back on the road, then?
TRAVIS: If you wouldn't mind.
SAM: How is Horse doing today?
TRAVIS: Horse?
SAM: How's Horse?
LAURA: What is his name?
LIAM: I was wondering the very same thing,
actually, all night. I was wondering what we would call--
LAURA: This horse? Maybe he has a name. Molly?
TALIESIN: Does the horse have a name? If it did,
I'll make one up.
MATT: It probably had a few names, in travel, and
you've gone through a few horses.
TALIESIN: Try not to name them. We're just going
to end up eating them.
MATT: So whatever you come up with.
TALIESIN: His name was Winter's Crest. If he lived
that long, that was when we were going to butcher
him and eat him. You can rename him, it's fine.
LAURA: I like it, it's like a celebration.
TALIESIN: That was the plan.
SAM: Maybe for short we'll call him W.C.
LIAM: You were going to butcher, at Winter's
Crest, and that's a special treat?
TALIESIN: It means you're going to eat meat, and
then you're going to make some jerky, and then
you're going to buy another horse with the money
you make.
MATT: Interesting point, too: For most of you,
Winter's Crest would have little meaning. It's
largely celebrated in continents to the west, as
it is specific to a historic event that did not
happen in Wildemount. But you're a carnival, so
you guys have more of a vast and strange knowledge.
TALIESIN: We celebrate everything.
MATT: When he says Winter's Crest, maybe Beau.
LIAM: Have I ever read about it?
LAURA: I feel like my mom saw lots of visitors
from other places.
MATT: It's possible, but just for a bit of
information.
MARISHA: I feel like the snooty town that I came
from would have a Winter's Crest festival, like
how we have Oktoberfests out here. Even though we
have no real business having them, yeah.
TALIESIN: Just glögg. Lots and lots of glögg.
MATT: As you guys look off, at this conversation
with the horse, the horse is currently about 30
feet off in the field, eating grass out of the
field.
TALIESIN: If you're on the road long enough, you
eat a lot of animals. You eat a lot of beasts of burden.
LAURA: I wander over to the wagon and I go and sit
down and start drawing, because I need to. I need
to spend a little time.
LIAM: I pull Nott over. Do you know what W.C.
means in Zemnian?
SAM: What does it mean?
LIAM: Toilet.
SAM: It's a pun.
(laughter)
LIAM: I give her a little fistbump.
MATT: As you guys gather up, in the fresh morning
air, back into the cart.
MARISHA: Do some pull-ups on the tree branches.
MATT: As Beau gets nice and swole for the
morning.
LIAM: Vasquez.
MARISHA: Just a little bit.
TRAVIS: You're just too bad, Vasquez.
MATT: (laughter) Vasquez is a pretty good print.
I think we were talking, Vasquez and Starbuck
from the new Battlestar are both good character
prints for Beau. Yeah, love that. As you guys
bring the cart back up onto the Amber Road,
northward, you begin your second-day trek. You
guys push on for a few hours. Is it still Beau and
Mollymauk keeping point?
TALIESIN: I'll keep.
MARISHA: I don't mind.
MATT: I'll have both of you roll a perception
check, please.
MARISHA: Do we have the highest perception?
TALIESIN: Ugh. I did until it bounced.
MARISHA: Fuck. I almost got-- samesies. 11.
TALIESIN: Five.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: I have decent perception, what's yours?
MATT: Calm fields.
TALIESIN: I might be distracted looking for things
that I can pluck out of the fields. All right.
MATT: You push on for a few more hours, the
afternoon staring to get late. You can choose
soon, when it gets dark, to set up camp again and
stay another evening out in the fields, or you get
a sense looking at the map that you had procured
that if you push an extra hour or so past, you
could probably make it to Alfield before the
night's done.
SAM: Let's do that.
TALIESIN: Most of us can see in the dark, it's not
a big deal.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: Okay. You guys just hunker down in the
wagon, okay? You be safe.
MARISHA: Deal.
LIAM: Must be nice.
TRAVIS, LIAM, and TALIESIN: (singing) Must be
nice.
TALIESIN: Can't say that, ah!
MATT: All righty. You guys push forward, kind of
pick up the pace a bit, but the horse and those of
you who are on the sides of the cart, if you wish
to, you can jog along the side to alleviate some
of the burden.
MARISHA: I'm going to scan still while I'm--
MATT: Keeping an eye out.
MARISHA: With my shitty vision.
MATT: Okay. The sun does eventually close towards
the Cyrios Mountains to the west and night begins
to fall. At this point, you do see just over the
distance in the hill as darkness comes, you can
see the faint glow, a cluster of light, of a
village in the distant hills. You get the sense
that this is probably Alfield at the perimeter of
your vision. As you continue to push forward,
you've now gone past eight hours of continuous
travel into the ninth hour. I would like you all
to roll a constitution saving throw, please.
MARISHA and TALIESIN: Natural 20.
LAURA: Whoa. That's because you guys are-- oh, no,
you're riding in the cart.
MARISHA: I'm riding.
TRAVIS: 16.
MARISHA: I'm just like: What's wrong?
LIAM, SAM, and LAURA: Nine.
MATT: Nine as well? Wow. It's like Rammstein on
that side of the table.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Nein! Cookie monster.
MATT: All right. So the three of you take one
level of exhaustion.
LAURA: Aw. How do we do that in here?
LIAM: How does that affect us, again?
MATT: This is a good thing to look up.
Essentially, per point of exhaustion--
TALIESIN: So you go to your HP.
MATT: There you go. So you have disadvantage on
ability checks until you take a long rest to get
rid of it.
LAURA: Disadvantage on abilities?
MATT: Yes. On ability checks, so skills and things
like that.
LAURA: Okay, okay, okay.
MATT: All right. You guys are-- you're a few--
you're probably about a half mile away from
Alfield and it looks, even at this distance, a bit
smaller than Trostenwald, where you were. You can
see the faint clusters of trees on the north,
eastern and northeastern sides of the city,
otherwise it's just in this pocket behind a few
hills. It's a bit podunk in size, you can gather
from this distance, but it's welcoming. There's a
flash of orange light on the outskirts of town.
LIAM: Did that look arcane to me?
MATT: No, it just looked like a flash. I mean, it
could have been arcane. It's hard to tell at this
distance, it's quite a ways away.
TALIESIN: That's weird.
MATT: There's a second one. (flash) You faintly
see what looks like the distant curl of flames
beginning to spread across what appears to be a
roof.
TRAVIS: Oh shit.
LAURA: Oh no.
MARISHA: Think we just watched someone commit
arson, you guys!
TRAVIS: That's not really a--
MARISHA: Let's go kick their ass.
TRAVIS: Yeah, let's do that.
LAURA: Does it look like the fire is spreading at
all?
MATT: I mean, as you sit here and watch--
LAURA: We're walking.
TALIESIN: Let's head that direction and start
yelling at people.
TRAVIS and TALIESIN: Full sprint.
TRAVIS: Fire!
MATT: You guys begin to go into a faster jog in
that direction. As you do, you can see the fire is
now beginning to consume a handful of buildings
and the flames are beginning to flicker higher.
You begin to hear in the distance a very faint
high-pitched yelp or some sort of a screech. It's
hard to make it out at this distance, it's an open
field area and it's mingling with what sounds like
now dozens of voices screaming and entwining. As
you can see the uncontrolled flames still
progressing on the eastern side of the village,
you can just see, as you get within a few hundred
feet of the western side of Alfield, people just
running. Villagers, probably a few hundred of
them, are now just running out of the town as you
guys begin to approach. Towards you and out into
the field. So as you're approaching, they're
coming your direction.
TALIESIN: I'm going to stop one and ask what
happened.
MATT: As you glance over, you see a family of five
halflings rushing right past you. The mother is
dragging two of the younger ones by the hand while
the father is running alongside the eldest
daughter, probably in her teens. The father wears
a leather cap and has a handlebar mustache and
simple farm clothing. As you shout out, he makes
your eye contact.
TALIESIN: What has happened?
MATT: "Oh, I don't know what happened. They
started to burn the buildings and these things
"started rushing. The city is under attack."
LAURA: What things?
MATT: (panicked) "Big things. Dog-faced. I can't--
Come on." They just keep running.
LAURA: Dogs are attacking the village!
MATT: At this point, you guys can see more people
are fleeing. As you get closer, about 100 feet
outside the city, you watch as the droves of
people are beginning to get-- at least either the
ones that are actively fleeing have made it out of
the city, or in the process the stragglers are still
coming through. You see a young human man with
scrappy, tattered brown hair, a bit of blood
dripping down his face, running before his back
arches and he falls into the grass. You can see an
arrow protruding from his back. At that point, you
can see, standing up from behind one of the
exterior walls of the city, a humanoid creature
stretching up to about seven feet tall, muscular
torso with thin dog-like legs. You watch as it
extends its neck with spots of fur, its ears
curled upwards as it has a dog-like snout at the
front of it.
LAURA: Werewolves!
MATT: You watch as it leaps onto the back of this
fallen villager, bites into the shoulder, and tears
a chunk out. Swallows it before it growls into the
air (yipping howl).
LAURA: Is that a werehyena?
SAM: Have we seen these things before?
MATT: You have. You've encountered a roving band
of these on your way southward.
LAURA: What is it?
SAM: I think they're-- well, we don't know what
they're called. We just fought them. I don't know
what they're called; we fought one before!
LAURA: You know how to kill them?
SAM: You just hurt them until they die.
MATT: It swallows the flesh, grabs the body, and
then darts back into the city, dragging the corpse
of the villager it's just killed with it
rapidly.
TALIESIN: That's weird.
LIAM: Is it a walled-in city or just parts here
and there?
MATT: No. They're small and waist high, and
shoulder high walls that are partitions here and
there, but it's largely a farming city.
LIAM: Not fortified at all?
MATT: No, not at all.
LAURA: Is he within range to hit with a spell?
MATT: No, he's about-- well, depends on the spell.
Right now he's about 200 feet from you and he's
running into the city. You can see the flames are
further in but you can see the orange glow
flickering in the distance.
MARISHA: Can I do a quick scan and see if I see
more?
MATT: Perception check.
MARISHA: Don't fuck this up. That's okay, 17.
MATT: 17. In the immediate vicinity, you do not.
You see more people from the village starting to
run out, screaming. You see a handful of
crownsguard come out, one of them looks wounded
and is, "To the north. Where are they coming
from?" You see the two of them dart off northward
into the city. What are you guys doing?
TRAVIS: I chase after the crownsguard.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Go after the one that stole the guy.
MARISHA: We'll go after the one that stole the
guy.
TALIESIN: Is this making my spider sense tingle,
can I track them?
MATT: No.
TALIESIN: Okay.
MATT: You get the sense, at the moment, there's no
active idea that these would be considered a
creature that would draw your attention.
TALIESIN: Okay, all right.
MATT: Are you leaving the cart there, on the
outskirts?
TRAVIS: Yes.
LIAM: We leave the toilet behind and we run in.
MATT: All right, as you go charging into the city,
you're pushing past fleeing villagers and you can
see some of the buildings now have been locked
shut. You can see faintly through the windows
furniture being boarded up from the inside. People
are hunkering down for whatever this assault is.
As you enter, you see the crownsguard went
northward but the one creature that you saw charge
in went straight towards the heart. Right now you
can see there's two main streets that bisect this
small village. There's one that goes at an angle,
northwest to southeast. One that goes right
towards the center, west to east. As you head
towards the center you can see the flames are more
near that central square. As you guys begin to
run, push past a few more people, the smoke is
starting to billow up and you can see now there's
embers rising and then falling. This very faint
ashy rain of small points of reddish-orange light
that begin to fall with the ash. As you turn
around one of the buildings, there's one of the
side walls and four crownsguard all ducked down
behind the wall with crossbows and longbows, all
back behind it. You can see one that's adorned
with more ornate armor. You see a person there
with elven features, but hint at a mixed
lineage. They have their helmet on the ground,
showing shoulder-length blond hair that's turned
red in places from a spattering of gore. Through
gritted teeth they curse in pain as the bandages
are applied to what you can see is a wound right
around the midsection in the thigh area. Another
soldier is in the process of wrapping it. You
watch as they go, "Gah! You fool, bind the wound,
"don't stuff it." Goes and they pull a bolt back
into the crossbow and nock it at the ready.
Glancing up and seeing you approach, they scan
past you-- most of you now with weapons at the
ready, it seems, charging forward. "You!" You
suddenly have an array of arrows, about five or
six, come over the wall. One of them manages to
pierce the back of one of the crownsguards' heads
and falls and crumples to the ground. They all get
lower again. You hear in the distance (growling yips).
The individual looks back to you. "You, are
you able-bodied?"
LAURA: Yeah.
SAM: Very.
MATT: "And you're armed."
TRAVIS: We are.
MATT: "30 gold a gnoll ear. Now get in there and
help."
TRAVIS: A gnoll?
MARISHA: 30 gold a gnoll ear?
LAURA: For each one? How many are there?
TRAVIS: Just go get them.
MATT: They give you a look like-- "Just go!"
LAURA: I just don't want to get overwhelmed is
all.
MARISHA: Nott and Jester, do you guys have ways to
block arrows?
MATT: (whoosh) Two of them glace up and fire two
crossbow bolts over the wall and duck back behind.
You hear a heavy smashing of wood, some more barks
and gibbering echoing around the way. You can see
now flames curling up to the top of the building
that you're all right next to, before the small
wall that bisects the entryway.
LAURA: I have a shield.
TALIESIN: I start one of my swords on the back of
my neck.
LIAM : We are sitting ducks here. What do we do,
Fjord?
TRAVIS: It's all on the other side of a wall?
MATT: Correct.
MARISHA: Let's go towards the wall.
MATT: To give you perspective now.
SAM: Oh. This'll help. Hey side note: where's my
fucking wine?
LAURA: Did you leave it?
TRAVIS: You mean your water?
MARISHA: Did you leave it outside?
SAM: Is it gone?
MARISHA: No, it's just on the table.
LAURA: Whoa! Oh my gosh. Where are we?
MATT: You guys--
LAURA: This is so cool. Look at that flame on the
side of the roof.
MATT: You are all right over this side area,
corner. Arrange yourself as you feel you wish to
be. Over there on the far end of the village.
SAM: Oh wow. What a cool map.
MATT: If you wish to, you can place yourselves
where you wish or show me where you want them to go.
LIAM: I would be pressed against the wall of that
house.
MATT: Right here?
LAURA: Before I ran over here, I'm going to Caleb.
I'll hit you on the shoulder and say, bless you.
And I'm going to give you Blessing of the
Trickster just in case you want to stealth because
you're squishy, yo.
LIAM: Okay, so I have advantage on stealth?
LAURA: Yes.
LIAM: Thank you.
MARISHA: I'll be with Jester.
SAM: The enemies are just all over that
direction, right?
MATT: With what little bit you've looked over to
the side you can see there are some up on the
rooftops in the distance. You can see their dark
figures silhouetted by flames, and other bits of
light that normally fill the streets in the center
of the city. Most you can see are these up here and
you can already see a few bodies of guards and
civilians that are lying on the ground, carved
open and not moving. You see spatters of blood.
You still hear them barking and giving orders next
to each other (rabid barking).
LAURA: How far away are the ones on the roof?
How long is the distance from us?
MATT: Over here? At this distance it's hard to
say. I'd say probably in the neighborhood of about
70 to 80 feet from you. You guys, I would like, if
you are trying to stay out of sight, make a
stealth check, please. Those of you with a point
of exhaustion, you have disadvantage.
MARISHA: Natural 19.
LAURA: Six.
TALIESIN: 21.
SAM: 15.
LIAM: 16.
MARISHA: 25.
TRAVIS: 14.
SAM: So revealing--
LAURA: Yeah, well, I'm exhausted.
MATT: That's okay. As a group, for the moment you
guys haven't drawn their attention. You're still
right next to where there are crownsguard who are
in the process of a firefight with whatever is in
this vicinity of the city. However, you may or may
not make it through, for the moment, unseen. You're
not certain how many there are. But you can hear a
lot of yipping and growling right around this
large, two-story building that is currently
engulfed in flames.
SAM: I have an idea. We need to move away from
here, right, Fjord?
TRAVIS: We do. We have to use the cover of the
buildings.
SAM: All right, I think I can do something that
would make them fire many of their arrows at
something, but not us. Should I do that and then
as soon as they fire their arrows we can run?
TRAVIS: Diversions are absolutely--
SAM: Diversions! That's what it's called, it's a
diversion. All right, may I move, is that a thing?
MATT: You may, you're stealthed currently.
SAM: I take out a bit of fleece, and repeating the
words and doing the hand gestures that I've been
taught and tracing the image of a creature on the
fleece, I will make a Silent Image of the guard
who told us 30 gold a gnoll. I'm going to have the
image of that guard dash across, slowly, dash
across this alleyway. Like that way.
LIAM: Maybe amble more than dash.
SAM: Yes, not dash, just walk in a way that he
could be easily shot.
MATT: Interesting point of order, you're not too
certain of the gender of this individual, kind of fluid.
SAM: Okay, great, that long-haired guard
individual.
MATT: There you go. As the figure leaps over the
wall and begins making a run towards the center
area, about four different arrows pass through its
form before one of these gnoll creatures goes
lumbering forward and slashes out to it. This
gnoll, interestingly enough-- the other ones you
see and the one you saw before the city are all
built and muscular. This one seems to be porous.
With a brief bit of view, you can see there's
clumps of fur and exposed bone and part of its
skull is just pushing out of its snout with teeth
gnashing. As it tears into the illusion, it claws
through, confused, and looks over in your direction.
As you're finishing drawing your blade across your
back, what normally would be cold energy suddenly
flickers into this beacon of bright white light.
SAM: Ooh, nice.
MATT: Something clicks in your mind and you're
like, "Oh, I know you."
TALIESIN: I'm preparing. How close am I to this
thing?
MATT: This entity would be here now. It would have
just left out into that section there.
TALIESIN: Does it see us?
MATT: It does now.
TALIESIN: I'm going to use Vicious Mockery at it,
really quickly.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: Can I invoke Duplicity?
MATT: You may. I'm giving you all one round
preparation before we roll initiative.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I was going to say, we're in it.
This is a fight. So anything you want to do now,
do it.
LIAM: I mutter a few words and my form starts to
blink in and out of view. There is another Caleb
next to me and another Caleb next to me. Shifting,
blinking, flashing back and forth and it's hard to
see where I am.
MATT: Okay. Is that concentration?
LIAM: Yeah, it is.
MATT: All right, I'm going to put a concentration
marker on you just so we remember it.
TRAVIS: Can I also, knowing that we're probably
going to be up close, danger close, I'm going to
cast Armor of Agathys on myself. You see a
spectral frost start to harden around my armor in
a shimmering light.
MATT: That's cool. So that's you. That's you.
You're going to Vicious Mockery.
TALIESIN: I'm going to use Vicious Mockery. I'm
going to look at him with my eyes glowing, and my
sword glowing, and in Infernal say, (rasping) The
light comes to blind your eyes and burn your
flesh. Yeah, 1d4.
MATT: He rolled a 13 minus three. I believe it's
wisdom, correct?
TALIESIN: Yeah, it's a wisdom saving throw.
MATT: I'm pretty sure that's a ten and that does
not make your DC.
TALIESIN: Yup, so he takes three psychic damage
and he has disadvantage on his next attack roll.
MATT: Yes.
TALIESIN: I'm going to use my bonus action-- yeah,
fuck it, let's go for it-- I'm going to activate
both swords.
MATT: You drag the other edge of your blade--
TALIESIN: Should I? Yeah.
MATT: You've taken a total of six damage and your
max HP is down by six. But you have currently the
new invoked Rite on each blade.
LAURA: Can I use my bonus action really fast?
MATT: You may.
LAURA: To say a little pray to the Traveler, and
I'm going to cast Spiritual Weapon.
MATT: You may do that. Where are you going to cast
it?
LAURA: I'm going to cast it right above this
zombie gnoll. It's going to be in the shape of a
giant lollipop. Like a bludgeoning lollipop.
MATT: You watch as this flash of purplish energy
suddenly apparates into the air. This thick-like
wooden handle that is jammed into a massive,
bludgeoning, solid piece of sugary goodness.
LAURA: Yes!
LIAM: The old fashioned swirly kind?
LAURA: Yeah!
MATT: With that, you can make an attack with that
as soon as it comes out. Make a melee spell
attack, please.
LAURA: Okay, 17?
MATT: 17 does hit.
LAURA: Ooh, seven. Seven radiant damage.
MATT: Seven radiant damage, nice. As it strikes
down, wham! From the creature, already watching
its bones and its form shakes--
LAURA: Oh wait, oh wait, oh wait, I was looking at
the wrong spell, hold on. Oh, 1d8 plus three!
Seven plus three-- Ten!
MATT: Ten. Oh, that'll be enough. You watch as it
pulls back with the Infernal shouting of Mollymauk
causing it to prepare itself for a lunge. As it
gets low, its jaw snapping open, you watch as bits
of its skin fall onto the ground as it does so
(snarl). And right before it leaps, (wham) it just
smashes it into the ground and its bones go flying
and scattering in every which direction.
ALL: Oh!
TRAVIS: Is that one of the were-thingies? Damn!
LAURA: That ear is mine!
MATT: All right, so Beau, what are you doing? You
all have one round of prep. Right now, you've gone--
SAM: I cast a spell. Can I also move?
MATT: You can move, yeah.
SAM: As soon as the arrows flew by, I'm going to
dash across the alley.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: And I'm going to send my duplicate after
her.
MATT: Okay. You're running that way?
SAM: Yep. As far as I can go.
MATT: All right. And you send your duplicate over
there as well?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: All righty. And Beau?
MARISHA: I'm also going to use my speed to dash
across. I can move 40. Can I peek into this window
and see if I can see anything in here?
MATT: Sure. Easy to see in this perspective. You
glance inside--
MARISHA: Stealthily?
MATT: All right. As you glance inside, you can
just barely see around the corner. The place is
tossed. It is shattered and ruined. It looks like
it was once the interior of a small tavern of some
kind, but the kitchen is wrecked and you can see
two of these gnolls are in the process of grabbing
large sacks out of the kitchen and pulling them
out through the front door on the opposite side of
the building.
MARISHA: Oh shit. Okay. I turn to Nott. I go--
SAM: Look at two unicorns inside?
MARISHA: The gnolls!
SAM: They're inside the--?
MARISHA: Shh.
MATT: I would like you all now to roll
initiative.
MARISHA: Natural 20.
ALL: Whoa.
MARISHA: That's the second one of the night.
SAM: Oh wait, is this an ability check?
MATT: Yes, so these are with disadvantage.
LAURA: Oh, really?
LIAM: Oh, scheiß.
MARISHA: No good?
LIAM: That was worse.
MARISHA: Oh no.
TRAVIS: (German accent) That was worse.
LIAM: That was already bad.
LAURA: Initiative is an ability?
MATT: It is.
LAURA: Are attack rolls?
SAM and MATT: No.
LAURA: Okay. Did I already ask that?
SAM: Nope. Don't worry, though; I touched all your
dice, so they're going to roll great tonight.
LAURA: Thanks. Thanks, Sam.
TALIESIN: He may have licked a couple of them.
LAURA: Can you lick this one?
MATT: 25 to 20, anybody?
TRAVIS: 25 to 20.
MARISHA: 24.
LAURA: I'm going to put it back over here. I'm
going to try it. Maybe it'll roll really well with
your spit on it.
TALIESIN: It's a very pretty die.
LAURA: It's so pretty, right?
MATT: 20 to 15?
TRAVIS: 16.
MATT: 16. All righty. 15 to ten?
TALIESIN: Nine. Oh, nope, never mind, yeah.
TRAVIS: Wow, guys. Wow.
LIAM: Mm-hmm.
MATT: All right, ten to five.
TALIESIN: Nine.
LAURA: Seven.
LIAM and SAM: Six.
MATT: Okay, so that order.
TALIESIN: I want them to get a little closer
anyway. They're all far.
LIAM: It's all part of the plan.
LAURA: Mm-hmm.
TALIESIN: It's going to go great.
MATT: Molly, then Jester. Then Caleb?
LIAM: Yeah.
SAM: And Nott.
LIAM: What'd you get?
SAM: Six.
LIAM: Oh, all together at last.
MATT: All righty, so. Top of the round, as some of
this has happened. The one gnoll skeletal form has
shattered onto the ground. Some of the other
gnolls begin to look over in that direction, and
see a few of you over by the guards now, standing
up and darting over the way. They're preparing for
some sort of... whatever's coming. But first of the
round is you, Beau.
MARISHA: I turn to Nott.
SAM: Huh!?
MARISHA: Hey, you want to take these guys? You
ready for this?
SAM: (panicked stuttering) I'm going to drink from
my flask.
MARISHA: Get ready. I want them to come to this
window, okay? I'm going to go (whistles) through
the window. Try and get their attention.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Right there?
MATT: Make a performance check.
MARISHA: To whistle? Not great. Not great at all.
Three.
MATT: All right. The whistle has a bit of volume
to it. Unfortunately, with the sound of all the
breaking of furniture, them all growling at each
other, and the general screams in the vicinity,
it's lost in the chaos. It's not necessarily a
quiet atmosphere to draw a guard's attention. The
gnolls don't seem to care much for a whistle
around the window. They're more focused on
grabbing and running out the front, other way,
with whatever they're taking.
MARISHA: Is that my action or a bonus action?
MATT: I'll let that be like a bonus action, we'll
say.
MARISHA: Bonus action.
MATT: Because you were waiting for something to
happen.
LIAM: Mercer-ful.
MARISHA: Shit. Going in! I jump through the
window, and before one of them leaves, I'm going
to crack them with the staff right over the head.
MATT: Okay. With a 40-foot movement, that brings
you--
MARISHA: Can I go in through the window?
MATT: You do. As you go through the window,
because they've mostly shifted into the other room
now; that's where you see them moving. They're not
in the room that's closest to you, so you go jump
through the window, over the mass, make your way
through the living room, and you watch as they're
exiting the door. You get all the way through.
MARISHA: I thought it was much closer than that.
MATT: Unfortunately, no. But you do manage to make
it all the way to this door there.
MARISHA: Oh! They're going out the back door. I
thought they were going out that way!
MATT: Nope!
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: Is that still what you want to do?
MARISHA: That's bad disadvantage. Fog of war.
MATT: Well, here's what you do. As you rush
through to go after them, as they're fleeing out
the other side, you come to the doorway and you
can see there's one gnoll right in front of you
that hasn't noticed you rushing behind it. It's
currently throwing a corpse of one of the
villagers onto a cart that's sitting right outside
of that door. That cart, which is piled up with
other corpses, and bags, and whatever things they
were robbing from the inside of this building that
they've thrown onto this cart. You can now see
there's four gnolls that are gathered around it in
the process of throwing things onto it, and it
looks like they're getting ready to start pushing
it. They haven't noticed your arrival, as you've
just darted into the doorway. What are you going
to do?
MARISHA: Okay, I'm going to double ba-- Ah, I can't
move anymore, can I?
MATT: No, that was your move to get there.
MARISHA: I'm going to spend a ki point and do
Patient Defense.
MATT: Well, as your action you can just go into it
without having to spend a ki point.
MARISHA: Oh, really?
MATT: Because you already used your bonus action.
The ki point allows you to do it as a bonus
action, but you can just do it as an action any
time.
MARISHA: Ooh. Great, I'll do that.
MATT: You just go into the dodge action.
MARISHA: I'll just hold back and wait.
MATT: Right, so you're holding back in the
doorway, and you're ready to use the door to help
defend you if it needs to. Okay, that ends Beau's
turn. It's now their turn.
TRAVIS: Oh, shit, already? Oh god.
TALIESIN: Yeah, this is what was coming.
MATT: They rolled really high in the initiative.
TRAVIS: What are we calling these things?
ALL: Gnolls.
LIAM: G-N-O-L-L.
MARISHA: I thought I was going to still be a lot
closer to Nott.
LIAM: (sings) G-N-O-L-L.
LAURA: (sings) K-N-O-L-L
MATT: Visibly off to the side, there is...
SAM: N-O-L-L?
MATT: Yeah, that's going to be two of them firing
their bow-- Actually, no, three, because they
watched you come out. There's three of them that
are going to be firing their bows at Beau.
LAURA: Oh no!
SAM: Beau, bow, Beau, and bow?
LIAM: Bobobo-bo bo-bobo.
MATT: They all have disadvantage on the attack,
however.
SAM: She's in Patient Defense; she's going to be
fine.
MATT: As this one fires off in the direction of
your duplicitous form, as it disappears through.
As it's the only thing it can visually see. It's
going to stay behind the wall. That's three
attacks at disadvantage against Beau.
MARISHA: And they all have disadvantage.
MATT: They do.
MARISHA: Because I did Patient Defense?
SAM: You're going to be fine.
MATT: First one with a longbow, that's a 15?
MARISHA: Miss.
MATT: Right. Misses. The first one, you watch as
it just moves past you and slams into the door.
The next one, from this guy up here--
MARISHA: I immediately go: whoops.
MATT: That's a 12 and a two. The other one misses
into the wall. This one over here is going to fire
at you. That's a 16 and a 14, plus three, 17.
MARISHA: 17 is my armor class.
MATT: The first two: one hits the door; the other
one, you duck out of the way; and the third one
comes and it's piercing right towards your chest.
It's going to deal 2d8, seven points of piercing damage.
MARISHA: Okay. I'm going to use Deflect Missiles
for my reaction.
MATT: Oh, right! Because you got that for your--
Okay. As a reaction, you watch this one arrow that
you can't quite duck out of the way--
MARISHA: (grunting exertions)
MATT: All right. So go ahead and make the roll.
MARISHA: But it's not super-- I'm still level
three, so it's more like a cat swat.
MATT: Yeah, you're trying to swat it and see if
you can carry the momentum with it.
LAURA: 20!
MARISHA: That is seven on the dice, plus seven,
14.
MATT: You reduce the damage to zero and you catch
it.
SAM: Whoa.
MATT: If you want to, you can spend a ki point to
throw it, if you want to.
TRAVIS: Oh! Throw that shit!
MARISHA: Yeah, let's do it! Just because I can!
MATT: All right, where are you throwing it to?
TRAVIS: In the foot.
LIAM: At the bitch who attacked you.
SAM: Or the guy in front of you.
MARISHA: I'm going to do it at the guy in front of
me, who's right behind me.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: So I'm going to catch it, and I'm going
to spin around in a full flourish, and I'm going
to just throw it like a Gambit card with the
momentum that it's got.
MATT: All right, so as you grab it, you spin
around and throw it. Go ahead and make the attack roll.
MARISHA: What's the attack roll?
MATT: It should be your--
MARISHA: What is it? I've never done this before!
MATT: I know. This is new.
MARISHA: It's brand new!
MATT: Here we go. You just make a ranged attack
with it, so roll a d20, add your dexterity modifier
and your proficiency modifier, so same as any of
your other attacks, because it counts as a monk weapon.
MARISHA: Okay, 16.
MATT: 16 hits. It takes 1d8, so roll 1d8, plus
two.
MARISHA: Four. Four damage total.
MATT: All right. I wonder, does it add your damage
bonus to it, or the original weapon, because it is
your strength throwing it back. Pardon me, folks,
while we're figuring out new abilities they can use.
MARISHA: You make the attack with proficiency and
the missile counts as a monk weapon for the attack.
MATT: It is your attack, so you get to add your
dex bonus.
MARISHA: So six total.
MATT: All right, so six points of damage. You
watch as the arrow just sinks into the chest of
its thick hide armor. (snarling)
MARISHA: I go: Hah! Ooh.
MATT: The other ones that are throwing stuff onto
the cart hear this commotion and turn around and
look at you. Three of them continue just throwing
stuff onto the cart faster, while the one that's
immediately in front of you spins around and
stands tall. You can see it looking down at you a full
foot and a half, almost two feet taller than you.
(snarling) It's going to go ahead and grabs a
spear off the side of the wall that it had leaning
against and it's going to try to thrust it at you.
It still has disadvantage on the attack, though,
because you're in your stance. That's 16.
MARISHA: Miss.
MATT: This one, as it goes and thrusts with the
spear, coming off of the adrenaline of the
deflected missile, you duck low, and then kick the
spear up, which slams into the top of the door frame
and completely misses you. He's now stepping into
the door frame, completely filling it as you're
backing up into your space, and the two of you are
in this very intense, small, occupied block.
MARISHA: And I go: no, seriously dude, did you see
that?!
TRAVIS: My legs are jumping around like crazy
right now.
MATT: These guys are going to begin pushing the
cart and it's going to move at half their movement
to there. This one here is going to move up to
here, right around the side of this wall, and it's
going to take its longbow and fire at you,
because you're the one they can see.
MARISHA: That's fair.
MATT: Disadvantage. That is a 15.
MARISHA: Miss.
MATT: This one, actually, you see over at the
fire, and you grab the front of the armor of the
gnoll and pull his in front of you, and it actually
hits the back of his armor, splintering it, and
the smell hits you.
MARISHA: I just go, excuse me for a second. Thank
you.
MATT: As you let him go, there's this thick, oily,
horrible liquid that's matted in the fur, and the
touch of it's nasty. The smell itself is very
acrid of rotting flesh and mangy fur. That's going
to end all those guys there, they're pushing
there. All right, that ends the gnolls' turn.
Fjord, you're up.
TRAVIS: Yeah, okay. With my 30 feet of movement,
can I wrap around the far side of the house and
just get to cover of the corner?
MATT: That's exactly where you can get.
TRAVIS: Now there is an individual over there that
sucks, right?
MATT: Correct. You see it has a longbow and is
currently reaching back and it's pulling another
arrow and getting it notched up.
TRAVIS: I beg for forgiveness, I'm going to try
some shit. I would like to cast--
MARISHA: We're all trying some shit, it's okay.
TRAVIS: Crown of Madness.
(cheering)
MATT: All righty, so what's the save on that one?
TRAVIS: It is wisdom saving throw, I believe, let
me double-check. Yeah, wisdom saving throw.
MATT: No, that's an eight. I'm pretty sure that
does not hit.
TRAVIS: So he becomes charmed, and a jagged crown
of iron appears around his head, and madness glows
in its eye.
MATT: That's concentration, correct?
TRAVIS: Yes, it is.
MATT: I'm putting a concentration circle on you.
All righty, the charmed target must use its action
before moving each of its turns to make a melee
attack against a creature other than itself you
mentally choose. So it has to be a melee attack.
TRAVIS: Oh, melee. Fucking shit, I saw the bows.
Damn the words in this book!
MATT: That's okay.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: But I can make him move towards something,
right?
MATT: That you can.
TRAVIS: Okay, good. I'm going to have him climb up
on that roof and attack that other fucking gnoll
that's up on that son of a bitch.
MATT: Okay. Since it has to use its action before
its movement, you watch as it looks up at the top
of the roof, (snarling) and leaps up, climbs,
scampers up to the side, and gets right up into
base to base with this guy, confusing the other
gnoll, who looks down at it, like it's about to
help him, and it doesn't seem to notice there's
any sort of threat there, but it can't make an
attack on this round.
TRAVIS: That's fair. Can I use my bonus action to
use my Mask of Many Faces to make myself look like
a gnoll? No, they're taller. They're too tall.
MATT: Well, they're medium, they're not--
TRAVIS: Two feet taller, I can only do a foot
taller or shorter.
MATT: It's cutting it close, you'd look like a
small gnoll.
TRAVIS: I'd like to do it.
LAURA: A teeny gnoll.
MARISHA: He's the runt.
MATT: You are visible to a number of gnolls in
this courtyard. You don't have any movement to
back away from that edge, unfortunately.
TRAVIS: I was hoping to just be-- Because I can't
see that far-- to be right here to hit the only
guy that could see me on the ground there.
MATT: Right, but you're right on the corner,
that's how you were able to see him and send him
this way.
TRAVIS: The guy on the roof can see me as well?
MATT: Yeah, they can both see you. Just so you
know. The rest of them probably can't, but you
transform yourself into a gnoll-like appearance.
All right. Does that end your turn?
TRAVIS: That is it.
MATT: All righty. In the back of the alleyway, one
of the gnolls stands thicker, more angry, and more
ornate than the rest of the pack. You see heavy
scale mail armor across the torso, and a large
helmet across its head. You look as thick spines
about a foot and a half to two feet long are woven
into the scales themselves off the shoulders, the
back of the helmet, and the sides of the armor.
They look natural, as opposed to metal, like long,
bony spines that are put onto it, both as an
ornate adornment, or possibly just a means of
defense and to look scary. It begins barking and
steps forward, giving motions to some of the other
gnolls, and the ones that are on the cart continue
pushing it, as it steps forward--
LAURA: Oh no.
MATT: To there.
TRAVIS: I should have used it on that fucker.
MATT: It's going to go ahead and use--
SAM: Is that a crownsguard?
LAURA: No, he's like a Grandmaster gnoll.
SAM: No, the guy next to him.
LAURA: Oh. I feel like that's a zombie gnoll.
MATT: It's going to use Incite Rampage.
SAM: Oof, what does that mean?
MATT: It looks over towards the one that's right
next to Beau and goes, (snarling). The one that's
in the middle of the area with you hears that,
grins, and then gets an extra attack against you,
with disadvantage. And a four. That defense is
helping you out. It goes to strike again, and as
it comes out with its claw, it's putting its spear
to the side.
MARISHA: I do a little duck.
MATT: It misses you entirely. That's going to end
its turn at the moment. Then it goes to the guards
on this end. These guards are going to fan out.
TRAVIS: (raspy voice) Hey, come on, let's go.
MATT: Then they dart back around this way. They're
going to find a corner next to you, Jester, and
take a shot at the gnoll that's up on the roof,
next to the one that you have charmed. Shit,
that's going to miss. Five plus five. He fires and
it goes wide, you see it vanish into the rising
cloud of embers and flame. That's going to end the
guards' turn. They're getting around and preparing
for the next round to shoot a volley.
LAURA: I pat him on the shoulder and say: don't
worry, nobody saw that.
MATT: They glance over their shoulder and is like,
"Shh!" Molly, you're up.
TALIESIN: I'm going to take a run. Am I going to
do this? Am I going to be this idiot? Yeah, let's
be an idiot. I'm going to take a run to try to get
cover at the other house. I'm going to try to run
across the alleyway.
MATT: This way?
TALIESIN: Yeah.
LAURA: Dashy-dash?
TALIESIN: Dashy-dash.
MATT: (counting) It will put you at about there.
TALIESIN: Yeah.
MATT: But that's your round.
TALIESIN: That's my round. I just (zooming).
MATT: Cool. All righty. That ends Molly's turn.
Jester, you're up.
LAURA: Okie dokie. I'm going to send my duplicate
out against the wall on this house.
MATT: Over here?
LAURA: Yeah. Against that wall. She can go up to
30 feet. And I'm going to run across--
MATT: That space?
LAURA: Yeah, can I get against the wall further
in? Yeah, right there, that's good.
MATT: Okay. That's your turn? You still have an
action.
LAURA: Oh yeah, I'm going to use my bonus
action--
MATT: You currently cannot see anything for it to
attack. You need to be able to see a target for it
to attack something. So you'd have to be either
further out. You can do it as part of your
movement, as you run across, make it move and
attack, and then continue back--
LAURA: As I'm running, can I use my spiritual
weapon and--
MATT: Can you move it 20 feet?
LAURA: I think it's 30 feet. Let's see. 20 feet.
You're right, I'm sorry. 20 feet.
MATT: Which direction?
LAURA: Towards the giant guy and hit him!
MATT: Make a roll.
LAURA: Hit him with the rock! 15.
MATT: 15 unfortunately does not hit.
LAURA: Boo!
MATT: It just misses, you watch as the shield
comes up and deflects the large glowing mace of a
lollipop. Then you continue the rest of your
movement to dart behind the building. At this
point, you've all pretty much shown your cards
that you're here and part of this fight. You're
the only one who's up in the air.
LAURA: For my action, can I still see my duplicate
around the corner right there?
MATT: Correct.
LAURA: She is going to cast--
MATT: Well, you would be able to as you're
running.
LAURA: Okay. She is going to use the cantrip
Sacred Flame!
MATT: Against?
LAURA: Against the same big guy!
MATT: These would be things you would have done before you
ran across.
LAURA: Yes, basically yes, that's what I did.
Technically I did this before I moved.
MATT: Just letting you know that usually you have
to do that as part of your movement. Dexterity
saving throw. That is a 12.
LAURA: Good! He has to beat 13! It hits him!
MATT: It takes 1d8 points of radiant damage.
LAURA: Yes it does! Four.
MATT: After the shield deflects the lollipop, the
flash of radiant energy burns across the armor and
the torso. Instinctively it puts up the shield to
try and deflect the blow from the eyes.
(screeches) Looks out and doesn't see where it
came from, but it's singed a little. That ends
Jester's turn, Caleb and Nott, you're up.
LIAM: Yeah okay, I will move along the table over
here to this spot.
LAURA: Well, that's one method to be able to
reach.
LIAM: I think I have a clear view of the big gnoll,
correct? From there?
MATT: The big one? You do.
LIAM: I mutter a few arcane words under my breath
and a circle of flame spins around my hand and
three beams of fire shoot out towards this big
guy. I cast Scorching Ray. Each one is a separate
attack. First one is a 16.
MATT: 16 hits.
LIAM: Second one is also a 16, the third one is a
17.
MATT: All three hit.
LIAM: So 6d6 on him.
SAM: 6d6?
LIAM: Because they all hit. That's four, six--
TRAVIS: What dice are you rolling there, big guy?
LIAM: Nine. That's the six?
TRAVIS: No, your d20, which one was it?
LIAM: This one.
LAURA: That's the Grog one.
LIAM: Oh, thank you. (counting) That's a total of
19 fire damage on him.
MATT: 19 points of fire damage. As the three beams
arc out and blast, you see as the large gnoll, who
seems to be a pack lord or leader of some kind,
sees this coming. Tries to put the shield up, but
all three blast into its armor. You watch as
flames burn out of it suddenly. As it withdraws
and takes a step back-- (grows and howls) It just
looks angry. It looks hurt a little bit, but
mostly angry.
LIAM: I probably have ten feet of movement which I
would like to use to move back to where I was and
try to not hyperventilate against the back of this
building.
MATT: Okay.
LIAM: Dead center. Yeah. Okay. Good.
MATT: Good to know.
LAURA: I like that you're facing the wall so it
looks like--
LIAM: No, I'm like this. I'm doing this.
MATT: Nott, you're up.
SAM: Nott's going to poke her head into the window
where Beau is inside. Beau is within a few feet of
a baddie, right? I'm going to shoot the baddie
next to Beau. 15.
MATT: 15, that doesn't-- oh wait, for a regular
gnoll that just hits, barely.
ALL: Regular gnoll!
(laughter)
TRAVIS: That's all I heard!
SAM: Nine points, that's including sneak attack
damage. Plus fury of the small, so 11 points of damage.
MATT: Well, it's your level, right? You went up a
level so technically--
SAM: Ten points of-- wait, what did I say? Nine?
12! Thank you.
MATT: 12 points of damage. As this gnoll is in the
process of slamming through the front doorway, the
doorway has been bashed inward on each side and
Beau is in the process of dodging and weaving and
getting out of the way. You find one opening and
fire your crossbow bolt. It goes through the
window, through the doorway bisecting the two
different rooms and straight under the clavicle
near the heart section of it. As it pierces in,
(screams) and it coughs up a bunch of blood onto
the front of its hide armor. It's not dead, but
it's pretty hurt. That was a pretty nasty blow.
SAM: Movement, I will use to climb up into the
second floor window. That's not me. The one next
to your right. There you go.
MATT: Go ahead and make an athletics check.
SAM: That was good, but it's disadvantage. That's
better. Athletics. It's a straight ten.
MATT: Ten is exactly what you needed. That was the
DC to get up onto the second floor. As you come up
into the second floor, you immediately climb and
leap up through the window into a chamber that is
filled with roaring flame.
SAM: (screams)
MATT: Trying to avert your gaze, the heat is
pressing into you. There's a table that's on fire,
most of the roof has been burned away. There's
beams that have fallen. You're like, "This was a
"bad idea!"
SAM: I say: This is fine!
(laughter)
SAM: Can I use my dash? Was that all my movement?
MATT: No, that was your movement to get up there
and you could use your bonus action if you'd like to.
SAM: Okay, I'll use a bonus action to get-- Is
towards the window less fiery?
MATT: It's still burning, but you're going to have
to leap over the flames to get there.
SAM: Sure.
MATT: I'll say make an acrobatics check to try and
leap over parts of broken--
SAM: It was two threes.
MATT: You make it across. You leap onto the first
beam and it breaks. You're like "Ah, that burns!"
You leap again onto the next one, "Ah, that burns
too!" Eventually, you get over there. Your boots
are on fire, and you're having to pat them out
real fast. You suffer five points of fire damage
getting across the room.
SAM: Rough.
MATT: But you are in an area where it seems it's
just embers, and most of the flame is catching
behind you for the moment. You get the sense that
it might begin to spread in the next minute or so,
but at this point, you're not immediately in the
threat of flame and you have a look down into the
entirety of the courtyard with a little bit of
cover. In fact, it would be considered half cover
up in here.
SAM: Half cover. I'm done. Hey, look at that, it's
me in the window.
MATT: At which point, you can see the skeletal
gnolls that are out there all at once turn and
begin shambling forward. There's one this way that
begins to run up and take a swing at your
duplicitous form, before striking out with no
effect. This one spins and comes up into Beau and
then there's one that emerges from--
LAURA: I'm going to point out I've been doing
it wrong because I was thinking of my duplicate as
like Trinket was, which had movement the same as
me, and it is a bonus action to move my duplicate,
which I did not realize. I'm going to stop doing
that.
MATT: That's okay, we learn what the new abilities
do.
LAURA: Yeah, I just looked it up and I'm sorry.
MATT: That's all good.
SAM: So your duplicate is somehow less useful than
Trinket? Is that what you're saying?
(laughter)
LIAM: She doesn't give a shit about that bear.
MATT: Out of the doorway here, another one of them
bursts through and runs to the back and sees the
direction where Jester is in the process of
glancing over to the side.
LAURA: Oh! That's real me!
MATT: It uses its action to charge up into combat
with you. It can't actually make an attack this
turn, but it's right up to you. Its gaping,
vacuous skull, open sockets, trying to bear down
on you. That's going to end their go, except for
the one that's striking at you, Beau.
TALIESIN: There's one on the roof still, too.
MATT: Well, that's not one of the skeletal ones.
That's going to be, with disadvantage, 17 to hit.
MARISHA: 17 hits.
MATT: 17 hit. It bites out towards you with its
broken toothy jaws and you suffer six points of
piercing damage as the jaws clamp down on your
forearm and you're like "Oh god!" It's pushing now
to try to find the space next to the larger gnoll
and they're both currently blocking the doorway
from your escape.
MARISHA: I'm doing the animal control thing and be
like: No, no, bad.
MATT: Which, by the way, top of the round. Beau,
your go.
MARISHA: My go, okay. Let me put these hit points
in. Apply changes.
LAURA: This makes my duplicate way less fun if I
can't move her.
TALIESIN: You get bonus actions all the time.
LAURA: That's my spiritual weapon.
SAM: She may move if you move away from her 30
feet; she may just come with you.
LAURA: 120 feet.
SAM: Oh shit. But you can leave her out in the
open.
LAURA: Yeah, at least she's directing fire.
MARISHA: Okay, I'm going to do something creative.
I'm going to take the arrow that Nott just fired
into the guy's chest. I'm going to grab it. Can I
rip it out with my off-hand, spin around, and stab
him back in the blade?
MATT: Awesome, go ahead and roll for your main
attack.
MARISHA: God blessed fuck. That's not good. That's
a ten.
MATT: You pull it out. There's a horrible pained
yelp as you yank it out. As you spin around and
attempt to slam it into its back, its giant, thick
gnoll arm slams into the door frame and blocks
your ability to pass forward. You get caught over
its arm and have to withdraw.
MARISHA: Okay, I'm going to take my other off-hand
attack on the one that just bit down on me. I'm
going to rip from it and elbow crack it right in
the nose.
MATT: The one that just bit you? All right, go for
it.
MARISHA: Damn it. That's 11.
MATT: 11? 11 doesn't hit unfortunately. Lot of
whiffing on both sides when it comes around Beau,
but as you attempt to strike out with the elbow,
it does strike its skull, and its jaw unhinges and
snaps it back into place.
MARISHA: Shit, that was my bonus action, wasn't
it?
MATT: Yep.
MARISHA: I can't use a ki point, can I?
MATT: As a bonus action, you can use a ki point to
do two as your bonus if you have it. Flurry of Blows.
MARISHA: I was wanting to do a ki point to do
Patient Defense again.
MATT: No, you used your bonus action, sorry. You
want to move or you want to stay where you are?
MARISHA: Yeah, can I back up into the house and
close the door?
MATT: The door frame is pretty banged up, you can
try. You can certainly try.
MARISHA: Sure!
MATT: Taking a step back, one has spears, so
you're still in its melee range as you try and
close the door. They'll both get attacks of
opportunity on you if you do that.
MARISHA: No, I'll stay.
MATT: Okay, so you stay there holding your
position. That ends Beau's turn. The gnolls go.
Before we do anything, the one that's right next
to the guy on the wall, what do you want it to do?
TRAVIS: Melee, so if he has a weapon or anything,
hit him. If not, just knock him the fuck off the roof.
MATT: He has a spear or you can make a shove, up
to you.
TRAVIS: Spear!
MATT: All right, so the spear attack, it's going
to, as it climbs to the top and lunges out with
its arm. Go ahead and make an attack roll for me.
TRAVIS: Oh, okay. Plus anything?
MATT: It is plus five.
TRAVIS: That's a 20.
MATT: Sorry, plus four.
TRAVIS: That's a 19.
MATT: 19 definitely hits. Go ahead and roll 1d6
damage plus two. Two hands technically, so that
would be 1d8. Sorry.
TRAVIS: Yeah, that's much better. Nine.
MATT: Nine. Nein! It jams the spear with both hands into
its friend and the gnoll yelps and grabs it and
pulls it out and looks at it confused and angry.
Trying to figure out what exactly happened. As it
does so, it's going to attempt to shove it off the
wall that just hit it. Make a roll for the
athletics check of the other gnoll.
TRAVIS: Adding my modifier or its?
MATT: Its modifier.
TRAVIS: 16 plus?
MATT: 16 plus two. It beat it. It rolled a 17.
After it gets stabbed and looks back at the gnoll
that you took control and Sparta-kicks it off of
the edge of the roof. It slides and tumbles down,
landing onto the ground prone right next to Molly.
It does suffer one point of falling damage. Molly,
you watch as it tumbles and hits the dirt next to
you and it's like (groans). You watch as this
mystical crown of weird iron horns are floating
above its head.
TALIESIN: Is this--?
MATT: That takes up his turn. This guy's going to
move forward and advance. This is unfortunate for
Beau, partially. This one is going to fire at
Beau. This one actually can see Nott and this one
is going to take a shot at Nott as well. So one
attack against you, Beau, from that gnoll there.
That's going to be 11, misses. It actually hits
the wall and embeds itself into the side of the
door frame. The two attacking you, Nott-- You do
have partial cover on these guys. Half cover will
be plus two bonus to AC. The first one is going to be a
20.
SAM: Hits.
MATT: The second one is a natural two. The one
that does hit you, you suffer nine points of
piercing damage. A lot of nines tonight! As the
arrow suddenly arcs upward and hits you right in
the side of the jaw and carves through part of
your neck that way before it exits out the other
side. You have this big gash on the side. It
doesn't quite hit the jugular, thankfully, but it
is pretty messy as you are starting to bleed down
the side of your neck.
LAURA: Isn't she harder to hit because she's so
little?
MATT: Yeah, but that one had some decent aim.
These guys here continue to push forward that way
and they're going to use their other action to
push forward. This guy is going to go ahead and
throw another body up onto this as the other one's
pushing it. They don't get quite as far because
one of them stopped pushing, but they're getting
to the edge of the map. The one that's snarling
there is watching them vanish behind. This guy
around the edge is going to, let's see. Seeing you
yelp up in the window, he's going to take a shot
at you. Beau's currently being dealt with two of
them and you're up in the flames right now. That
is going to be a 15, which I do not believe hits.
SAM: No.
MATT: This one strikes the ember wood on the
outside and breaks through, but it only comes
partially out and is embedded, missing you by an
inch. That finishes the gnolls' turn, I believe.
Oh, this guy is going to turn and take a swing at
Beau with a spear, two hands. That is a 16.
MARISHA: Miss.
MATT: 16 misses. It swings out and you actually
catch the spear off to the side and you're now in
a strength tug of war with its own weapon as
it's--
MARISHA: My stick! Mine! Drop it! Bad! Do you want
to play or not?
MATT: Ending their go, it goes to Fjord's turn.
TRAVIS: Crown of Madness piece of shit. Can I go
ahead and send, using my action to maintain it,
can I send that stupid ass back up the roof?
MATT: Let me double-check something.
TALIESIN: The damage may have--
TRAVIS: Knocked it out. No!
MATT: I don't know if that's the case. It's not
just that. It already moved on its turn, it takes
its turn, you have to spend your action to maintain
the spell, so it won't do anything on your turn.
So either you continue to maintain the spell, and
then next turn it's still under your control, or
you do whatever you want--
LAURA: Or you drop it because he's prone and Molly
will get super advantage on hitting him.
SAM: Super advantage!
TALIESIN: Yeah, I don't know what the crown is.
TRAVIS: Fuck it, I'll drop it and I'll come into
the street, down the way 30 feet. But I look like
a gnoll.
TALIESIN: Concentration's gone.
MATT: Oh, that's right. Thank you.
TRAVIS: But I still look like a gnoll.
MATT: Yes, you do.
TRAVIS: That will be my turn.
MATT: All righty, are you holding your action to
do anything?
TRAVIS: I guess, because I dropped it, I have it.
MATT: You have your action because you didn't
maintain the spell.
TRAVIS: With my action, I'm going to cast
Hexblade's Curse on that big son of a bitch.
MATT: This guy?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: I believe it's a bonus action to do that,
isn't it?
TRAVIS: It is.
MATT: So you still have your action.
TALIESIN: You could even make it to get into his
face.
TRAVIS: With my action, I will Eldritch Blast from
where I am.
MATT: Go for it, make the attack roll.
TRAVIS: Thank you. Skadoosh. It's a 15 plus six,
21.
MATT: That hits, go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: Amazing, 1d10. (counting) Sorry, I
should've looked at this beforehand. 14.
MATT: 14 points of damage. As you rush up, you
watch as this squatter gnoll saunters out in the
middle, points to the seeming leader of this
cluster, and as it does, the soot and ash from the
ground begins to affix itself around the inside of
its armor, holding it in place for the moment.
With the other hand holding the suddenly
appearing barnacle-studded blade, you unleash
this blast of eldritch energy that slams into the
center of the armor. You watch as the energy
courses through all of the crevices between the
scales that are overlapping. As it fades, you
watch as this bit of steam and blood come out of
its mouth, and it turns right to you, its head
turning, it spits a cluster.
TRAVIS: (yipping)
MATT: We'll get to that. That's your turn?
TRAVIS: That's it.
MATT: Okay, it's his turn now. Now it-- (shrieks
and growls)
(laughter)
MATT: And goes running and rushes up towards you.
You watch as previously it just had this large
pole on its back? It pulls it and brings it loose
as you see a large two-handed glaive come swooping,
which doesn't actually-- it can get to there and
still hit you because of its reach. As it runs
forward, it brings it down. It's going to
multi-attack you twice with it.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: First one is going to be a 21 to hit?
TRAVIS: Oh, that'll hit.
MATT: And a 17 to hit.
TRAVIS: Both hit.
MATT: Both hit. All right.
TRAVIS: That's okay, I've got the armor. It deals
damage when you hit me.
LIAM and LAURA: Ooh.
MATT: That is eight points of slashing damage on
the first hit. Wham! As the large polearm-- the
axe-like hooked blade at the end of it. You can
see the same spines that are on its armor are
affixed to the edge of it. As it slams down
towards you, the armor bursts, this cold energy
that-- how much damage does he take?
TRAVIS: I got ten temporary hit points at
second level, so he takes eight points of cold damage.
MATT: Slick. Second strike? He rolled a one. That
is going to be four points of slashing damage for
the second strike.
TRAVIS: So he'll take two points of cold damage
and I'll take the other two points.
MATT: Nice.
MARISHA: You have so many fun gadgets!
MATT: Oh! He does get back his Incite Rampage. At
which point, he's going to go ahead and glance
over towards the gnoll that is-- hmm.
SAM: The grassy gnoll?
MATT: The grassy gnoll, yes. Thank you, Sam.
TRAVIS: Thank you, Sam.
MATT: All right, yeah. The only one that they can
currently see that's in melee range at the moment,
because the wall's there, is going to be the one
next to Beau.
SAM: No, really. Thank you, Sam.
MATT: Sincerely. So after it strikes you twice
with the glaive, bits of ice shards spray off with
each blow now affixing to the ash and the energy
that's instilled this armor after you blasted it.
It looks over to the one right in front of Beau
and goes (growls and snarls) and it glances over
its shoulder, and with renewed strength, pulls the
spear free from your grasp and goes for another
strike against you as a reaction.
MARISHA: Bad dog.
MATT: That is going to be a 19 to hit.
MARISHA: How much?
MATT: 19.
MARISHA: That one hits.
SAM: How many are engaged with you right now?
MATT: Two.
MARISHA: Three? Two?
LAURA: She's so wanted.
MATT: That's going to be seven points of piercing
damage.
LIAM: Apologies to my friend.
MATT: All righty, that's going to end his turn and
the guards back here are going to come forward and--
TRAVIS: Oh, let's go this way!
MATT: They're both going to fire at the one on the
rooftop.
SAM, TRAVIS, and TALIESIN: Hey!
LAURA: (laughter) And a miss and a miss!
MATT: First one's a miss. Second one is a 16. That
hits.
SAM: Hey!
MATT: It's an eight plus two so that's ten points
of damage. Based on the Crown of Madness damage it
took earlier, the spear's enough to finish it
off. You watch as on the top, it goes and draws an
arrow and pulls it back, looking down at you as
you're down in the square. Then one of the guards
pulls its crossbow and (shrieks) it stumbles back
and falls dead on the ground.
TRAVIS: Here we go.
MATT: That ends that one, the other guard over
there. They're going to go ahead and move up the
side and step out now that it seems to be opening
and is going to fire towards the skeletal gnoll
that is currently in the process of harassing the
image that as far as they're concerned is just
Jester. It's going to be-- yeah, that hits.
Without issue.
TALIESIN: I'm not used to melee combat. This is so
terrifying.
LAURA: Yeah, right?
TRAVIS: Get up in that.
TALIESIN: I don't want to get up in that.
TRAVIS: Get a whole bunch of stank right in your
face.
MATT: Pulls out the heavy crossbow and fires and
does 11 points of damage, which is enough to
shatter the skeletal gnoll witherling. As it falls
to the ground and breaks into a scattered pile of
bone bits and dried gnoll flesh. That ends the
guards' turn. Molly, you're up.
TALIESIN: I'm going to stab this thing that just
fell right in front of me. Just going to stab it.
MATT: It is prone, so I believe you have advantage
against it. Yep! With each attack.
TALIESIN: Question about Rite of the Dawn, is it
just plus three or is it just my wisdom or is it
also a--?
MATT: Wisdom bonus is against undead creatures.
TALIESIN: Okay, this is not an undead creature.
MATT: It is not. There are undead creatures
among the pack, but there are none there. It's just
straight Rite damage.
TALIESIN: So it's just an extra 1d4. Okay,
just checking. That's how that works. Okay, cool.
See if I hit? Thank you. 13?
MATT: 13 unfortunately misses. The first strike--
TALIESIN: Oh my god.
MATT: As you swing down onto the ground, it
scrambles about and pulls its shield up just in
time. Your blade catches the edge, embeds itself
an inch into its rear.
TALIESIN: I hit it with the other one.
MATT: You use your one blade to push the shield
off to the side as it's still there, and trying to
jam downward. Go for it.
TRAVIS: Definitely hit.
TALIESIN: Come on. Oh, thank God. 21.
MATT: 21 hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: (chanting) Level three! Level three!
TALIESIN: So that's nine points of damage.
MATT: Nine points of damage. You manage to jam
underneath and hit it in the chest. It shrieks with pain
and pushes the blade out of its body with a sheer
flexing of its muscle. It begins to try and get up
off the ground. It's hurt, but it's still standing or about
to be standing in a moment. You can move if you'd
like to.
TALIESIN: Yeah, that's right. I can break combat
with it. It doesn't matter, right? At this point?
Or does it get an attack of opportunity?
MATT: It does get an attack of opportunity, but it
has disadvantage on him.
TALIESIN: There's no way I can circle up onto the
wall, is there?
MATT: Onto the wall?
TALIESIN: Yeah. Get a little vantage on him.
MATT: You could.
TALIESIN: I want to be able to hop on because I want to
head that direction afterwards. All right.
MATT: You get up onto the wall.
TALIESIN: And that way, if he tries to run or do
anything, I can futz with him.
MATT: Cool, that's fine. Molly, your turn is over.
Jester, you're up.
LAURA: Yay! I'm going to run away from this guy
that's next to me. I'm going to run out into the
alley so I can see people.
MATT: This way?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: As you rush out, it takes a swing attack of
opportunity towards you. This is going to be with
a club. It has a heavy wooden club and it makes a
giant arc towards you as you speed away. That is
19 to hit.
LAURA: Can I use a reaction on that?
MATT: You can, yeah.
LAURA: I'm going to say "I am rubber and you are
glue" and use Hellish Rebuke on him. In Infernal.
MATT: All right. Well, first, the club hits you
and you take five points of bludgeoning damage.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: As you turn around, you say that at him and
unleash your Hellish Rebuke. He has to make a
constitution saving throw, I believe it is,
right?
LAURA: Maybe. Hold on.
SAM: You have to save first.
LAURA: I'm applying my changes to my health.
SAM: Now close out of that.
LAURA: This is so much!
MATT: It has to make a constitution save-- No,
that's dexterity saving throw, which it does not
make. It's seven. So it suffers 2d10 cold damage. So how
much did you deal?
LAURA: Oh, 2d10. Okay. Nine.
ALL: Nine.
TALIESIN: This is becoming a thing.
LIAM: So sorry, guys. There you go.
MATT: As you dart away, you release your fury and
anger, and you watch as suddenly this blast of cold
water and ice energy burst out of its body. The
inside of its somewhat cavernous ribcage is now
filled with frost crystals, jutting out and
breaking parts of the ribs. It looks heavily
damaged, but still standing.
LAURA: Ooh, chilly!
MATT: All righty.
SAM: You still have your action, right?
LAURA: I know, and my bonus action!
MATT: Yeah.
LAURA: So for my bonus action, I'm going to send
my lollipop towards the giant guy and try to hit
him. At the same time, I'm going to cast-- What am
I going to cast? Radiant-- No, Guiding Bolt!
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: With, you know, I'm going to do a little
flourish, like pink energy comes out.
MATT: All right. Go ahead and make your spell attack.
LAURA: Okay. Spell attack? Ooh, that's good.
That's a 19 plus five.
MATT: That hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
LAURA: Okay.
TALIESIN: That's new dice, man.
LAURA: Yes, yes, yes.
SAM: I touched one.
LAURA: You didn't touch these ones.
SAM: That's why they rolled so shit.
LAURA: Six, eight, nine radiant.
ALL: Nine!
MATT: What's up with the nines? It's getting
ridiculous.
TRAVIS: CritRoleStats is going-- (clicking).
MATT: Yep.
LIAM: We're losing subscribers in Europe
right now.
LAURA: That's radiant damage, and then the
Spiritual Weapon--
MATT: All right. Guiding Bolt: the next attack
against it has advantage.
LAURA: Oh, good. Then the Spiritual Weapon will
have advantage. Great!
LIAM: Halt den Mund!
LAURA: Oh, good. So that's 20.
MATT: That hits. Go ahead and roll damage for Spiritual
Weapon.
TRAVIS: Nice!
LAURA: Where's my eight? Six plus three is nine!
ALL: Nine!
MATT: This is absurd, guys. This is absurd. All
righty, does that end your turn?
LAURA: Oh, I'm going to use the rest of my
movement to run over and try to get behind this wall.
MATT: You're from over there, that's (counting)
20, you have ten more feet. You can get there.
LAURA: That'll work. I was going to go to the
brick wall.
MATT: Oh, the brick wall. You'll get up onto it.
LAURA: Yeah, sure, why not?
MATT: It's considered rough terrain, so you
technically can't get all the way on the other
side. You climb up onto it. That finishes your
turn. As you finish blasting with the Guiding
Bolt, at the same time as it slams and sparkles
you watch as the lollipop clubs down onto the
back of its head. That ends your turn. Caleb,
Nott, you're up.
LIAM: Okay. I start moving back towards the same
vantage point I had before and I see Jester above
me, and I see a guy over there covered in ice, and
I whip around and the diamond comes up and I go
(sizzling) and I was about to make it acid, but
there's ice everywhere so it's ice now. Chromatic
Orb off to the big guy in the middle of town
square, yeah.
MATT: Go ahead and make the attack roll.
LIAM: It misses entirely.
MATT: It spins and hits the ground. You watch as
ice crawls up the side of the building. I will say
it does manage to put out part of the fire that is
currently burning the building.
MARISHA: You did a good thing here. You did good
today.
TALIESIN: You made lemonade. Way to make some
lemonade.
MARISHA: You just got the participation trophy.
LIAM: Then I use the rest of my movement to press
my back against the wall and go nein, nein, nein.
MATT: As you move out, where are you at now?
LIAM: Still behind the same building.
MATT: You dart out and fire, and then back. All
righty. That ends your turn. Nott!
SAM: Just a little perspective here. The gnolls
pushing away the cart, how many are there? And
what are they--?
MATT: There are currently three that are gathered
around it and in the process of pushing it.
They're getting momentum as it's going.
SAM: No obvious weak points on the cart or
anything?
MATT: Make a perception check. It will take your
bonus action to do so.
MARISHA: Take out a wheel!
SAM: It's going to take my bonus action to do so?
Then I will not look at the cart.
TALIESIN: It will move slower if we kill them.
SAM: I'm sure it will, but I don't know if I could
kill one in one shot. Instead I will, using my
goblin feet claws, just dig in and I'm going to go
upside down so I can see into where Beau is and
shoot one of the ones next to her.
LAURA: You can do that?!
SAM: I don't know!
MATT: As you dig in and hang down, you watch as
your hood and hair hangs upside down. You pull the
crossbow down. The tension of the bolt is holding
it in, thankfully, otherwise it would just fall
from its upside down standpoint, and you
fire! You can go ahead and make a strike.
Technically you have two that you're in view of
here, they both have three-quarters cover because
of the nearby door and the angle.
SAM: The ones next to her?
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: Ugh. Well, I got to hit them.
MATT: Which one are you shooting? The skeletal one
or the--?
SAM: The one that I hit before.
MATT: Okay, so that one. Go for it.
SAM: That is 17.
MARISHA: I think that hits, right?
MATT: 17 would hit if it didn't have
three-quarters cover, which gives a plus five bonus
to AC.
MARISHA: Oh, poopers!
MATT: Unfortunately, it's just the large part of
the door frame in the way, there's Beau in the
way, and there's a lot going on in that moment. As
you go and fire it just zips past and slams into
part of the now broken door that's coming off the
hinges.
TALIESIN: Man, I hate level three.
SAM: Cool. I'm going to go pop back up to the top
floor, and use my bonus action to hide.
MATT: All righty. Go ahead and make a stealth
check.
SAM: Nope. Ten.
MATT: You get down low, but your hood and hair are
now frizzed and poking out the side. That ends
your turn, Nott. This one is going to rush
forward, pursuing Jester. That one is going to
attempt to continue to whale on Beau. That's going
to be a 15 against Beau.
MARISHA: Miss.
MATT: Misses, you just duck out of the way as it
tries to bite you and slam your elbow onto its
snout, knocking it out of the way. Just holding
on, holding off in this doorway. The one that runs
up towards you is going to attempt to hit you
again with a club. That is going to be a 19. Again.
LAURA: Ugh!
MATT: Oh that's a d4, sorry. That's six points of
bludgeoning damage. Whack! As the club hits you in
the back of the head as you're just climbing over
the top of the wall. You have to catch yourself
from tumbling face first into the dirt on the
other side. You manage to catch your footing on
top of the wall. But it's now up, and in
combat with both you and the guard from earlier.
That ends their turn. Top of the round, Beau,
you're up.
MARISHA: Oh god, okay. I'm going to taste a little
bit of blood that's now in my mouth, get real
fucking pissed off, and I'm going to do a Star
Wars-style flourish and go crack down to the new guy.
MATT: The skeletal one? There's a skeletal one,
and there's the one that's been fighting you this
whole time.
MARISHA: Which one looks like he has less damage?
MATT: The skeletal one hasn't been damaged yet,
but it looks a little more fragile. The one that
got shot by Nott earlier still has the big--
MARISHA: Let's do the skeletal guy.
MATT: Go for it. Do the attack.
MARISHA: Not good at all. 14.
MATT: That hits. Doesn't have as strong an armor class
as the other one.
MARISHA: Okay. Eight points of damage.
MATT: Eight points of damage. That one's already
been damaged previously. As you bring the staff
down with both hands, whack, you slam right
through the center of its chest and clavicle. You
watch as the torso breaks and folds from the
weight of the blow. The skull tumbles off and hits
the ground, and it falls into a pile of bones and
rags.
MARISHA: I'm going to use my bonus action. With
that momentum, I'm going to stick the staff in the
ground, and use that to lift myself up and do a
two-footer kick into the other guy.
MATT: Go for it. Single attack?
MARISHA: Let's do Flurry of Blows.
MATT: All right, so this is your third ki point?
MARISHA: Nope, this is my second.
MATT: Right, because you did the-- No, because you
did flurry earlier, didn't you?
MARISHA: I did, but I did it as an action, not on
a bonus action, and you said I didn't have to use
a ki point.
MATT: No, a Flurry of Blows, I thought.
MARISHA: I did Patient Defense, I did one Flurry
of Blows--
MATT: You did the dodge action, as an action,
which doesn't take any ki points. You spent one
doing a Flurry of Blows earlier.
MARISHA: I spent one doing deflect, and then one
to do Flurry of Blows.
MATT: This is your third one.
MARISHA: No. This is the second one. This is the
first Flurry of Blows I'm doing.
MATT: I'm sorry, that's what I was asking, my
confusion. Cool, so go for it.
MARISHA: Shit, I don't remember. This was what I
rolled, right? Okay, not good. Ten.
MATT: Ten against him? Nope. As you kick both feet
forward, one hits and skims off the shoulder. The other?
MARISHA: The other is okay. 15.
MATT: 15 just hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: (singing) Pour some sugar on him.
MARISHA: Seven.
MATT: Seven points of damage? All righty, based on
the damage that you had sustained earlier and the
blows from earlier, as you strike him with the
other foot, you snap the side of his jaw, which
breaks out. As he stumbles backward, you take the
back of the staff and crack up underneath the jaw,
snapping the neck the rest of the way, and it
falls to the ground, no longer moving. You still
have your movement.
MARISHA: Now I'm going to look around, and I'm
going to step back and into the house for just a minute.
SAM: Into the house?
TALIESIN: This is fine.
MARISHA: This is fine. Just so I have cover. Right
in the doorway.
TRAVIS: Just going to take a quick timeout.
MARISHA: Quick timeout.
SAM: There's a really loud ticking clock in the
room with you.
MARISHA: You hear a (faint scream) in the
distance.
MATT: With that, this gnoll is going to stand up.
Molly's on the wall.
TALIESIN: I know, I'm being an asshole.
MATT: It's okay. Stands up.
TALIESIN: Man, I'm normally the one with shaky
hands.
MATT: That's more because these walls are not the
most sturdy. There you go. Stands up to you. This
one is going to step forward into the way. This
one is going to join in there. Those three now in
visual range. These two are both going to take
shots at Jester. This one's going to take a shot
at Fjord. Two longbows aiming in your direction.
That's a 20 and a natural one. The second one
misses. You suffer eight points of piercing damage
as the arrow sinks right into your torso, right in
the stomach area, and pierces through. You catch
it with your hand, but it's still a few inches
into your actual midsection. Then there's the one
over here that turned around and sees you now
engaging with the current pack leader.
TRAVIS: But I'm a gnoll! Ah!
MATT: That's a 15.
TRAVIS: I'm just confused, that hits.
MATT: That's going to be six points of piercing
damage. This one now slams into the side of your
knee, and hits the meaty part, so thankfully it's
not locked in the bone or any of the joint, but it
hits you in the side and you buckle to that side
from the pain.
TRAVIS: Understood.
MATT: This guy over here is going to leap down and
begin helping push the cart.
ALL: No!
MATT: With that, the cart pushes another full 40
feet and is currently off of the board. Let me
mark it over here.
MARISHA: How do we feel about the cart?
LAURA: We got to get the cart!
SAM: I can take a shot at the cart, but what is
one arrow going to do?
TALIESIN: We can take out people pushing it.
MATT: That finishes the gnolls' turn there. Oh,
there's the one that's attacking Molly. It's going
to take its spear and attempt to two-hand strike
at you. That is cocked.
TALIESIN: Does he have a spear? I thought he had a
bow. Oh, he's got both.
MATT: 13 to hit, which I don't think hits.
TALIESIN: No, it does not hit.
MATT: You, on the wall, dance off the way, leap as
it goes up. All right, and I believe that's all
the gnolls immediately in the vicinity that are in
combat. That ends the gnolls' turn. Fjord, you're up.
TRAVIS: Yeah, great, awesome, sweet. Can I use
Eldritch Blast against the big fucking guy,
because he didn't get any closer for a melee
attack, right?
MATT: You're still within his attack range,
because he has the glaive. You do have
disadvantage on Eldritch Blast.
TRAVIS: Oh. Imma fucking move out of his attack
range. Does that give him attack of opportunity?
ALL: Yes.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'm doing that anyway. I'm going to
move back towards the corner where I was going.
MATT: Right there?
TRAVIS: No, all the way back. Back towards my
original hiding place.
MATT: You pull back to the corner there. As you
pull back, he takes a step forward and reaches out
with the glaive to try and strike you.
SAM: Does he have any disadvantage or anything?
MATT: Nope. That is a 23 to hit.
TRAVIS: That hits.
MATT: That is going to be ten points of slashing
damage. As you back away, arcs downward.
TRAVIS: I will now, out of his melee range,
Eldritch Blast. Ugh, God, that's not great. 13.
MATT: 13 does not hit. Now that it's seen the
Blast, after it strikes and grins you hear this
(hyena chuckle) under its breath. You turn around
and go to strike out with the Eldritch Blast, and
it pulls one of the other gnolls nearby and yanks
it in front of him, just as the shield takes it
off, then sets him back in place. Deflects it with
its own guy.
TRAVIS: Nice. As I'm pulling around the corner,
can I use my bonus action to drop the stupid,
runty gnoll look?
MATT: You don't have to spend a bonus action, you
just drop it. Pulling back from the fire, yeah,
you can get just around that corner. The guard
lets you by.
TRAVIS: I need cover.
MATT: That ends your turn. The leader at this
point makes this loud gibbering sound that echoes
throughout the alley, turns, and runs off to
pursue the cart.
SAM: He left!
TRAVIS: We're at level three, that's got to be an
acceptable option right now.
SAM: No!
LAURA: That means we almost killed him, that's
what that means! We almost had him.
MARISHA: Do we chase after him?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: That ends his turn. The guards now, who have
notched their crossbows again, are going to take
shots at both of those guys right there. Fucking
two. That does hit. The other one gets hit.
LAURA: Have we killed any of the gnolls-gnolls?
TRAVIS: Yeah, it's simple numbers. Them leaving is
a good--
MATT: Molly, you're up.
TALIESIN: I'm taking a slice at this guy again. I
don't have advantage anymore.
MATT: You do not. He is not prone anymore,
unfortunately.
TALIESIN: Slice number one. Oh, for fuck's sake.
Ten.
MATT: Ten does not hit, unfortunately.
TALIESIN: Slice number two. That hits, thank you!
23.
MATT: 23 will hit. Go ahead and roll damage.
TALIESIN: That's five points of damage and two
points of extra damage.
MATT: Radiant? All right. The first one, you swing
and it ducks out of the way, and attempts to
strike upward with its spear. As you do, you knock
it to the side, with the scimitar that missed, and
with your other hand, strike down right across its
face. You arc through and you actually carve one
of the eyes in twain. You see a large red mark
where you've split part of its face, and it's hurt
really bad, but it's still standing. There's gore
dripping out of the socket where its ruined eye
sits. (snarls)
TALIESIN: I'm going to try and circle around it to
get out of the way of the archers. I'm going to
hop back off and get behind him.
MATT: You can do that without a problem. You
leapfrog off of him, grab his shoulders, and land
behind him, scimitars at the ready. Okay, ending
Molly's turn. Jester, you're up.
LAURA: What about the guards?
MATT: The guards already went. Oh, she didn't
fire. Sorry, thank you for reminding me about
that. The other guards did go, she did not-- They
did not.
LAURA: Aren't they going to attack this skeleton
one that's right here next to both of us?
MATT: They throw their crossbow to the ground and
pull out a morningstar, and does a sideswipe
towards this-- That is a 19. We'll say that
straight up hits. That does five plus eight points
of damage to that one. I don't think you've
damaged that one yet, right?
LAURA: Yes I had. I did the Hellish Rebuke to it.
MATT: That's right, you did! That was the wrong
one. All right, with that, they swing backwards
with the mace and hit the side of the skeletal
head, which shatters immediately upon impact,
ruining its form, and is no longer part of the
battle.
LAURA: I am so surprised I fall off the wall!
MATT: You are. You tumble that way.
LIAM: Get out of the city!
MATT: All righty. Jester, your turn.
LAURA: Okay. Are either of those two gnolls over
there damaged?
MATT: From what you can tell, nope.
LAURA: Okay, well, I'm going to use my giant
lollipop, and it's going to swing and hit a couple
times and try to hit one like a bat.
MATT: Go for it.
LAURA: Okay, this is the one you licked.
SAM: Okay.
LAURA: Eight.
SAM: (sad trombone)
LAURA: Sam's spit: not a good luck charm.
MATT: As it swings in the air and spins, they both
take one step back and it hits the dirt, and they
both look at each other, and (chuckles).
LAURA: Shit. I'm going to cast Cure Wounds on
myself, and then I'm going to leap off the wall
with great flourish and land next to Caleb. Okay,
that's a good idea. I'm going to land next to the
guard. Then I'm going to skip away to the
building.
MATT: There you go. All righty. That ends Jester's
turn. Caleb, Nott, you're up.
LIAM: Okay, I'm just going to do my same dog and
pony show trick, I'm going to go to the corner, I
should be able to see two or three gnolls, I
think, over there, yeah?
MATT: Yes, over here.
LIAM: Okay, so (sizzling) starts to burn in my
hand, Chromatic Orb out to hit whichever one--
MATT: That one's probably the easiest to see right
now.
LIAM: Then that's the one I'm going to go for.
Come on. Oh, that's good. That's a 17.
MATT: That definitely hits.
LIAM: Thanks, Keyleth.
MARISHA: You're welcome, boo.
LIAM: That is 3d8, so where is my eight-sided die?
There it is. This is fire, and it is 11 points of damage.
MATT: As it bursts into it, you see the fur burn
and singe and (whimpers) pats it out and the
flames subside, you see it's charred and burnt,
and you see the flesh is cracked and blackened.
It's injured, but it's standing.
LIAM: Okay, and I inch back again and say,
(singing) If it ain't broke, don't fix it. And
hide behind the building.
MATT: That ends your turn. Nott?
SAM: There's two gnolls in front of me that I can
see, right?
MATT: You can see those down there. The one just
got blasted with the familiar fiery explosion of
Caleb's Chromatic Orb. The other is untouched.
SAM: The other one, I will point at and I will
remove a tiny rotten tart from my pocket and
crumple it onto the floor and take a feather and
move it around over the crumbs, and say: Hey, what
happens to a frog's wagon when it breaks down? It
gets toad away! And I will cast Hideous Laughter
on the gnoll.
TRAVIS: Hideous indeed.
MARISHA: No bad Halle Berry lines.
MARISHA and LAURA: What happens to a toad when
it's struck by lightning? The same thing that
happens to everything else.
MATT: Wisdom saving throw? That is a natural 11.
What is your spell DC?
SAM: 13.
MATT: 13. All right.
TALIESIN: I like the theory that he doesn't burst
into laughter, he just holds the groan pain.
LIAM: I would like to think that he does laugh
hideously and despises himself for it.
MATT: Did you shoot the one who was blasted with
the fire or the one that was untouched?
SAM: The untouched one.
MATT: You watch as the one that was currently
untouched that was drawing another arrow glances
up and hears, and goes, (uncontrollable laughter)
and falls to the ground. (manic laughter) Laughing
this horrible hyena chuckle, and it's billowing
out into the street, clutching its stomach and
dropping its weapons to the side and just rolling
on the ground. Its friend next to it is like, huh?
Looks up and sees you.
SAM: Okay. All right, I'll use my bonus action to
hide.
MATT: Go for it.
SAM: Oh, I have to stealth. Oh, God damn. Okay,
that's 13.
MATT: Okay. That ends your turn. There are no more
of the undead types, so they're off the thing.
Beau, you're up.
MARISHA: Okay, I step out of the burning building,
sauntering like a badass John Woo film.
LIAM: Doves go everywhere.
MATT: That's five feet of movement.
MARISHA: Yeah, and looking at this one, I go: Hey,
your friends have an inside joke without you.
Pointing at the guy on the ground. As soon as he
turns, I go whack like a baseball bat, right
across his head.
MATT: As soon as he glances over to the side, he
looks back just as you're already in his face.
MARISHA: Oh, that's good.
LIAM: Swing it high, Beau.
MARISHA: 25! No, sorry, 24!
MATT: 24, that'll definitely hit. Roll damage.
LIAM: Swing away.
MARISHA: I'm going to take that, that's a 13,
sorry, ten, nope, 11! Math.
MATT: 11 points of damage. Whack! You watch as
about five or six gnoll teeth go flying from the
impact, the jaw quivers as spittle and blood goes
careening off the side of the impact. It falls and
stumbles, if you want to follow it up.
MARISHA: I'm going to, using that momentum, do a
helicopter flourish above and go crack down over top.
MATT: Go for it.
MARISHA: That's a natural 19!
MATT: That hits, go ahead and roll damage.
MARISHA: Oh, wait, this is technically an
off-handed.
MATT: Right, so it's a d4 for this one, but we're
using the staff for a flourish.
MARISHA: Ooh, that's a four, so eight points of
damage.
MATT: Eight points of damage. Wham! As you bring
it down over the top of the head, it falls and
gets up, it's dazed and beaten within an inch of
its life, it's ready to go. It's barely standing
at this point, one eye is lolling around and
trying to find, and the other one is swollen shut
now and can't actually see anything. It's in a bad
place.
MARISHA: Fuck. I'll hold.
MATT: Okay. That ends your turn, Beau. The guy on
the ground is just laughing his ass off. At the
end of its turn, it's going to try and make a
saving throw. No, that is a two. It is still
laughing on the ground. This one, seeing the rest
of its allies run, turns around and is just going
to run.
SAM: That's the one you just hit?
MARISHA: No. This here.
SAM: How many are over there? Oh, I didn't see
it.
TALIESIN: Two, and I've got one.
MATT: This one, seeing another one flee, is going
to attempt to try and flee after. You get an
attack of opportunity.
MARISHA: I have advantage on that?
MATT: You do not.
MARISHA: Fuck. Oh, but that's still good. 18.
MATT: That hits, roll damage.
LAURA: Kill him!
MARISHA: Is that with my regular attack?
MATT: Yes.
MARISHA: Eight damage.
MATT: You knock and crush him to the floor. As he
tries to run, you whack and hit him, and you watch
him take a few steps and skid and fall onto the
ground, and he's not moving. The one over here,
who is not currently in the process of knowing
that everyone else is fleeing, because he's been
stuck over here, is going to try to take a spear
attack at you, Molly.
TALIESIN: I'm going to snap at him. I'm going to
use Blood Maledict.
SAM: Hellish Snap.
MATT: Which is good, because he rolled a natural
20 on the first roll.
TALIESIN: Yeah, no he ain't.
MATT: Disadvantage, that brings him to a 15.
TALIESIN: That is my armor class.
MATT: So it just hits you.
LAURA: But at least it's not a critical attack.
TALIESIN: Nope!
LIAM: All his friends are running away, and he's
going, "Me and my friends are going to kill you."
MATT: Eight points of piercing damage. Its eyes go
dark and it pulls back, and still it seems its
sense of smell can still find your placement in
the vicinity, and as you pull out of the way, it
still manages to find you. The spear pierces right
around where the hip is, and you pull back,
gritting your teeth. That's going to end its go.
TRAVIS: My turn.
MATT: Yep.
TRAVIS: Can I hop around the corner again?
SAM: (engine revving) Start up the full.
TRAVIS: I'll go ahead and use my 30 speed to close in on
the proned-out. Great, and I'll use Eldritch Blast
against that.
MATT: All right, it has disadvantage against it
because it's prone.
TRAVIS: 11.
MATT: 11. As it's rolling around on the ground,
it's difficult to find a proper shot, and you
fire, and it hits the dirt next to it, sending a
bit of dust over it. It stops laughing for a
second as the dust-- He laughs even harder at the
actual dust.
TRAVIS: That's it. That's my turn.
MATT: That ends your turn. All right. The guards
go. The leader continues to run, and is now
disappearing into the smoke and ash. You don't
have a visual on the cart at the moment, it's now
pressed into where a lot of the fire is, and it's
obscuring their escape. These guards are going to
move forward as they load their crossbows, and
they're both-- actually, because he's on the
ground laughing, you're coming out on the roof,
they're going to turn and fire at the one that's
in front of Molly. It does have three-quarters
cover because of the wall. They're trying to help
you out.
TRAVIS: We need the assistance of guards, guys.
MATT: Hits the wall and deflects.
TRAVIS: It's hard.
MATT: That does hit! That is a 21, actually, so
that does, even with the bonus to armor class from
the three-quarters cover, it still hits.
SAM: Those guards are killing more than we are.
MATT: With that, as it's there in front of you
with its spear, after stabbing you, it pulls back
and one crossbow bolt out of its forehead.
Its jaw goes slack and falls to the ground, dead.
TALIESIN: Oh, come on.
SAM: Don't you want to ask that nameless guard how
he wants to do this?
MATT: Well, there's still one left on the ground,
which we'll say for the purposes of narrative
here, who wants to do this?
TRAVIS: What, you really want to do something?
SAM: Is it our turn soon? Caleb and me?
LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: Well, when we come back around, it would be
Molly's turn, Jester, then Caleb and Nott. So
whatever you guys want to do in this moment before
it comes back, let me know.
SAM: I would like to jump down from the wall and
run as fast as I can after the leader and the cart.
TRAVIS: Really?
MARISHA and LAURA: Whoa!
MATT: Make an acrobatics check.
SAM: Oh, disadvantage. Jesus. 11.
MATT: You jump off the side and you land, you do
suffer four points of bludgeoning damage as you
hit the ground and your feet buckle, and you
actually slam and your face hits the dirt, but you
use your momentum to scurry back up, and beginning
to move forward, you get-- and if you're using the
rest of your--
SAM: Dash, everything.
MATT: I need you to make a concentration check, by
the way.
SAM: Oh.
MATT: Make a constitution saving throw, because
you did take--
SAM: This is a saving throw, that's not
disadvantage. 16.
MATT: Yeah, so you maintain control over the
Hideous Laughter. Okay. You rush into the cloud of
ash after them, and you begin to see some of the
shapes ahead of you of the gnolls there, pushing
the cart. You're still behind them by about 30 or
so feet, and right as you rush forward, darting
in, the heat from the embers entering your lungs
burn, and you put your mask over to block and help
filter a bit, with the cloth and bandages, and
right as you rush forward, you see the back of
the heavy armored leader, that's bringing up the
rear of where the cart is, and he turns and sees you.
SAM: Oh god.
MATT: As soon as you finish your movement, it
spins and looks in your vicinity, to see that
you're alone.
SAM: Oh god.
MATT: Takes his glaive.
SAM: Oh god!
MATT: And closes the distance with a giant
downward swing.
SAM: Oh god!
LAURA: What did you do?
TALIESIN: Wait, is it his turn already?
MATT: At this point? The narrative timing on
this.
TALIESIN: Because I was going to run that way too,
I thought we were still--
LAURA: Yeah.
MARISHA: Yeah, who was allowed to run?
MATT: Well, Nott's after you.
TALIESIN: Okay. So I will--
LAURA: But we didn't get to go, because Nott just
jumped it.
SAM: Yeah.
MATT: All right, cool. All right, well let's roll
it back a little bit here and see how this helps
you. All right, cool. So. No, it's fine. So
Jester, Molly, what are you guys doing?
TALIESIN: I was going to run to see where the cart
was going. Full dash.
MATT: Okay. As you sprint off, with a full dash,
you don't quite get as close as Nott does.
TALIESIN: No, I wouldn't.
MATT: Because Nott is much faster.
TALIESIN: Is he triggering my spider sense at
all?
MATT: No.
TALIESIN: Okay.
TRAVIS: What's your spider sense?
MATT: It's not really a spider sense.
TALIESIN: I know, but you know.
SAM: But it's a spider sense.
LAURA: Basically.
MATT: You're about that far back, I would say.
LAURA: I was going to have my duplicate go over
and touch the guy laughing on the ground, and cast
Inflict Wounds.
MATT: Go for it.
MARISHA: Dope.
MATT: It's a melee spell attack, correct? You have
advantage on it because he's currently
incapacitated.
LIAM: If he's still around when she's done, I
would have done my same single--
LAURA: Natural 20.
LIAM: Yeah!
TRAVIS: That'll be all the damage.
MATT: Oh my god. So roll the dice.
MARISHA: He's going to turn into powder.
LAURA: Five, six, 13, 26!
MATT: As he's laughing, your image walks up with a
skip, bends down and touches him, and he suddenly
withers into this completely dried-out husk of
what the gnoll once was, the life force drawn and
cast out of his body. He stops laughing, and the
body falls like a mummy to the ground.
SAM: Your duplicate can cast spells?
LAURA: Yeah. That's why it's more fun if I can move
her.
TALIESIN: That's why it's like a bear.
MATT: All right, finishing those turns, back to
the top of the round.
LIAM: No, I would have leaned out, if I had seen it
was dead, and no enemies, I would use my
movement, my action to move further up to the
corner, not much besides that, but join where
Fjord and the duplicate are. That's it.
MATT: That ends your turn.
TRAVIS: Your friend took off running.
LIAM: Nott?
LAURA: That's all happening right now.
LIAM: This is simultaneous.
MATT: Beau, your turn.
MARISHA: Hearing you say that, I'm going to be like,
I guess we're-- race you! I'm going to take off
running after Nott.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: 40 feet speed.
MATT: You manage to catch up right around
basically where Molly is there. Do you have a ki
point left?
MARISHA: I do.
MATT: If you wanted to use your--
MARISHA: That would just get me-- I'll save it for
right now. But I can see Nott, and I can see the
guy, and I can see the cart.
MATT: There's cloud and ash, embers pushing into
the atmosphere now, the nearby building are
actually in flames and engulfed on the side here.
MARISHA: That was a double move?
MATT: That was a double movement to get to there.
MARISHA: All right.
MATT: As you and Molly are 15, 20 feet from each
other, and ahead you can see the shape of Nott, and
you can see the leader of them. You can now see
from nearby buildings that about ten other gnolls
are all gathering around the cart and they're all
leaving. They're all carrying giant sacks on their back,
dragging bodies and corpses behind them.
MARISHA: Ten?
MATT: Yeah. This wasn't the only gnolls that
attacked the city.
TALIESIN: This was just our little patch. Our
gnoll patch.
MATT: Finishing Beau's turn, it comes back to
Fjord. The rest of the gnolls continue pushing the
cart. A few join them, giving it momentum.
About six more of them begin stepping up,
flanking the leader, who's now staring at the
three of you.
TALIESIN: Now's not the time!
TRAVIS: I'll run forward using my 30 feet but
I will call out: Nott, get back here!
SAM: What? Don't blow my cover.
TRAVIS: Let them go!
SAM: Okay. What?
MATT: That ends Fjord's turn. The leader sees the
three of you there, puts the glaive away with one
hand, turns around as he draws his longbow and
fires an arrow right at you. That is a 17 to hit?
SAM: Hits.
MATT: That is eight points of piercing damage.
MARISHA: Are you down?
TALIESIN: He is so down.
MATT: The arrow strikes Nott in the chest, who
falls unconscious onto the ground, the ash and
embers starting to spill over her unconscious
body. With that-- because I believe-- yeah, it can
make two attacks with its longbow. He's going to
make a second strike now. This one's going to be
at-- I'm going to make it-- He can't decide at the
moment. This'll be a four, Molly. That is a
natural 20.
(groaning)
MATT: That is 18 plus three. 21 points of
piercing damage.
TALIESIN: You got to be fucking kidding me,
really?
MATT: He rolled a nine on a d10. And it's a crit.
TALIESIN: Oh, I'm down.
MATT: Molly goes down.
SAM: Oh, shit.
MATT: With his movement, he puts the bow back away
and keeps walking with the rest of the gnolls.
MARISHA: I grab Fjord and I say, just wait. Wait.
Let them go.
MATT: You watch as all of them turn around and
they all begin to gather. You hear this cacophony
of different gibbering cries in the distance as
they're all starting to call themselves back to
leave the city. They all step into the clouds of
smoke and ash in the distance before eventually
all the shapes disappear.
MARISHA: I want to watch them as far as I can to
try and pinpoint a direction that they're heading in.
MATT: Okay, make a survival check in this moment.
LIAM: It's dark, too.
MATT: It is dark.
MARISHA: Not great, 11.
MATT: Okay. It's hard to tell with all the smoke,
you can't see the moon, you can't see the
placement of the sky, but you make a note of which
direction they're traveling based on the street.
Those who are both on the ground as Beau continues
doing this, you guys begin to rush up and you see
both Molly and Nott on the ground.
LAURA: I run up and I'll cast Cure Wounds on
Molly. Then I'm going to run over and do the same
thing at level two to Nott. That's six points of
healing for you, I'm sorry.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
LAURA: I'll run up and cast it on Nott. Oh no, Nott!
I pull her up into my lap. Oh, that's good. 13--
oh, 13 plus five! No, plus three.
MATT: That immediate first breath is filled with
pain, both from the wounds you've sustained and
the immediate influx of burning ash that sweeps
into your lungs. Both of you come to consciousness.
SAM: (gasping) Oh my gods!
TALIESIN: What were you thinking?
SAM: I was just going to follow them from afar. I
forgot they had bows and arrows.
TALIESIN: That's literally the only thing that's
been happening.
SAM: I thought they wouldn't see me because of the
smoke. Oh boy.
TALIESIN: I'm going to put out these fires. Oh,
I'm not getting up.
MARISHA: Ah shit, the town, you guys! And I'm going to
go back and start trying to put out the fires.
TALIESIN: I'm going to crawl back towards the--
MATT: As you guys begin to regather your troops,
more of the crownsguard that you see have been
battling and have been partially wounded by a lot
of the other gnolls are beginning to gather their
dead, beginning to try and put out what fires they
can and acknowledge which buildings can't be
saved. As you begin to take what remains of your energy to
do so, we're going to go ahead and take a break.
We're going to take a break here, and we'll have a
little denouement to this episode tonight. But
before I leave, we have another contest tonight.
Our friends at Wyrmwood actually have a pretty
cool giveaway tonight. As part of their new
Kickstarter, they have this all-inclusive package
here, which is both a dice box, with a leather
base, and on the inside here an all-inclusive
package for your dice.
SAM: We don't have those.
MATT: No, they just started producing them. These
are walnut Adventurer's Arsenal kits, and we're
giving away two of them. The keyword tonight is
map, M-A-P, based off last week's episode, thank
you Deven. During the break in Twitch chat only,
come in there and when you're prompted go ahead
and enter the keyword, map, into the chat only
once. More than once and you will be disqualified.
Two of you will be chosen during the break, and
we'll come back to see who wins that. See you guys here
in a few minutes.
[break]
MATT: Welcome back, everybody. That was on the
air, well done. The winner of the Adventure
Arsenals are, we have two of them, TheBravestKoala
and GrandmasterBlaq. Congratulations to both of
you guys for the win, go ahead and Danoba will
reach out to you and get your contact info and
we'll get those to you. For those of you who are
curious to look at it, this particular
Kickstarter you can find on wyrmwoodgaming.com
to look and see the cool thing this new release is
going to entail, so thank you very much, Wyrmwood.
All right, with some of the flames dying down, 30
minutes or so of the chaos descending, the
Crownsguard begin to come back, those that are
still living, many of them wounded and tending to
their wounds, or helping the survivors that are
still within the town. You see some families are
starting to unblock their entranceways and the
people who had escaped the city are slowly
beginning to filter in. You can hear the sobbing
in the distance of families that are coming back to
homes that have been destroyed. The smoke still
chokes the air, and at this hour now it's probably
pushing close to 11:00 or later. But as the guards
come through and begin to take in the essence of what's
happening, the armored individual that helped you
when you first arrived and gave you the command to
aid in this approaches. You see their half-elven
face, solemn and tense, approach and extend a
hand. "There aren't many who would immediately
"jump into the fray as you did. I would say that we
would have lost many more, and perhaps all of my
"men had you not been there, so thank you."
LAURA: Of course, I say as I cut off the ears of
some of the gnolls.
LIAM: You beat me to it. You said 30 minutes went
by, I wanted us to be doing that already.
MARISHA: We're like: Oh no, put out this fire!
LAURA: These people have lost everything!
LIAM: I was just waiting for you to pause.
MATT: Yeah, no worries. Unfortunately, for the
three skeletal ones you only manage to get one
full ear.
LIAM: That's fine.
LAURA: That's okay because we got two ears
off of all the other ones.
MATT: You did. We'll say for that, for those who
would've been destroyed or damaged, let me go
ahead and roll and see how many ears you're able to
pull off of those bodies.
LAURA: I'm also going pull off a chunk of tail and
see if it will pass.
LIAM: I'd like to think that we leaned down to the
same gnoll, cutting, and went, same hat? Same hat.
MATT: You manage to pull up about 12 ears intact
between all the fallen bodies. Some you killed,
some maybe you didn't. You came across the body
elsewhere in the square and just took the ear.
MARISHA: I totally remember kicking this guy's
ass.
MATT: Other guards are collecting them as they go
and there are a couple moments where someone was
going for an orc-- or a gnoll that you had killed
and you went to the guard and went, nuh-uh, and
they backed off. But anyway, the soldier head that was
speaking with you extends a hand and they say, "I
"am Watchmaster Bryce Feelid, assigned here to
Alfield, now in my fourth year. Thank you."
MARISHA: Watchmaster?
MATT: "Watchmaster Bryce Feelid."
TRAVIS: What were those creatures? Have you
encountered them before?
MATT: "We've encountered them before, yes, in
smaller hunting packs, maybe a half-dozen at a
"time, usually on the outskirts. They don't come to
civilization like this. It's generally too
"dangerous for them, in the smaller numbers they
travel. What the fuck are they after?"
TRAVIS: Such a grizzly scene, they seemed to be
carrying away bodies on that cart they had.
TALIESIN: That was weird.
LAURA: Did you notice they had some undead
gnolls with them?
TRAVIS: I did.
TALIESIN: There were.
LAURA: Have you ever seen anything like that?
MATT: "I've maybe crossed one or two as part of
the roving packs, it's not terribly uncommon."
TALIESIN: What turns them like that? Is there
something in the water?
MATT: "I have no idea. I don't know the ins and
outs of their creepy bestial lifestyle. I mean,
"what--" And you watch as they sit down for a
second, leaning against the wall, thinking and
scratching at their chin, "Word came of a small
hunting party of these beasts spotted to the
"south, so we sent a small troupe to slay them naught
but two hours before they struck here. We had sent
"more than half of our men's strength to go and
deal with them, so we were unprepared and, at the
"time, unguarded for the most part. We were caught
at half strength. It can't be a coincidence. They
"must be desperate to assault head-on
like this. There's plenty of small game in the
"surrounding wood and they're known to be provoked
to violence, but I've only heard of gnolls picking
"off the outlying folk, those that wander too far
from the fields."
LAURA: Do they eat the bodies?
MATT: "They eat what flesh they can get a hold of,
but we went through a number of the buildings and
"they've ransacked two of the inns. They completely
took the entire butcher's stock. They've carved
"the city of whatever meats, fresh or dried, we
had."
TALIESIN: Word came? Word came that they were in
the south? Where did word come from?
MATT: "Word came from some of our crownsguard who
were running a patrol."
LIAM: We have seen these things as far south as
Trostenwald. Further even.
MARISHA: Has there been something else going on,
that you can think of, that might have cut off
their food supply?
MATT: "Not that I can think of. For the most part,
this far south, other than a few run-ins here and
"there, they aren't-- conflicts of this size don't
make it past Bladegarden."
MARISHA: Bladegarden?
MATT: "It's where most of them-- It's where most
of the Empire's military and guard are trained and
"then sent out throughout the rest of the valley.
That's a lot of meat that they've acquired from
"us, and they've lost many, I thought, of their kin in
this battle as well."
LAURA: Too much meat. What are they feeding?
MATT: "Or what's making them so hungry?"
LAURA: Oh. Or that.
TRAVIS: Indeed. My concern is that they'll return.
We've fended them off for now, but they'll come back.
MARISHA: Especially if they're as desperate as you
say they are.
MATT: "I've sent three of our scouts to try and
find out where they went, track wherever they're
"taking their spoils. Reports come in that most of
the bodies they took were dead, perhaps not all.
"We have to do our best to at least recover any
survivors, wipe out what remains, and prevent this
"from ever happening again."
MARISHA: Have you heard local farmers complaining
about them stealing livestock? Missing livestock?
MATT: "I'm going to look into that, actually. I'm
sorry, I'm still gathering my thoughts."
LAURA: (gasps) W.C! I get up and I run and see if
our horse is still there.
MARISHA: Oh, W.C.
MATT: Okay, so you charge out to the far city and
you do find W.C., still affixed to the cart,
currently chewing on a small bag of oats where one
of the families of villagers who fled have come
back and begun to feed him.
LAURA: Thanks, man! Thumbs up to the family, I'll
run back to the group.
TRAVIS: Are you going to run back to the group, or
bring W.C. with?
LAURA: No, I'm going to leave it out there.
TRAVIS: Oh, cool, okay.
TALIESIN: Petting zoo.
LAURA: Yeah, they're petting him.
MATT: To the rest of you, Bryce says, "Well, as
rash as it was said-- and our coffers are not as
"strong as they could be, I will request more of a
monetary influx up north-- for the ears you have
"taken you will be paid. Any more that you find,
those will be paid as well."
TALIESIN: Well, and we're going to need some
lodging anyway, so perhaps some trade could be
worked out.
TRAVIS: Indeed, we could provide some extra
muscle, perhaps for some lodging while we stay and
maybe we could aid your men and their efforts to
exterminate this foe.
MATT: "Well, I would normally put you up in the
Candleglow Inn but--" They gesture over towards the
large building that you had walked through that's
now currently--
TALIESIN: It's literally glowing like a candle
right now.
MATT: "That is ironic now that you point it out."
TALIESIN: I feel really bad for saying that out
loud.
MATT: "Let's just not let Thadeus know that his
life is--"
LIAM: I have a question. After listening to this
for a while, I start looking around the town, would
you say that with all these burnt buildings
everywhere, that if I start picking through the
rubble I would find enough charcoal to reduce
the costs I would need for Find Familiar,
eventually? Because I still need the incense and
the herbs, but if I get a lot of charcoal from these
burnt homes--
MATT: I will say if you take 30 minutes to find
good pieces of charcoal, and roll an investigation check.
LIAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Nein.
LIAM: Yeah, done and done. That's good, and I have
a good investigation too. That is a 23.
MATT: All right, you manage to reduce the cost of
you next Find Familiar spell by three gold pieces.
LIAM: Yeah, good, that's good.
MATT: From the hopes and dreams of Alfield. So
Bryce looks at you. "I can have you put up at the
"Feed and Mead tavern."
SAM: Feed and Mead?
MATT: "Feed and Mead tavern. It's not the most
comfortable place, but it'll do."
MARISHA: It's a good name.
MATT: "I did not name it, but pass it on to Crute,
the owner."
TRAVIS: Crute?
MATT: "Tell him that Bryce sent you and you are
being put up by the Crown for as long as you are
"hunting these creatures."
TRAVIS: We appreciate that. Hopefully, there won't
be another call to action while they're here, but
you can count on us if there is.
MATT: "Of course. Well." They reach into a pouch
and begin to count out the gold for the number of
ears you've collected. With twelve ears--
LAURA: 360 gold.
MATT: Mm-hmm.
MARISHA: Dope.
MATT: After bringing the ears forward, they glance
over. "Actually, I'll be right back. I may need to
"acquire a bit more change." And after a brief
wait, Bryce returns and you are paid the full amount.
TRAVIS: Damn.
MATT: So 360 gold at your disposal.
SAM: Should we divvy it up equally?
LAURA: If we do, that's 60 gold apiece. That's
Laura talking.
(laughter)
MARISHA: I'm fine with that.
MATT: Bryce says, "We hope to hear back in the
morning of our scouts' findings. If you wish to,
"if you can hunt whatever remains of these
creatures and bring back proof that they've been
"wiped out, I'll see what I can have sent southward
of Zadash to make it worth your while."
MARISHA: In the meantime, you wouldn't have
anything that might help us and our little
expedition, would you? Healing potion might be
nice if you got one hiding away somewhere in a
closet, forgotten.
MATT: "I don't mean to be brusque, but at the
moment I think we have a number of our guard who
"are in more desperate need."
MARISHA: Fair.
LAURA: I can help them... in the morning.
(laughter)
MATT: "I'm sure that would be appreciated. For the
moment, you all look about as battered as I feel. Rest
"up, come--" Let's see, they would be at-- "Meet me
outside of the Broad Barn."
SAM: The "Rod Bawn"?
MATT: "The Broad Barn."
LAURA: The broad?
MATT: Barn. Broad Barn.
They point it out to you, it's on the
western side of the town. "There, we'll make sure
"you get the basic supplies necessary. Hopefully,
we'll have information on where to go, and if you
"so choose, we could conscribe you to be under our
intent to destroy these creatures. Think on it,
"rest, we'll speak in the morning." Bryce turns
around and limps off with a few of the other
crownsguard. As you guys eventually find your way
to the Feed and Mead, you are immediately met by
Crute, who is this ornery, salty-looking dwarf of
tousled white-gray hair, this single tuft of a
beard that dangles down towards the belly button
before it hits a ring of gold, goes, "Oh, so I've
"been told you're the ones who were coming to
sleep. Got one of our two rooms for you."
SAM: One?
MATT: He never quite makes eye contact with you.
He's looking at your shoulder, or right above your face.
SAM: I think he's got two glass eyes.
MATT: "Come, I'll show you." Turns around and
leads you to your space. There are four beds
jammed in here. It's like a youth hostel-type
living situation here, but it's functional.
LAURA: Are they doubles? Fulls? Queens? Twins?
MATT: They are pretty much as twin bed as you can
get.
MARISHA and TALIESIN: I'm fine with the floor.
TRAVIS: I'm great with a bed.
LIAM: I've already got the silver thread out and I
am looping it over any open window and by the door.
TALIESIN: Was there beer downstairs? Was there
ale?
MATT: You can go ask.
TALIESIN: I'm going to drop my things and run
downstairs.
MATT: Okay. You come downstairs and there's nobody
inside, this is not a tavern night for a lot of
people. "Right, can I help you?"
TALIESIN: Is there drink? Is there smoke?
MATT: "Smoke we don't have. But drink, that I can
give you."
TALIESIN: I'll take something interesting.
MATT: "Interesting, you say. Heh." Takes out a
bottle, looks like a deep green glass, and uncorks
it. Takes a small shot glass that has a bulbous
bottom, pours it to the very top with this liquid
that looks a deep sea-teal green, and slides
it forward.
TALIESIN: Fast or slow?
MATT: "Well, depends on how much you like to
dream."
TALIESIN: How much?
MATT: "For that, and for what I heard you did,
it's on the house."
TALIESIN: Nonsense.
MATT: "For the night. You want more, you're paying
top-shelf price."
TALIESIN: What's top-shelf price?
MATT: "For that drink there, that would run you
about three silver."
TALIESIN: I put a gold on the table.
MATT: "Not going to complain."
TALIESIN: Consider it an advance, it's been a
rough night for everybody."
MATT: "Right, right, of course."
TALIESIN: And I'm going to sip this mother.
MATT: It has a very smoky, oak-barrel flavor to it
at first as it hits your tongue and then it burns
into this very medicinal, herbal, almost anise
mixed with burnt charcoal.
TALIESIN: That sounds nice. I'm going to sit, and
sip this, and grin, and very silently have a mild
nervous breakdown about what just went down.
MATT: Okay. As you all slowly come to rest,
exhausted, sore, beaten, trying to fall asleep to
the distant muffled sound of shouts and wailing in
the streets--
LAURA and MATT: And Jester jumping on the bed.
TRAVIS: Jester!
MATT: You find yourself to rest, preparing for
what the morning may hold, and that's where we're
going to pick up for next week's session.
LAURA: Worst roommate ever.
LIAM: You're not the only one. Caleb is going: one
gold, two gold, three gold, 60 gold.
LAURA: 60 gold, Caleb!
LIAM: This was a good idea.
TALIESIN: This is working out weirdly, I'm
excited.
MARISHA: We all have an extra 60 gold, yeah?
LAURA: For all the work that Beau did.
(laughter)
MATT: That was some Jackie Chan shit. You were in
the doorway, dodging everything.
TALIESIN: We now need to have a Stephen Chow
night, that was some crazy shit.
LIAM: We are hitching out stars to your wagon.
(laughter)
LIAM: She just shot some Sun Chip out of her
mouth. You're welcome, internet!
MATT: Gif that.
MARISHA: Oh, there it is, I found it.
SAM and LAURA: (groan)
MATT: Waste not, want not. That's my wife, ladies
and gentlemen. Thank you guys so much. Thank you
guys for watching. Thank you, D&amp;D Beyond, I'm
learning more and more about the app and I'm
enjoying it, thank you for supporting the show.
Thank you all for joining us tonight, we'll see
you next week, and is it Thursday yet?
LIAM: Nein!
MATT: Good night, everybody.