MATT: Hello everyone, and welcome to tonight's
episode of Critical Role, where a bunch of us
nerdy-ass voice actors sit around and play
Dungeons &amp; Dragons.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we do!
MATT: Apparently, someone's got mail on Drag
Race!
LIAM: That was like standing at the dock going,
"Three, two, one, jump!" and Travis was the only
one who jumped in.
MATT: Yeah, well done, though. Welcome guys! Before
we jump into tonight's episode, we have some
announcements to get through. First and foremost,
returning once again this week, our fantastic
partners and sponsor for the beginning of this
campaign, D&amp;D Beyond! An awesome Dungeons &amp;
Dragons tool for use for your campaigns, whether
you be DM or player, and Sam, do you have anything
to say about that?
SAM: Hi! Hey, our partner this week is D&amp;D Beyond,
that's www.dndbeyond.com. They'd like to invite
Critters to check out "And Beyond," the monthly
developer update and Q&amp;A session for D&amp;D Beyond.
D&amp;D Beyond product director Adam Bradford will
share the latest thing the team is working on and
answer questions from the community. The next
stream will take place tomorrow, the 16th of
February, at 11:00pm-- nope-- 11:00am Pacific.
Check it out at twitch.tv/dndbeyond and to
celebrate, I'm giving out a prize tonight. It's
another contest, all of you can play, and here's
the rules: using D&amp;D Beyond, you have to create a
character, right now, a level three character, any
character, go!
MARISHA: On our app?
LAURA: What?! That's going to take so long!
SAM: (intense timer countdown song)
MARISHA: Hang on, it's refreshing! You should've
given us warning!
SAM: (singing) D&amp;D&amp;D&amp;D Beyond. D&amp;D Beyond! D&amp;D!
LAURA: I did it!
TALIESIN: Aw, damn it!
SAM: What? I don't see it. It's there. She did
it.
LAURA and TALIESIN: I did it!
LIAM: Sphincter, Sphincter, Sphincter!
SAM: Oh, you know what? I don't know how to call
it!
LAURA: I have 138 hit points?
SAM: Wow! Wait, at a level three character? No,
she's level 15!
TALIESIN: Callous, 25 hit points! Already done,
right there!
SAM: All right, Taliesin wins. See how easy it is
to create a character with D&amp;D Beyond?
TALIESIN: A level three blood hunter earth
elemental.
SAM: I'll give you a hint: your prize is attached
to my mug.
TALIESIN: Oh, no.
Wait, wait, wait! No, leave it! Put it
back, I want to do this properly.
SAM: What're you doing?
TALIESIN: Lift, lift, lift.
(laughter)
MARISHA: Did you just--
TRAVIS: You hit Randomize Your Character.
SAM: Do you see how easy it is? We all created a
character in, like, 25 seconds!
LAURA: This random character that I just created
is really fucking cool.
TALIESIN: I'm actually really impressed with this
fucking character.
LIAM: Aw, I don't want to have Sphincter next to
Caleb now!
SAM: Wait, you really named it "Sphincter?"
LIAM: Yes. That's the name I gave them! That's as
far as I got! Delete. Oh, there goes Caleb.
TRAVIS: What is your name? Panalanalam-- Pana--
MARISHA: Panlanann.
TRAVIS: There are four "N's" in that name.
MARISHA: I am Panlanann, the wood half-elf blood
hunter!
SAM: What was yours, Taliesin?
TALIESIN: Callous.
SAM: Callous? What was yours, Laura?
LAURA: I was Alight, a level 15 fire genasi.
SAM: Her name was Alight?
LAURA: Alight.
TRAVIS: I am Eomita Deephollow, lightfoot halfling
fighter.
MARISHA: Dude, my abilities are balls, though. I
have a five dex and a four wisdom. That's sad.
MATT: We're using those characters for the next
campaign.
TRAVIS: No, no, no! No!
MARISHA: Wait, you got dope stats!
TRAVIS: Because I'm awesome.
MARISHA: Look how fucking crap these are!
TRAVIS: You're in big trouble.
MATT: Thank you very much, Sam, congratulations
Taliesin, and thank you D&amp;D Beyond for being our
sponsor. Quick reminder to those of you who have
an Amazon Prime account, you can get a free
subscription to the Twitch channel by going
through your actual-- yeah, you do it through
Twitch! You link your Amazon Prime account to your
Twitch name and you are able to subscribe to one
channel for free a month. If you have not
subscribed and you want to have the VODs available
to you before they go up on Youtube, that's the
way to do it, for no additional charge. Check it
out. Talks Machina--
LAURA: Sam, stop touching my shit. Look at that!
He rolled ones, ones, and ones!
LIAM: Kids!
LAURA: I'm sorry. Sorry, Matthew.
MATT: It's okay. We haven't started yet, so
technically it's a buffer. Talks Machina, next
Tuesday at 7:00pm Pacific. We'll be here on Twitch
and Project Alpha where our host, Brian W. Foster,
will discuss what happens and transpires in this
episode tonight, so check it out next week on
Tuesday. The podcast of last week's episode is
available for download, so those of you who missed
last episode or want to listen to it on your drive
or commute, or you just like the audio to create
your imagination-scape, last week's episode is
available to download now wherever finest podcasts
are located to be downloaded. Any other major
announcements from you guys?
LIAM: A little thing that is totally improvised. A
couple of weeks ago, a Critter named Courtney--
forgive me if I'm getting that wrong-- She tweeted
a picture of her with this scarf that she was
making for Caleb, and she made the hashtag
#ScarvesForCaleb and then people started talking
about it. I retweeted because I thought it was
awesome, and they came up with the idea to make
scarves for Caleb-- But not for me-- to give to
shelters: Homeless shelters, to veterans, to
anyone who needs scarves or hats or mittens. I
think it's a great idea, and you would make me
happy. This is beautiful, I love it, thank you,
but don't pile me up in scarves. Send them to
people who need them. I just think it would be a
nice thing to do.
MATT: That's awesome guys, I love it. Once again,
826LA, our fantastic charity we've been supporting
since the very beginning of this show, almost three
years ago now. They do fantastic work. If you
have the opportunity to give your time to it, or
want to help donate, or at least look up and see
what they do, I recommend you do it, they are
fantastic, so thank you guys. Unless anybody else
has anything else to interject, I believe it's
time for us to jump in to tonight's episode of
Critical Role.
[click, TV static]
[groovy Critical Role theme]
MATT: Welcome back. You guys are getting sloppy.
Welcome back. Last we left off, our gathering of
friends have been traversing northward along the
Amber Road, with the distant destination of
Zadash, one of the larger cities of the Dwendalian
Empire, as your destination. Upon traveling, you
passed a caravan, spent an evening amongst trees,
where you found a wayward cluster of wandering
buffalo...-like creatures. You continued northward
for a second day, rushed on past sunset to rest in
the city of Alfield, a small farming town that's
along the way to Zadash. However, upon noticing
that some of the buildings in the eastern side of
town began to light up with flame, you began to
approach rather rapidly, seeing members of the
city, citizens fleeing and screaming, and there
seemed to be some sort of attack. Upon going into
the town, you realized that a number of these
buildings are being set fire by an incursion of
gnolls. You were immediately brought in by
Watchmaster Bryce, who offered to pay you for each
set of gnoll ears that were brought to them, and
you jumped into the fray, managed to kill quite a
few, many of them still left with their quarry, it
seems, which happened to be quite a number of
bodies and/or citizens still living, that were
dragged off into the ashen and cloud-covered
night. Upon returning, many of you bruised,
beaten, and at one point in danger of worse, you
were given an evening's rest at the Feed and Mead
Tavern, and were told, if you were interested in
pursuing future coin in helping with the current
conflict nearing the city, to meet Bryce out by
the Broad Barn.
ALL: The Broad Barn.
LAURA: That's why I wrote Broad Barn down.
MATT: That is why.
LIAM: I wrote "Rod Barn."
MATT: That's a different place entirely. You guys
all bundled up into a singular room above the
floor of the Feed and Mead. Found yourselves
exhausted, passed out, and got an evening's rest,
so you've all gotten a long rest. You've healed
up. You've recovered your abilities. As the
uncomfortable warmth of the morning kicks in, with
your small room and number of warm bodies
encompassing a very tight and not very drafty
space, the partially humid early hours draw you
from consciousness. You all begin to stretch your
sore muscles and decide what endeavors await you
with the new day. What do you guys want to do?
LAURA: What do you guys want to do today?
TRAVIS: That bed was not my favorite.
LAURA: I liked it.
TRAVIS: Little stiff.
MARISHA: You should try sleeping on the floor.
It's actually really good support.
TALIESIN: It's good for your back, it's really
true.
TRAVIS: You use a pillow, or are you just on the
floor?
TALIESIN: Pillow.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Do you have to pray over your swords or
anything this morning?
TALIESIN: No, everything's fine. They just do what
they need to do. I just have to keep them clean.
TRAVIS: Yeah, well, we were sharing a room one
night, and Molly has a ritual. I think it's part
of his custom. Yeah, he performs over his swords.
TALIESIN: I have to take care of them or else
they'll stop working, of course.
MARISHA: Sure.
LAURA: Do they need to feed?
TALIESIN: They do actually, yeah. I've got to feed
them some, well-- it's complicated. I don't like
to go too deep into it, but I've got to use my
bloodline on occasion. Actually, since we're
already on the road, I should be honest, I wasn't
entirely telling the truth when I talked to you
that night.
TRAVIS: No! Stop it!
SAM: You seem so honest.
TALIESIN: Oh, you're just a bundle of truth too,
aren't you?
LIAM: What is a bloodline?
TALIESIN: I suppose it's only fair. I did tell you
that these swords are special, and that they use
the blood of my family to activate themselves. I
know I might have said I was from a long line of
priests, and--
MARISHA: Oh my god, you killed your whole family.
TALIESIN: I didn't kill my whole family.
MARISHA: Oh, okay. Never mind, keep going. I'm
sorry.
TALIESIN: Our family were less the priests, and
more the sacrifices. We may have stolen the swords
and run. That's why I've been trying to keep a bit
of a low profile when it comes to some of the authorities.
TRAVIS: Yeah. I mean, for fear of your life you
ran?
TALIESIN: It's been a long time, but I'd rather
not run into them.
LAURA: What gods were you being sacrificed to?
TALIESIN: Oh, I couldn't tell you. It was my
parents, I was just wee by the time that happened.
SAM: Is there a roving band of priests that are
trying to find you right now?
TALIESIN: Oh, I hope not. I mean, it's been a long
time.
MARISHA: Where's home? Where is this place that
you stole--
TALIESIN: My parents never spoke of it. Somewhere
out east.
LIAM: You got to the circus from that, how?
TALIESIN: Well, it was a bit of a mess, but I just
ended up there eventually. Just looking for a
place where I could rest, I suppose?
LIAM: That's funny, you gave me an answer, but you
didn't really give me an answer.
TALIESIN: Well, I don't know you that well.
MARISHA: That's what he's been doing this whole
time.
TALIESIN: That requires a drink.
TRAVIS: I understand that sentiment. Trying to
find a little respite, a little peace.
TALIESIN: It's a good place to be if you want to
run, but not run.
SAM: Are there any others of your family out there
on the run?
TALIESIN: Not that I've ever met.
LAURA: Was it just your parents and you that were
being sacrificed?
TALIESIN: You know, I don't know. I never thought
to ask.
LAURA: Did they want to kill you or just take your
blood?
TALIESIN: Apparently they needed us alive for it,
so there was that.
LAURA: Oh! So it wasn't so bad, they just slowly
drained you.
SAM: Doesn't sound that bad. Yeah, they're not
going to kill you.
TALIESIN: So I was told.
MARISHA: Isn't that what you're doing to yourself
on a daily basis?
TALIESIN: It's not that bad, though, it doesn't
leave a mark really.
TRAVIS: You're in control of it. You're using it
for yourself?
TALIESIN: Oh yes, of course. It can come in handy.
LAURA: Does it have to be your blood?
TALIESIN: Oh yes. Of our bloodline, apparently.
MARISHA: Have you tried any other bloodlines?
TALIESIN: Well, I've cut a lot of people with them.
Would you like to take a run at it? You could be lucky.
MARISHA: I'll save that for another day.
TALIESIN: I had a funny feeling.
TRAVIS: I'm tempted.
SAM: What about you, Fjord? Are you going to vomit
any seawater this morning?
TRAVIS: (retching)
SAM: Oh, watch out!
TRAVIS: Nah.
TALIESIN: Could've been worth five copper on the
open road at one point.
TRAVIS: I seem to have missed my calling.
TALIESIN: Always could use a circus geek.
MARISHA: How'd you sleep, aside from the crappy
bed?
TRAVIS: I know what you're asking. I didn't have
any other dreams. It was fairly restful.
LAURA: No dreams at all?
TRAVIS: None I care to speak of.
LIAM: Do we think there's anything left of this
town?
TALIESIN: That is a question.
TRAVIS: Anything left?
SAM: It didn't seem like the whole thing was on
fire.
TRAVIS: We couldn't quite see it at night, that's
true. Maybe we should go down.
LIAM: I would like to take a walk and see what it
is we're out to save.
LAURA: We can steal some things!
LIAM: Maybe we do that second, and first we take a
walk.
TALIESIN: How do we get paid? There was talk of
pay.
LAURA: I thought we already got paid.
LIAM: We did, but Molly was drinking, so maybe he
does not remember.
TRAVIS: He said he was going to bring the rest, I
think, later.
TALIESIN: I've got to say, there's worse ways to
make a living.
LIAM: I counted 60 gold.
TRAVIS: Hey, Molly, didn't you say Bryce said it
would come later?
MATT: Bryce had said if you wanted to continue to
help with this then there was more money.
LAURA: Let's keep helping!
MARISHA: Yeah, I mean, it's not a bad gig.
LAURA: We could stay here forever and just kill
gnolls.
SAM: That was very scary. One of them almost
killed me!
LAURA: But think about how good we would get over
time.
SAM: That's true. The 10,000-hour rule?
LAURA: Mm-hmm!
TALIESIN: Nott the gnoll killer.
TRAVIS: Jester, we agreed not to put anyone in
harm's way in an excessive manner.
LAURA: When did we agree that?
TRAVIS: Did we not?
LIAM: I don't remember that, either.
TALIESIN: I don't recall making that arrangement.
LAURA: Did we agree to that?
TRAVIS: Maybe I thought that was an unspoken
thing.
LAURA: Usually when you agree to something you
have to say it out loud. Most of the time. Unless
it's, like-- We just agreed to it! You said it,
you said it!
SAM: What did you agree to?
LAURA: I can't tell, it's a secret! Oh! But she's
serious about it, I can tell!
TALIESIN: You're so good at this.
LIAM: Well, my social anxiety is getting the best
of me. I'm taking a walk. Goodbye.
MATT: The door slams behind Caleb briskly making
his exit.
LAURA: Do you want a donut this morning? It's a
little more stale in the bag, I have to let you know.
TRAVIS: I think I'm fine.
LAURA: Do you want one?
TALIESIN: Oh, yeah. More donut for us.
MARISHA: I guess we should greet the town.
TRAVIS: Fair enough.
LAURA: Wait! When did we say we were going to meet
Bryce?
SAM: Why are you yelling?
LAURA: I thought they were leaving.
TRAVIS: Actually, I think they'll find us.
MARISHA: Yeah. Maybe we could just stand in the
middle of town and go, "Bryce?" until they show up.
LAURA: In front of Broad Barn.
MARISHA: Okay, I have a question about this Broad
Barn thing. Is Broad Barn the name of an
establishment, or is Broad Barn a very broad
barn?
TALIESIN: It's a very long barn.
MARISHA: It's a very big barn?
LAURA: What if it's a street? We didn't clarify,
did we?
MARISHA: What if it's a tavern? I don't know, I
got confused in his delivery.
LAURA: I bet we can ask the guy downstairs.
MARISHA: All right, yeah.
TALIESIN: He seemed nice last night.
TRAVIS: We go downstairs.
TALIESIN: I'll follow for this.
LIAM: It's a Zork game. We go down the stairs.
MATT: I know, apparently. You head downstairs to
the only other real location within the Feed and
Mead Tavern. There's Crute still there off to the
side and one very dirty and ashy civilian who is
currently slowly scarfing a meal with a thousand
yard stare. Looks like they had been close to the
action and chaos the evening before. As you walk
down, Crute looks across and goes, "I see you're
"awake. Would you like breakfast?"
LAURA and TALIESIN: Yes, please.
MATT: "All right. It'll be about an hour. Because
it's just me."
SAM: An hour? All right.
MATT: "It's just me."
LAURA: Do you want some help? I'll come help you!
MATT: "Come on!"
TALIESIN: I'll go in for this if it means a faster
breakfast.
MATT: The two of you jump in with Crute in what is
a not very well-kept kitchen, but functional. The
gristle, who knows how long it's been there. It
might add to the flavor, who knows.
TRAVIS: A-rating for the city of Los Angeles?
MATT: We'll put it at a B in Panorama City.
TALIESIN: Wow, that's an in-joke.
MATT: You guys go ahead and help out. It does
manage to cut down the time for breakfast
preparation. Eventually food is presented.
LAURA: After we've cooked, I'm going to switch out
his salt for his sugar.
MATT: Make a sleight of hand check.
TALIESIN: I want to see if I see this. I don't, do
I?
MATT: You're too caught up in the meal-making.
LAURA: 19.
TALIESIN: Oh, yeah, I definitely don't see this.
MATT: Neither does Crute, as you manage to do so
swiftly. Practiced, like you've done this before
in many other establishments in the past, maybe.
LAURA: After we cooked.
TRAVIS: You just give us all diabetes, that's
great.
TALIESIN: The frittatas are going to taste real
weird.
MATT: As you guys finish your breakfast, the rest
of the day is yours.
MARISHA: What does the town look like when we step
out front? How bad is it?
MATT: As you emerge from the tavern-- and Caleb,
you've already seen this-- you see that the fires
have now been reduced to maybe a dozen wide plumes
of gray-white smoke on the eastern side of the
city. It rises from the ashes and charred wood
remains and wood frames where some buildings used
to be. It seemed much more dangerous and chaotic
last evening, but looking at it now in the day,
it's no more than maybe a dozen buildings or so
that were affected. They were more centralized to
cause the most chaos suddenly at that time of
night. You get the sense as soon as you look
around that the folks of the city are on edge,
understandably so. You see the people are trying
to pick up their lives and move on in the face of
what recently occurred. The very air holds this
tension as you look around you. People walk past
you with sacks of grain and tools, their eyes
wide, darting around for unseen danger and
glancing past the two tieflings, immediately,
instinctually step back a bit and make a wide
berth. You watch children run from doorway to
doorway, trying to stay out of the street as long
as possible. It seems like it's trying to carry
on, but it's going to be a process. Some folks are
rummaging through the remains of the respective
buildings. You glance over near where the central
portion of your conflict last night took place,
where the Candleglow Tavern is, and there you see,
amongst the smoldering rubble of the inn, a single
halfling man sifts through the wreckage, a
crownsguard helping him lift heavier beams. You
see as he plucks what he can of his former life
from the rubble.
SAM: Should we go over and talk to him?
LAURA: Sure.
SAM: Do we recognize this person?
MATT: You have not met this person, no.
LAURA: You're a halfling, too, so maybe you should
talk to him.
SAM: I'm not technically.
TALIESIN: I'm going to walk over.
SAM: I'll join. We'll just go over and scare the
shit out of him.
TALIESIN: Need a hand?
MATT: You can see a halfling man, maybe in his
fifth decade or so. He has ashy blond hair and a
face cracked by smiling, though now too dour and
soot-covered to see any sort of smile on his face.
As he pulls through some of the rubble and he's
making a small pile on the side, he looks up and
goes, "Oh, right. Can I help you?"
TALIESIN: We were part of this commotion last
night. We were wondering if you need a hand with
anything right now?
MATT: "I mean, if you don't--"
TALIESIN: I'm taking off my jacket.
MATT: "You don't have to! Okay, okay." As you dive
in, you spend the next ten minutes helping move
through some of the heavier beams that collapsed.
There is still somewhat of a structure, mainly of
the bottom floor, but a lot of the top floor, the
one that you were in last night, has fallen in
over time. So it's moving some of the bigger beams
out of the way. As you're pulling through and
moving some of the larger pieces of the structure,
the halfling man goes, "I appreciate the help.
"Name's Thadeus. Thadeus Candleglow."
LAURA: Oh, this was your place?
MATT: "It was."
LAURA: Oh, wow.
MATT: "20 years since I was left this place. Built
by my grandpaps, Reedus."
SAM: Were you here when the attack happened?
MATT: "Oh, I was here. When they all came in, I
was gone. I wasn't about to stay around, you know?"
SAM: Did you happen to see where they came from?
MATT: "Oh, I did not. I was in the process of
cleaning dishes and dealing with a couple of my
"patrons. One of them--" and he points over to the
rubble. You can see what looks to be a skeletal
body that's been partially collapsed. "I suppose
Leiman's probably not going to be a regular anymore."
LAURA: Oh, no.
TALIESIN: You going to rebuild, give him a fine
plaque?
MATT: "Rebuilding requires something called money.
I think I'm probably going to gather what I can
"here and shop up north and see what other
work I can get myself to."
LAURA: How much gold do you need?
MATT: "I don't know. A building establishment like
this. I'm not entirely certain, but I could check
"in. I assume it's probably a few thousand gold
pieces for the structure."
LAURA: I just had that, too! I'm sorry, I don't
have it anymore. But I could try writing to my mom
to see if she'll help you.
MATT: "That's really sweet."
TALIESIN: Or, as another thought, since you were
basically robbed, who were they? What happened?
Has this happened before?
MATT: "Oh, this hasn't happened as long as I've
been here, and I've been here most of my life,
"here in Alfield. You hear about these things
wandering on the outside, and you know crownsguard
"keeps you safe. Anything comes too close, they
just shoot them in the face with a bunch of arrows
"and shit."
LAURA: I love him so much!
SAM: Thadeus, did they seem to be after anything
in particular? Were they here for property or
people or gold or food?
MATT: "They didn't take any of the worthwhile
stuff, thankfully." He points over to a pile and
you can see there's some brass urn or vase that's
been smashed and dented by the conflict. You can
see bits and pieces of a few keepsakes that might
be worth a little bit of money that have been
brought out. "They just mainly took all of our
food stores. Most of my meats, most of my salted
"meats, the dried meats, the fresh meats, the
butchered meats. They cleared out the butcher down
"the street."
LAURA: Shrimp scampi. Butterfly shrimp.
TRAVIS: Coconut shrimp.
LAURA: Fried shrimp.
SAM: Don't engage them.
TALIESIN: We're all going to die now.
MATT: "That's a real curious-looking face you got
there."
LIAM: Excuse me, I saw in the middle of the fray--
Sir. Excuse me.
SAM: In Halfling, I say to him, I've also been a
victim of a horrible attack.
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
SAM: Oh, minus. Ten.
MATT: But in Halfling, that helped. "Yeah, sorry.
What can I do?"
LIAM: I'm sorry, I was part of the fray as well. I
was right in the thick of it. I saw a cart piled
high with bodies. Are there people missing from
town?
MATT: "Quite a few. You'd have to ask around some
of the crownsguard."
LIAM: How has the rest of the village fared? Is
everything as poorly off as you are?
MATT: "I mean, plenty of folks seem to get through
this okay. They only took down a few buildings.
"I'm more worried about the folks that were plucked
from their homes."
LIAM: Is yours the only business that was hit?
MATT: "I haven't looked around, to be perfectly
honest. I've been a little focused on--" and he
gestures out with his hands at the rubble that was
once his life.
TALIESIN: You had a lot of meat, didn't you?
MATT: "Well, you have to present meat. A lot of
people around here eat meat."
TALIESIN: Would you say that you offer a larger
selection of meat than some of the other
establishments in town?
MATT: "If you're asking me, then the best meat.
Don't know about quantity, but quality was--" (tongue click)
TALIESIN: I feel like I've been robbed of the
experience of your fine, fine meat products, and
I, for one, would like you to rebuild so that I
might try some of your meats.
MATT: "Well, if at some point the gracious gods
see fit to bequeath upon me a strike of good luck
"and I can get to rebuilding, my friend, one day,
you may be able to try one of my meats."
TALIESIN: I'm going to take a look-- Is the friend
who's dead skeletonized?
MATT: Oh, yeah, burnt charred.
TALIESIN: Oh, burnt, okay. Where is this butcher
that you mentioned as well?
MATT: "Oh that's--" He steps out through where the
doorframe is still standing, the one that you
defended yourself through most of that battle,
just a free-standing frame now.
MARISHA: Was I in the butcher's? Because that
would be some real horror-level shit.
TALIESIN: I think you were in the barbecue shack.
MARISHA: That's kind of awesome.
MATT: He points over to a building across the way,
which is one of the buildings that was nearby. He
says, "That there's the Ruddy Top Butcher, well,
what remains of it," and you can see that building
too. It's still standing, and it's nowhere near as
damaged as the Candleglow Inn, but it's sustained
quite a bit of damage, and it looks like the roof
has fallen in.
LIAM: I'm sorry, Mollymauk, another question for
you: Is there maybe-- I hope it is still
standing-- but a supply store?
MATT: "Yeah, if you're looking for farming
supplies, general supplies, there's--"
LIAM: I'm sorry, I'm in the need of some incense.
MATT: "Oh, you could probably find something like
that there, The Broad Barn."
LAURA: Oh! It's a store!
MARISHA: Question answered. I'm sorry, I'm
standing by Fjord. Question answered!
TALIESIN: It's like half a question, because
you're wondering why it's called that at this point.
LAURA: I bet it's big.
TALIESIN: At least wide.
MATT: "At one time it was a barn, but the farm
stopped giving up crop, and so they converted the
"barn itself into what was a general store, because
they started selling off the tools they didn't
"need, but that made them more money than the crops
did that year, so we started importing more tools,
"and for the past 30 years the Broad Barn has been
our commonly known general supply place there on
"the western side of Alfield, so if you want
to--"
SAM: This is really fascinating.
LAURA: Wow, this is a really good talk that we've
had.
MATT: "Of course."
TRAVIS: Did you just out-talk Jester?
LAURA: I think I'm going to go look for the Broad
Barn
TALIESIN: That's an idea. Don't pack up shop just
yet, we're going to see if we can do something
about these terrible creatures that have been
roaming around.
LAURA: Maybe we'll find all of those thousands of
gold for you, and you can build your shop back up.
MATT: "Well, y'all look like you're geared up to
be making a mess. You going after these things?"
TALIESIN: We are, perhaps, persons of action.
LAURA: We're really tough. We have no fear.
MATT: He leans in real close to you, getting on
his tippy toes to meet your gaze, and he says,
"Well, if you manage to go and kill some of them
dog people, you tell them Thadeus Candleglow says hi."
LAURA: I will.
MATT: "Thank you."
TALIESIN: She really will.
MATT: "Good."
LAURA: Here. It's a moldy donut. Be well,
child, the Traveler is with you.
MATT: "I'm not a child, but I appreciate the
gesture."
LAURA: You know my name! I leave.
MATT: "Gesture. Her name's Gesture!"
TALIESIN: It is a gesture, like Prince.
MATT: The adventurer formerly known as Jester. He
takes a bite, and (spitting).
LIAM: Also, I'm sorry, just between you and me, I
know the look on your face a little bit, you seem
a little manic. If you have friends you can stay
with right now, you know you don't have to rebuild
it today. I recommend you take it slow.
MATT: "I don't think I have much of a choice at
the moment." He gives a long stare towards you
that fades past a little bit beyond. "Anyway, I
should get back to picking up the pieces. Excuse
"me," and starts gathering more stuff from the
rubble, and the crownsguard behind goes over and
takes the things he's already gathered, and begins
putting them into a small crate, and doesn't engage.
MARISHA: While they were having that conversation,
I'm hanging back with Fjord, if you're cool with that.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MARISHA: Question: If you were a crazy, ravenous,
dog humanoid person thing, what would make you
really hungry all of a sudden? I didn't phrase
that question very well.
TRAVIS: No, I knew where you were going with it,
though. How do we ring the dinner bells, is what
you're saying. How do we get them to come to us?
MARISHA: Yeah. It seems like they're into meat?
Kind of anything.
TRAVIS: Well, they done took it all, I think.
MARISHA: Also, they're really hungry, more so
now.
TRAVIS: Why more so now?
MARISHA: I don't know. Why more so now?
TRAVIS: Well, they took all the Luby's Cafeteria
with them, so I don't think they're going to be
hungry for a bit.
MARISHA: But what if they are still hungry?
TRAVIS: Then we would need to roast some meats.
MARISHA: You know who else was really hungry out
of fucking nowhere?
TRAVIS: Who?
MARISHA: Big angry toad man. Devil toad guy. I
feel like I should get better names for all these things.
TRAVIS: Yeah. He was hungry all of a sudden?
MARISHA: I don't know. I mean, it might be a
coincidence.
TRAVIS: You thinking some of them gnolls had
some fiendish qualities, perhaps?
MARISHA: Well, considering some of them were
undead.
TRAVIS: Right, shit.
MARISHA: There was that whole zombie gnoll thing.
TRAVIS: I forgot all about that.
MARISHA: Yeah. How could you forget that?
TRAVIS: I have some weird dreams. What did you have
in mind? Other nights.
MARISHA and TRAVIS: What?
(laughter)
MARISHA: I legitimately didn't understand what you
said.
TRAVIS: Oh, nothing, I got shit in my teeth.
MARISHA: Are you okay?
TRAVIS: Yeah, fine. Did you have a plan? Did you
want to do something to wrangle them--
MARISHA: I was just striking conversation.
TRAVIS: Oh, sorry. Well, maybe we'll follow them
to the Barn Broad.
MARISHA: Okay, let's go to the Barn Broad.
TRAVIS: Broad Barn. I was fucking with you.
MARISHA: I was going along with you.
TRAVIS: Yeah, that's all right.
TALIESIN: When did we hire Tom Stoppard to write
this?
MATT: I know. Seriously.
TALIESIN: I couldn't deal.
MATT: Where are you guys off to?
LIAM: To the Broad Barn.
MATT: You were told it was on the western edge of
town, and since most of the city is built on two
intersections of main road, you follow the core
essential east to west path, and on the way out,
where you first entered last night, even though
you just ran past it, you can see there is indeed,
right on the edge of town, almost like the town
was built to fill the gap in between, a very large
barn that looks to have hundreds and hundreds of
feet of coiled rope on the outside. The front doors are
wide open and you can see a number of folks are
coming in and out, many of them with cleaning
supplies, heavy pieces of cloth, buckets, whatever
can be used to start getting rid of the remaining
black splash and ashy covering of last night's
destruction. You also notice, as you approach on
the outside, there's a bit of commotion. You see a
dozen or so crownsguard, and a handful of armed
volunteers, that all appear to be in regular civvy
farmer clothing, that are all gathered in a loose
huddle, with Bryce among them. You hear a loud
grating voice from within that huddle. As you
approach from the outskirts, you see a middle-aged
male gnome of ruddy complexion and slicked parted
dark hair. He wears very clean maroon and gold
robes, and that would lend an air of elegance,
were he not hopping around and pointing fingers.
You see as he starts shouting between the crew,
waving his hand around, "Without any warning, it
was your job, Bryce! With Ruben cold dead, that
"leaves no Lawmaster to preside, forcing me to take
that position as well. I do not need that added
"responsibility, but until we get a new Lawmaster
instated from Rexxentrum, I have no choice." Bryce
pipes up at this point, glancing over and seeing
you guys' presence, "Starosta, I've sent a request
"to both Zadash and Bladegarden for a supplementary
force, but it may be weeks before any would
"arrive. Can we send trained hands at my approval
to retaliate?" At which point, the Starosta, which
has now been identified, says, "We cannot spare any of
our forces while the surviving guard are drawn so
"thin. Out of the question! Maintain a vigilant
perimeter and deflect any further incursions."
Bryce nods slowly. "Can we at least have
permission to hire mercenary strength to
"retaliate, then? I feel not being proactive before
the gnoll force can fully regroup would put us at a
"severe disadvant--" At which point is cut off by
the Starosta. "Yes, that's fine! Hire outside! I
"don't want any more of my citizens' deaths on my
record. Dismissed!"
He immediately pushes through the
crownsguard and storms off, which is hilarious to
watch a gnome storm out of a group of people, and
off with a huff is escorted by three crownsguard
from behind, out of that space. The crowd begins
to murmur and disperse, and go about their
business. Bryce turns and smiles at all of you.
They've washed up from last night's damage and
dirty conflict, so as they approach--
MARISHA: I turn to Jester, and I go, look
inviting. Look heroic.
MATT: "I'm deeply sorry about that. Starosta Kosh
is high-strung on a holiday, and tensions have
"never been this high since he was assigned here
eight years ago, so please don't take that to
"heart. He's just a--"
LAURA: Dick.
MATT: "Your words, not mine."
TRAVIS: Seems some people handle pressure better
than others. He doesn't seem like the handling type.
MATT: "No. Those in higher political positions
rarely do, it seems. Anyway, I want to thank you
"all again for your aid last night. I can't fathom
the further death toll, had you not been there and
"jumped in selflessly as you did. Thank you." Bryce
trails off and looks back towards where Starosta
Kosh had stormed off and goes, "Fucking Dwendalian
political bullshit. We've needed a more trained
"guard here for weeks, especially with Xhorhas
bleeding into the valley, but we're far too south
"to matter. Any request has been declined due to
all necessary forces being needed at the garrisons
"by Brokenveil. If they were doing their jobs at
the Bluffs, we wouldn't have so many reports of
"violent beasts in the valley in the first place,
but here we are. At least I've gotten approval for
"a bit more cash. To that, while I do not know what
your business here is in Alfield, if you are still
"interested, we are in need of some skilled
mercenary work."
LAURA: We're going to kill all of them!
TRAVIS: We couldn't help but overhear that you
were asking for some aid. How long were you
thinking you might need these replacements?
MATT: "Well, until at least this threat has been
dealt with in a satisfactory way. I've
"unfortunately not had my scouts return after
they were sent the night before, which does not
"bode well, but I suspect that we should see some
sort of hopeful backup sent by Zadash or
"Bladegarden within the next week or two. In the meantime,
we're a bit of a sitting duck scenario, so I've
"sent a few guards to go to Zadash to see what
other mercenaries could be sent forward. We do
"have some folks traveling along the road and will
keep an eye out to see if anybody else is looking
"for some coin, but for now, you are our first line
of defense. Or offense, if you will."
TRAVIS: Well, I think I speak for all of us, we're
certainly up to the task for a bit. Well, maybe
for a little less than a bit. Can I ask, are there
any other threats to this town, besides those gnolls?
MATT: "Oh, there are plenty of threats. Let's see,
famine, syphilis--"
TRAVIS: Things that come on legs and with weapons,
I mean.
LAURA: Syphilis can come with legs--
TALIESIN: I feel like that was worth pointing
out.
TRAVIS: Why do both of you know that?
MATT: "You're not wrong."
TALIESIN: Tiefling thing.
MATT: "This backwards place has its fair share of
issues, as I've come to learn as being not from
"the region, but it seems to me that nothing on
this scale has quite assaulted in some time. I
"mean, there have been wandering rumors of terrible
things and creatures wandering past the Xhorhas
"border for as long as the Dwendalian Empire has
been around. It's the whole reason that the
"garrison's up north. But this far south, generally
the guard can keep things at bay. This is a very
"organized thing, I don't like it. I don't like it
at all."
TALIESIN: It's new, then?
MATT: "Well, this is new. Nothing on this scale."
TALIESIN: It seems, from what we've seen, that
they were hungry.
MATT: "I've done a bit of research overnight, and
it seems that gnolls are known to be very
"aggressively hungry creatures. Could say famished
to the point of obsession."
LAURA: I feel their pain.
TALIESIN: I can understand that.
LIAM: So you wish to hire us. How much? We are
very experienced, but we'd like to know what we're
talking about in advance. What kind of money are
we talking about?
MATT: "The deal stands. 30 gold per gnoll ear,
proof of a dead gnoll. If you can recover any of
"the missing townsfolk here in Alfield and bring
them back safely, I'd be willing to pay 25 gold a
"head, returned."
SAM: What if we find a dead body and bring it
back?
LIAM: Is there some lesser number for those?
MATT: "There is, because even if they are gone, we
would wish to bury those we've lost. I could
"probably muster ten gold per retrieved member of
the Alfield citizenry."
LAURA: Specifically their heads, too?
MATT: "Preferably all of them. Whatever you can
find."
LIAM: It is permissible, is what they're saying
here.
MATT: "Seeing what these creatures did last night,
I don't know what state you'll find any of
"them, but I'm being hopeful."
TRAVIS: Do you know what area they might have gone
to?
MATT: "They seemed to be heading east, to a
northeast direction. That's where the scouts went
"before they left. I wish I had more information
for you, but that may be the place to start."
LIAM: Could you tell us at least what the
landscape is like in that direction, what is over there?
MATT: "There are some spotty woods on the
outskirts of the town that Alfield was built
"into. Beyond that, it's rolling hills and fields.
There are some older, long grown-over settlements
"that have been abandoned. Small-scale, but
honestly, beyond here it's mainly fields."
LAURA: I bet we can find some ghosts.
TALIESIN: I always love a ruin.
MATT: "If I might offer some advice: If you do see
a ghost, don't engage."
LAURA: Do you know where they are? So we know how
to steer clear?
MATT: "My dear, there are ghosts everywhere in
this world. It's far more ancient than you assume."
LAURA: Ooh!
MARISHA: Bryce, some of these gnolls were undead,
or raised from the dead. Do you have any inkling
as to why, or have you seen that problem around
here before?
MATT: "I don't know as to why, but it's not
uncommon, from what I could ascertain. Whatever
"dark powers they worship, it seems, allows some to
progress beyond death. Rumors are that when gnolls
"go hungry and left to feed on each other, what
remains rises to fight alongside those that still live."
LAURA: That would be why some of them have chunks
missing out of them.
LIAM: This comes from research you have done, that
you have read up on? Would you be able to share
this reading with me, so that we are fully
prepared?
MATT: "Honestly, I just shared with you most of
all that I had learned."
LIAM: Just a small book.
TRAVIS: More of a pamphlet, actually.
MATT: "The only other bit of information I was
able to pull from that was, they have this thing,
"this entity that they worship. It has a name."
Pulls out a few small notes.
LAURA: Fire hydrant.
SAM: Does it start with an A? Sometimes if you go
down through the alphabet, A, B--
MATT: As you're saying this, they pull a small
series of notes from their pocket. "Yeenoghu."
SAM: With a Y? That would have taken forever.
MATT: Let that be a lesson, young halfling.
LIAM: With a Y? Yeenogru?
ALL: Yeenoghu.
MATT: "I don't know how to pronounce it, I only
read it. I apologize."
TALIESIN: Do I know anything about Yeenoghu?
MATT: Make a religion check. With advantage.
TALIESIN: A religion check? 18.
MATT: It sparks a memory in you. Information
floods your mind, and you recall hearing about
various demonic leaders of the Abyss. Creatures
that once walked the prime plane. You see images
of this large, bestial, feral, angry demon.
Ever-hungering, ever wandering to conquer and
devour in its wake, leaving destruction, fetid
meat, and waves of yipping, angry hyenas to devour
what was left behind.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
LIAM: Sorry, another question. May I call you
Bryce?
MATT: "Of course."
LIAM: Bryce. We were just about to go inside the
barn here and get outfitted for this-- for many
things, but especially now that we are going to go
take care of this problem. Do you have any sort of
pull with these people? Might we get any
friendly--
TRAVIS: Advance?
LIAM: No. Well, sure, but I'm talking about some
sort of discount for getting ready for the road.
We're not that flush.
MATT: "It's not so much about that, more than
these aren't well-to-do people in their own right,
"and right now, honestly, rebuilding--"
LIAM: It's asking a bit much, I was too forward.
MATT: "That's all right. But you, as I know quite
well from personal experience, have some coin to
"your name. Perhaps that will be of aid to you."
LIAM: Yes.
TALIESIN: One last quick question, though. What do
the gnolls normally eat?
MATT: "As far as I could tell, whatever living
things they can get their hands on."
TALIESIN: Those buffalo creatures that we see
roaming around?
MATT: "Probably."
TALIESIN: Good to know.
MATT: "I will say, if there are any surviving
captives, then haste is very much key. For if they
"are as hungry as they seem, regardless of the
massive volume they have acquired through the
"evening, I know not how many their number is, or
how hungry they are. Take too long, there may not
"be much left to find."
LAURA: We'll get this stuff and head right out.
LIAM: Sorry, my curiosity gets the best of me,
always. You are talking about buff-- "buffaro"
creatures, or something? We saw these beasts on
the outskirts of town. They look brown-furred,
beast of burden-type creature? Do you know what
those animals are?
MATT: "Right, yes. The valley aurochs."
LIAM: Valley aurochs? Got it, thank you. All
right, we should get ready for the road. Walking
into the store.
LAURA: Was it hit at all? Was the store that we're
going into destroyed at all?
MATT: No, this was far enough west. It was mainly
just a few buildings in the eastern side. Coming
from where the woods were, it seemed like they
were using cover of tree and canopy upon the
incursion, then immediately assaulted partway into
the eastern part of the city, burned it from the
middle, and then used the flames to escape out the
back. What were you about to say?
MARISHA: (gasps) Bryce?
TRAVIS and MARISHA: (exaggerated coughing)
MATT: "Yes? Are you all right?"
MARISHA: Sorry, a lot on my mind. Speaking of the
aurochs, I asked you yesterday if you'd heard if any of the
farmers had had their cattle hit? You heard that
yet?
MATT: "I could ask around. It does happen on
occasion."
MARISHA: It's fine. We'll ask on our way out. It's
good.
TRAVIS: Hey, Caleb?
LIAM: Yeah?
MATT: "If you'll excuse me, I do have something to
get to. But good luck and godspeed."
LAURA: Have fun dealing with the dick.
MATT: "I'll do my best." Bryce turns around and
leaves.
LAURA: Did I recognize Starosta Kosh? Did he seem
like the type that would have made a little side
trip down to-- because he seems like the type.
TRAVIS: Was that a character-DM inside joke?
MARISHA: I know; I feel like I learned something.
MATT: Make an intelligence check.
TALIESIN: I'm filing, I'm putting a wall
between that.
SAM: I can't read your dice at all.
LAURA: Intelligence, 18.
MATT: The robe coloring is what caught you, and
the hair. The specific slicked and parted comb.
You have seen this individual before. You were
younger. Maybe eight or so years ago. Eight or
nine years.
LAURA: Good to know.
TALIESIN: You're just made of secrets, aren't you?
Just made of secrets.
TRAVIS: Caleb.
LIAM: Yeah?
TRAVIS: In my personal holdings-- I don't really
remember putting this there-- but apparently I
have five sticks of incense that I have no
intention of using.
LIAM: Oh yeah?
TRAVIS: Will that do you any good?
LIAM: Well, that would be worth about-- how much,
DM?
MATT: What does this incense come from?
TRAVIS: I think it was part of a thing. I don't
know.
LIAM: A pack or something?
TRAVIS: It's D&amp;D Beyond. I don't know.
MATT: Oh, so it's part of an adventuring pack,
then.
TRAVIS: I think so, yes.
MATT: It would be negligible by comparison. I'd
say maybe, at most, five silver's worth. At most.
LIAM: That is really very--
TRAVIS: Changed your day, didn't it? Everything's
coming up flowers now.
LIAM: Yes, this has helped me immeasurably.
TRAVIS: Don't mention it.
LAURA: Wait, wait. How much incense do you need?
LIAM: Well, it depends on how much I want to do
with it. I want my cat back. But I was in the
realm of 15 or 20 gold I'm going to spend here
today, if they have that much.
LAURA: On incense?! And that five sticks was five
silver's worth?
LIAM: Did anyone say that out loud?
SAM: She has a good eye for value.
LAURA: That is a lot of incense to burn.
MATT: Well, there's a lot of parts to--
LIAM: It's not quantity. It is the quality of
the incense. And this was top-shelf, but I still
need more. So, in we go. And then I say: Thank
you, big guy. And I punch him and I walk in.
TRAVIS: As he walks away, I'm like: Ow!
(laughter)
MATT: I think both of you do that, as you both
separate.
LIAM: Keep up a good face for two seconds.
MATT: As you walk into Broad Barn, there are five
other individuals that are coming through and
picking up thick cloth for cleaning. One person is
picking up a few different burn balm kits. On the
far end, as they're checking out, there is an
extremely old gentleman with this giant, gnarled
tuft of a chin beard that merges with this halo,
like a lion's mane of white hair. He has this
really thin, long, crooked nose. Almost like
Engywook from NeverEnding Story, but no glasses.
He's trying to keep a smile in the rather dark
faces of the people that are coming in, with the
evening's events coming around. As you guys walk
in and approach, he glances down and goes, "Well.
"If y'all need something, y'all just let me know."
SAM: Oh boy. West Virginia.
LAURA: Do you have any pickles?
MATT: "Y'all want pickles?"
LAURA: You seem like the type of place that would
carry pickles.
MATT: He leans back and rummages through what
sounds like a small paper bag.
LAURA: They come in barrels, usually. You get
barrels of pickles.
MATT: There's a small glass mason jar with two
pickles and he goes, "I'm willing to part with
"these here pickles!"
LAURA: Is it poop in a jar? Or is it pickles?
MATT: No, it's pickles. It looks like he may have
just pulled it out of his lunch.
TRAVIS: Only you would put poop in a jar, Jester.
LAURA: That's true.
MATT: "I could part with them for around three
copper?"
LAURA: That is a good deal, sir, and I will give
you the copper.
TALIESIN: Do you need more copper? Are you all
right?
LAURA: No, hold on. No, I've got copper around
somewhere.
TALIESIN: Okay, because I'll give you two copper
if I get one of those pickles.
LAURA: Okay! Here, I pick some lint off one of the
coppers that I have.
MATT: He takes the copper from you.
TALIESIN: I pass him the two copper.
MATT: He takes the copper from you. Slides forward
the pickles and goes, (laughs) "Good deal!"
LIAM: Excuse me. I just inhaled my own spit.
MATT: "Don't do that! That is not conducive to a
lengthy lifetime."
LIAM: (Speak N Spell voice) I am okay. (as Caleb)
I am needing a very fine kind of incense, and I
don't know if that is the type of thing this
establishment would carry, but it's very
important. Do you have that sort of thing?
MATT: "You want incense? That's fancy."
LIAM: I'm sorry, it's very noisy in the shop. What
did you say?
MATT: "It's really fancy, them incense."
LIAM: Well, look at me. Can you not tell how fancy
I am?
MATT: "That's why I'm curious."
LIAM: Well. You know, I've been on the road a long
time and I'm carrying a smell with me, if you
cannot tell.
MATT: "I got incense!"
LIAM: To the point, I like it. I would like to
spend about 20 gold worth of incense. Do you have
that much? I don't mean cheap shit.
MATT: "What kind of establishment do you take me
for?"
LIAM: Well, it's a barn, ja?
MATT: "Touch." He wanders away from there and
gathers any semblance of anything that could be
considered incense to some degree. It's a massive
volume, it's-- when he said quality over quantity,
this is definitely a quantity circumstance. Two big
burlap sacks filled with all sorts of fine ground
herbs and things that could amount to--
LIAM: I would like to make an insight check to
make sure it's not oregano.
MATT: Go for it.
LIAM: Come on, where's the druid? That's what
would be for oregano. That's Vex. This one.
LAURA: But she would know if you were swindling.
LIAM: Perception?
MATT: No, that'll be insight.
LIAM: Insight? Oh, that's much better. That is an
elf.
TRAVIS and LAURA: A what?
MATT: An elf.
LIAM: Elf. 11. You just learned something,
everybody. It's 11 in German.
MATT: He seems to be doing the best he can.
LIAM: Good. This is really good. I will give you
17 gold for all this.
MATT: "Deal!"
LIAM: One. Two. (continues counting)
SAM: While he's counting this out, is there anyone
else in the store? Anyone at all?
MATT: At this point, there's three other people in
the store, and they're slowly filtering out.
SAM: Do I see any little trinkets or anything?
Little brass things? Little baby bottles? Anything?
MATT: It seems that most everything they have
here-- a lot of them are basic farming supplies.
There are a few metallic joints that could be used
for when you're tapping a keg. They have some keg
taps there. They have-- oh my god.
LAURA: You're such a dick.
LIAM: 16.
SAM: Oh, that one fell.
LIAM: 16. And I push the 16 gold forward.
MATT: (slamming) "I appreciate your patronage."
LIAM: These are heavy.
TALIESIN: I know this may be a stretch, but do you
have maybe any healing potions or anything like
that? Or maybe-- this might be weird-- some kind
of poisons maybe?
MATT: "That's pretty weird. I'm going to say
there, sir, I mean you look pretty weird. That's a
"pretty weird request. No, we do not carry
poisons."
TALIESIN: For dealing with pests on a farm. That
sort of thing.
MATT: "We have insecticides."
TALIESIN: Think that will work on a gnoll?
TRAVIS: Yeah! Insecticide. Pesticide. Herbicide.
MARISHA: An insecticide generally refers to
insects. And we're talking gnolls.
LAURA: But it's usually poison you put--
TRAVIS: Yeah, but you ever chugged a bunch of
insecticide? That's a bad day.
TALIESIN: Stuff is stuff, it's bad for anybody. I
guess.
LIAM: Is it flammable? Do I know if it's
flammable?
MARISHA and TALIESIN: How much is it?
MATT: "For about a vial that big? A silver."
MARISHA: You're going to have to use a lot.
TALIESIN: What would that really-- If I were to
drink that right now, what do you think that would
do to me?
MATT: "Probably have some real serious shits
for a few days."
TRAVIS: It's like Visine.
TALIESIN: Wow, really?
SAM: May I examine it?
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: Okay. I'm going to look at it. Smell it. Look
at the fluid. Do I know anything about this
chemical at all?
MATT: You do. It's a very diluted form of acute
poison, to the point where it wouldn't actually
affect any larger creature. But if put in a large
batch of water used to spray down crops, certain
insects-- what are they called again? I forget--
aphids, things like that would die off.
SAM: Aphids? Oh, that's nothing. It won't really
do much.
TALIESIN: Do you know about these sorts of
things?
SAM: Sometimes. Not a lot.
TALIESIN: That's very impressive.
LIAM: Nott, you're selling yourself short.
SAM: Speaking of-- and I'll ask him for the
components to make acid. Does he have that stuff?
MATT: Yeah. In a very Anarchist Cookbook kind of
way. He doesn't sell you acid, but there are the
materials available where you could create it.
SAM: Okay. How much for all this shit?
(laughter)
MATT: How many vials' worth are you looking for?
SAM: Just one.
MATT: Just one? "This will run you about 12
gold."
SAM: All right. That's fine.
LAURA: Oh, can you throw a med kit in there
with it, if you have any left?
MATT: He looks around. "I'm afraid we're clear
out. Bit of a-- "
LAURA: You have things going on.
MATT: "Lot of things. Sorry."
LAURA: It's fine.
MATT: "My apologies."
LAURA: No, it's okay. I have this pickle.
MATT: "It's a good pickle."
TALIESIN: It was.
MARISHA: Is it a good pickle, though?
LAURA: I haven't tried it. I just drank the juice,
but he ate it.
TALIESIN: I ate mine. It was quite good. Now we're
just sharing the juice at this point.
MARISHA: Guys, let's go kill gnolls.
TRAVIS: Just the juice?
TALIESIN: Juice is great!
TRAVIS: It is. With a little whiskey.
MATT: (groans)
MARISHA and LAURA: Picklebacks!
MATT: Brine drinkers.
MARISHA: Nom nom nom!
TRAVIS: Like cheeseburger in a shot glass.
MARISHA: Yeah, so good!
MATT: Ugh, stop it.
LAURA: Are we prepared now to go?
SAM: Wait, no.
LIAM: No, I have things to do.
SAM: Do you sell any healing potions?
TALIESIN: I asked that.
SAM: You asked that already?
TALIESIN: Yeah, I did ask that.
SAM: Oh. Never mind!
MATT: "We're not really purveyors of healing
potions, and those that have are usually held by
"the Crownsguard."
TALIESIN: Wait, the Crownsguard? Really?
LAURA: We didn't ask Bryce for any healing
potions.
TALIESIN: We should ask Bryce for some healing
MATT: You actually asked the night before, and
Bryce had said that they're currently being used
to tend to the people that were in really bad
places. It's hard to walk through a war zone and
be like, "Hey guys! Do you have supplies?"
TRAVIS: What do you need to do for the rest of the
day, Caleb?
LIAM: Well, I would really like to get my cat
back, so I would need about an hour to go do a
little stuff. Do you have anything else to do?
LAURA: I mean, there are people getting chopped up
and eaten. But if you really want a cat.
LIAM: What are we doing? Are we taking our cart?
TALIESIN: Take the cart? And get some meat from
the butcher?
LAURA: We might be able to go faster.
TRAVIS: I think if we were a little spread it
would help.
LIAM: Well, okay. Maybe I can put it on hold,
although I really hate to. But let's come up with
what are we doing? What is the plan?
TRAVIS: Well, I would follow the direction they
left last night. See if we can find a trail.
SAM: We're just going to go into the belly of the
beast? Because one of them shot me and killed me
with an arrow. We could draw them out.
TRAVIS: Yeah, you just stay behind Caleb. You'll
be fine.
LAURA: You didn't die, Nott. I saved you.
SAM: Thank you so much, but I don't want to be in
that predicament again! Can we draw them out somehow?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
SAM: They are fond of meat. Here's my idea. We
stage a barbecue contest. Finest in the land! All
the best barbecue will be there! And then, when
they come to sample our wares, I run and you kill them.
TRAVIS: You know, I love that idea. Small thing,
though. Time, again, is of the essence.
SAM: Because you want to slow cook that stuff to
be really good. It's true.
TRAVIS: Right. Dry aged. Really get a good hickory
chip under them. Problem is, people might be dying
in the meantime. So if we could find a more
expedient solution?
LIAM: Oh, so were you thinking of having a
barbecue here or setting up a barbecue on the road?
LAURA: I'm think in the middle of a field, yes. So
that it's--
LIAM: Just a random field?
LAURA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: It'll take a while to make the signage
alone.
LAURA: So it seems like less of a trap.
TRAVIS: Beau had an idea! Get them, Beau! You tell
her--
MARISHA: No, you take it for her, please.
TRAVIS: Beau had a fantastic observation. If we
happen to see one of those beasts of burden on
our way out tracking, maybe we could wrangle one
up and use it as a bait.
LAURA: And if we don't see one, then Fjord, you're
the biggest.
TALIESIN: That's fair.
LIAM: Either way, we will probably need the
cart.
TALIESIN: We could also see what they still have
at the butcher's.
TRAVIS: To bring people back.
LAURA: And bring people back!
SAM: And maybe one extra horse.
MARISHA: What did you say, Molly?
TALIESIN: Or we could see what else they still
have at the butcher's. There's a butcher.
MARISHA: Well, the butcher got severely cleaned
out.
TALIESIN: Well, we just heard that, he might--
TRAVIS: I think you're right. Extra horse. We need
the cart.
LIAM: To carry one of those beasts if we kill
one.
MARISHA: If we can try and figure out a way to
set up our operation on the edge of the forest so
that we're not in the middle of a field, in the
open--
LIAM: Well, is the point to try to-- I'm sorry, no,
you finish your thought.
MARISHA: Hills are bad to fight in, unless you're
on top of the hill. That's good.
LIAM: I'm not a tactician, but I have a question.
MARISHA: Go ahead.
LIAM: Are we trying to go back to these things where they
live? Their lair, their home, their camp? Or are
we hoping to luck into them on the road or--?
TRAVIS: I think we'd be making a best guess at this
point. My best hope is to find out where they are.
What it looks like where they're staying, and if
we can, without confrontation, get some survivors
out of there. That would be ideal.
LIAM: I like that idea as well.
MARISHA: Actually, that's not a bad idea at all.
Maybe we could have like a survivor round up team
and a defense team?
LAURA: But then how do we get all of the ears?
TRAVIS: I'm just putting it out there: maybe
survivors before ears.
MARISHA: We can always go back out and get more
ears whenever we damn feel like it.
LIAM: Well, that's the thing. We can do both, but
there is a timestamp on the people. We should take
care of the people first. Because then we're
increasing how much gold we will bring in because
if they die then we will not get as much money for
them if they are alive. We should get them alive.
Get them out. Kill the baddies if we can at the
same time, and if not, go back a second time.
TRAVIS: I thought you said you weren't a
tactician, look at you!
SAM: He's very smart.
TALIESIN: Extremely tactile.
TRAVIS: Caleb's plan! Let's do it!
LIAM: No social graces. Let's do this.
MARISHA: Let's go!
TRAVIS and MARISHA: Break!
SAM: Are we getting another horse?
LAURA: We're going to ask Bryce if they have a
horse to spare.
SAM: Why don't you four go get horses? Me and the
C-man will go get some incense and stuff.
TRAVIS: C-man? I thought I was the seaman? Fucking
get your titles right. Come on, brother, you know
you want to! I'm a proud son of a bitch!
SAM: Sorry! You're a seaman.
LIAM: Wait, so now we need time?
TALIESIN: We're going to go get a horse, you don't
need to be here for that.
LIAM: Oh god. I really want my cat, but maybe--
SAM: Let's go get some incense! I need to buy some
tarts.
LIAM: We'll get the tarts. Maybe it would be
handier as a bird.
LAURA: You need a tart?
SAM: I need a tart.
LAURA: Oh, well, why didn't you say something?
Hold on, let me dig.
SAM: That's a bag of pastries!
LAURA: There's this one--
SAM: Wow!
LAURA: Hold on. I think there's a blackberry one
somewhere in here.
SAM: Ooh, I can't tell what this used to be.
LAURA: It's kind of gross; I'm sorry.
SAM: Is that the top or the bottom?
LAURA: I can't tell anymore. It's all black.
Sorry!
SAM: I have two tarts!
MATT: Yes. Very stale.
SAM: I'm taking them.
MATT: You can't tell if the sour smell is
intentional flavor or just time taking its toll.
It'll be tart one way or the other.
TRAVIS: Do we see any crownsguard around? In the
street.
MATT: Over time you will. They're scattered a bit
thin and a lot of them are currently focused on
either perimeter watch, in case they come back, or
helping out those that need help inside the city.
TRAVIS: I'd just like to find one, if I could.
MATT: Within ten minutes of wandering through the
city as you guys have gathered yourselves and
begun heading towards the eastern side, you see a
crownsguard who is currently walking by with some
washrags under one arm and a little streak of
dried blood down the side of their face. Looks to
be a young man probably in his mid-20s or so.
Longish hair that's been heavily braided on the
sides and then pinned to the back in a tuft of a
ponytail.
TRAVIS: Howdy!
MATT: "Yes?"
TRAVIS: Sorry to bother, but we've been
commissioned by Bryce to make a little expedition
to go after those gnolls and we're going to need
an extra steed if the Crownsguard has one.
MATT: "We're not allowed to give out any
Crownsguard supplies. If you're looking for a
"steed, you'd probably have to go to the On the Wind
Stables. They're going to be your best bet."
TRAVIS: Where would those be?
MATT: "Right--" and points over towards the
northern side of the town. It's one of the
buildings that's taken a little bit of fire
damage.
TRAVIS: Are you concerned about the people that
live in this town? Clock's ticking on their lives
and you want me to go get a steed from another
stable instead of saving their lives?
MATT: "It's not--"
TRAVIS: I sure would hate to have to report this
to Bryce. I think they'd be pretty upset about it.
MATT: Make a deception check.
TRAVIS: 13.
MATT: "Look, I mean no offense whatsoever and if--
I can go find Bryce and see if we-- the
"Watchmaster would be much more suited to--"
TRAVIS: Your name?
MATT: "Reggie."
TRAVIS: Reggie. I'm disappointed, Reggie. I don't
know what else to say. Let's go.
(laughter)
LAURA: Should we go to the stables then?
TRAVIS: Fuck yeah. Now!
LIAM: Reggie, this town has been hit hard, you
look very weary and maybe a little down on your
luck yourself. Maybe I'm just reading into things,
but I would gladly pay you a silver for this horse.
TALIESIN: Let me tell you, Reggie, it would be the
best deal you could possibly make. I'm going to
use Charm Person.
MATT: Did not make that DC check. Reggie glances
over at you. He goes, "Let me see what I can do,"
and quickly makes his way northward to the outside
of the stables.
TRAVIS: Very nice!
TALIESIN: Thank you!
MATT: About five minutes pass and you can hear the
clopping of hooves as Reggie comes back with a
very obstinate beast on the reins. Dragging it
towards you, slowly guiding it. Reggie doesn't
seem to be a very trained individual when it comes
to handling creatures, especially beasts of
burden. "Will this do?"
MARISHA: Oh good, I see you brought us your best,
Reggie. Thanks, man.
TALIESIN: Ignore her, she's very difficult.
MATT: Hands you the reins.
TALIESIN: You're a hero. Thank you.
MATT: "Best I could do. Good luck."
LIAM: Here's that copper. Thank you.
MATT: "Thank you."
TALIESIN: I hand him a silver also.
MATT: "Thank you. Thank you."
LIAM: Silver's way too little for a horse.
TALIESIN: You said silver and we're being fair!
MATT: "Just bring it back-- it's on loan! It's on
loan."
TALIESIN: If we come back, it comes back.
LAURA: Probably. We definitely won't use it as
bait for the gnolls. Okay, bye!
TRAVIS: We make our way over to where we left our
other horse and cart.
MATT: Okay, easy enough to find. You placed it at
a hitching post with a little bit of feed over the
evening. Your cart and horse are safe and at your
disposal.
MARISHA: I saw them take off into the forest. I
tracked a little bit right between those trees. I
don't know, we can start there.
LAURA: I bet they left a lot of tracks and
probably some cart things.
TRAVIS: I don't know why, I thought you were going
to say they left behind poop.
LAURA: They probably did! Oh my god! They weren't
wearing any underwear, were they?
MATT: They were wearing cobbled-together or
scavenged bits of leather and hide armors.
LAURA: But did it have holes for their butts?
MATT: It seemed like most of them would have had
some means of disposing of their excrement.
LIAM: They don't care, they're swinging low and
leaving it behind.
MATT: They weren't very well-dressed.
TRAVIS: If that's the direction you saw them head
off in, check it out.
MARISHA: I'll be on the lookout for cart tracks.
LIAM: As we go, and also, we didn't have time, so
here, off you go. I will sit in the cart and go blind.
MATT: Okay. While you are sending Frumpkin to
keep a watch, you are keeping an eye out
for tracks. Make a survival check, please.
MARISHA: It's not my strongest, but it's okay.
LAURA: I'm keeping an eye out for poop.
MARISHA: 16. No wait! I rolled a natural 16, so
19! I thought it was a 13; I apologize.
MATT: Very quickly you come upon a number of gnoll
footprints in the ground. Seem to be multiple cart
tracks. That was the one that you saw.
LAURA: (gasps) Oh no!
MARISHA: Wait, are there nearby towns? Are there
other nearby villages?
MATT: There were multiple carts.
MARISHA: Oh, we only saw one.
LIAM: The last one.
MARISHA: Okay, can I get like an odd estimate of
maybe how many gnolls we might be dealing with
based on the amount of tracks?
MATT: With that roll, I'd say you surmise
somewhere in the neighborhood of about 18 or so
gnolls. From what you can gather on the tracks
that you found.
TALIESIN: Would my Hunter's Bane be useful for
that? For tracking these creatures?
MATT: You can attempt to glean information.
TALIESIN: Since they technically have some undead
around them?
MATT: For the specific-- sure. Go ahead and make a
survival check to see if you can even find those tracks.
TALIESIN: Just a standard one? Standard survival
check. All right.
MATT: Well, technically you're tracking undead, so
you get advantage on this one.
TALIESIN: 17.
MATT: Same degree. You find the tracks, you see
there is the remnants of this gnoll horde
returning towards a similar direction. You find
three sets of cart tracks.
MARISHA: I turn to the rest of the group and I go:
Good news, we're real stupid if we thought we
couldn't track them, because there's a fuckton of
them. That'll be easy. Bad news is, oh god,
there's a fuckton of them. That's it.
TRAVIS: Yeah, that is bad news. Are the carts all
heading in the same direction or would they split up?
MATT: They all converge into one path. They head
through the relatively thin woods that surround
the northeastern side of Alfield. As you progress
on that path out to the other side of the woods,
continue into the northeastern fields where the
rolling hills begin, these hills seem to go on for miles.
LIAM: Frumpkin would be in the air 300-400 feet in
front of the cart and I wouldn't do 100% of the
time, but I would talk for three minutes and then maybe
go: hold on one sec (magic sound effect) and then
come back. So intermittent.
MATT: Go ahead and make a perception check.
TRAVIS: Tall grass on these rolling hills?
MARISHA: Or is it just open fucking hills?
TRAVIS: Picked by beasts or--
MATT: No, no. It's tall grass across the hills--
LIAM: Seven.
MATT: The grass can vary anywhere from knee-high
to chest-high in places. The hills towards the
top can get a little more rocky. There are patches
where the grass doesn't grow as well and there's
open dirt and broken shale. After about an hour or
so of tracking in that direction, you come upon the
Rillway Road, which is the main road that heads up
towards Felderwin. You can see it a little ways off.
LIAM: Also, in this time I would have told the
rest of the group: Before Nott and I arrived in
Trostenwald, just outside the city limits, we were
waylaid by gnolls previously and they were hiding
in grass just like this. It was very much like
this so we should be-- I'm getting very nervous
right now looking at it all.
TALIESIN: In theory, am I actively tracking these
creatures? The undead at least.
MATT: The undead tracks are falling in line with
her tracking. They're moving as a group, but there
are far less undead tracks than there are regular
gnolls, so as best you can to keep tabs on it.
TALIESIN: I'm curious how much of this Hunter's
Bane I can actually be using right now.
MATT: You'd be leading if she hadn't made an
equally good roll, so now both of you are leading this.
TRAVIS: The grass, is it dead or vibrant
green?
MATT: Vibrant green, for the most part. The wind
is picking up a little bit and you can see,
especially when you start coming up over some of
the bigger hills, you can see the waves cresting over
the hillside and causing the shift of it. It's a
very beautiful space.
TRAVIS: Is it still the morning hour or about
midday?
MATT: At this point now, you've been travelling,
we'll say an hour and a half. It's getting close
to noon.
TRAVIS: High noon?
MATT: Yes.
LIAM: You know, I know it's actually about 11:37,
so we're not quite there yet. By the position of
the sun.
TRAVIS: Oh no! Don't do it! Oh no!
(nervous laughter)
TALIESIN: He's sorry!
TRAVIS: It was right there!
MATT: I know. Anyway.
LIAM: Beholder!
MATT: Don't think I'm not tempted.
MARISHA: How rough and how open is our situation
right now? Are we in the middle of an open field?
MATT: You're pretty much in the middle of an open
field. But the tracks you can see-- Because you
can see the Rillway Road south of you and the
tracks begin to shift further north. As they were
heading back, they were keeping off the road best
they can as well. You also do notice that within
the tracks you do find bits of grass that are
spattered with drying blood. You don't know how
fresh it is. Go ahead and make a perception
check.
MARISHA: Remember how I was like, this is the
worst situation to be in?
TRAVIS: Mm-hmm.
MARISHA: I feel like this might be the worst
situation to be in.
TRAVIS: Right.
MARISHA: Survival?
MATT: Perception.
MARISHA: Perception? Oh no. Did you see that?
LAURA: It's a one?
MARISHA: One.
MATT: As you're having this conversation with
Fjord, you're just not paying attention to the
road in front of you.
MARISHA: God.
LAURA: If we're sitting in the cart, is the grass
taller than us or is it way lower than us?
MATT: No, it's about as tall as the cart at times,
at times it's lower. You guys do stand out amongst
the grass. As you head over the hills, or down
below, you are above the grass line without an issue.
LIAM: Walking on the ground as a human, is it up
to here, or--
MATT: Yeah, it's about up to your chest at times.
Waist to chest. It varies.
LAURA: If I stand up in the cart as we go, can I
see out into the grass?
MATT: Yeah, if you wanted.
MARISHA: What if I gave Jester a ride on my
shoulders? While we walked.
SAM: On a moving cart?
MATT: What could possibly go wrong?
LIAM: You've seen Teen Wolf, ja?
MARISHA: In the cart, and I'm holding you. It'd be
kind of cool!
MATT: I'll allow it. Go ahead and make a
perception check, Jester.
LIAM: Here goes all Jester's teeth.
LAURA: 19!
MATT: Make a strength check.
MARISHA: Okay. Like a saving throw or just a
check?
MATT: Just a check.
LIAM: Come on, roll a 20. Make it happen.
MARISHA: That's okay. It's a 14.
MATT: Right as your eyes catch something, you drop
for a second, but Beau's beneath you (groans) just
barely holding you, the elbows start to buckle a
bit, but rallies and (groans) holds you up above.
You flatten your back out and give a graceful pose
as you look ahead.
LAURA: I'm flying! I'm flying, Jack!
MARISHA: (strained) Yeah, you are!
TRAVIS: King of the world!
MATT: As you guys are coming up over a hill, you
get a good view down, and you can see between the
tall grass and the high weeds that are beginning
to cluster this vicinity, there is a series of
large hills that all break down into this valley
where the grass just ends in this area. It looks
like it's barren rock and dirt. You notice, with
that perception check, a few carts, a few broken
boxes, some tables or contraptions. There's some
semblance of civilization here amongst these hills
off the road.
LAURA: (gasps) There's carts! I see the carts! I
jump up and down in her hands.
MARISHA: Oh god-- (grunts)
SAM: Are there people in the carts?
MATT: She drops you.
LAURA: Oh, are there people in the carts? Can I
see?
MATT: They appear to be empty.
LAURA: They're empty!
SAM: Abandoned?
LAURA: Maybe.
SAM: I'm going to start drinking.
MARISHA: Jester, I'm going to put you down.
MATT: Okay. How much do you drink?
SAM: I'm going to take three big swigs.
MATT: Okay, good to know.
LIAM: I would like to use Frumpkin to do a
once-around from above to see if any of those
beasts are on the horizon anywhere for us to kill,
and also if there are any survivors or anything here.
MATT: Perception check for Frumpkin.
LIAM: That is a 13.
MATT: 13, good to know.
LAURA: Should we pull the cart over and sneak up?
TRAVIS: Yes. By foot is how we should proceed.
LAURA: Okay. Let's pull the cart over and hide it
in the grass.
MARISHA: Yeah. I help Jester hide the cart.
LAURA: Oh, but our horses. What if they get
eaten?
SAM: (nervous) It's all right. It's fine. We don't
care about the horses. Let's just save ourselves.
Who cares about the horses?
LAURA: But how are we going to get all the people
back if we don't have horses to pull the cart?
SAM: That's true.
LIAM: From 100 feet up, I can see through
Frumpkin's eyes all of us being a bunch of dumb
fucks in the back of the cart.
MATT: It's true.
SAM: Should we leave someone back to protect the
horses?
TRAVIS: No.
MARISHA: Seems a waste.
TRAVIS: Would you want to be the one person that
got attacked with the horses by yourself?
SAM: No.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I didn't think so. We stick
together.
SAM: All right. I'll be part of the Fjord
expedition.
(laughter and groaning)
LIAM: The crew! The crew groaned!
LAURA: I heard a groan.
SAM: That wasn't a groan, that was like-- ugh.
LIAM: Disgust?
TALIESIN: That was nausea!
MATT: I feel like I passed a stone.
TRAVIS: Yep. Now I'm ready to die.
(laughter)
MATT: All right, what's the plan, guys?
LAURA: I'm going to-- does anybody have to
sneeze?
TRAVIS and SAM: What?
LAURA: Anybody feel like they need to--
TALIESIN: Should we?
SAM: Sneeze? What? Why--
TRAVIS: That would give away our stealthy
approach.
SAM: Oh. I see.
LAURA: Because... Bless you! I give you Blessing of
the Trickster.
TRAVIS: Holy shit.
LIAM: I was waiting for the punchline.
TALIESIN: What does Blessing of the Trickster do?
LAURA: You have advantage on stealth.
TALIESIN: I have advantage on "smealth," that's
great.
MATT: "Smealth."
TALIESIN: On "smealth." He who "smealth" it.
MATT: Mm-hmm. All right, what are you guys doing
with the cart and the horses?
LAURA: We're hiding it in the tall grass.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: No rocks around, right? No stones or
boulders in the field?
MATT: Not that big. The hills themselves are--
it's just large rolling hills in this whole valley area.
TRAVIS: I was trying to get it in the depression
of a rolling hill and just--
MATT: Okay. You have to back up a bit to get it
out of view.
LIAM: I'd like to point out that we came up with a
loose plan, but we're not doing that plan.
LAURA: What was our loose plan? We didn't see any
of them?
TRAVIS: We haven't seen anything yet.
MARISHA: We're not in any tree line or anything.
LIAM: Also, in a pinch, we could kill the horses.
TRAVIS: Kill the horses? Oh, to use as-- that's
right, we could.
LAURA: But we won't be able to pull the cart. I'm
really strong, but I don't know if I can carry
that many people.
SAM: She's lying, she's not really strong.
LAURA: I am really strong, though.
SAM: Really?
TALIESIN: We wouldn't have to kill the horse, we
could just send the horse--
TRAVIS: Let's find out what we see first, and then
we'll decide.
TALIESIN: Sure. Recon.
LAURA: That's not normally how you test strength.
SAM: I don't know, I'm not strong.
MARISHA: Let's flank. Around.
TRAVIS: Everybody fan out in a firing line, just
one straight line--
SAM: We're going away from each other?
TRAVIS: Just within eye distance, right? But keep
a line.
TALIESIN: Answered my question. I was curious what
flanking was.
TRAVIS: Keep in line. We're going to move towards
the cart. We're going to use the tall grass.
LAURA: Towards the three carts?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MARISHA: Do we need to have some sort of awesome
whistle or something? To communicate with each other?
TRAVIS: I'm open to it, if you have any.
MARISHA: Oh, what was that thing you did in the
circus? That was cool.
(whistling)
LIAM: (spitting noise) I can't do that.
(various whistling noises)
LIAM: How about we don't make any noise at all,
but we just sneak in?
TRAVIS: Yeah, let's do that.
MATT: Having placed the cart where what you assume
is the best you can hide it, who is helming the
hiding of the cart?
LAURA: Me!
MATT: Go ahead and make a survival check.
LIAM: I will also help with that.
MATT: All right. If you're aiding, then do it with
advantage.
LIAM: Okay. Lift with the legs!
LAURA: 13.
MATT: Okay. I mean, sure.
LAURA: I get some grass and I put it on the cart.
SAM: Put your alarm around the cart! You do it all
the time!
LIAM: Do we have the time for that right now?
SAM: How long does it take to cast?
LIAM: Right now, it will take me 11 minutes to do
that.
LAURA: Yeah, do it, do it!
TRAVIS: People's lives. Urgency. Clock. Time. All
that stuff.
LAURA: Ten minutes. Okay.
SAM: All right, let's just go.
MATT: What is the marching order?
LIAM: We're coming in as a line together.
MATT: All right. What's the order of the line,
then?
TRAVIS: We're all even moving forward.
LAURA: But what is the order of the line?
SAM: I'm to the left of Caleb there on the end.
LIAM: I don't want to be on an end. I don't want
you to be on the end.
TRAVIS: I don't mind being on an end. How about
that?
MARISHA: Yeah, I imagine that the ends are going
to be where you need the most strength, right?
LIAM: I would grab Nott by the shoulder and pull
us into the middle somehow.
TRAVIS: You want to be in the middle?
LIAM: Yes.
SAM: Let's walk with Molly. There. Boom. Got it.
MARISHA: Great.
MATT: All right. We have: Molly, Nott, Caleb,
Jester, Beau, then Fjord. Okay. I would like you
all to make a stealth check, please. As you make
your way through the grass.
TALIESIN: That helps.
SAM: 21.
TRAVIS: 15.
MARISHA: 16.
LIAM: 12.
TALIESIN: 16.
LAURA: Ten.
LIAM: Those monster calves.
MATT: As you guys stay low to the grass, pushing
through with your hands carefully as you go,
hearing the wind occasionally rise and fall with a
distant (shh), the various waves of grass beating
against itself, you come upon where the grass
begins to fall off. You stay low as best you can
before the grass itself comes to an end right on
the outskirts of where the central area between
these hills begins. There, as you poke your head
through, you can see three carts that are
scattered a bit amongst a mineshaft yard. The
exterior of a mine. You can see large, wooden pan
tables; some pickaxes that are leaning against the
side, the remnants of some lanterns that have
rusted. There are the three carts. The carts
themselves are spattered with blood. You notice
three creatures, similar to the gnolls that you
saw the night before, but smaller and dog-like.
These are just basic hyenas that are gathered
around and are licking the blood that's soaked
into the wood. One of them ends up finding a piece
of meat, or something that was hanging from one
side, and tears it off. Another one comes over
(whines) and bites onto it, and they begin tearing
and fighting over it before one of them pushes the
other over and it (yelps). It goes back and begins
licking the blood off the side of the wood. These
three hyenas are just scavenging on the outskirt
of these carts.
SAM: They're just hyenas? They're not magical,
undead hyenas?
MATT: Not from what you can tell.
TRAVIS: Can we see how many entrances there are to
this mine yard?
MATT: From this distance, you can't see any
entrances.
MARISHA: Do you think they're centurions?
LIAM: I think they're going to make a big fucking
stink if we--
MARISHA: If they see us? I'll bet they're the alert
system.
LAURA: (whispers) We should kill them!
MARISHA: But we have to kill them all at once.
LIAM: That is correct.
TRAVIS: I could make a distraction. Nott, Beau,
are y'all fast, quick, and quiet?
SAM: Yes.
LAURA: Sure.
TRAVIS: Who else?
SAM: No, just us.
TALIESIN: I'm quietish.
TRAVIS: There's three of them, right?
MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: All right.
MARISHA: You want to try and make a distraction
and bring them closer? To us? Then we can jump out
of the grass? Do the old "jump out of the
grass--"
TRAVIS: About how far from the edge of the grass,
where we are, to them?
MATT: About 50 or so feet. 60 feet.
TRAVIS: Can I use Minor Illusion to create a plump
little bunny and have it hop out of the grass? But
its front leg looks a little lame.
MARISHA: Oh, buddy.
MATT: Quietly, this plump, wounded, with a hint of
pink to the fur around the arm where it looks like
it may have been bleeding a bit, begins to hobble
its way silently out of the grass, just beyond the edge.
SAM: I'm going to hide.
LAURA: Yeah, I'm going to hide.
MATT: You guys are still hidden.
TALIESIN: I'm going to draw one of my swords and,
just out of experiment, try and get it to do that
weird thing it did yesterday. With my hand.
MATT: You initiate the Rite, and as you do, the
blade begins to give a faint, radiant glow, a
whitish-yellow light that you will almost
instinctually hold low in the grass to make sure
you don't become a beacon amongst your hiding. You
watch as one of the hyenas (sniffing) and begins
making its way. The others look over (snarl)--
they begin to gather up, and the three almost go
into this pack swoop formation in the direction of
the rabbit, closing in. 40 feet, 30 feet, 20 feet.
With a rapid bolt, one of them runs forward and
leaps out towards the rabbit and skids into the
dirt past it, right to the front of the grassline
where you are, Beau.
TRAVIS: Now!
MARISHA: (slamming)
LAURA: I use Sacred Flame on the one next it.
MATT: Okay, and who is doing what else?
TALIESIN: I'm going to stab the third one.
MATT: The three of you rush out and attack, three
individual ones. What are you guys doing?
LIAM: I will send Frumpkin down to the one that
Jester's attacking, right up against it to
distract and chirp in its face.
MATT: All right. Beau, go ahead and attack first.
MARISHA: I'm going to take the blunt end of the
staff and go right for it as it skids by, I'm
going to take right in its neck. Ooh, not great.
Ten.
MATT: Ten? You go to swing, and as it sees you
suddenly, it backs away, and your staff hits the
dirt right next to it. (snarls) It just barely
misses it. Caleb, you following up?
LIAM: Caleb sends Frumpkin right down to the
one that Jester was attacking and I will send out
a Fire Bolt at the same time.
MATT: Go for it. Roll your attack roll for the
Fire Bolt.
LIAM: That's at advantage if my birdie is
bothering him up close.
MATT: Right. Okay. Wait, you're going for the one
that Jester is attacking?
LIAM: Yeah, the one that Jester is attacking.
MATT: Okay. Go for it.
LIAM: That is-- oh, that's good. That is 21.
MATT: 21 hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
LIAM: These spells are all still new to me. Oh, that's a
big one.
MATT: One point of damage.
LIAM: Big one point of damage.
MATT: It begins to burn this small circular image
on the hyena's body. (yelping)
Go ahead and--
LAURA: It just has to make a dex save of over 13.
MATT: With a natural one, he does not.
LAURA: Yay. Then he gets four more damage,
radiant.
MATT: That's enough. With the blast of the Fire
Bolt, and the incineration of the Sacred Flame,
you watch as that hyena bursts into fire and flops
to the ground while it burns, smouldering, its
flesh becoming the meals it had previously feasted
upon. Molly and Nott?
TALIESIN: I'll take my run first? That's a-- wow.
17. My brain.
MATT: That hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
TALIESIN: That's seven points, plus three radiant.
MATT: The first strike just completely cleaves it
in half, like its momentum, running, almost like
it hits the blade, and you hold it out and the
momentum just carries it over, seamlessly carving
through it.
TALIESIN: Am I close enough to hit the third one
that's still left with my second attack?
MATT: You can have movement to close it. There's
one right in front of Beau, so you're a little
ways away, but you can close the gap, while Nott
and--
MARISHA: I didn't get my bonus attack on that guy.
Can I get my bonus attack?
MATT: Yep!
MARISHA: Okay. I want to try and bring my heel
down on top of it as it tries to scooch away.
Fucking-- did you see that?
TRAVIS: I did.
LIAM: Yep. 17 to a three.
LAURA: You need to not use that dice for the rest
of the night.
MARISHA: Nine.
MATT: Nine.
MATT: Nine, again!
SAM and TALIESIN: Nein!
MATT: At first it hits the dirt, and it backs up.
You move out with your heel to go ahead and swing,
and it actually ducks underneath and tries to snap
at your heel, as Molly closes the gap, and--
TRAVIS: Would you like to go?
SAM: I release my bolt at that same one.
MATT: All right.
SAM: 20.
MATT: All right. Go ahead and roll damage. With
sneak attack.
SAM: 13.
MATT: Yeah, Molly, as you rush up, you watch as a
bolt just goes right through the side of the
hyena's head, and it just falls lifeless to the
ground. All three of them out in a split second.
TRAVIS: I don't want to, like, make y'all alarmed
or anything, but that was kind of fucking efficient.
LAURA: Everybody but Beau, you were missing like
crazy on that one.
MARISHA: You know, I had a long day yesterday,
okay?
TRAVIS: Hands are sweaty?
MARISHA: Just was faster than I thought.
LAURA: Hey, look! We can use this hyena meat as
bait!
TRAVIS: You're right.
SAM: I'm going to go pull my bolt out of the
thing. Is it recoverable?
TALIESIN: Good shot.
MATT: Yeah, thankfully it was a clean enough shot,
didn't seem to get caught or shatter against any
of the bones.
TRAVIS: Quick perimeter check to see if we alerted
anything, anything's looking at us.
MATT: Perception check.
TRAVIS: Natural 19.
MATT: Glancing about the vicinity, does not look
like anything else is moving or near or has
noticed your presence.
TRAVIS: Move to the cart, quick check of anything
left behind, clues.
SAM: Do we need to drag these bodies?
TRAVIS: There's no bodies, just blood spatter.
MARISHA: Do you mean the hyenas?
SAM: The hyenas.
TRAVIS: Oh. We've got to figure out where we're
going first.
TALIESIN: I'm also going to point out, they hadn't
been eating the hyenas anyway, so maybe leaving
bodies of their pets is not the greatest idea?
LAURA: Toss them into the grass, then, to get them
out of view?
TALIESIN: That might be a smarter way to go.
TRAVIS: Do it.
LAURA: Okay, I'll pick them up and throw them as
far as I can into the grass.
MATT: Okay. Like a massive shotput, you watch as
tiny Jester, with a double spin each, chucks these
relatively heavy beasts deep into the grass field,
where they vanish with a heavy thud into the field.
LIAM: She's like Miss Trunchbull from Matilda.
TRAVIS: You're a lot stronger than you look.
LAURA: Thank you! Hey, what happened to the little
bunny, though? I'm going to look for the little
white rabbit.
TALIESIN: Oh dear.
MATT: Bunny appears to no longer be around.
LAURA: That's really sad, they ate it.
TRAVIS: Yeah, boy, sure did.
SAM: We'll have a funeral later.
TALIESIN: I'm going to keep a hold of my sword,
but I'm going to wrap it in the coat so it's not
glowing ridiculously.
LIAM: There's just the carts, there's the one mine
entrance?
MATT: You don't see an entrance to the mine, you
just see mining equipment.
MARISHA: Oh, mining. I misunderstood that, too.
MATT: You see pieces of equipment, and the
interior of this hill valley, this short little
valley, seems to have been prepped for some sort
of mining expedition.
SAM: There's no mine hole?
MATT: You don't see one at the moment.
LIAM: I'll take a look around to see if there's
anything, where they started or anything like that?
MARISHA: I'll take the opposite side that he's
doing.
SAM: I'm going to look in the carts.
MATT: Okay. You look in the carts, and they are
empty. You see a few wayward pieces of cloth,
everything in there is bloodied and caked, and has
streaks of it being licked up. It looks like the
hyenas had been at it for a while, trying to clear
off what was left behind from wherever the bodies
that were within were taken. I would like you both
to make investigation checks, please. And you're
following the tracks?
TALIESIN: Mm-hmm.
MATT: Make a survival check.
TALIESIN: With advantage?
MATT: Because there are undead as a part of this,
I will let you.
TALIESIN: Survival check.
MARISHA and TALIESIN: 14.
LIAM: 20.
MATT: It looks like the dust and the dirt in this
vicinity has been freshly swept or dispersed
intentionally, meaning that once this little
valley had been entered, and the carts had been
emptied, something was smart enough to
intentionally cover their tracks. You, however--
you rolled a 20, you said? As you begin to look
about the base of the closest hill, facing away
from where you guys had entered, in an eastern
direction, you see a pattern of grasses that seem
to be interwoven, as opposed to a natural pattern,
there is a consistent mesh to the way they've been laid.
SAM: It's a comb-over.
LAURA: It looks like how we put the stuff over the
cart.
MATT: As you glance over, you can see a net of
grasses that has been woven and thrown over,
leaving a small gap on the edge, where you can see
the dark exterior of what was a mine shaft
structure entrance.
LAURA: That's way smarter that what we did.
MARISHA: A ghillie net.
LIAM: But we'll remember it for the future.
TALIESIN: Yours was hand-crafted.
SAM: Why don't we just take this one?
MARISHA: That's what I was going to say, is it
heavy? How big is this thing? Can we fold it up
and stuff it in a bag?
MATT: It's about 12 foot by 12 foot.
MARISHA: Oh, that's big.
LAURA: It could fit in a backpack. Maybe roll up.
MATT: It's pretty thick.
SAM: It's got sticks.
MATT: Well, it's thrown on and put against the
grass, it doesn't have sticks in its sides.
SAM: Does it have a frame of any sort?
MATT: No, it's laid on the side of the hill.
SAM: Oh, it's a blanket! Oh, okay. We can take
that.
MARISHA: We can grab it on our way back and throw
it on the cart.
LAURA: Throw it on the cart as we're leaving.
TALIESIN: I miss being low enough level that we
just take everything we find, no matter how useful.
LAURA: Like in Skyrim, just wheels of cheese. All
the cheese.
TALIESIN: We're going to be cracking open clay
pots.
MATT: The scavenger levels, man. All righty. It is
too big for you to carry with you, but it can
definitely be taken with you should you exit.
LIAM: How about what's behind the grass, let's
discuss this instead.
MATT: All right. As you pull it back, you do see
the wooden support structure of the interior of a
mine shaft. As soon as you pull it back and look
inside, it looks like a barricade has been
partially placed up on each side. You see piles of
broken furniture, stools and chairs that are
shattered and jammed into each other to form some
sort of a barricade on each side. You can see
dry-rotted pickaxe handles, and other pieces of
general wooden beams used for construction that
are all pushed up against the sides, with a small
path, maybe about three feet wide, that you could
walk through to enter. It looks pitch black on the
inside. There is no light source outside of what
little bit of daylight is coming through from the
entrance.
LIAM: Sorry, I was thinking about a thing you were
saying, there is a way through for us?
MATT: There is a way, there's about a two, three
foot gap between this barricade where it made its
way in, and once you enter through, you can now
see, since there has not been dust put, there is a
definitive trail of blood that has dragged through
and caked in the loose dirt and dust.
TALIESIN: Should I give it a little light, or no?
SAM: Wait, before we go in--
TRAVIS: You're anxious to go. You want to go
first?
SAM: No! Jesus, no. No, please. There were hyenas
out here, right, posted as guards? If one of the
hyenas had gone (hyena howl), would something have
come out of this hole to come get us?
LIAM: I mean, that is a fair assumption, yeah.
SAM: Then why don't we make that sound, and wait
for something to come out, and kill it.
LAURA: Well, but what if it alerts a lot of the
gnolls, and then we don't have the element of
surprise at all anymore?
LIAM: Well, we're talking--
SAM: You want to go into that dark, scary cave?
LAURA: It doesn't look that bad to me.
SAM: It is a dark, scary cave!
TRAVIS: Frumpkin is still just a sweet little
bird, so I thought maybe a little quick flight in--
MARISHA: Canary in a gnoll mine!
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Oh! Oh, smash!
LIAM: Jesus.
MARISHA: We have to do it, it's too perfect.
TRAVIS: Canary in a gnoll mine.
LIAM: That was good.
TALIESIN: That was so painful.
MARISHA: Sorry.
LIAM: Do not be sorry.
TALIESIN: There's limits.
TRAVIS: I don't know if that's something Frumpkin
can do, unless, Nott, you just wanna go in there
and go kamikaze.
SAM: No! I'm drinking again.
MATT: Okay. You are now officially intoxicated.
SAM: I don't have to roll, it just happens?
MATT: Yep.
SAM: Great.
MATT: For the next hour.
LAURA: What does that mean?
SAM: I'll go in if you need me to.
TRAVIS: Oh, shit! Oh, shit! Oh, yes!
TALIESIN: No! Oh, wow!
LAURA: Is that where "the Brave" comes from?
MARISHA: That was going to be my question!
TRAVIS: We get her hammered, and she's the most
fucking badass.
LAURA: Oh my god, this is awesome.
TRAVIS: Oh no.
LIAM: Frumpkin has been a sparrow before. Sparrows
don't have darkvision, do they?
MATT: No.
SAM: It's a night sparrow, he should have said.
LIAM: No, it is a regular sparrow.
TRAVIS: My only concern is if we draw them out,
there could be more than us, right? I just want to
get a quick peek, if we can.
LIAM: Well, I mean, I can send him in there, he'll
probably hit the wall a few times, but if there's
any fire or anything--
TRAVIS: You wouldn't mind?
LIAM: No, you know, I can always bring him back,
but be careful, all right? But there he goes.
MATT: Yeah, there's no light in there. About 25
feet in, go ahead and make a perception check.
LAURA: Yeah, you won't be able to see anything
through it.
LIAM: 21.
MATT: 21. What faint light is coming in from the
interior-- are you looking through?
LIAM: Yeah, I am.
MATT: Yeah. As soon as you come inside, about 40
feet in, the shaft widens into a common area. You
see a handful of tables, some chairs, similar to
what was placed within the barricade, some sacks
strewn about, some torn open and scattered across
the ground, some that are still lobbed in the corner.
LIAM: Is that from a light source inside, or from
sunlight coming in?
MATT: This is just a very high perception roll
with what little light is making its way in there.
And that's where it goes dark, and there's a
(thud) as Frumpkin hits a sloping ceiling.
MARISHA: And dies?
MATT: No, just hits the ground.
LIAM: Please, no!
MATT: Hits the ground, stunned.
LAURA: It's like those birds that hit our windows
at home.
MARISHA: That's right, yeah.
LIAM: Okay, well, I think I have seen all I am
going to see for the moment, but I didn't see
anything in there.
MATT: Not in that main area.
LIAM: Nothing living in there that I saw?
MATT: Not with what little bit Frumpkin saw with a
quick glance before it got too dark and then he
hit the ceiling.
LIAM: Okay. Nott, my friend, I think maybe this is
a time where you could-- please don't go crazy,
but maybe go in 30 or 40 feet, there's a room in
there, and I don't think there's anything in
there, but you would see.
SAM: (drunkenly) I'm just going to go in there and
get the gnolls.
LAURA: I'm gonna bless you before you go. So you
can be sneakier.
SAM: Great.
TRAVIS: Consonants are gone!
SAM: Can sparrows hear?
LIAM: I can hear through my sparrow.
SAM: I could bring the sparrow, you could at least
hear what's going on, like a walkie talkie.
MARISHA: Like a walkie talkie!
LIAM: That's correct. Richtig. Go.
SAM: Okay. I'll take the sparrow, jam it in
there.
LIAM: Wait, I don't want to get punched in the
face while I'm blind. Somebody please put a hand
on my shoulder--
SAM: Oh, you got to hold his hand.
LAURA: Are we going in?
SAM: No, he's going to go into that other place.
LAURA: Oh, okay.
LIAM: If something bad is going to happen, just
shake me.
MARISHA: I'll punch you in the face.
LIAM: No, don't do that, just shake me.
LAURA: Just tickle his balls.
LIAM: Don't do that, just--
SAM: I'm going to go in.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: Punch him in the balls.
MATT: You move past the barricades, heading
towards the shaft-- the barricade, there's a lot
of stuff jammed up here at the front, almost like
it was barricaded from the inside long ago, and
then was cleared out partially, going through. You
make it through the 35 or so feet of the shaft, in
towards where it opens up, and you almost trip,
because your toe catches something, and you catch
yourself, and you look down to see a long piece of
rope that was stretched across that just got
tugged, and falls slack.
LAURA: Oh no, you didn't see that?
MATT: You hear a (creak) and with your darkvision
glance up and see what appears to be a large log
that had been affixed to the ceiling. (whoosh)
Comes rushing towards you. Make a dexterity saving throw.
LIAM: You are a wee baby rogue!
SAM: Great check! Disadvantage. Great check!
LAURA: Good! Phew!
SAM: What is this, dex save?
MATT: Dex saving throw, yeah.
SAM: 24!
MATT: With disadvantage! You, even in your
somewhat hazy drunken stupor, see it just in time
and back up as it (whoosh) right past your nose
and slams into the wall to the left of you. It
hits, and you see the dust settle from the
ceiling.
TRAVIS: That, my lads, was a dragon.
MATT: You guys all hear this (slamming) from the
inside.
LIAM: Oh shit.
SAM: I'm okay, it was just wood.
MARISHA: What's going on?
LIAM: I've heard a confusing thing. Something fell
down, but okay, we're good.
TALIESIN: I think we might have lost the element
of surprise.
SAM: Is it a bigger space in here?
MATT: It is, actually. It opens up to be about 35
feet across from side to side, about 45 or 50
towards the end and then it seems to descend into
two different pathways.
SAM: Any signs of life? Anything?
MATT: Make a perception check.
SAM: Eight.
MATT: At the moment, no. But as you're glancing
about, you can see that there are bags of supplies
that are partially sundered and torn open. You can
see tools, some that look pretty interesting,
there's a crowbar on the ground across the way,
there's other sacks that haven't been spoiled yet.
You see some of the burlap is dry rotted and pulls
right apart, and it looks like there might be some
useful things in this chamber.
SAM: Okay. Real quick, I'll just poke through one
of the bags.
MATT: Make an investigation check with
disadvantage.
SAM: Oh, well then, okay, eight!
MATT: You glance through and find a bunch of
mildewed rice grain. Right as you hear a (snort).
SAM: I will freeze and slowly turn to the sound.
MATT: You glance over, and from the right chamber
you see as two gnolls have appeared in the
entranceway and have entered up, called from the
sound of the heavy impacting thud on the wall but
a few moments ago.
LAURA: Are you stealthed?
MATT: They both-- no, he's not. She is not, sorry.
They both arrive to the top of the-- (sniffing and
growling). They both grab their spears.
SAM: I'm going to say, "Help me! Help me now,
please come in, save me, save my life!"
LIAM: Help me, help me now, save my life. We have
to go in! Here we go!
MATT: What are you doing?
SAM: I am going to draw and fire at one.
MATT: As they're both right there, rushing towards
you, you say this and you're going to pull out and
fire at one. The one to the right or the left?
SAM: The first one who spotted me.
MATT: The one that first spotted you would be the
one on the left, so as it's rushing towards you, go
ahead and fire.
SAM: Okay, 18.
MATT: 18 hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
SAM: Eight.
MATT: Eight points of damage, not--
SAM: Ten, 11 points of damage, because I'm going to
use Fury of the Small.
MATT: Okay, 11 points of damage. It hurts, but
it's still rushing forward. They both begin to
rush in to close the gap. The rest of you guys rush in;
to get to him, it will take the full round to get
there. You guys use your movement and dash in.
Those of you who don't have darkvision, you can't
see anything.
TALIESIN: I also uncover my sword at this point,
which gives off a little bit of light.
MATT: A faint bit of light. At this point, any of
you with ranged abilities right now would be able
to strike. But before you do, two of the gnolls
rush in and are attempting to attack the small
goblinoid female who has walked into their lair.
The first strike, that is going to be a 21 to hit.
SAM: Definitely hits. Any of us.
MATT: That is six points of piercing damage as the
spear jams into your shoulder and scrapes down the
front of your chest, glances off the rest of your
armor and it hurts, but you're fine. You're still
feeling a little fuzzy anyway. The other one
attacks, that is going to be a 15 to hit.
SAM: No.
MATT: No. This one you do see coming, and you
dodge out of the way. But they're both right up in
your face right now, snarling and (growling). With
that, the guys who have ranged attacks, go for it.
LIAM: Wait, so the whole party ran in?
MATT: Yes.
LIAM: As that was happening, the two humans in
tandem said, "Wait, let them draw out their-- fuck!"
MARISHA: It's so dark!
MATT: So you guys have disadvantage on any of your
attacks rolls because you cannot see. You are
blind in the chamber.
LIAM: Are we doing initiative or are we just
going?
MATT: For this round, because there's just two
gnolls at the moment, I'm just going through
actions here to keep going.
LIAM: Dancing Lights!
LAURA: Guiding Bolt on the one closest to me.
TRAVIS: Eldritch Blast on the other one.
MATT: Okay, so the one that's closest to you will
be the one that already took damage from the bolt
so roll for attack for the Guiding Bolt.
LAURA: 21.
MATT: 21 hits. Roll damage.
SAM: Jesus.
LAURA: Six, nine, ten.
MATT: Ten points?
LAURA: Ten points.
MATT: The one that's now taken a crossbow bolt to
the throat and has taken a Guiding Bolt, this giant
blast of light explodes around this gnoll as it
yelps and it encompasses its torso with this
glittering light. Now the next attack against it
has advantage. It is super hurt, but still
standing. You're making your attack.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I rolled the first one, which was a
24, but with advantage. That's less, so 24.
MATT: You were attacking the other one, so you do
not get the benefit.
TRAVIS: Oh yeah, I'm sorry. 24 for the first
roll.
MATT: Still hits, go ahead and roll damage on that
one.
TRAVIS: Oh balls, that's--
MATT: What are you using?
TRAVIS: Eldritch Blast.
MATT: It's a d10 for damage. That's a d12.
TRAVIS: Oh, that is a 12. Sorry, my bad.
SAM: That's the other character.
TRAVIS: Old habits, they die hard. Nine points of
damage.
MATT: Nine points of damage on that one. It gets
blasted by the bolt of eldritch energy; however,
it's still snarling. Currently they're both
looking over at the sudden surge of newcomers.
TALIESIN: I've also got a distance attack. I'm
going to use Devil's Tongue on the one that just
survived your hit.
MATT: Okay, what does that do?
TALIESIN: I'm going to use Vicious Mockery. In
Infernal: You will feed the dogs in hell.
LAURA: Oh, wow, I understood that. It was scary.
MATT: They rolled an eight, minus-- yeah, it does
not make the save.
TALIESIN: It takes 1d4 psychic, which is three
points of psychic damage and has disadvantage on
its next attack.
MATT: Got it, great.
LIAM: Four globules of light, Dancing Lights. The
room is lit up.
MATT: All right. The room fills with light at this
point. The chamber fills, you can now see the
scenery around you. Nott, you're up first. Since
you're the first one to get a shot. There's one
that's super hurt and one that's kind of hurt.
SAM: I'll go for the super hurt one. Who's right
in front of me, right?
MATT: Correct.
SAM: What's wrong?
MARISHA: It fits in there!
LAURA: Oh yeah, that's the thing!
SAM: That's what I'm doing. Laura discovered this
last week.
LAURA: It stays up super good.
MATT: Nott, they're both right up in your face
snarling.
SAM: I'm going to go to the super hurt one and be
like (scream), grab it and I'll do Shocking Grasp.
MATT: Okay, so go ahead and make your melee spell
attack, I believe it is, right?
SAM: Yep, that's a 19.
MATT: 19 hits.
SAM: Okay, I don't know how to do this. Hold on,
is this a ten? No, that's a ten, this is an eight. Seven.
MATT: Seven it is. As you reach up and grab it
with your hand, you watch as a burst of electrical
arcane energy surges through its body. You watch
as veins pop up its torso to its neck before it
collapses into the ground. You have to duck out of
the way before it slams. It would have crushed you
if you'd stayed in the space you were, but you
sidestep in time as the gnoll falls to the ground, lifeless.
SAM: Am I in range-- where's the other gnoll, is
it right on me?
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: Okay, I will bonus action disengage and run
all the way around to the other side of the room.
MATT: Okay. On the other side. As you're doing
that, the gnoll that's right there sees you rushing
off, but now it's more attentive to the one who
blasted it there. I'd say, for the sake of
distance, since the moment you saw you fired, it
probably couldn't close the gap, so it's going to
drop the spear, pull out its longbow, and take a
shot at you from here.
TRAVIS: Oh, shit.
MATT: It's going to be a 14 to hit, what's your
armor class?
TRAVIS: 14.
MATT: 14, all right. Not a great roll, you take
four points of piercing damage.
TRAVIS: Four points.
MATT: It catches you right in the middle of the
sternum. The armor takes the brunt of it and it
mostly just snaps at the impact, but it hurt.
It'll bruise. That ends the remaining gnoll's
turn. Next up would be Beau.
MARISHA: Oh, are there any close to me?
MATT: There's one you can close the gap with.
There's only one that's currently standing in the
room, the other one's been killed. It was shocked to
death by Nott.
MARISHA: Okay, I'll close the gap and come at it
with a big double swing from my staff.
MATT: Go for it.
MARISHA: Finally a decent roll. 19.
MATT: 19 hits, go ahead and roll damage.
MARISHA: Six plus four. That's ten points of
damage.
MATT: Ten points of damage, that's enough to do
it. It had already been damaged previously by
Fjord's Eldritch Blast and you watch as it snarls
and pulls out its bow, pulls back, notches and
releases the arrow. Moments after it's released,
with a quick burst of action you saunter up to its
side and hit it across the torso with the stick.
You feel seven different ribs break as it doubles
forward. As it looks at you for a second, you take
where the staff has broken in and jam upward
to where its lungs would be and it (chokes)
and falls to the ground, dead.
MARISHA: I shake it off my staff a little bit.
TRAVIS: Damn, you broke its ribs to get to its
organs.
MARISHA: It's effective.
LAURA: (singsong) I cut off the ears.
MATT: You guys take a moment here--
TALIESIN: Put them in the jar?
LAURA and TALIESIN: It's an ear jar!
LAURA: Our pickle jar--
MATT and TALIESIN: --Is now an ear jar.
TRAVIS: What happened? How'd they find you?
SAM: I don't know. They're very clever. I was
sneaking all the way down and they still
discovered me. I don't know how.
TALIESIN: We look at the rope connected to the
log.
MATT: Yeah, as Nott's saying this, your eyes wander
off of her over to the right where you see this
heavy tree covered in jagged bark that's
(creaking).
SAM: That happened after they discovered me.
TRAVIS: Right.
LAURA: Ooh, what are all these bags in here?
SAM: I was about to go through them, do you want
to help?
LAURA: Yeah!
TRAVIS: I will keep an eye down the tunnel that
they came from while they pillage.
MARISHA: I'll look around. Are there any other
entrances?
LIAM: As you're looking, I'm going to pull all the
Dancing Lights down to one and put the rag over it
and walk beside Beau so that she can see.
MATT: Okay. There are two shafts. Both seem to
descend. Both curving off in opposite directions.
They both have the wooden frame for support.
SAM: Wooden shafts.
LIAM: Come on, you people. We need a corner, and a
camera for the corner, and a long paper hat for
you to put you in the corner.
LAURA: I didn't even react to it, he had to point
it out.
MATT: Looking around, it looks like this was a
common area. This is the closest chamber to the
exterior of the mine. It looks like there were a
number of tables here, that a lot of them have
been knocked over and broken. A lot of what would
have filled this chamber has been pushed into the
barricade you saw up front. You're helming the
investigation? Go ahead and make an investigation check.
MARISHA: That was me. Me and Caleb.
MATT: You guys are looking down the shafts.
They're looking in the sacks.
MARISHA: Oh, sorry. For the bags, yeah.
MATT: Both of the shafts just descend and curve
out of view. They go to a steady 45-degree decline.
SAM: I'm helping, no? No.
LAURA: Do I get advantage because they're
helping?
MATT: You're too drunk to help.
TALIESIN: I was helping.
MATT: You're looking as well? Sure, take advantage
then.
LAURA: That is not as good. Investigation. 11.
MATT: 11? Okay. You glance around. You find
there's an untapped ale barrel, there's an
untapped water barrel, there's a hooded lantern
that still has a functional bit of oil in it,
though it's only about half-full and very rusted
over, but you clear off the glass on the outside
and it'll work fine. You find a sledgehammer that
the handle is not so rotted to the point where it
wouldn't be functional, but a fair sledgehammer if
you wanted to break any rock or stone. The crowbar
that you had seen earlier, that can be acquired.
LAURA: We should write this stuff down.
MATT: You find a small lightweight rod about that
long that has a short piece of waxed twine
hanging from one end.
LAURA: Is it metal, did you say?
MATT: No, it's not metal. It feels almost like a
hard clay.
LAURA: With wax?
MATT: With a waxed piece of twine on one end.
TALIESIN: Can I make a knowledge test to see if I
would know what this is?
SAM: A knowledge test? You mean an intelligence
check?
TALIESIN: Well, is this intelligence, or what
would this be? I'm trying to think-- I might have
come across this?
MATT: You had as good a chance as anybody to have
come across this, so if you want to make an
intelligence check.
TALIESIN: Just an intelligence check? I'm trying
to remember. 11?
MATT: You haven't come across one of these.
LAURA: Well, I have it. Then the water--
SAM: A water jug and an ale.
LAURA: A water jug and an ale jug.
SAM: Not jug, it was a barrel.
TRAVIS: Casks.
LAURA: Oh, so I can't carry that with me? They're
big?
MATT: No, they're big, heavy, filled things.
TALIESIN: We can put them aside. We will be
bringing them out of here.
MATT: You, make an intelligence check.
LIAM: Okay, that's okay. That's, Scheie, where did it
go? Over here, D&amp;D Beyond. It is ten. Yeah, I
rolled very low.
MATT: Ten, okay.
TALIESIN: (whispering) Human, want a lantern?
MARISHA: Oh, yes. Did you light it? Is it a lit
lantern?
TALIESIN: I haven't lit it yet. You can light it,
I'll help.
LAURA: It's hooded, so you can close off the
light.
MARISHA: Oh, I can close it on and off, right?
Like one of those things?
MATT: Once it's ignited and the oil's lit, yeah,
you can open and close the hood.
TALIESIN: I'm one-handed, so I can't really help
you light it.
TRAVIS: Well, what've we got, are we happy?
LAURA: Yeah, I found a small rod and a crowbar and
a sledgehammer.
TRAVIS: Are you going to carry the sledgehammer?
LAURA: Is it heavy?
TRAVIS: Not for you, Beast Mode.
MATT: Nott, you're an alchemist.
LIAM: Does the rod look like crudely made or
prettily designed?
SAM: Apparently I'm looking it over.
MATT: Yeah, as you're looking over it, it's not
beautifully made, it looks functional like a lot
of the tools here, there isn't a lot of
presentation more than function as what you bring
into a mine.
LIAM: Okay, no carving, no glyphs, no nothing like
that, just caked in shit?
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: Okay.
MATT: You take the rod and smell it and a familiar
scent hits your nose. You've worked in your
alchemical time with small-level explosives. As
part of the elements of the alchemist's fire,
there is a reagent catalyst that when the
chemicals mix it causes a minor explosion and then
burns heavily, there is an element of that, but
it's very, very strong and a very intense scent to
it. As soon as you smell it, it brings back
memories of accidents that have happened in the
past on a very small scale. You immediately get
this wave of cold shiver down your neck, that this
is a very dangerous object if used improperly.
SAM: Yeah, careful with that. I think maybe none
of us should hold that. Maybe Fjord, he seems sort
of responsible. No, don't make it a mustache.
(laughter)
SAM: It could blow up your face. It could blow up
your face. Yeah, it's a boom-boom stick. That's
the alchemical term.
LAURA: Oh shit.
SAM: I think if you put it near fire it could go
explode. Who wants to hold it... who is not Jester?
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'll take it.
LAURA: Give me my pencil, though. No!
SAM: Oh great, throw a sharp object.
TALIESIN: Anyone watching at home, the physics was
really demanding on that one.
LAURA: Can I put the sledgehammer on my back?
MATT: Yeah. You can sling it in with your--
LAURA: My shield?
MARISHA: All right, guys, left tunnel or right
tunnel?
TRAVIS: I'll tuck the rod into my belt.
SAM: It's fine, I'll go down the tunnel and scope
it out for us.
TALIESIN: Well, before we do that, we should
remember to check for traps maybe.
SAM: Oh.
LAURA: Oh, can you do that?
SAM: I don't know.
TALIESIN: I certainly can't.
TRAVIS: You can?
TALIESIN: No, I can't. I can't do any of that.
LAURA: I can look for them.
TALIESIN: I won't be able to find them.
SAM: I can look for them too, I don't know what a
trap looks like.
LAURA: Well, what did that one look like that you got
hit with before?
SAM: Big piece of rope, probably should have seen
it.
LAURA: Maybe look for ropes crossing the ground.
SAM: All right.
TRAVIS: Maybe we view this an opportunity to grow and
we look for those now.
SAM: I will make a mental note.
TRAVIS: Great.
SAM: Look for big pieces of rope.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Anything that looks out of the
ordinary, out of place. On the wall, on the floors--
LIAM: Have a peeky-poo around as you go.
TRAVIS: Are you still shithoused? Are you fucking
hammered still?
SAM: Don't tell me what I can and can't drink.
(laughter)
LIAM: You know, she does this from time to time,
she becomes a little unpredictable, but you can't
argue with the results, you really cannot.
MARISHA: I kind of like her when she's like this.
It's good.
TRAVIS: Okay, she needs another shot.
SAM: You want me to go ahead again?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
SAM: Oh boy.
LAURA: Which one are we going down, though? There's
two entrances, aren't there?
MATT: There are two paths, yes.
SAM: I'll go down one, just a little ways, and then
I'll come back.
LAURA: You should actually stealth, though, this
time, okay?
SAM: I will stealth. I'm going to stealth.
LAURA: You have a blessing.
SAM: And search for traps.
MATT: Okay, so make a stealth check first.
LAURA: With advantage.
SAM: Oh good. Okay, 20-something.
MATT: Well, with advantage, but then disadvantage
from the drunk, so it's just a straight roll.
SAM: The first roll?
MATT: Yes.
SAM: 13.
MATT: Okay, good to know. Then you're going to
check for traps?
SAM: Yes.
MATT: Make an investigation check with
disadvantage.
SAM: With disadvantage?
MATT, LAURA, and LIAM: Because you're drunk.
SAM: That affects-- yeah.
LIAM: You can't tell me what I can do, Matthew.
MATT: Dexterity-based and intelligence-based
checks.
SAM: That's all of the checks. So zero.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: Oh wait, no! No, I did the math wrong, it's
ten. I'm drunk, guys!
TRAVIS: I know the feeling.
MATT: Okay, and which path is this you're
checking?
SAM: Left.
LAURA: I was going to say left. I knew.
SAM: I love you.
TRAVIS: Do you want to check air current
temperature? Nothing? Anything?
MARISHA: Yeah, little drafts, anything like that?
MATT: You don't sense any draft, the air is pretty
stagnant, actually.
TRAVIS: Temperature equal on both sides?
MATT: Seems to be. On the left path, you do not
notice any traps, anything akin to what you
stumbled across as you entered. It does seem to
descend and curve out of the way, but begin to
snake a bit. You get about 15 to 20 feet down
before it begins to rapidly curve left and right,
it's only about ten feet wide. You can continue if
you want.
SAM: No thanks. Okay, I'll go back and report what
I've heard, or what I've learned.
LAURA: Do either of the two paths have more tracks
coming in and out of them?
MATT: They both seem fairly equal. You've been
keeping tabs on footfalls in here. There's traffic
both ways.
TRAVIS: You know what could be really handy in
this situation is some of that fancy fucking
thread of yours.
LIAM: For keeping things-- alerting us of things
coming here or--
TRAVIS: Yeah, I don't mind commiting to one of
these tunnels, I just want to make sure nothing
comes behind us or comes up from the other way.
LIAM: Yeah, that's a good suggestion. First, what
are we doing? What did you find out down that way?
SAM: It just keeps going and starts snaking, and
there's no traps, though.
LAURA: Let's go down the right one.
SAM: Why?
LIAM: I think we should also send you down that
one as well to have a look around.
SAM: All right. Here I go.
(laughter)
MATT: Make a stealth check, please.
SAM: Okay, and looking for traps. Stealth with--
MATT: Disadvantage.
LAURA: No.
MATT: Oh, it's straight roll because--
SAM: Okay, 25. 24. Something. It's a lot.
MATT: All right, and investigation check with
disadvantage.
SAM: Investigation is 13.
MATT: With disadvantage.
TRAVIS: Because you're hammered.
SAM: Yeah. 13.
TRAVIS: Yes!
MATT: You begin to curve down the right path and
there is a slight depression on one side that you
glance over and look and it looks like some of the
burlap that had been torn from the sacks earlier in the
tunnel had been used to cover a three and a
half foot wide pit that has been laced over to
hide its presence.
SAM: It's just burlap over a pit in the ground?
MATT: Yeah, it's affixed with a couple of rocks in
the sides, it's very light and would have fallen
through. It only covers part of the path. The
tunnel is about ten feet wide and the right side
of it is where that pitfall is. You notice it and
go. "Oh, hmm." This one does not snake, this one
continues in a continual curve for another 40 or
so feet before you're starting to get a little far
from your friends. You can continue if you want.
SAM: It just keeps curving and curving?
MATT: It looks like it's going in a downward
spiral.
SAM: Oh, a downward spiral. Okay, I'll go back and
report what I saw.
MATT: Great album.
TALIESIN: So true.
SAM: All right, so one path goes "wiggedy woo" and
the other path goes "zibbidy zow."
TALIESIN: Were there any traps?
SAM: No traps. Oh yes, there was a trap! To be
fair, there was one trap. I thought you meant any
sprung traps. There was a trap.
TRAVIS: You sussed it out.
SAM: I sussed it out. Don't worry, I'll take care
of it.
LIAM: How far down did you go each way?
SAM: 40 feet down the "ziggedy zow" and like 25
feet down the "zibbidy zoo."
LIAM: Well, my instinct tells me that if there's
something there, that they would trap it so
probably more valuable, if we're going on nothing,
take the path that is trapped.
LAURA: I agree.
TALIESIN: Hear, hear.
SAM: You're so smart.
LAURA: Unless they want us to think it's the path
that they've trapped.
SAM: Reverse psychology!
LAURA: That's right, and it's actually the path
that is least resistance.
TALIESIN: Unless they knew that you would think
that.
SAM: Oh, reverse reverse psychology!
LIAM: These are dog people? Let's take the path
with the trap.
TALIESIN: Trap, trap.
SAM: Right path.
MATT: As you all slowly begin to descend down the
right path.
LAURA: We're stealthing!
MATT: We'll come to that in just a second. We're
going to go ahead and take a break. Since it's a little
past nine. We'll be back here in a few minutes to
pick up the descent further into this mineshaft.
LAURA and MATT: Into madness.
LIAM: Down the wooden shaft.
MATT: Before we get to that, however, we do have a
giveaway from our friends at Wyrmwood, as you saw
last week we have another of their black walnut,
two of their Adventurer Arsenals to give away again
this week. If you haven't seen, they're awesome,
well-made, and if you open it up on the inside it
has space for you dice, for your pen, a place
for a mini or eraser or anything else you want to
carry into your game. It fits into the dice box
that comes with it as well. We're giving away two
of these during the break. To enter this while
we're gone at the break you can go into the Twitch
chat and enter, when you're prompted, the code word
gnoll. That's G-N-O-L-L. Do not enter it more than
once or you'll be disqualified, and we'll come
back from the break with two winners to this.
Thank you so much. We'll see you guys here in a
minute.
[break]
MATT: Welcome back. We have our two winners in the
chat over the break. Congratulations on winning
the Wyrmwood package to ding0atx and
lunaimperial.
ALL: Woo!
MATT: Congratulations to the two of you guys.
Danoba will reach out to you and get your contact
information and we'll get those sent to you ASAP,
so well done.
Yes, all right. You chose the right or the
left again?
SAM and LAURA: The right.
MATT: The right, okay. Down the path, the shaft
winds for about another 150 or so feet before it
slowly levels out into a long chamber of multiple
levels. What once looked like a solid mining vein
is now strewn with bones and flayed skin pinned to
the rock walls with scavenged nails, blood
spattered across them with intent painted a jagged
smile of sharp teeth on each of these four hides.
A faint source of light in the center flickers, a
small stone altar holding a cluster of candles in
the central level platform. It looks like about
six gnoll-like figures have gathered around this stone--
LAURA: We were stealthing, we were stealthing.
MATT: I know. We're going to get to that in just a
second.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: While a strange seventh figure places small
wet stones upon this altar, smaller than the other
gnolls. Let's get a perception check real fast
from two of you. Who's leading the--
SAM: I would have been bringing them down, right?
LIAM: You can see in the dark.
LAURA: Yeah, I can see in the dark, I'll look.
MATT: We'll say since you two would be in the
front then for that, you jumped up first.
Perception check, both of you.
SAM: Five.
MARISHA: This sucks.
LAURA: 11.
MATT: Okay, so you don't see much of the figure.
Also, right now, I'll have you guys all do a
stealth check, please, as you make your way down.
TALIESIN: Do I still have advantage?
LAURA: No, he has advantage now, sorry.
TALIESIN: That's okay.
SAM: 22.
LAURA: 15.
TALIESIN: Nine.
LIAM: Ten.
MARISHA: 22.
TRAVIS: 15.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Oh no.
SAM: Looks like this is the wrong path, everyone.
We should probably go back to the other. Sorry.
MATT: This figure looks gnoll-like, you see the
ears and the snout, but as it reaches down and
picks up these wet stones and places them in the
altar, giving small, dark, muffled barks and
yipping sounds, you see elements that look like
smooth human flesh. The more that you focus in,
you can see this looks to be a humanoid figure
that is wearing pieces of hollowed-out gnoll-like
armor. A hood missing a jaw that's placed over the
top of the head, sections of arms worn like a
glove with the hand missing, sifted through. It
seems that a lot of the body parts are discolored
and rotting a bit, from what you can see from the
candle light that's flickering across it. Long
bonelike spines, similar to what adorned the armor
of that pack lord that you battled in the middle
of the city last night, are also affixed to the
outsides and pierced through elements of the
shoulders and head of this flesh gnoll hide that
it's wearing. As it growls, mimicking the sounds
of the gnolls that it seems to be residing along,
the other gnolls around look, pacing from foot to
foot impatiently (growls and grunts). Begins to
speak louder and louder at this altar as it places a
final wet stone on it. All the remaining gnolls
begin to bark in unison together (bark and howl).
LAURA: (whisper) Should we stop this?
MATT: They all at once leap onto the altar and
begin tearing into the stones, which are not
stones. They were glistening. At this point you see
hearts that are now being torn and swallowed by
the gnolls at the altar.
LAURA: Should we kill them all?
SAM: No.
TRAVIS: Don't make a sound.
LIAM: (vomiting)
MARISHA: Oh, that was well done.
MATT: They finish devouring the hearts and the
humanoid figure begins to bark a few more times
and then in broken Common says, "The hunger will be
fed: ours and hers. Come," and points to two of
them, "Help me carry more meat below. The rest,
stay. Feast on what remains." Turns around and you
now look across the way. On the other side of the
chamber, darkened, you see a gnoll leaning in
familiar armor: the one that you had battled and
had left with the carts is watching from the
far end of the chamber down on the lower third-level
platform.
LAURA: The big mama jama?
MATT: The weird gnoll priest, I guess you could
say at this point, that's been helming this little
ritual, goes and joins the armored gnolls and steps
aside and follows second, and the two gnolls that
were assigned by it leave as well, leaving four in
there in the chamber currently.
SAM: Including the armored one or no?
MATT: No, the armored one leaves with the priest.
LIAM: Did you describe any light source in here
that they're working by?
MATT: The candle altar. Yeah. It's not an
extremely bright light, but for those of you who
are human, it's enough where you can make out
shapes once your eyes have adjusted to the low
light interior.
LIAM: Got it.
MATT: You watch as they begin to grab the bodies
on the ground. You can see there are now-- The
grinding of bones as they drag broken corpses
across the floor and begin to tear into the torsos.
LAURA: While that's happening, I'm going to cast,
very quietly, Cure Wounds on Nott next to me,
because I saw you're bleeding, yo.
SAM: Oh, sorry. What does that do?
LAURA: You just regained nine hit points.
SAM: Ooh, nine.
TALIESIN: This is getting ridiculous.
LAURA: Yay.
MATT: (barking) You watch as four hyenas fill into
the space where the gnolls are and begin to sit at
bay, waiting for the gnolls to finish feasting. One
of them gets close, and the gnoll just grabs its
head and shoves it against the wall, and it snaps
into the wall and then backs up and then waits its
turn. You can see the other hyenas that exist in
this space, naturally scavengers, have to wait,
being at the lowest of the totem pole.
TRAVIS: How many total?
MATT: Four gnolls, four hyenas.
MARISHA: Fuck.
LIAM: The one that got thrown into the wall? It
got stunned or hurt, it didn't get any--
MATT: It didn't seem to be too much. More to just
keep it away from the meal.
TALIESIN: We know they go down very quickly.
MARISHA: I'm afraid if we keep waiting, more will
just show up.
LAURA: Yeah. Let's kill them!
LIAM: (whispering) Here we go.
SAM: What? We're just going to go? There's no
plan?
MARISHA: Well, maybe we can draw a few over to us
and take them out on our terms.
MATT: If you're planning to engage, should I show
you the layout of where they're placed?
ALL: Yes!
SAM: He says coyly. "Would you like to see the
layout of the room?"
TRAVIS: I don't like seven on eight. I am not a
fan.
SAM: Seven?
LAURA: But they're little.
SAM: Six.
LAURA: The hyenas are little.
SAM: Oh, Yasha's with us, right?
(laughing)
LIAM: The hyenas are just doggos.
SAM: Yeah, they've got like four hit points. You
can take out two of them in one go. If you were,
you know, Grog.
MATT: So here we have--
LAURA: Oh, one's an archer, two's an archer,
three's an archer.
MATT: They all tend to carry a bow on their
backs.
LAURA: Shit, four's an archer.
MATT: You can see now the hyenas that are waiting
patiently. This one got knocked into the wall.
They're scooting at the sides, waiting for them to
finish their meals. You guys are right up here
where the shaft opens, glancing down into this
chamber. That was where the priest and the other
gnolls had exited.
SAM: We're up on top, up there?
MATT: You guys are up on here. Which, for the
purposes of--
TRAVIS: Good thing we're metal.
MATT: It's fine.
TRAVIS: I mean, I hate it, but--
SAM: Is there any way to even the playing field a
bit? Any strategy? Fjord and Caleb, come on?
LIAM: What about the boom stick that you have? We
can chuck it into the--
LAURA: Oh! Wouldn't that be really loud? Wouldn't
that draw them back, though?
LIAM: Yes, it would, but--
TRAVIS: Plus we're in a mine.
LAURA: It might bring the whole thing down on us.
SAM: Maybe we could use that to escape later.
LAURA: Yeah, definitely.
TRAVIS: There's a big column that's in between
them, right?
MATT: Correct.
TRAVIS: Is it a column or a stalagmite?
MATT: It looks like it was a stalactite that then
was reinforced as a column to help
maintain the structure.
MARISHA: If we can make some sort of distraction,
to get their attention, and if we can put or
heavy hitters, our people up front, we can try and
hold them in this mouth, ranged people in the back.
TRAVIS: Do you want to throw the rod at the
column?
LAURA: I feel like we should do that when we're
leaving. We shouldn't do that before we go in.
Because we're not going to be able to get to
anything.
TRAVIS: There's another path down.
LAURA: Well yeah, but this is very loud. It would
draw things up here.
LIAM: Where would you want this distraction to be?
Because I can make a little--
TRAVIS: Behind them, and make them turn away from
us. Because we're in a fatal funnel up here at the top.
LIAM: I can make a little dancing golden person of
light appear down at the bottom of the passage.
MATT: A fifth gnoll begins to wander its way into the
chamber.
MARISHA: You see, more are going to keep coming.
MATT: It goes over and kicks one of the hyenas off
to the side. It sits there (snuffling and whining).
TALIESIN: We can see now or try the other way.
LIAM: If there's more in there, they're just going
to come in here anyway.
BEAU: And it's not confined.
TRAVIS: I genuinely feel like we should go the
other way.
SAM: The other way? This is it, this is the other
way.
TRAVIS: There's a whole other path.
SAM: It's nothing.
TRAVIS: No?
SAM: That's nothing.
TRAVIS: Do you know?
SAM: No, I'm guessing.
LIAM: Here's the question: do you think these
things are going to come out of here right away,
or is it worth a shot? Maybe there is a way
around, to a way they're not expecting?
MARISHA: Normally, miners build coal mines with
connecting shafts and double exits in case one
side collapses. You always want another way out.
We just don't know where they've put everybody.
We're here looking for villagers, remember?
LIAM: You know, there's nothing saying we have to
run in here if we're not feeling this. We can
backtrack and look in the other direction. In
fact, I'm leaning that way.
MARISHA: Hey, Matt. DM question? If we were to try
and back out of here, and draw them towards us,
what would that be? Just a tunnel?
MATT: Yeah, this tunnel is a ten-foot wide tunnel
that continues backward.
LIAM: Plus we do have a map here.
SAM: Five gnolls. We've got these guys.
LAURA: We can try attacking them, and if it gets
bad, then we use the TNT.
LIAM: Use D&amp;D?
MARISHA: Yeah, that's what I heard.
SAM: D&amp;D?
LAURA: No, TNT.
TALIESIN: The longer we wait, the more things are
coming.
SAM: Maybe it's the whiskey talking, but I think
we've got these guys.
MATT: If you wanted to, turning you backward here,
there's this path here. We could continue the
tunnel back this way.
MARISHA: It's only a death funnel if we're the
ones dying, right? If they're dying, that's good
for us.
SAM: How far is it on the map from where we're
standing to the farthest gnoll?
MATT: The farthest gnoll there? About 60 or so
feet.
SAM: We can definitely do a distraction to get
some of them to turn away from us. At least we get
a round in.
LAURA: Get a surprise round.
LIAM: I can make a little golden person dance
behind that guy there.
LAURA: We can get a surprise round on all of
them.
MARISHA: Surprise round, get as many range and AoE
spells off as we can?
LIAM: AoE? Surprise round? What are you talking
about?
TALIESIN: Be helpful!
TRAVIS: Can I use this planning moment to cast
Armor of Agathys on myself?
MATT: You may.
TRAVIS: Spectral frost collects from the air on my
armor.
MATT: Which, as a note to remind you from last
time--
TRAVIS: I didn't give myself enough cold damage.
MATT: Correct, yeah, so keep that in mind.
SAM: Okay. Are you going to try your thing or
should I try my thing first?
LIAM: What is your thing?
SAM: I don't know. I can try something! I can do a
similar thing, have them see something behind
them, but you can do the same thing. Yours are
already cast, right?
LIAM: Not right now, no. But it's like that
(snaps), it's easy, this one.
SAM: Okay. I could try to get one of them to fight
with one of the other ones of them.
LAURA and MARISHA: Yeah, that's good.
LIAM: Do that.
SAM: I'm going to sneak up, down the steps to that
little crook in there.
MATT: Right here?
SAM: Little further back, yeah. Is that all right?
Do I have to roll or anything?
MATT: Roll a stealth check.
SAM: Oh, shit. Okay, with disadvantage?
MATT: Do you still have the gift?
LAURA: No, you still have Blessing.
SAM: Oh, so 26. That puts me within 30 feet of
those guys, right?
MATT: Oh yeah.
SAM: And what are they doing? Eating hearts?
MATT: At a closer glance, you look and see. One of
them currently is holding a pair of legs that are
no longer attached to a torso, and is stripping
the flesh from the thigh and leg, tearing into it.
Takes a piece and chucks it off to the side, and
the two hyenas fight over it. Another one back
there, you can see, is clutching a scapula, the
back of a shoulder blade, and is breaking the
bones in half and sucking the marrow out. At a
quick glance, you get the sense that some of these
may have been denizens of Alfield as of 24 hours
ago.
LIAM: I'm going to start throwing up again soon,
so let's either do this or backtrack, please.
SAM: Are they carrying anything on their bodies,
on their person? Anything, canteens or weapons or
equipment or anything?
MATT: The gnolls?
SAM: The gnolls.
MATT: Most of them have a longbow slung over their
shoulder, and have a spear that dangles off to the
side, or has been jammed in the ground next to
them.
LAURA: While he's doing it, I'm getting ready. I'm
doing this. I'm going to cast Mirror Image of myself.
MATT: Duplicity, or are you doing Mirror Image,
the spell?
LAURA: Mirror Image.
MARISHA: Let's all agree that if this goes bad, we
run.
LAURA: Suddenly, there are three me's around
myself.
TRAVIS: If we need to close it off, light the tip
of that little wick and throw it.
LIAM: Are we going right now?
MARISHA: Oh God.
SAM: Are any of them holding anything that they
put down for a second, or they got it firmly in
their claws?
MATT: The one that breaks and sucks the marrow out
of one of the large, shoulder blade areas takes and
grinds the teeth against it, scooping out
whatever's inside, then throws that piece onto the
ground next to it, then takes the arm and begins
to splinter the middle of the arm bone and try to
get the marrow out of that.
SAM: Are you going to do your thing?
LIAM: Are you about to go?
SAM: I don't know. You tell me.
LIAM: I'm going to really quickly mutter a few
arcane words, then there is another Caleb blinking
in front of me a little bit and behind me a little
bit. It is hard to see me at the moment.
LAURA: Are you casting Blur or Mirror Image?
SAM: What are those words?
LAURA: I want to know for my own sake.
LIAM: I don't care.
MARISHA: Can I get more into a place with Beau? In
this crux, mirroring Nott. Stealth check? Natural 20!
MATT: Does your spell have concentration? You are
concentrating on a spell at the moment. Beau, you
quickly leap and land with no sound, catlike
reflexes.
MARISHA: Three-point landing.
MATT: Your foot does slide for a second as you
glance down, and where you stepped in, it looks
like there's a bit of leftover pieces of people.
MARISHA: I (gagging).
SAM: I whisper a couple words and use Mage Hand to
pick up the little piece of shoulder blade he
dropped and throw it in the face of the other
guy.
MATT: Okay. It slowly lifts, and one of the other
gnolls that's eating (splat), (growling), and the
other one goes (yipping), and they go back to
eating.
SAM: They don't care. Thought they would kill each
other, I don't know. That was it. We're level
three, that's all I got!
LIAM: (whoomp) A little halfling-sized person of
light appears behind the gnoll at the far end there.
MATT: What is it? What are you using?
LIAM: I'm using Dancing Lights. You can use the
four lights to make a little person, a little
humanoid shape of light. It is doing a little
macarena behind the gnoll all the way. I have 120
feet of range.
MATT: That spell is not concentration? Right,
okay.
LIAM: Yes, it is. But I would know that. I'm not
going to do that, because of my keen memory that
Caleb has, but not Liam.
SAM: I'm going to turn around and whisper to
Caleb: Are you going to do the thing? But I'm
using Message, so no one can hear us. Are you
going to do the thing? If not, I can do my thing.
LIAM: I send Frumpkin through the chamber and down
and starts battering into the walls here.
MATT: As soon as Frumpkin begins doing that, you
watch as the one that's nearest on this side, the
one that had dropped the arm piece earlier, takes
the bow off its back and begins to notch an arrow,
looking around. It's going to take a shot at the
bird fluttering through. That is a 17. What's Frumpkin's--?
LIAM: Oh, I'm sure that hits. Yeah.
MATT: Six points of piercing damage. The bird goes
(thud) on the ground and then dissipates. You
watch as the four hyenas suddenly rush in towards
where the bird had fallen, and they all go to the
spot where it landed and find an arrow lying
there, and (snarling and yipping).
LAURA: I cast Spiritual Weapon above the two
gnolls directly in front of me.
MATT: The range on that is--?
LAURA: Range on that is 60 feet.
MATT: You're placing it where? Right there?
LAURA: Yeah, right there. It's going to giant
lollipop down and smack one of them in the face.
MATT: All right. Which one?
LAURA: This one. The one on your left.
MATT: Okay. Go ahead and roll a spell attack.
LAURA: Ooh, 19 plus whatever!
MATT: Nice. Roll damage on that, that definitely
hits.
LAURA: That is nine force damage, and that's my
bonus.
SAM: Damn.
LAURA: Then I can do a cantrip. For my action, I'm
going to cast Sacred Flame at the same dude.
MATT: Same dude? That is a 15.
LAURA: He saves, so is it half, or--?
TRAVIS: What kind of a check was it?
MATT: That would have been his dexterity saving
throw, right?
LAURA: Yes. "Must succeed," so it probably doesn't
do anything.
MATT: Yeah, then no damage. Okay, that ends your
turn. Everyone else gets one action and then we
roll initiative.
LAURA: Can I run down the steps and hide behind
a barrel like it's going to make any fucking
difference at all?
MATT: Sure. You won't get to hide, though, but
you're there. You're standing next to a barrel.
All righty, who's up next?
TRAVIS: I'm ready.
MATT: Fjord, what you got?
TRAVIS: Can you point to one of them that is not
undead? Just looks like a regular gnoll, or I can
just pick one.
MATT: You can pick one. All of the gnolls in here
look like regular gnolls.
TRAVIS: Great. Did you aim at that one?
LAURA: No, I aimed at the other one.
TRAVIS: Okay, I'll take that far one.
MATT: What are you doing?
TRAVIS: Can I focus and summon my falchion into my
hand?
MATT: Yep. It appears into your space in a burst
of dull greenish-blue fire, and there you see it,
dripping with salt water across its blade.
TRAVIS: Can I use my bonus action to cast Hex at
that right gnoll?
MATT: You may. That one is now hexed. You watch as
the gore that's been dripping from the front of
its body seems to roll up its torso in reverse
before it slips into its armor and grasps itself,
the darkened shadowed gore now holding it in place
as the Hex curse.
TRAVIS: Can I reach back and fire Eldritch Blast
into it?
MATT: You may.
TRAVIS: 16.
MATT: That hits. Plus 1d6.
TRAVIS: Six plus four, ten, 1d6, 15 points of
damage.
MATT: 15 points of damage. (explosion) That one
immediately drops what it was eating as the blast
slams into it, as it's confused by the wrapping of
the Hex. As it reels and almost stumbles onto its
back, its foot crushes one of the nearby skulls,
and there you see this gaping wound in its chest
where the armor's been sundered. There's a smoking
plume of blackened, horrible, shaded smoke pouring
from it.
TRAVIS: Can I use my distance to move over here,
if I may?
MATT: That's as far as you can, there.
TRAVIS: Am I in your line of sight, Jester? Does
anybody need that?
LAURA: Nah, you're fine.
MARISHA: Nope.
MATT: Beau?
MARISHA: Okay, I'm going to do something weird,
and I hope it works and doesn't fuck the rest of
us. I'll move up right here next to Fjord. 40.
That works good there.
MATT: That's 20 there.
MARISHA: Let me go one more. That's good. Then can
I reach in my bag and grab out, in my little
pouch, grab out a handful out of my 1,000 ball
bearings?
TRAVIS: You do have 1,000 ball bearings, I
remember that. We had money. She bought a lot of
fucking ball bearings.
MARISHA: A lot of ball bearings! Can I take it
and-- you know how you can take your pocket and
flip it inside out? And have a bunch of ball
bearings go (metallic clinking) across this way?
MATT: You hear hundreds of tiny metal clangs in
succession as ball bearings begin to spray down
the stairs and scattering across the floor of this
central makeshift ritual room. As they run through
the semblances of gore and the areas of the
stonework that are exposed between, you have spent
your action scattering.
MARISHA: Is that my action? Okay, I'm going to
spend a ki point, and as my bonus action take
Patient Defense.
MATT: Nice. As soon as you empty those out, you
get back and go into your defensive position,
preparing for any sort of assault. Caleb?
LIAM: The effect of that hasn't taken place yet,
correct?
MATT: The ball bearings, in this moment, are now
clattering down into the ground.
LIAM: Did Fjord hit one successfully?
MATT: He did, yes.
LIAM: That same one? I am just going to Fire Bolt
it. From yeah, yeah.
MATT: Roll for an attack.
LIAM: Fire Bolt. That is an attack range guy,
plus six that is a 15 to hit.
MATT: That hits, just barely.
LIAM: The damage is seven.
MATT: Seven points of damage. The one that you
had hexed suddenly goes up into flames with a
(dying scream) and falls back onto the ground.
LIAM: I'll use my movement to back up about 15
feet just outside of the chamber.
MATT: You are just there. As the flash of red
light arcs from his finger and lights up the path
before it impacts and kills the gnoll, Caleb then
steps back into the shadows, trying to get out of
the way. Nott?
SAM: Oh, I get a turn as well? Because I did the
Mage Hand thing.
MATT: Yes, but that technically did not initiate
into a combat. It just bothered one of them.
SAM: Mildly.
MATT: A temporary inconvenience.
SAM: Sure, I'll send an arrow down into the one
that Jester attacked.
MATT: Go for it.
SAM: That's 23.
MATT: 23 hits. Roll damage.
SAM: Nine.
MATT: Nine plus your sneak attack.
SAM: This is a sneak attack?
MATT: Because you were stealthed.
SAM: 14.
LIAM: Rogue, best class.
MATT: That one (explosion). The bolt goes through
the center of his forehead and embeds itself right
up to the very back. You watch as it (dying scream) and
falls into the ground over one of the piled corpse
pieces it was tearing through. Becoming one with its
meal. And then?
SAM: Crouch back and hide.
MATT: Okay, make a hide check to try and disappear
back there. Stealth on that one.
SAM: Advantage, but disadvantage, so 16.
MATT: Okay. You did your thing. Molly?
TALIESIN: I'm going to creep out against the wall
closest to me and try and hide in one of these
coves. Over in the corner, as far as I can get
into the--
MATT: You can get right into the similar space as
Nott there.
SAM: Does he see me?
MATT: I would say barely.
TRAVIS: Hello!
SAM: Hi.
TALIESIN: Since I'm too far away for anything too
crazy, I don't have a good bonus action. I will
use my Devil's Tongue, I'll use Vicious Mockery on
the gnoll that's currently in between-- not the
one that's-- actually, the one that's furthest from
us, because he's going to be the archer, and in
Infernal I'm going to say: I'm too disgusted to
think of anything clever.
MATT: It rolled a natural one on its saving throw.
TALIESIN: So yeah, that's three psychic damage and
he has disadvantage on his next attack.
MATT: Good to know. Now, everyone please roll
initiative.
TALIESIN: Natural 20.
SAM: Natural 20. Do I have to roll with
disadvantage, is this dex or intelligence?
MATT: It's technically a dexterity ability check
so it would be disadvantage, yeah.
SAM: Two, so six.
LAURA: That is so sad.
MATT: 25 to 20?
TALIESIN: 23.
TRAVIS: Yes.
MATT: Fjord, what did you get?
TRAVIS: Four.
MATT: Sorry. So who else rolled a natural 20?
SAM: I did, but I got a disadvantage.
MATT: Right, yeah. But don't you have advantage
with--
SAM: On stealth.
MATT: Just on stealth checks, that's right. So
Molly's up first. That's a fun little initiative
tracker thing from our friends at Axe &amp; Shield.
See how it helps out there.
TALIESIN: I was 23.
MATT: 23. 20 to 15?
MARISHA and LIAM: 17.
MATT: The gnolls rolled a natural 18 plus one, so
they're at 19. Gnolls are next.
TRAVIS: Oh, the gnolls are next.
MATT: Both of you guys are at 17?
MARISHA: I'm shaking.
MATT: 15 to ten?
LAURA: 13.
MATT: Jester got 13. Ten to five?
SAM: Six.
TRAVIS: I'm at four.
MATT: They hyenas are before Nott. Then we have
Nott, then we have Fjord. Molly, you're at the top
of the round.
TALIESIN: God, that's awful.
MARISHA: God, that's bad. I don't think I even
fucking spelled it right. I think I botched that
all across the board. I spelled it "Hyneas."
MATT: Gets the idea across. The special hyena.
LAURA: "Hyneas!"
MATT: What you got, Molly?
TALIESIN: I'm going to get a little-- Oh, can I do
this? No, I can't do that. Fuck. I know, I'm so
sorry. I should have my shit together. How far
(counting)? Oh god, that's too far to walk. I'm
going to try and get one little crevice. Actually,
I'm going to hold my position. I'm so sorry.
MATT: Hold your position?
TALIESIN: Hold my position and use one more Tongue
on one of the other guys.
MATT: All right. Natural 20 on the saving throw,
unfortunately.
TALIESIN: Oh, so no.
MATT: Sorry.
TALIESIN: (coughs) and I'm holding.
MATT: All right, that's your turn. All right, the
gnolls are up first. These two here are going to
pull out their bow and begin to fire at Beau.
Since you had been the first to appear at this
point and gather their attention. They both have
disadvantage on the attacks. That is going to be
an 11.
MARISHA: Miss.
MATT: The other is two 14s in a row, so it would
be 18 to hit.
MARISHA: Oh, hit. With disadvantage?
MATT: 17 to hit, sorry.
MARISHA: Hit.
MATT: Yeah, all right.
MARISHA: 17 is my armor class.
MATT: That would be--
MARISHA: This is with a bow?
MATT: Yep. That's going to be ten points of
piercing damage to you.
MARISHA: I'm going to cat-paw try to catch the
missile with Deflect Missiles. What do I spend--
Oh, wait. Oh no, wait, this is a ki point.
MATT: Well, it's a ki point to throw it back.
MARISHA: Oh no, it's a ki point to throw it back,
it's just a reaction. It's 1d10 plus seven. Nine
plus seven, so 16.
MATT: You catch it in mid-air and reduce it to no
damage.
TRAVIS: Fucking dope!
MARISHA: I hold it out like a microphone and go--
MATT: As you do that, the one in the bottom of the
ground, who is closest to you, grabs its
spear off the side of the wall. (growling) Runs up
the stairs.
TALIESIN: Does it hit the ball bearings?
MATT: That's what I'm--
TALIESIN: Oh, okay.
MATT: Rolling its dexterity check to see if it can
do so. It does succeed. It's a 15. It slips, but
it manages to make its way up the stairs.
MARISHA: I laugh at it, as it comes at me.
LAURA: He looks so stupid.
MATT: Coming into combat with both Fjord and Beau.
He's going to go ahead and reach out at you with
that. It's going to be a 16?
MARISHA: Miss.
MATT: 16 misses.
LIAM: I hope we at least heard the Looney Tunes
bongos (bongo noises).
MATT: After you drop the arrow, it comes up and
you parry this one off to the side and go back
into your defensive stance. That ends both of
those's go there. Now, comes to Caleb.
LIAM: Yeah, I can see from where I am, I can see
Fjord and Beau with one of these things. I'm going
to Fire Bolt right from where I am.
MATT: All right, go for it. Roll for attack.
LIAM: That's it. Aw, no.
TRAVIS: "Aw, no."
MATT: It strikes part of the stone altar,
splintering candle wax and pieces of remnant heart
chunks, but no impact unfortunately on the actual
gnoll.
LIAM: Sorry!
MATT: You going to stay where you are?
LIAM: Yeah. I will walk just inside the--
LAURA: Did you go, Beau?
MARISHA: I haven't, but we rolled at the same
time.
MATT: Right, so Beau, you want to go with your
action now?
MARISHA: Yes! I'm going to take my staff, I'm
going to try and crack this guy on the back of his
head where he is.
MATT: Go for it.
MARISHA: Jesus Christ al-fucking-mighty. 13? Does
that hit?
MATT: As you swing the bo back, trying to crack
him in the head, it actually slips on one of the
ball bearings you had left, and as it manages to
catch itself, it falls out of range of your sweep
of the bo. You're like, "Shit!"
MARISHA: I'm my own worst enemy! I'm going to do a
knee and a round kick-- Oh no, sorry. I can
just do one. I'm thinking in advance. One kick
with the knee!
MATT: All right, go for the attack.
TRAVIS: Damn.
LAURA: Do you want my dice bag?
MATT: You slip on one of your own ball bearings on
the second strike, and manage to catch yourself by
grabbing the fur on the outside of the gnoll and
using its body to right yourself, and then, "Ugh."
It's a little slick and sticky.
MARISHA: I wipe my hand on Fjord really quick.
MATT: All right, Jester, you're up.
LAURA: Okay. Have any of them been hurt yet?
MATT: That are standing? This one has been hurt a
little bit.
LAURA: Okay. I'm going to move my Spiritual Weapon
over to the one on the ground, directly in front
of Beau. Oh, I meant on the lower level. Yeah, and
it's going to hit him! Whoa. 16 plus five.
MATT: 16 hits, plus five hits even more.
LAURA: That's nine points of force damage.
MATT: Nine points of force damage as the lollipop
hits it in the back of the skull and it leans forward
and grabs the back of its skull with this
pounding, throbbing pain in its head.
LAURA: And then I'm going to use Toll The Dead on
the one in front of Beau.
MATT: All righty. So what does it have to roll?
LAURA: He has to roll a wisdom saving throw.
MATT: Okay. And the range of that one is?
LAURA: 60 feet.
MATT: So that rolls a nine plus zero, nine.
LAURA: Yeah! So he takes 1d12 necrotic damage!
Two. It's a little bell this time.
MATT: Just a little bell. You watch as a little bit
of blood comes out the side one of the hyena's ears.
TALIESIN: I like to think that your lollipop makes
Candy Crush sounds when it hits people.
LIAM: Jester, is the lollipop the flat kind or the
round kind?
LAURA: I'm picturing the flat kind, so it can
whack.
MATT: So the spiral kind? Gotcha. Are you going to
move at all, or are you going to stay where you are?
LAURA: I'm going to stay right there.
MATT: Okay, that ends your turn.
LAURA: And then I make my mirror images be like--
I guess they're doing that because I'm doing that
because they're my mirror images.
MATT: There you go! There is a whole dance number
over there of multiple Jesters. The hyenas go now.
TRAVIS: (sings tune to "Single Ladies.")
LIAM: That's the best.
MATT: Does succeed on his dex save. This one's going
to attempt--
TRAVIS: (singing) If you liked it, then you should
have put a ring on it.
MATT: Leaps up to there. Dexterity saving throw,
does succeed.
LAURA: Oh jeez, there's a lot of them. That's a
bigger one, it looks like.
MATT: Succeeds! They're actually
rolling pretty high for their saving throws. This
one will be a three, that one does not make it.
This one gets partway over and then falls prone
there. Uses the other half of its movement to get
up, but that's as far as it can get. It can't
actually attack for this round. It's going to use its
movement to make the rest of its run up to the top
of the stairs. So that one does not get an action
this turn because it slipped on the ball bearings.
It's going to be one attack against Beau.
MARISHA: Whoa, it was effective!
MATT: With disadvantage. That's a natural 20, and
a six.
MARISHA: Yeah!
MATT: Yeah, that does not hit, not at all. It's
plus two. The hyena rushes up and lashes out
towards you, and you just pop, slap it in the nose and
it pulls back.
MARISHA: Nose punch.
MATT: Yep. The two other ones that rush up and
come along the flank with the hyena to you, Fjord.
First one goes, that is going to be a 15 plus two,
17?
TRAVIS: That will hit.
MATT: All right. Actually, it has advantage on the
roll because of pack tactics. It didn't really
help, let's see here. You take two points of
piercing damage.
TRAVIS: Okay.
MATT: The other one is going to attack you.
TRAVIS: It will take ten points of cold damage in
return.
MATT: (laughs) Which causes it to shatter into ice
on the ground. It bites you and its snout
(explosion) T-1000 style. It shatters into a
million ice pieces.
TALIESIN: You lost a gnoll there.
MATT: Yep.
TALIESIN: No, you've got a gnoll. You should have
that looked at.
MATT: Thank you. The other one is going to take a
strike at you. Natural 20, it's a critical hit. 20
and ten. That pack tactics is nasty. That means
you, for dice wise, suffer eight points of
piercing damage. It takes ten and it explodes into
ice as well. Both of these hyenas rush up and
strike and both in succession disintegrate into
shards of ice across the ground.
LAURA: That is the coolest spell ever.
TALIESIN: It's so hardcore.
MATT: The spell is gone though, right?
TRAVIS: That's it.
MATT: That's going to end the hyenas' turn. Nott,
you're up.
SAM: Okay, I'll lean out from behind Mollymauk's
buttocks and rest the hand crossbow on his left
cheek and fire--
TALIESIN: I support.
SAM: --on the gnoll that's engaged with Fjord.
MATT: Okay.
SAM: Firing. Eight.
MATT: (laughs) As you drunkenly try and aim in the
direction.
SAM: It's that bulbous butt!
MATT: You almost pull the trigger twice, but you're
aiming at Fjord and you're like, "No."
TALIESIN: No advantage for engagement?
MATT: No advantage, but he can sneak attack if he
hits. That's how it works. You finally go, and one
of the elements of stone in the side of the cavern
wall (impact) as the bolt hits it and goes sideways.
SAM:Am I still hidden? No? That exposes me, do I
have to hide again? How do rogues work?
MATT: Yeah, you're revealed.
SAM: Oh, I was revealed. Okay. So I have to hide
again.
MATT: You have to find a way to obscure
something's vision to you before you can hide.
SAM: Sure, got it. Okay, I'll run up the stairs
then and hide back near where Caleb is. Other
side. And then hide.
MATT: That'll work. Go ahead and roll a stealth
check as your bonus.
SAM: Well, I've cocked. Terrible. Nine plus eight
is 17! Oh, wow, I'm so stealthy.
MATT: You're a rogue this go-round, man. All
right, that ends Nott's turn. Fjord, you're up.
TRAVIS: Oh, it is my turn! Can I use my bonus
action to move my Hex from my defeated foe to my
new foe right in front of me?
MATT: You may.
TRAVIS: Yeah, and can I whip my falchion around
and upstrike, just try and cut right through him?
MATT: Go for it.
MARISHA and TRAVIS: (singing) I whip my falchion
back and forth.
TRAVIS: That's only a 16.
MATT: 16 hits!
TRAVIS: Oh, good!
MATT: His AC's 15.
TRAVIS: Can I say two-handed?
MATT: I'll allow it.
TRAVIS: I've got to get in the habit of saying
it.
MATT: Yeah, you've got to say it. Two-handed, I'll
allow it.
TRAVIS: 1d10. That's a ten! Four-- that's 14
points of damage plus a d6, that's 15 points of damage.
MATT: So this one, that had already-- 15 points of
damage, right?
TRAVIS: Mm-hmm!
MATT: This is the one that you hit earlier with
it. As you swing with your falchion, just spinning
it in your hand, you arc upward. As you do, you
watch as the gore and shadow of your Hex, which
now seems to grasp around its chest, almost
reaches out to meet the blade in the middle like
the two bits of lightning hitting in the center of
the sky. As they impact, the blade carries through
the momentum, the strength coming from the blade,
not from your actual body. As you do, you carve
through a large portion of its torso. You watch as
the hide armor folds off, revealing this huge gash
wound in its chest. It (snarling and growling).
It's still standing, but it's horribly wounded
now.
TRAVIS: You fucked with the wrong one, son.
MATT: That end your turn, Fjord?
TRAVIS: That does.
MATT: All right, to the top. Molly, you're up.
TALIESIN: I'm going to run up to these two and
join the fray up here.
MATT: All righty.
TALIESIN: First, I'm going to take a swing at the
big guy.
MATT: Go for it.
TALIESIN: That's 16 to hit.
MATT: That hits! Go ahead and roll damage.
TALIESIN: And that's-- just using my normal one
for this one. That's eight points of damage.
MATT: Eight points of damage. As soon as it rears
from the attack, Fjord, you watch as in a flash
the cloak billows of Mollymauk's arrival. As the
cloak falls, you just watch as the gnoll's head
just rolls off of its shoulders. You can see the
blow that struck it.
TALIESIN: Bonus action with the glowing sword goes
down into the hyena.
MATT: Go for it.
TRAVIS: Well, hot damn!
TALIESIN: That's an 11 to hit?
MATT: That's its armor class. Hyena doesn't have a
whole lot of armor.
TALIESIN: All right, and that's eight points of
damage.
MATT: Eight points of damage. With the one strike,
you turn around and look at the hyena. (whoosh)
with the offhand and just carve right through it.
TRAVIS: With a flourish.
MATT: Wait, because that didn't have the--
TALIESIN: No, this one was the glowing one.
MATT: Well, the glowing one is your main hand.
TALIESIN: Oh, it was my main hand?
MATT: Then your offhand is the other one.
TALIESIN: Oh, okay. I didn't know how that.
MATT: So what damage would it have been without
the bonus?
TALIESIN: That would have been four.
MATT: Four damage? All right, so it's still there.
You carve through, and it's wounded, but it's
still (whimpering).
TALIESIN: I would have flipped them if I'd known.
LAURA: Couldn't you have attacked with your
offhand first?
TALIESIN: I was going to say, I would have flipped
them if I had known.
MATT: You could have.
TALIESIN: I was going to hit the one that didn't
have much left.
MATT: The idea is the bonus action attack happens
as part of the attack action.
TALIESIN: Sure, I'll do it reverse next time.
MATT: No worries, you can keep that in mind next
time. It's all good, you still beat the shit out
of it with your offhand. So that ends Molly's
turn. Those two gnolls in the back, this guy is
going to back up as he attempts to make a
dexterity save. Fails! So he falls prone, uses the
rest of his movement to get back up, so he can
only move ten more feet so he can't get that much
further away. He's going to go ahead and take a
shot, this guy is going to go ahead and pull back,
he's out of the bearing range and begins making
his way towards the door.
MARISHA: No!
MATT: They're both going to take shots at Fjord.
Actually, one at you, one at Molly. They're not
going to fire at you because you visibly caught
one and dropped it in front of them like, "Fuck that."
MARISHA: Aw, damn it!
TRAVIS: Fuck that!
MATT: Against Fjord, that's going to be 19.
TRAVIS: Oh, that hits.
MATT: And against Molly.
TALIESIN: Blood Maledict on that fucker.
MATT: Okay. That brings it down to a 14.
TALIESIN: Yeah, that don't hit.
MATT: All right, as the one that is going to fire
at you, Molly, pulls back its arrow, its eyes suddenly go
dark and begin to bleed from the inside. It
suddenly (snarling) and releases it, and you watch
as that arrow splinters against the central
column. The one that does come towards you, Fjord,
however, does strike true. You suffer eight points
of piercing damage as this one catches you right
in the abdomen, a little bit to the right, tapping
something kidneyish in that vicinity and you feel
this sudden dull pain and nausea overcome you.
That's going to end the gnolls' turn; Caleb,
you're up.
LIAM: I saw Nott dart in front of me and chuckle
to myself, see Nott walk past, I'm going to walk
forward and say: You are enjoying this too much,
but okay. Can I see these two? You said they were
backing away, correct?
MATT: You can see this one. This one is
technically being blocked by that central column.
LIAM: All right then, the diamond comes up, I spin
it and little charges of electricity crackle
around it, and I kick it out from my hand and it
spirals through the room to that one.
MATT: Go ahead and roll your spell attack.
LIAM: Come on, Grog! No.
LAURA: Oh man, Caleb, so rough tonight.
TRAVIS: (as Grog) Sorry.
MATT: What'd you roll?
LIAM: Two. Plus six is eight, did that do it?
MATT: No, unfortunately.
LIAM: Nein!
MATT: It skitters off the central column and goes
spinning out of control as the electrical sphere
shatters against the stonework and dissipates the
energy, absorbed by the surrounding stonework.
LIAM: But I was so eager that I actually came down
the steps my full movement.
TALIESIN: I'll also say I think we-- oh no, that's
right, you're double.
MATT: Yeah, that would be your full movement there.
Pretty close.
LIAM: I don't want to go there, I want to go to
the bottom of the steps behind Mollymauk and Fjord.
MATT: Ending Caleb's turn, Beau.
MARISHA: Right, okay. How far away is he? I'm
having a hard time seeing. Can I close the gap?
MATT: You could say maybe he's about 30 feet from
you.
MARISHA: Okay, can I do some cool monk shit and do
some wall running and leap and parkour and then
get to this guy?
MATT: You can certainly try. Make an acrobatics
check for me.
MARISHA: Acrobatics?
TALIESIN: I can see this is going to end up with
an Office parkour gif in your future.
MARISHA: Parkour! Oh, that's good! That's a
natural 18 plus six.
MATT: As you run off the edge, the hyena takes a
swing at you. That is going to be a 14.
MARISHA: Miss!
MATT: You feel it snap at your heel, but does not
actually grasp any of your body.
MARISHA: My foot just taps his arm just a little
bit and I leap off of his arm.
MATT: You push off of him, run across this wall,
leap, hit this pillar, and then, using the momentum, leap
and land right in front of the gnoll there.
MARISHA: As I'm leaping, I want to take the staff
and come down and go (crack) with a slap. Double
handed, piece of shit gnoll! Oh god, it's a two!
MATT: What was the other one?
MARISHA: That was my eight-sided die. I'm trying
to efficient my rolls.
MATT: Roll both? Yeah. As you swing down, the
gnoll manages to see you up in the air and side
steps as you hit the stonework.
MARISHA: I scream as I come down the whole way
going (screaming).
MATT: (gnoll laughter)
MARISHA: I just go (pop) and do a little jab,
okay. That's an 18.
TALIESIN: You just slap him in the face.
MATT: Damage on that one?
MARISHA: That's just a d4. Four, so eight!
MATT: Eight points of damage, nice! As it's
laughing, (laughing, punch, growling) its jaw is
dislocated and it snaps back into place. You see
some of its teeth broke. It looks kind of dazed
and hurt by it. It's looking pretty rough; it's
taken some hits in the past. That's the end of
your turn.
TALIESIN: He can't run anymore.
MATT: All right, that brings us to Jester.
LAURA: I say, "Don't laugh at my friend!" and I'm
going to send my lollipop over and hit it in the face.
MATT: Yeah, that'll do it, 20 feet.
MARISHA: Get a good hit, lollipop!
LAURA: I don't know if it's going to hit it. Eight
plus five.
MATT: 13? No, I'm afraid that will not hit. As the
lollipop comes around the corner, it sees it
coming, and moves to get Beau to intercede between
the lollipop and itself. At that moment, you're like,
"Oh, I can't quite--," and you end up withdrawing
and not making the strike this round for fear of hitting Beau.
LAURA: Toll the Dead!
MATT: All righty, so that's a wisdom save? That's
six, no!
LAURA: Yay! Okay, seven.
MATT: Seven points of damage. As you release the
surge of energy, the sound begins to vibrate
in its ears as it (whimpering) and it reaches up
as both of its eardrums burst on the sides of its
head and it falls to one knee looking like it's
completely ruined and dazed. And Beau, you have a
moment to coup de grce it. You (whack) and break
its neck with one swoop of the bo. Combined, you
both finish off that gnoll.
MARISHA: Sounds great.
TALIESIN: That's so cool. That spell is so cool.
LAURA: It's pretty cool.
MARISHA: Fuck yeah, that was awesome.
TRAVIS: Toll the Dead is the bomb!
MATT: Jester, you want to move?
LAURA: I'm going to hang out where I am.
MATT: Okay. End of Jester's turn. The hyenas. This
hyena is going to move past--
TALIESIN: Does Fjord get an attack of opportunity
on it?
MATT: No, that one was not in melee with
him. That one's going to move up to you, Fjord.
Attacking you, Fjord, that is a six.
TRAVIS: No, it doesn't hit! Thankfully.
MATT: Attacking you, Molly. That is a 20.
TALIESIN: That hits.
MATT: You take two points of piercing damage as it
snaps at you. Seeing that they're both beginning
to glance about and see that their allies are
starting to back away, and there's a lot of you up
in this upper area, they're both going to attempt
to break away with the rest--
TALIESIN: I'm definitely going to take an attack
of opportunity on that one.
TRAVIS: I'd like to, as well.
MATT: Yep, both of you do.
LAURA: We got to get that last gnoll before he
leaves the room.
TALIESIN: 14?
TRAVIS: 21.
MATT: Both hit. Roll damage.
TALIESIN: Is this main hand?
MATT: Main hand. This one is hanging on by a
thread. It's the one you damaged last round.
TALIESIN: Eight points of damage.
MATT: Yeah, you carve that one. You?
TRAVIS: 11 points.
MATT: As they're rushing, you both (whoosh)
simultaneously strike back at it as they're
attempting to flee and they stumble down the
stairs.
TRAVIS: Can we cheers swords?
TALIESIN and TRAVIS: Tink.
MATT: Perfect. Their bodies stumble to the ground
and end up-- it's weird because their bodies hit
the ground, and the momentum carries them as they
slide across the ball bearings, almost like
they're lagging.
MARISHA: Bad physics?
TRAVIS: What's that-- kerning? Curling.
MATT: Finished the hyenas' round. Nott, you're
up.
SAM: Seeing the gnoll's expression, I know it
well. It's one of fear and about to run away.
(laughter)
MATT: Make an insight check.
SAM: Okay.
TALIESIN: At disadvantage?
SAM: 19.
MATT: It is not disadvantage on wisdom checks. 19.
This gnoll looks like it's ready to fucking bolt.
It is on the way out of the room. The tide has
turned, it's starting to see more and more of you
appear at the top of the stairs as the hyenas and
its friends are being destroyed. It's going to run.
SAM: Okay. I'm going to put the hand crossbow up
and run as fast as I can, straight at it. Using my
bonus action to dash, I'm going to say to it: Hey,
you! If you spend all day in a well, well, that's a
day well-spent! I'll cast Hideous Laughter on it.
(laughter)
LAURA: I'm glad we still get shitty jokes.
MATT: It immediately goes (cackling) and falls on
the ground, on its back, and is now rolling with
laughter. Laughter that is echoing through the
halls and making its way through the tunnel.
SAM: Don't you worry. Fjord, kill him!
TRAVIS: You made it prone; it's harder to hit
that way!
SAM: Get closer!
TRAVIS: I'm trying! I would like to move up my 30
feet of speed.
MARISHA: I turn behind me, I go: Watch the ball
bearings! Watch the marbles!
MATT: Make a dexterity saving throw.
MARISHA: Shit.
MATT: As you hear that just as you reach the
bottom of the stairs.
TRAVIS: 13.
MATT: Okay, you get to the bottom of the stairs,
and you barely begin to slip and catch yourself.
It's a DC 12. However, you continue to run.
(counting) That's about as close as you can get on
your 30 movement--
TRAVIS: Can I use my bonus action to move my Hex
to the laughing gnoll on the ground?
MATT: Yes, you may.
TRAVIS: I'll cast Eldritch Blast at it.
MATT: Actually, make a concentration check. You've
taken some damage, and I forgot to maintain your
Hex's concentration.
TRAVIS: Oh. That's right. Saving throw?
MATT: Make two for me, if you don't mind.
TRAVIS: This first one is a 19.
MATT: Correct. That's fine.
TRAVIS: The second one is 18.
MATT: Yeah, you're fine. The Hex moves over--
TRAVIS: I'll remember that.
MATT: Whenever you take damage, and you have a
spell that's concentration, you have to--
TRAVIS: These spell rules.
MATT: I know.
TRAVIS: 14.
MATT: Eldritch Blast?
TRAVIS: Yes. Oh, sorry, plus six.
MATT: Disadvantage. Because it's still prone.
TRAVIS: That's even higher, so 14.
MATT: 14? Still misses, unfortunately. It hits and
gleans off of its armor. However, it isn't quite
strong enough to actually make a painful impact on
its body and slams into the nearby rock, causing a
spray of dust and debris.
TRAVIS: The attack has to hit for Hex to work,
right?
MATT: Correct. All right. That ends your turn,
Fjord. Molly, you're up.
TALIESIN: I'm going to run down the stairs the
opposite direction from the ball bearings. I'll
see where I can get, if I can get 30 feet.
MATT: That's as far as you can get, right there.
TALIESIN: I'm going to also use Vicious Mockery
again and yell: Shut up already!
MATT: That actually is a 16. What's your DC?
TALIESIN: DC on that, it just says wisdom saving.
MATT: Right. Against whatever your spell DC is.
TALIESIN: Where is my spell DC? Well, it's weird,
I'm not a spell--
MATT: Spellcaster technically. We will say for
the purposes of this it's eight plus proficiency
bonus which is ten plus whatever your charisma
modifier is.
TALIESIN: My charisma modifier is zero.
SAM: Yuck.
MATT: Yeah. Not a big deal. For now. We'll tighten
it up. Cool. So no effect there. Molly's turn is
over. The gnoll's turn. It is laughing its ass
off. Now does it make--
SAM: The end of its turn it makes a save.
MATT: All right. Which is a 17. It manages to
shrug off the laughter.
SAM: At the end of its turn.
LAURA: Oh, so it can't get up and move.
MATT: No. It's just on the ground going (confused
whimpering). It's about to try and get back up.
Caleb, you're up.
LIAM: I'm going to go along the edge of the steps
this way and come down toward it and I'm going to
now spin and flames lick around it and I'll go
(flick) and I flick that off my hand. This time is
also not good. It is a 13.
MATT: 13. It has disadvantage because it's still
prone.
LIAM: Oh. For my attack?
MATT: Yes. Against ranged spells.
LIAM: Same thing. Rolled the same thing.
MATT: Yeah, you release it and it just skids
across the ground. Like skipping a stone across a
lake. It slams into the wall behind it and
(explosion).
TRAVIS: I apologize.
LIAM: No, it's okay. No, I don't believe in any of
that bullshit. You all are crazy.
MATT: It's all good, man. Just survive to level
five and everything will turn. Unfortunately it
does not hit.
LIAM: No, don't worry about me. Keep going.
Everybody attack.
MATT: All right. Beau, you're up.
MARISHA: I want to do this as my two-handed
attack, but for flavor to skin it. I want to
stroll up, channeling The Rock. Charge up the
elbow. Then we go a People's Elbow. Come right down.
MATT: You have advantage because it is prone.
MARISHA: Just a full body weight (thudding). With
advantage? Can I consider it a two-handed attack?
MATT: You're just getting your attack, so yeah,
still with advantage.
MARISHA: Oh my god! Why?!
LIAM: Two and a three.
MATT: Here's what you do. You walk up. Tap tap.
Leap and right as you're in the air the gnoll
kicks out of laughter. Rolls out of the way and
you wham!
MARISHA: (yelling in pain)
LIAM: Never recover from that injury.
TRAVIS: Yep, that shit just hangs out in there.
MATT: The worst funny bone pain shoots through
your arm as you get up.
LIAM: You are going to be rubbing Tiger Balm into
that shit for years.
MATT: You still have your bonus. The gnoll actually
starts laughing again.
MARISHA: For flavor, my second attack isn't really
an attack. I'm in so much pain I go (yell) and I
kick a little bit.
MATT: Roll the attack. You still have advantage.
Yeah, because it's still prone.
MARISHA: Natural 20!
MATT: That will shut it up.
LAURA: I like that your revenge hits are always
really high. That's twice now that they've
laughed at you and you've hit them while they're
laughing at you.
MARISHA: Every time I try to show off it never
works. That's what I'm learning. Okay, three
doubled to six plus four. So ten.
MATT: So as it's laughing, you kick it in the head
and you see it stunned on the ground for a second
and its eyes kind of rolling in different
directions. Nice heavy crack to the side of its temple.
MARISHA: I don't care too much. I just roll over
and go fetal for a minute.
MATT: Okay, ending Beau's turn. Jester, you're
up.
LAURA: I'm going to skip over across the upper
level towards the far stairs so I can see it. I'm
going to send my Spiritual Weapon over to it and
smack it flat on the ground!
MATT: Okay, that does have advantage because it is
technically in melee with it.
LAURA: Jesus Christ, I don't think either of them
hit. 13 and lower.
MATT: Nope. It's just rolling out of the way of
everything. It's doing what Beau did in the last
fight, but on the ground.
LAURA: Then I'm going to Toll the Dead. Wisdom.
MATT: Unless it rolls a natural 19.
TALIESIN: This is amazing!
MATT: This one gnoll is just holding on so hard.
Jester, I think that ends your turn, unfortunately.
LAURA: Jesus fucking Christ.
(laughter)
MATT: The hyenas are dead. There's no hyenas
left.
TRAVIS: The proned-out gnoll is just making it
through.
MARISHA: Come on, Nott. Bring it home!
LAURA: I'm going to sit down on the ground and--
all my Mirror Images do the exact same thing.
MATT: You watch as four shimmering Jesters all
kneel down and shake their heads in their hands.
Beau is over there going (gasps).
MARISHA: It's almost something like a Jacob's
Ladder moment, the end of his life is being
stretched out.
MATT: This gnoll is going to need some serious
therapy. Nott, you're up.
SAM: I can't believe this thing is still alive.
It's still prone, right?
MATT: It's prone, yeah, so melee attacks have
advantage.
SAM: So I walk up to it, and then point-blank
shoot-- not point-blank, but far enough away that--
MATT: You're at disadvantage with a ranged
attack.
SAM: All right, I'll stand back ten feet.
TALIESIN: No, you'll still get disadvantage.
MATT: You have disadvantage from a ranged attack
up close and disadvantage against a prone
creature. Right now, with your crossbow, it's
disadvantage regardless.
SAM: Oh, well shit. Then I will draw a sword and I
will--
TRAVIS: Slap that bitch!
TALIESIN: Now you've got advantage.
MATT: Now you have advantage on the attack.
TRAVIS: Get your hands dirty.
SAM: Thank god. Okay, 18.
MATT: 18 hits. Go ahead and roll damage with your
sneak attack.
SAM: Okay, 13.
MATT: 13 points of damage. How do you want to do
this?
(cheers)
SAM: I think, since it's on the ground, I would
like to pin it into the ground, if I can, by
finding the thinnest thing on it and jamming my
shortsword into the ground.
MATT: As it's cackling and moving around, I like
to imagine this is all happening simultaneously.
Beau's on the ground holding her elbow, the weapon
misses, and it's rolling and cackling and starting
to get up and you're like "Hmm, there!" (thump)
Almost unceremoniously it's like (dying yip) and
falls limp on the ground where you place it. It's
almost like the slow push from Saving Private
Ryan. You're like, "Shh, shh, shh."
LAURA: You're terrible.
MATT: (dying yips) and it expires there on the
ground.
LAURA: I go around and I collect the gnoll ears
and I put them in the jar.
LIAM: As the room falls still, I say: Well, he had
a good run. A toast to that guy right there on the ground.
SAM: Yes.
TALIESIN: Cheers.
SAM: He was like Beyonc. He was one hot Knowles.
(laughter and groaning)
SAM: I don't know!
TRAVIS: One point of damage? All of us?
MATT: Everyone takes one point of psychic damage.
LAURA: I have a question. How similar do hyena
ears look to gnoll ears?
MATT: They are noticeably smaller and not gnoll
ears.
LAURA: What if we said they were baby gnolls? I'm
going to cut them off just to be safe.
MATT: Okay. Five sets of gnoll ears and four sets
of hyena ears.
LIAM: I'm going to call Nott over to the chest
over on that side there. Do you see anything wrong
with this? Is there anything hinky about that
chest?
SAM: I check for traps. Checking for traps.
MATT: All right.
SAM: This is an intelligence check?
TRAVIS: Are you still intoxicated?
LIAM: It's investigation, I think.
TRAVIS: Or has that shit worn off with some
activity?
MATT: The next ten to 15 minutes or so, you'll be
able to shake off the alcohol.
SAM: For now, I rolled an 11.
MATT: Okay. It does not appear to be trapped.
SAM: It's good!
LIAM: Does it look good?
SAM: It's totally good.
LIAM: Take a step back. You've earned this. I will
open it, just in case.
MATT: (clunk) It's locked.
LIAM: Oh.
SAM: I will pick it!
MATT: Okay. Go ahead and attempt, with
disadvantage, to pick it.
SAM: What am I rolling?
MATT: It's proficiency bonus, which is two, plus
your dex bonus.
SAM: Okay. Proficiency and dex. But disadvantage.
Okay. 21.
MATT: As the adrenaline pumps through your system,
it wakes you up a bit and even with the
intoxication that's been flooding your system, you
steal a moment of clarity and it opens without an
issue. You glance at it, and the chest looks like
it's been bashed in a little bit, like one of the
gnolls was trying to get into it and eventually
gave up, got flummoxed, and threw it on the
ground. As you open it up from the inside, you can
see essentially a central medical pack, if you
will. An emergency pack for any of the miners that
had gotten hurt or wounded. There are two healer's
kits in there. There are a number of disinfectant
herbs and funguses. Anybody who is proficient in
medicine would know how best to utilize those. I
don't know if any of you are.
TRAVIS: Nope.
MATT: Then it's a risky endeavor to maybe use one.
You do find a small leather hand pack that
contained four glass vials, three of which were
shattered from the rough movements when it was
tossed around, but one that is still intact. That
contains a healing potion.
SAM: Is it a healing potion?
MATT: It is. It is a greater healing potion, not a
standard healing potion.
LAURA: Whoa!
SAM: I hand it to Caleb. You need this more than
all of us. You're the squishiest.
LIAM: Well, that's probably true. Thank you. You
take the two medicine packs and then--
SAM: What do I do with these? I don't, all right
fine, I'll take them. I collect medicine packs now.
LAURA: I need them. I could probably use those.
TALIESIN: I also like the idea of maybe giving the
healing potion to the healer.
LIAM: She can heal without the potion.
TALIESIN: Can you heal yourself without the
potion?
LIAM: Of course she can.
TALIESIN: Oh, well all right then. That didn't
really occur to me.
SAM: I'll keep the herbs.
MATT: You can mark down medicinal supplies, would
be what you'd call it. You are not entirely certain
as to how they are applied, but they are probably
healthy.
LAURA: Can I look at them since I'm proficient in
medicine?
MATT: You're proficient in medicine? Yeah. I was
asking if anyone was proficient with it.
LAURA: Oh, sorry. I was writing down gnoll sets of
ears.
MATT: (laughs) Fair enough. The medicinal supplies
you have acquired can be utilized to remove
poisons, if quickly applied to where the poison
was put. It has two uses. If an action is taken to
apply it to a wound, whether a bite or a wound
that was poisoned, it can help remove the poison.
TRAVIS: Oh shit.
LAURA: It's an action you said?
MATT: It's an action to apply it, yeah.
LIAM: There was a lot of gnoll chatter in here,
and a lot of exploding orbs and stuff, so I'm
going to guess that we have alerted whatever is
beyond that we are here. How do we wish to proceed?
TALIESIN: Well, they make a lot of noise. They may
not have noticed.
MARISHA: Can I, since I'm in that general
vicinity, go 20 or so feet into this hole and
listen and see if I hear anything?
LIAM: They don't send orbs of fire through the
air, though.
MATT: As you step forward a little bit, make a
perception check.
LAURA: What was the question? I'm sorry.
TRAVIS: There was no question.
MARISHA: 13.
MATT: You hear echoing, muffled in the distance.
Some yipping, some conversation in whatever this
gnollish language is. You hear a deep, resonant
(deep breathing) and a distant (thump). An impact,
and a sound near (yips). That's all. Sounded quite
a ways away, like this echo had been traveling a
ways down this tunnel.
MARISHA: I bend down--
MATT: You hear a few other cackling chuckles that
echo shortly thereafter.
MARISHA: I turn around and come back to the rest
of the group and say: There's something bigger.
TRAVIS: Jester, could you give me a heal a little
bit? I took a little bit of a beating.
LAURA: Oh sure. Yeah, I'll cast Cure Wounds on
him.
MARISHA: I think there's something bigger at play
here. Whatever is driving these gnolls I think is
deeper in. Can I look around and see if I can find
anything like any papers, anything from that
humanoid that might be intelligible?
MATT: Make an investigation check, please.
MARISHA: Okay, 20 total.
MATT: Okay. Looking about the altar, you find some
smaller pieces of fresher flesh that have been
stretched over the edges of the altar, like on the
corners. You can see a similar grin across the
center. It's all blood splattered from the hearts
that were placed on there. As you wipe a little
bit of it away, you can see stained into this
loosely tanned human skin the same symbol of the
jagged smile. The jagged teeth that form a grin
that the various tanned banners that are stapled
into the stone walls show and reveal. But no
notes. No books, no parchment.
MARISHA: Can I try and figure out what this is, if
I recognize this symbol in any way?
TALIESIN: I'd also like to join in on that with a
religion check.
MATT: You've already made a religion check before,
and as you come up and join her, this particular
symbol, the grin matches the memory, the flash you
had of this entity.
MARISHA: Yeenogru?
LAURA: Yeah, Yeenoghu.
MARISHA: Yeenoghu?
MATT: You gather this is probably the symbol
that represents this entity.
TALIESIN: The cult of Yeenogru.
LAURA: Yeenogru or Yeenoghu?
MARISHA: Yeenoghu or what?
MATT and MARISHA: Yeenoghu.
TALIESIN: Mr. Magoo. Well, you know. Fake
confidence.
LIAM: Are you clear now?
SAM: I'm fine.
LIAM: How many fingers am I holding up?
SAM: More than I think I have on my entire body. I
think I just have four on each hand.
LIAM: And thumbs? Or--?
(laughter)
LIAM: You good? Do we need to get out of here?
SAM: Yeah. I'm good. We're fine. I mean, is this
the plan? We were supposed to free living people,
but we got some arms. We could bring those back.
LIAM: I don't think, I mean, yeah, we could,
but--
LAURA: He did say to bring back anything we could
find.
SAM: Are there any identifiable body parts?
MATT: You take a few minutes to look around, which
gives you two notifications. One, nothing seems to
be immediately coming in to search as to what the
noises were, and you do hear other distant sounds.
Impacts and cackling and stuff. You get the sense
that the tunnels deeper in have some activity
amongst the gnolls that live below whatever
they've converted this mine network to be. You
also see that all the bodies in this chamber have
been pretty much picked of any identifiable facets.
MARISHA: Jewelry, wedding bands, anything?
MATT: If you want to take some time to really pick
through it, you could try. Do you want to?
LIAM: No, we're still trying to get to people
here. Our options are we press forward to
something worse, or we backtrack and try the other
direction, or we get out of here.
TRAVIS: We have the silver thread up top, right?
SAM: Did we do that?
LIAM: Did we? No, we opted not to do that for
time's sake.
LAURA: We could do it now. As we move forward.
TRAVIS: Oh, it took a few minutes, didn't it?
LIAM: Yeah, we could do that now.
TALIESIN: How are you feeling, Fjord?
SAM: Yeah, Fjord, are we going to be Fjord
Explorers or Fjord Escapes?
LAURA: Jesus.
LIAM: Yeah. I could do that quickly. I could put
an Alarm here quickly. I could do it the fast way,
and know if anything is coming behind us. Is that
what we want to do? Do we want to go around? I
don't know, I'm a little terrified of what is down
there.
MARISHA: While he does that, can we, no we can't
take a short rest. It's not enough time.
MATT: That's up to you.
LIAM: That's a half hour is a short rest. Or an
hour is a short rest.
MATT: It's about an hour or so.
MARISHA: Nope. Ignore what I said.
LIAM: There's two ways that I can do this. I can
do it lickety-split or I can take my book out and
do it the harder way, but that's ten minutes,
about.
TRAVIS: I think it's in front of us.
MARISHA: There's something real big back there.
It's real big.
LIAM: We just have to march into it. Okay.
TALIESIN: I'm not convinced that they don't still
have people alive down there.
LAURA: I'm pretty much out of spells now. But
that's okay.
TRAVIS: A short rest doesn't get us spells back,
does it?
MATT: Not for her it doesn't. (singing)
Conservation!
LIAM: How are you with that sledgehammer on your
back?
LAURA: What do you mean?
LIAM: You're carrying a sledgehammer on your
back.
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: How are you with it?
LAURA: Oh. I don't know. It's a big weapon.
MARISHA: She's got a badass scythe.
MATT: It's more of a tool sledgehammer than a
weapon sledgehammer.
LAURA: Yeah, I've got a scythe. A sickle.
TRAVIS: I'd like to volunteer that perhaps we move
forward until we can see whether there are any
living people that we can help and we make a
decision then.
MARISHA: I saw nothing that would clue me in as to
what might be deeper and really big?
MATT: Nothing that caught your attention.
MARISHA: Okay. Let's go.
TRAVIS: That went far better than the village, but
also that big armored bastard wasn't there.
TALIESIN: Let's make a pile of these bodies, too.
Just in case, maybe they think that they took each
other apart.
LAURA: Let's set them up like they all were making
out.
LIAM: No, we don't have time for that here. We
have to get going.
SAM: Like some sort of a circle-jerky sort of a
thing?
LAURA: Yeah, yeah.
TALIESIN: On the way out.
LAURA: Loosely prop them up like that.
LIAM: When we're victorious we can do disgusting
things as we leave. Nott, I think you should take
point again.
SAM: All right.
LAURA: Did you do the--
LIAM: That I thought that was for going back the
other way. We want to know if something comes
behind us?
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: The reasons for doing that are slighter and
I don't want to blow my wad magically.
LAURA: Okay.
LIAM: If we were going the other way, I might.
TALIESIN: I agree.
LAURA: Let's go and be really smart and do this.
SAM: Am I drunk or am I not drunk?
MATT: If you were to take about ten more minutes,
you'd stop being drunk.
LIAM: We talked for seven minutes, yeah?
TALIESIN: All right.
SAM: All right. Wait for three more minutes and
then go.
MATT: Okay, so you want to wait until Nott shakes
off the--
TRAVIS: The booze?
MATT: The influence, the booze. Eventually, you
regain--
MARISHA: While we wait for those three minutes I
turn to Molly and I say, Do you remember anything
in your recollections of this Yee...ah...noghu.
LAURA and MARISHA: Yeenoghu.
TALIESIN: Yoplait.
MARISHA: Uh-huh. Yoplait is a female deity? Or a
male deity? Do you remember?
TALIESIN: It's hard to remember. It's a lot of
aggression, anger.
MARISHA: I'm wondering with that whole, you
know--
LIAM: Why are you curious about that?
MARISHA: Well, the guy. The guy running the
ceremony said that the hunger will be fed, "ours
"and hers," right? I mean, that's what he said,
right, DM? I didn't mishear that?
MATT: Yes.
TALIESIN: Do I remember anything about either
gender or that this would be-- Other than
I just saw a lot of aggression and a feral aspect of this.
MATT: That was it, yeah.
MARISHA: I just wonder who "hers" is. Who is
that?
LIAM: That is the crux of the matter.
MARISHA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Shall we go find out?
TRAVIS: Yep.
MATT: As you guys are having this conversation,
you hear one sound that varies very strongly from
the others that have encompassed this tunnel
sequence. You hear this female scream, this
high-pitched shrieking scream that says, "No! My
baby!"
LAURA: Oh, no! This is what happens when we sit
down and we talk.
TRAVIS: We got to go. Can't fuck around with mama
deaths.
LAURA: We're moving forward as quickly as
possible.
SAM: I charge ahead.
MATT: You guys rush down the tunnel deeper into
the maze of mineshafts--
MARISHA: What?
MATT: And we'll pick up on that next week.
MARISHA: No!
SAM: Whose baby? Where are they? Why were they
crying? We'll find out next week.
LAURA: That's one way to get your players to move.
There's babies dying.
MATT: Also, babies.
MARISHA: Oh my God!
TRAVIS: (singing) We fucked up the gnolls, fucked
up the gnolls.
LAURA: I like that our pickle jar is getting
filled with little--
TALIESIN: Filled with pickled ears!
LAURA: I'm smushing them down so that there's
like--
MATT: Oh god! So it's actually briney pickled
gnoll ears?
TALIESIN: Have you ever had pickled pigs' feet?
LAURA: Well, we drank all the pickle juice out of
it, so, really they just kind of have a pickle stink.
MATT: That's true.
TALIESIN: They're in their own juices.
MATT: Yeah, there you go.
LIAM: It's like a tip jar.
MATT: Yeah, it'll be an interesting, interesting
learning process of conservation of spells as you
progress down--
LAURA: Well, I was saving them but then
fucking Fjord asked for healing.
MATT: I know. That's okay. That's what cantrips
are for. That's what weapons are for.
LAURA: That's what I was using, cantrips.
MATT: That's what I'm saying, something to keep--
as you continue forward if you need to assault
things. All right. Oh, quick announcement which is
fun, so we're going to have a guest next week.
SAM: Oh. We are?
MATT: Our first guest of the campaign.
MARISHA: We didn't know about this.
MATT: Yeah you did, I mentioned it.
MARISHA: We knew this. We totally fucking knew
this.
SAM: Do we know who it is?
MATT: Yeah, next week we'll be able to have on our
show Khary Payton.
LAURA: Yay!
MATT: He's a long-time friend of a lot of us here,
we've worked a lot in the VO community. If you
aren't familiar with him, you should look him up.
If you've been watching The Walking Dead or Fear
of the Walking Dead, he's been awesome. On that
show for a long time.
LIAM: Teen Titan's Go!, plays Grimlock on
Transformers, all over the place.
MATT: Phenomenal voice actor, great actor. We've
been talking for a long time, he's been wanting to
play in this for a long time, but he's been very
busy, of course, those things, but he's in town
and he'll be joining us.
MARISHA: He's so nice.
MATT: I know.
MARISHA: He's such a teddy bear.
MATT: He's fucking awesome. So we'll have Khary
here next week. We're so excited to have him join
us, and go give him a little love. He's actually
at a Kansas City convention right now with Will Friedle.
TRAVIS: Oh, nice!
MATT: So if you're in that area over the next few
days, you should go say hi and give him some
Critter love or on the internet as well. So, yeah,
excited to have him next week. In the interim,
guys, have a wonderful week, we love you, thank
you for joining us, and is it Thursday yet? Good night.