MATT: Hello everyone! And welcome to tonight's
episode of Critical Role, where us nerdy-ass voice
actors sit around and play Dungeons & Dragons.
Slight delay there due to tech issues but we're
back online and all is well. Tick issues are a
problem-- It's a thing, I know. We're going to
jump in here shortly. We have a guest who'll be
joining us partway into the story. Before we get
to that, let's go ahead and get to our
announcements and get them out of the way because
we're a little behind. We'll try and rush through.
First and foremost, tonight our sponsor and has
been our sponsor from the beginning and onward
into the campaign, our friends at D&D Beyond.
They've been awesome. Sam! You seem ready to say
something?
SAM: You guys know what D&D Beyond is? It's
awesome. You should check out the site
dndbeyond.com. They also now have open alpha
access for an upcoming mobile app. The D&D Beyond
team is looking for additional stress testers and
you can sign up using the following links. Insert
links below me.
MATT: In case they aren't--
SAM: Oh, I have to read it? Okay, bit.ly/dndios
and bit.ly/dndandroid.
MATT: Bit.ly as in bit dot ly.
SAM: Yeah, they know what bit.ly is.
MATT: I'm just making sure!
SAM: Sure. Since D&D is such a dorky 80s thing to
do, I've composed a dorky 80s jingle for D&D
Beyond.
(cheering)
SAM: (singing) You got the perfect warlock, the
weapons and supplies, But you need a place to
track your stuff, 'cause you're so disorganized!
You click open the web page you heard about on
Critical Role. Now you're ready to kick some butt
in that mineshaft full of gnolls! It's D&D! D&D
Beyond. Yeah D&D! D&D Beyond. You got your stats,
you got your sword and you've got your invisible
wand! It's D&D! D&D (synthetic drum sound effects)
D&D Beyond!
(cheering and applause)
TRAVIS: Oh my god! If they don't make that they're
fools!
MARISHA: That was magic!
LAURA: I want to see that!
TRAVIS: We're going to make that right? We're
going to make that now.
MATT: There are moments like this that it makes me
a little sad that you're no longer a bard. At
least we keep the Scanlan alive with shit like
this.
TRAVIS: Tell me you were singing that in your car
on the way home from work.
SAM: I was.
TALIESIN: I can see action figures busting through
walls being held by hands (explosion sound
effects).
MATT: That was awesome. Thank you, Sam.
SAM: You had to imagine the synths.
MATT: Oh yeah, we were there. Thank you D&D Beyond
for allowing that to happen as well as being a
helpful tool.
LIAM: Les Mis was a stepping stone for that
moment.
MATT: Awesome. Next up. Reminder guys who have
Amazon Prime, with Twitch Prime, you can actually
subscribe to a Twitch channel for free. One a
month with your Amazon Prime account. If you have
it, connect it to your Twitch account and you can
subscribe to Geek & Sundry or any other Twitch
channel you are a fan of, for free.
LIAM: (as Mickey Mouse) Comes with Prime!
MATT: What is going on? I'm so scared.
TRAVIS: You hit a particular high note and we're
trying to do our best squeaky voice.
MATT: It's a really good idea to taunt the DM
before you start playing. I think it works out
really well for everyone involved.
LIAM: Like the internet, we like to obsess about
your every little movement.
MATT: Of course, that's okay. I have a sense of
self. Talks Machina, of course, will be discussing
tonight's episode next Tuesday with our host W.
Foster. Brian W. Foster. It's been a long day. W
Foster!
MARISHA: It's very formal.
MATT: Isn't it though? When he dresses up nice?
Tuesday at 7:00pm Pacific here at Twitch and
Project Alpha to discuss what happens tonight.
Check that out. Laura, you said there's a merch
update.
LAURA: Yes! Hey! I don't know if you guys have
gone to the store lately but there's stuff in
there. The reason that I was talking today is
because I was informed that there's actually some
more CR dice, not the Vox Machina dice-- those
aren't back yet, but the CR dice are in stock if
you've been wanting some of those. There's also
stickers and keychains and t-shirts-- lots of
t-shirts you should check them out-- and notebooks
and awesome pencils.
LIAM: Still got that art book.
LAURA: That art book and an apron for the Slayer's
Cake.
SAM: Just one?
LAURA: Just one apron.
MATT: A single apron, get it now before it's
gone. Awesome, thank you, Laura.
LAURA: Supplies are limited.
MATT: The podcast for last week's episode is
available for download where all fine podcasts are
available on the internet. If you have friends
listening to the audio version, they be caught up,
now. After this episode probably, they'll start it
now. You get it. We announced at Emerald City
Comic Con we have a limited release, only 1000
copies of the physical copies of the Issue #1 of
the Vox Machina Origins comic.
(shouts of excitement)
MATT: Oh, I haven't seen it yet!
LAURA: I haven't seen it in person yet!
TALIESIN: It's all about the back.
SAM: Don't open it! Your hands will touch it and
it will no longer be mint!
(groaning)
TRAVIS: Now it's worth more. Keep going.
MATT: There'll be 1000 copies there. The limit is
only five copies per person per day.
MARISHA: Oh my goodness gracious.
SAM: You're on the back of a comic book?
LAURA: Hey, and it's the Slayer's Cake apron that
I was just--
MATT: (laughing) Thank you Laura for pointing that
out.
(exclamations of awe)
MATT: Dark Horse is releasing that for this
special event. Please check it out if you are
going to be there. Grab a copy if you want. It is
March 1st through the 4th, and our good cast
members here Laura and Travis will be there.
LAURA: Yes we will as well as-- You're going to be
there too.
MATT: Oh shit! Well, there you go. You can go tell
him how much you liked his character tonight.
Speaking of the comic book: Issue five will be
released on digital platforms of that very comic
March 7th. Those that want to keep up and get to
the next chapter of the six issue arc, issue five
comes out March 7th so keep an eye out for that
and we'll have announcements as that comes. You
can look for a sneak peek at the artwork at
geekandsundry.com. Once again, our campaign is
pushing our fantastic friends at 826LA. They're an
amazing charity group that takes underprivileged
kids or children and young teens who don't have
the opportunity to get in depth and learn about
creative writing and give them a safe space for
them. They do wonderful work. Check it out if you
have the opportunity. See if you can give either
financially or with your time and you can
volunteer to be part of the program. It's really
great. Other than that, appearances are as they've
been and I think--
SAM: I have one more thing. A quick shoutout to a
critter named Carol who is an awesome fantasy
writer and friend of the show. She's been feeling
a little under the weather but she's been watching
our new campaign and I wanted to wish her a speedy
recovery and thanks for watching.
MATT: Love to you, Carol. All right guys, without
further ado, let's dive into tonight episode of
Critical Role.
[click, TV static]
[groovy Critical Role theme]
(laughter)
MATT: Welcome back. The DM will remember that.
LIAM: Are we doing a show right now?
MATT: We are.
LIAM: (whimpering) Okay.
MATT: Welcome back. Last we left off: The group of
adventures in seeking a warband of gnolls which
had attacked the city of Alfield they were passing
through on their way to Zadash. Began to track
them as to where they had retrieved a number of
bodies, both dead and living of the civilians of
the town and taken them with them. You eventually
track them to an abandoned mine a number of miles
away from the city to the northeast. You entered,
narrowly missed a trap or two, managed to recover
a couple of interesting items, delved off to the
left side during the first divide of pathways, and
came upon some sort of small ritual with a number
of gnolls and some humanoid figure wearing bits of
gnoll as an armor or cloak. Doing a ritual-- after
he had left along with the previously armored
gnoll that you had battled during the incursion at
Alfield. You tore into a number of hyenas and
gnolls that remained within the chamber and upon
defeating them, took a moment to take a breath,
get your bearings before hearing a muffled boom in
the distance, some sort a low vocalization, some
cackling, and eventually the scream of a woman
saying, "No, my baby!" You began to run and give
chase. That is where we're picking up this week.
Grabbing your weapons and keeping your mettle
about you, you charge further down the tunnel. The
shaft curves to the right in a wide spiral about a
few dozen-- there we go. What was that?
TRAVIS: The shaft curves to the right.
SAM: You said "The sha--" and she laughed. Like
before you were done with the word shaft.
LAURA: Because the shaft curves to the right,
y'all.
LIAM: It's her psychic power.
TRAVIS: It's usually to the left, but whatever.
MATT: It's okay.
SAM: Not from her perspective.
(laughter)
MATT: Boom!
MARISHA: That's fair.
TRAVIS: Too fast! Like a fencer! That was
amazing!
LAURA: Only you.
(laughter)
MARISHA: Walked into that one.
LIAM: Well.
MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Life or death. Here we go.
MATT: The tunnel continues in a wide spiral before
eventually snaking a bit--
(laughter)
MARISHA: You're an asshole.
MATT: --before sharply turning to the right. The
tunnel straightens out before emerging into a
chamber of-- goddamn it guys, this is serious!
Lives are at stake here. Okay.
(laughter)
MARISHA: What were you going to say?
TRAVIS: You got it. We're with you. Life or
death.
SAM: The path--
MATT: The tunnel straightens out before emerging
into a chamber of mixed natural rock walls and
simple stone work. Two other tunnels mark this
chamber as a Y intersection or like a second
common room. Similar to the one you that you
originally encountered when you entered the mine.
Tables and stools are strewn about the area, with
a pair of hyenas currently picking at junk for
scraps. You see bits of meat that are being
dragged across the ground by them about 20 feet
off to the left. Two thick natural pillars of rock
currently stand as load bearing portions of the
chamber breaking the open space while a crumpled
section of the floor drops into a pit below. Two
closed doors, to the left of where you're looking
into it, are guarded by a skeletal gnoll and two
standard gnoll warriors, one of which has
apparently pulled a small child from one of the
doors. The sound of muffled cries coming from
beyond the closed door. Four other gnolls rush
from within the chamber into the right tunnel
exiting on the opposite side. What do you guys
do?
MARISHA: Four to the right?
MATT: You watch as four of them rush into the
other exit. There's an exit to the left and an
exit to the right. They exit the room to the right
and then there's three left: two regular--
MATT, TRAVIS, and MARISHA: (singing) Regular
gnolls!
MATT: --and then one skeletal gnoll and then two
hyenas that are currently picking at scraps. You
can see as the gnoll pulls the child out, is
currently in the process of crying and they're
both looking at each other like-- still holding
the child by the arm essentially-- but currently
is bickering with the other gnoll.
LIAM: From our vantage point, it is the entrance
that we're at and then there is doors to the
left--?
MATT: Let me go ahead and give you a visual.
TRAVIS: (singing) Visual aid, visual aid.
LIAM, TRAVIS, AND MARISHA: (singing) Visual aid,
visual aid.
LAURA: Oh no! If this is like a running thing this
whole campaign--
TALIESIN: Oh, there's no getting away from this.
(laughter)
(Oohs and ahs)
LAURA: Look at that opening, it's so cool
looking!
SAM: Where are we?
MATT: You guys are entering from this side.
LAURA: Oh that's a little door? That's the door
you we're talking about?
MATT: Yep.
SAM: There's too many options!
MATT: Essentially, over here-- You can place
yourselves as you feel necessary. Off to this
side, in whichever marching order you prefer.
LIAM: I will be at the rear.
MATT: I figured as much.
LAURA: How old is the child that got pulled out of
the room?
MATT: At first glance, it's hard to see,
especially for those of you who are keeping their
light low, because there is no light source in the
chamber. Those with dark vision will be making out
most of the details here.
TRAVIS: I'll be up front. I can do that.
MATT: All right, that would put Fjord up at the
front.
LAURA: I'll be behind Fjord.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: I can't see shit.
MATT: Given this, you guys are deciding what to
do. There's, in a brief moment of quiet, a loud
boom that shakes the interior of the chamber. You
watch as both the hyenas (squeal) look up, scared.
The two gnolls immediately look about. Dust and
rocks begin to settle and fall from the ceiling as
it shakes and then comes to rest. A moment later,
a cloud of dust and smoke comes billowing out this
side of the chamber where the four gnolls had run
previously. Then the rumbling settles. The gnolls
themselves are spooked. Then, distracted from the
child at the moment, both peeking over, the undead
gnoll stands there glancing about, seeming
unaffected by the current scenario. Passive
perception, the highest on this would be
Beauregard, Caleb, Molly, and Jester, I believe.
Actually, Caleb and Beauregard would not, because
they don't see anything. You guys hear sounds, and
you're waiting for any inclination of light to
kick in.
LAURA: What do we see, though?
MATT: You guys see the faint appearance of some
sort of a flying creature, very small, emerge from
the tunnel that had recently expelled all this
dust and smoke.
LAURA: Frumpkin size or smaller?
MATT: Frumpkin size. (humming) It hovers in the
air in a few places, and then locks itself over
here onto this far wall, on a higher perch.
TRAVIS: Fucking bugs.
LAURA: Did you see that?
TALIESIN: I think I saw that. Did you see that?
LAURA: I saw that.
MATT: (snarl) Another moment passes, and the
gnolls relax. You watch as the immediate dread of
the recent explosion sound, the shocking and
rocking of the room, seems to have passed over
them. They both go back to paying attention to
their recent vicinity, which includes the small
child, which is still quietly sobbing in the
painful grasp of this large curled gnoll hand.
TALIESIN: On the count of three?
SAM: Wait, are we just going to attack?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
SAM: We should distract them--!
LAURA: Radiant blast!
SAM: Oh, Jesus.
LAURA: Sacred Flame, I mean.
MATT: All right. The ones who are making the
initial strike on this--
SAM: I could distract them or something first!
TRAVIS: Eldritch Blast for me, yeah.
LIAM: I will also do that as well, following suit
with everybody.
MARISHA: Wait, are things happening?
LAURA: Don't hit the kid!
MARISHA: We can't see! Do you have your lights?
MATT: Caleb, you don't see anything.
LIAM: Oh, okay.
MATT: The ones who can see in the dark right now,
which would be the four of you, you guys get a
round of attack on this.
TRAVIS: Nice.
MATT: Where you're currently positioned, I would
like you all to roll initiative before we get to
your round, just so we have it.
TRAVIS: Come on, first roll of the night! Be
fucking amazing.
TALIESIN: Yay!
MATT: Not so much?
TRAVIS: I've had better.
MATT: All righty. So--
SAM: I'm not drunk anymore, right?
MATT: No, that's worn off.
LIAM: Great. How about Nott?
MATT: 25 to 20?
MARISHA: 20.
SAM: 24.
ALL: Ooh!
SAM: Natural 20.
MATT: All right. 20 to 15.
TALIESIN: 16.
LAURA: But you can't see, Beau.
MATT: She's missing the initial round.
LAURA: Oh, this is for the whole thing.
MATT: Correct. This is just general combat.
LAURA: If I'd have known that, I would have rolled
better for the whole thing.
MATT: That's true. Sorry about that. That's okay.
LAURA: I wasn't trying so hard.
MATT: 15 to ten?
LAURA: Ten.
TALIESIN: That's very adequate.
LIAM: I have rolled a nine.
TALIESIN: This is going to be the thing for the
entire campaign. This is going to be the joke that
never goes away. Nein!
LIAM: (singing) Regular gnoll, regular gnoll.
LAURA: Oh no, oh no.
LIAM: That's it. Just nine and regular gnoll,
that's all that we have. That's campaign two,
ladies and gentlemen.
MATT: That leaves-- you rolled a what?
TRAVIS: An eight.
MARISHA: Nines and gnolls. That's our group name,
you guys.
TALIESIN: No! Don't joke, don't ever.
SAM: It's one of the best rolls you can make in
the game. What is our initiative shit?
LAURA: Ah!
MATT: Nott, you're up first.
SAM: Okay, but I didn't see, and you guys decided
to attack first. I will grace you going first if
you prefer.
LAURA: You're going to hold your turn?
MATT: You feel the tension rising and you're like,
I'll follow their lead.
SAM: Does that mean I still get to move and shit
when I do my move?
MATT: That means you're holding your action.
SAM: Then I'll go now. Because they're more than
30 feet away, right?
MATT: Yeah. You can see what's out there, you just
don't notice the bird.
SAM: Hand crossbow, it says 30/120. I've got to be
within 30 to hit them without disadvantage, right?
If I run out there, they'll see me and I won't be
sneak attack anymore, right? How does this work?
MATT: If they don't know you're there, which this
is currently what's considered an ambush round,
you still have advantage on your first strike if
they're not aware of your presence. Which means it
would cancel out that disadvantage.
SAM: I can take my shot from here.
MATT: You can, yes.
SAM: All right. I will fire.
MATT: All right.
SAM: Ooh! 17 plus a lot. Six! 17 plus six to hit.
MATT: That hits. You do not get sneak attack on
this because you do not have advantage on the
strike.
SAM: I thought you just said I had advantage!
MATT: You had advantage, but you have disadvantage
because they're beyond the--
LIAM: It cancelled out your advantage. It's just a
straight roll and you lost the sneak attack.
SAM: Could I run forward and still get the sneak
attack?
MATT: You could try it.
SAM: That's what I will do. Undo.
LAURA: Roll again, because you might get natural
20!
SAM: Now I have to roll for stealth, right?
MATT: You've been stealthed as you crept up on
this from the last time, so go for it.
SAM: I'm rolling to hit?
MATT: You already hit on that.
LAURA: Roll again for advantage, you might get a
20.
SAM: Okay. Still 17 plus six.
MATT: Now you get a sneak attack, go for it.
SAM: Cool.
LAURA: Did you find it?
MARISHA: I did! It was nowhere it should have
been.
SAM: 11 points. Not very good rolls.
TRAVIS: Which one are you aiming at?
MATT: Not bad, either.
SAM: The one that's holding the child.
MATT: As it's holding the child and it's looking
down at the young boy, lifting it off the ground
and bringing it towards its jaws as its teeth open
wide, its lips curl back like it's ready to take a
quick little nibble of the child's arm. Suddenly
the bolt hits it in the side of the jaw and it's
sticking out. (squeal, snarl) It starts looking
over in your direction and it looks right towards
you. (growl)
SAM: Can I use my regular-- regular gnoll. Do I
have remaining movement as a bonus?
MATT: No, it's your full movement to get there.
Bonus action you can dash if you want to.
SAM: Yes. I will dash away, but I can't hide. I
will dash behind those rocks to my right.
MATT: Over here?
SAM: Yes. In those skulls or anywhere around
there.
MATT: That works fine there. Beau.
TRAVIS: She can't see shit.
LAURA: I'm not Beau.
MATT: Sorry. Beau, you lose your turn. It's been a
long day, I'm sorry. Molly, you're up next.
TALIESIN: I'm going to run straight in, take a
look around. Is the undead one the closest one to
me?
MATT: It is, yes.
TALIESIN: Push me a little more against the wall.
MATT: Over here?
TALIESIN: Yeah, over there. I'm going to hit that
undead one with Vicious Mockery. Actually, I'm
going to hit the one that has the kid with Vicious
Mockery, not the undead one.
MATT: Okay. Same roll, puts him at a two, natural
roll, so he's affected by it.
TALIESIN: Oh that's right, I don't have to roll to
hit. Just a wisdom saving throw. That's three
points of damage.
MATT: All right, and he has disadvantage on his
next attack roll.
TALIESIN: Yes. (rasping) Drop the child!
TRAVIS: Jesus Christ.
TALIESIN: Get used to it.
MATT: The skeletal gnoll turns to you (cracking).
It seems to hear it and there's something about
the speech and the connection to this entity that
cause it to shudder for a moment. That ends your
turn?
TALIESIN: Yep. I'm holding waiting for them.
MATT: Next up is Beau. Wait, no. Sorry. That's my
problem, I wrote Beau twice on this.
TRAVIS: I'm the only other one that can see.
LAURA: I'm Beau number two!
MATT: Jester and then you.
LAURA: I lied! I am not going to do the Sacred
Flame, I'm going to do Toll the Dead because
that's a wisdom saving throw.
MATT: Okay! Toll the Dead to which one?
LAURA: To the one holding the kid.
MATT: All righty. Constitution saving throw?
LAURA: That's a wisdom saving throw.
MATT: That is going to put him at a 15.
LAURA: Aw, he saves.
MATT: Sorry. As it seems to ring within its head,
the impact of the necromantic magic, currently
still reeling from the pain in the throat from the
bolt, it seems to shrug it off, unaffected. Then
Fjord, you're up.
LAURA: (rasping) Next time I'm going to really
hurt you! I said that in Infernal.
TALIESIN: Oh, yeah!
TRAVIS: Which one of them is the undead looking
gnoll?
MATT: Right there.
TRAVIS: That guy. I would like to aim at the dude
on the right, the one closest to you, and I will
carry over my Hex that is still up since it lasts
an hour, so for my bonus action I will cast Hex on
that motherfuck.
MATT: All righty.
TRAVIS: I would like to use Eldritch Blast.
MATT: Go for it. Roll for the attack.
TRAVIS: Plus six, that's a 20.
MATT: Yeah, that hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
TRAVIS: Nice. This is a 1d10 plus four. That's 11
plus five points of necrotic damage for 16 total.
MATT: 16 points of damage, all right. As it's
standing on this upper portion of the rock floor,
it glances back as you guys enter. You guys see a
flash of light from the arcing of the arcane
energy as it streaks across and slams into its
body just in time to see another shadowed shape
emerging out of this tunnel to join the fray. As
it falls back (snarling, chattering). That's going
to end the initial round of combat. Now we're into
the initiative order. At the top of this, you guys
glance over and the four of you, at least, see
this shape begin to emerge from around the wall.
You see this tall, spindly humanoid figure that
begins to curve around the side. Khary, if you
want to join the table.
(cheering)
TRAVIS: Spindly, what?
MATT: If I can have you roll initiative when you
get settled in there.
TRAVIS: Oh, man, I don't even know what that
means!
LAURA: I've got to see this dice as you roll it.
MARISHA: Do you want a dice tray, Khary? We have
an extra one down here.
KHARY: Oh my goodness, look at this!
MARISHA: Look at that.
TRAVIS: The luxurious life.
LIAM: Welcome, friend! Welcome!
KHARY: This is the first time this dice has been
rolled, ladies and gentlemen.
TRAVIS: Do it.
MARISHA: It's a christening roll!
LIAM: It's a one!
KHARY: It's a one?
TRAVIS: Welcome! Welcome!
LIAM: One of us! One of us!
[laughing]
KHARY: Thanks for having me, guys. I'll just be
taking this.
LIAM: Storytelling!
LAURA: You weren't even rolling those dice?
KHARY: Yes. All right, here we go.
MATT: You, having succeeded at some of your other
business, begin to creep further into these
tunnels and suddenly see a cluster of unidentified
individuals rushing in here and attacking these
gnolls in front of you and the surprise of it
apparently puts you off for the moment.
KHARY: Just a little.
MATT: We'll come to you in just a moment. Good to
know. At the top of the combat round, Nott, you're
up first.
SAM: That was it? We cycled through a whole round
of combat?
MATT: The surprise round. The humans can't see
anything, unfortunately. Everything you'll be
doing will be at disadvantage after this point.
SAM: I'll have to move. I'll lean around to get
around that stalagtite.
MATT: Around here?
SAM: No, just so I can get an eyeline on the one I
already shot once.
MATT: Back over here?
SAM: Yeah. Anywhere. I'm going to move right back
in a second. I'll lean around, reload. Oh, god!
Fire again.
MATT: Go for it.
SAM: Do I get sneak attack? No, right?
MATT: No, because you're not hidden.
SAM: Shitballs. 20 to hit.
MATT: 20 hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
SAM: Eight.
MATT: Eight points of damage. That'll do it,
actually. As it's holding the child and lifting it
up by the arm in the air, it looks like it's ready
to run away and grab it with it. As it turns to
flee, you catch it in the base of the skull and it
falls to the ground. The child falls prone onto
the floor next to the now lifeless gnoll body.
SAM: What does the child look like? He or she?
It's a boy?
MATT: It looks to be a young boy, probably between
six and eight years old. You're not quite sure of
the age.
SAM: And human, I don't know anything about. Is it
injured?
MATT: You haven't got a strong bead on it but he
looks to be humanoid.
MARISHA: Six or eight years old?
MATT: Around that age group, you'd assume.
TALIESIN: Some would say seven.
LAURA: Yes! The field is ours now!
SAM: No! I'm too scared to go over there. No,
there's a child in need. We've got to help.
TRAVIS: You're sober now, right?
SAM: Yeah. Nott's going to scurry over to the boy
as fast as she can scurry.
MATT: 30, and then you can use your bonus action
to dash if you want to.
SAM: Yep, all the way to the little boy.
MATT: That'll do it. You can get right to the
little boy.
SAM: (screech)
MATT: As you run up, the little boy's like,
(screaming) Just starts screaming bloody murder in
the tunnel.
[laughing]
SAM: I'm good! I'm a good one! I'm good!
MATT: (screaming) He starts crying even louder,
somehow scared of you more than the gnoll.
[screaming]
LAURA: Now it's a horror movie.
MATT: That's your turn, Nott. Beau, you're up.
You're hearing all these sounds, but you can't see
anything.
MARISHA: I'm going to turn to Caleb and be like:
Can you do the thing? The lights?
LIAM: Get back to me in a second, in about nine
seconds.
MARISHA: I'm going to wait until he casts Dancing
Lights.
MATT: You can't move in there if you hold your
action, but you can move in and then hold your
action if you want to. You're just not quite sure
where you're walking.
MARISHA: Okay. Sure. I will stumble forward. I
will head towards Molly because I'm going to
follow his fluorescent purple coat.
TRAVIS: Just doing this?
MARISHA: Molly! Molly!
MATT: He's easy to see because Molly has this
faint, luminous glow around the sword from his
right. You see that as a beacon. You're like,
"That I know, that I can follow." You cozy up
right next to Molly and carefully prepare
yourself.
MARISHA: Where are they?
MATT: What action are you holding? If any.
MARISHA: I-- Because I moved and I'm not near
anything.
MATT: Correct.
MARISHA: So I'll take the Dodge action.
MATT: Okay. Dodge action. You're just being
careful. All right, ending Beau's turn, Molly,
you're up again.
TALIESIN: I'm going to rush the undead one.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: Spinning swords at bloody high speed and
take two shots.
MATT: Go for it. Do you want to be on the higher
ground here or--?
TALIESIN: Ooh! Can I do the higher ground?
MATT: Yeah, you can.
TALIESIN: I'll do the higher ground. That's
exciting.
LIAM: Now taking the stage, it's Mollymauk!
TALIESIN: That sucks! I'm taking your--
LAURA: I was trying to help!
TALIESIN: Nope!
MATT: And your off-hand?
TALIESIN: That's a 15.
MATT: 15 does hit.
TALIESIN: Okay. Yep. No. That's at least eight
points of damage.
LAURA: That's great!
TALIESIN: That's okay. That's okay. I'm now
engaged in combat with him, so that's fine. I am
whirling dervish that hits nothing at this point.
SAM: As per usual.
TALIESIN: I'm a hippie with poi right now. Might
as well be a pair of pois. Wah! Wah!
MATT: Good to know. End of Molly's turn, Jester,
you're up.
LAURA: Oh! Okay. I'm going to move forward into
the room. To about, yeah, there's good, sure. I'm
going to try it again. Did the guy up there get
hurt at all?
MATT: Yeah, he's been damaged, yes.
LAURA: Yes? Then I'm going to cast Toll the Dead
at him.
MATT: All right. That is a 14.
LAURA: Fucking A, piece of shit!
TRAVIS: What's the save?
LAURA: It's 13 because I'm lame!
MATT: Sorry. As you try and release the energy
once more, it can't quite get a bead on the
gnoll's head. It's moving around and dodging and
you can't focus on it.
LAURA: I'm going to start unsnapping my sickle to
get it out to hit things.
MATT: Okay. As you're fussing with this side,
that's the end of your turn. All right. Caleb,
you're up.
LIAM: I cannot see anything, so I cast Dancing
Lights. I put one above my head and as soon as I
get a little bit of light, I send one over Beau's
head and then I send one about 20 feet beyond Beau
and then the fourth one, even beyond that one so
there's a line of four lights because I don't know
what the chamber is shaped like.
MATT: The chamber erupts into bright light like
there's four torches now lifting brightly at the
entire space.
TRAVIS: Ah, god!
MATT: Bright visuals there, you can now see the
child on the ground being scared shitless by the
goblin trying to help. The undead gnoll that's
currently locked in combat with Molly. You see the
two hyenas that are both snarling and getting
ready to pounce on whoever comes too close. The
one wounded gnoll over there. As well as, if you'd
like to describe yourself.
(exclamations of excitement)
SAM: Where is he?
LIAM: You know, Matthew, the guiding lights, those
little '"foomphs" of light, they only have a
10-foot radius, so probably the edges of the line
that I have cast just barely makes it flame.
MARISHA: They're like market lights so it's
pretty. Yeah.
LIAM: Of course. It is, of course, pretty. Never
mind, just continue.
MATT: Yes. So.
KHARY: The thing you probably notice about me,
first of all--
TRAVIS and MARISHA: (high-pitched) Ooh!
SAM: No. You can't have a better accent than all
of us.
KHARY: --is my hair. My billowy, white afro.
TRAVIS: Yes!
KHARY: Fingers of curly hair radiating in all
directions. That should be the thing that you
notice first about me but that's not it. It's my
eyes. My eyes, as white as my hair. My pupil-less
eyes as white as my hair. As white as the hair
dripping down from my chin to a straight point
about three or four inches below. I think that's
all you really notice.
TRAVIS: Shit!
MATT: Caleb, do you wish to move?
MARISHA: I'm in love. What?
MARISHA: Oh!
LIAM: Oh. Fuck that. I will stay where I am. No,
thank you.
MATT: All right. Fjord and the gnoll going at the
same time. What are you doing?
TRAVIS: Eldritch Blast again at that motherfuck.
MATT: As this gnoll here has taken the impact is
going to rush over towards Mollymauk to attempt to
take a strike. While another gnoll who's bloodied
and partially crushed is now hobbling its way up
out of this tunnel and spins around to see you up
against the side of the wall (growls and yips).
All right, Fjord?
TRAVIS: 16 plus six, so 22?
MATT: That hits. The gnoll's going to be striking
you. That's a three, that's not going to happen.
No.
TRAVIS: Eight plus four is 12 plus four points of
necrotic for 16 total points of damage.
MATT: All right. The reason it misses is right as
it swings towards you, Fjord raises the back of
the sword and fires a blast of eldritch energy
that hits the back of the gnoll's shoulder as it
tries to spin and strike you. As it does, it goes
wide. It pirouettes on its foot and stumbles back
into the open hole. (high-pitched yell)
TRAVIS: Oh, there's an open fucking hole?! That's
good to know! Oh, shit!
MATT: Yeah!
LIAM: Did you hear the sound go (high-pitched
yell)? So it's not ten feet, it's big.
TRAVIS: Okay. Good to know! Fuck.
MATT: You're a ways away. It's hard to see.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Uh-huh.
MATT: Described your initial description of the
room, though, so now you know. As you, who has not
given your name yet, but you turn around and see
this gnoll as it looks towards you. It's leaning
towards-- normally, it would be seven-foot, but
it's hunched and wounded and as it turns down, it
snarls. Takes its spear and attempts to pin you to
the wall a bit. That's going to be a 12. What's
your armor class?
KHARY: My armor class is-- what is it? It's 15.
MATT: 15? It does not hit.
TRAVIS: Yeah!
MATT: As it swings, you push out of the way in
time, parrying it with your hand and your cane off
to the side and it smacks into the stone and
sparks off of it for a second, hitting flint. All
right, that ends the gnolls' turn. The hyenas go.
Both of these hyenas now, turning around and
seeing what's happening are going to rush forward.
This one is going to run up alongside and attack
Molly. This one is going to rush over to Nott.
LAURA: Oh no.
MATT: Attacking Molly, that's going to be a 16 to
hit?
TALIESIN: That hits.
MATT: All right. It's going to be--
TRAVIS: Dance harder, dance harder!
MATT: --two points of piercing damage. As it snaps
up and bites the edge of your foot, you have to
kick and shake it off on the rocks to get it to
let go. The one that's striking towards you, Nott,
that's going to be an 18 to hit?
SAM: Hits!
MATT: You take only one point of piercing damage.
It gets one little bite on the side of your elbow
and you immediately pull away and kick it
instinctually in the chin, going (yelps). The kid
is now freaking out of his mind as now there's,
from his perspective, two snarling beasts
cornering in. That's going to end the hyenas'
turn. All right. Your go.
KHARY: I would say, if this thing is this close to
me.
MATT: Yeah, it's right up against you.
KHARY: It's right up against me. I think I should
push him away.
MATT: If you feel the need, yeah.
KHARY: Let's see. Thunderwave?
MATT: Certainly!
SAM: Skadoosh.
MATT: Is that a wisdom saving throw or
constitution--?
LIAM: It's a constitution save.
KHARY: That is a constitution save.
MATT: That is a three. A natural two plus,
actually plus zero. So two.
TRAVIS: Oh, yeah, that fails.
MATT: Yeah, that fails.
SAM: Your spellcasting modifier--
TRAVIS: He rolled a two, you're fine.
LIAM: 15!
KHARY: 15. It failed. Ah. Well, great.
MATT: 13, I believe. All right, cool. Go ahead and
roll the damage of that.
KHARY: With this?
MATT: Well, it should say it on the spell there.
MARISHA: I think it's 2d8?
LIAM: Thunderwave is 2d8. Yeah. 2d8 there. You
want the one that's shaped like a diamond. Here it
is. Yeah. That's good and then roll one more time.
Oh, that's good!
KHARY: Five and seven?
TRAVIS: 12. Damn!
MATT: 12 points of damage! As you turn towards it,
describe what you do with your spell as the gnoll
pulls back with its spear.
KHARY: I take my reed of a wand and whip it. Three
times.
MATT: (whipping sounds) As the third one hits,
there's a burst of energy forward. You watch as
the gnoll gets blown back, slamming into the stone
wall and falls back to its knees before getting
itself up. It was previously wounded, now it's on
death's door. It looks like it's starting to
hobble and try and flee.
TRAVIS: Would you say you whip your reed back and
forth? You whip your reed back and forth?
KHARY: I do. I whip my reed. I whip my reed back
and forth.
MATT: Do you wish to move?
KHARY: I do. I wish to move away from this
gentleman that I just knocked against a wall and
how about we take a perch on top of-- there we go,
baby.
LIAM: Oh, look at that fucking miniature!
MARISHA and LAURA: So cool!
MATT: That finishes your turn. At the top, Nott,
you're up.
SAM: Okay, I've got this thing on my arm? So with
my other hand, I will (high-pitched whimpering)
grab its face (normal voice) and I will say a few
a words that Caleb told me and cast Shocking Grasp
on it!
MATT: Okay! What is the spell save on that?
SAM: Shit, how do I find out? You click on it.
MATT: Oh, it's a spell melee attack. So go and
roll--
SAM: Ooh! Nine.
MATT: No. You try and reach out, but the snout is
too slobbery and your hand slips off of it and it
discharges the spell having no effect.
SAM: (yelps)
MATT: (yips)
SAM: Oh, god.
MATT: All right.
SAM: Let's see here. I've still got some bonus-y
stuff. Can I disengage? No, because--
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: Okay. I'll disengage, grab the boy, and try
to lead him behind the-- there's an overturned
table?
MATT: There is an overturned table. Yeah, these
are overturned tables over here.
SAM: Like right there.
MATT: Oh, right next to you. Yeah, you're right.
Right there.
SAM: Can I do that?
MATT: You can, yeah.
LAURA: Will the hyena get a bite on the kid?
SAM: We'll find out.
MATT: As you drag the child away, while you've
disengaged, you pull the child out of the range of
the hyena and it sees the opening and snaps out
towards--
LAURA: Children have no hit points!
SAM: I'm sure this one is hardy.
MATT: (chuckles)
LIAM: (singing) Careful, the kids you pull.
LAURA: (singing) Hyenas will bite them.
MATT: The hyena bites down and its jaws clamp into
the child's clavicle and chest. You hear this
clenched scream that's immediately muffled as you
watch a bit of blood begin to pour out of the side
of his mouth. As you pull the child from its jaws,
the child is alive. For now. Unconscious and
bleeding out.
(groaning)
MARISHA: Thank god it wasn't me this time.
MATT: That ends your turn, Nott. Beau, you're up.
MARISHA: Okay, seeing the situation that Nott is
in, I'm going to immediately run over and attack
that hyena.
MATT: Putting you there easy enough.
MARISHA: I'm just going to run up and go, "Yeah,
get!" Go kick and just kick it real hard.
TRAVIS: G-I-T.
TRAVIS and MARISHA: Git!
MARISHA: Natural 20.
TRAVIS: That it is.
MATT: Roll some damage.
MARISHA: I use my staff as a little bit like a
jumping leverage point to give me a little bit of
momentum and--
TRAVIS: Mini pole-vaulting?
MARISHA: Yeah. What do I do? I roll 1d8 and then
double it. That sucks, but that's six plus four,
so ten.
MATT: That's enough to do it. As you kick, the
hyena gets launched and arc through the air,
slamming into this table which busts it up against
the wall onto its side and you can't even see the
lifeless body of the hyena. It's currently buried
beneath the overturned table. That's your first--
MARISHA: Can I do a bonus action to use my med kit
on the kid? My healer's kit?
MATT: It's an action to use a healer's kit,
unfortunately. You still have some movement.
MARISHA: I'll just move over to the kid and hold
the wound.
TRAVIS: Stem the flow?
MARISHA: Yeah.
MATT: Okay, so you get down with Nott at this
point and you're trying to think of some way to
apply pressure to prevent the bleeding. Okay, that
ends your turn. That brings us to Molly.
TALIESIN: I'm taking a roll at the big guy. First
strike.
MATT: That's right, I forgot to put the undead guy
on the initiative order which he would have gotten
a round. We'll say you and him go simultaneously
at this point since you engaged him.
TALIESIN: That's fine because that's a 19 to hit?
MATT: That's a 13 to hit you. What's your armor
class?
TALIESIN: 15.
MATT: Yeah, even as it goes to strike at you with
some sort of rusted battleaxe, you still manage to
lift your foot out of the way and strike down
towards it.
TALIESIN: This is with the good sword, so this--
ooh, so this is (counting) 13 points of damage?
MATT: That's adding your wisdom modifier?
TALIESIN: That's adding my wisdom.
MATT: That'll do it. You shatter it with a strike.
As it attempts to swing towards you with the axe,
you duck out of the way, spin around, and backhand
it with your right enchanted scimitar, watching
the bones (boom) explode and scatter across the
ground. Like so many pebbles being thrown across
the floor.
TALIESIN: With my off-hand, I'm going to take a
swipe for the hyena over there.
MATT: Go for it.
TALIESIN: Come on. There we go! 20 to hit.
MATT: That hits. Roll damage.
TRAVIS: It's good to dispatch two in one turn.
LAURA: Yes!
TALIESIN: That's nine points of damage. I would
love to just kick that fucker right into the--
MATT: Yeah, you do.
TRAVIS: Yeah!
MATT: It gets down and jumps to pounce towards you
and you lean back and kick it and it tumbles down
to the darkness below. You wish to move?
TALIESIN: I'm going to move to the other side. I'm
going to start running towards the stranger just
to the left of-- yeah, I'm going to move towards
that cover right there.
MATT: Here?
TALIESIN: No, the other way. Towards me. Right
there, yeah.
MATT: Gotcha. That ends your go, Molly. That
brings us to Jester.
LAURA: Okay. Did I see the child go down?
MATT: You would've, yes.
LAURA: Okay. Then I am going to run over to the
kid.
SAM: You don't have to.
Just kill-- the kid's gonna live.
LAURA: No, all these other people are helping this
kid, so I guess I will too. Somebody better kill
that big gnoll, though.
SAM: Do you really care about the kid?
LAURA: I don't.
SAM: Then don't help.
LAURA: I don't care but now I feel guilty.
MATT: Are you going to healer's kit, Cure Wounds,
what are you doing?
LAURA: Should I use my last spell on this kid?
SAM: Hells no!
LAURA: I'm going to use a healer's kit to
stabilize him.
MATT: You don't have to make a check for that. You
get down and start pulling heavy rolls of soft
cotton fabric and various balms to help treat the
wound, and help staunch the flow of blood and bind
the child to the point where it's no longer on
death's door.
LAURA: The whole time I'm grumbling like: Oh I
could have gotten that last Toll of the Dead! It
would have heard a really good bell and instead
I'm doing this!
(laughter)
MATT: Perfect, that ends Jester's turn. Caleb,
you're up.
SAM: Angry healing.
LIAM: I cannot see anything except for Fjord, so
if I move forward up to where he is, am I able to
see any gnolls or any other kind of baddies where
I am?
MATT: Right there you can barely see the one
across the way that's on the ground getting up.
LIAM: Then I'll let my hand blacken and I will
fire off a Fire Bolt at him from here. Which I'm
sure will miss. Yeah it is. It misses.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: The call before it was clutch!
LAURA: Oh no!
LIAM: I turn to Fjord as it misses and say: Eh,
yeah.
(laughter)
MATT: Okay!
TALIESIN: We've got to get you glasses.
LAURA: Oh my god, Caleb needs glasses!
MATT: Caleb needs glasses.
LIAM: I have them, they're right here!
MATT: That ends Caleb's turn.
LAURA: A new prescription!
LIAM: I need an intelligence bump is what I need.
Boomp!
MATT: The gnoll's been wounded. It is going to
take a--
LAURA: Glasses make you smarter.
MATT: He's going to take a longbow off its and
looking over and seeing the Fire Bolt that almost
struck it, it's going to spin back towards you and
pull and arrow. It's going to take a shot at you
from across the way, Caleb.
LIAM: What do you mean?
MATT: This one remaining wounded gnoll is going to
take a shot at you with its longbow. Just checking
real fast.
LAURA: Your scarf will protect you!
MATT: Yeah, sure! You're well within its first
range increment.
LIAM: I have a very high AC. It's okay.
MATT: That's a natural 20.
MARISHA: Oh my god!
MATT: However--
SAM: However nothing.
LIAM: Unload it, give it to me!
MARISHA: He's trying to find a positive.
LIAM: No, don't find a positive!
MATT: Oh, that's good actually! He rolled a one on
the weapon die. It was a d8, it could have been a
16. Two plus two, four points of piercing damage.
That could have been a lot worse!
TRAVIS: That's pretty bad for him, though.
LIAM: No, actually that hurts an awful lot.
MATT: The gnoll released the arrow. As it hits you
in the stomach, it comes piercing out the other
side, pinning your jacket to you torso. You feel
like the pain and the warm pulse up your back from
the wound. It's almost numb at first and then you
feel the shock hit you as the gnoll turns and runs
this way.
LAURA: Oh no! I should have Tolled the Dead on
him.
MATT: And he's way over there.
That's going to ends the gnoll's turn while
you're going Fjord. Because you're going in the
same round as this is happening, so you
technically could intercept.
TRAVIS: I'd like to get line of sight on him. I
look back at Caleb with his failed attempts and
say: Let me try mine. I'll move my Hex over to
him.
MATT: The Hex is on him.
TRAVIS: I'll fire an Eldritch Blast in his
direction. That is only a 16.
MATT: A 16? 16 hits, actually. You needed a 15 to
hit.
TRAVIS: Four plus four, eight. Plus three points
of necrotic for 11 damage.
MATT: As it turns with its bow, Fjord runs around.
Holding your sword out, another burst of eldritch
energy smacks into the back of the gnoll. You hear
(screeches) as it falls to the ground and slow
bits of curling green and blue eldritch flame
begin to burn and consume the corpse before
eventually it goes out, leaving most of the body
intact. Its back shoulder blades now a black cave
where its body once was.
LIAM: You ganked him at the last second?
LAURA: Someone bring me those ears and bring them
to my jar!
MATT: That being the case, the combat has come to
an end.
LAURA: How many gnolls was that we just killed?
TRAVIS: Three.
LIAM: Well don't we send a lot of them down the
hole. We didn't get their ears. So bad job.
LAURA: We only sent one down the hole.
TRAVIS: We got two ears.
MATT: Correct. They're sets of ears. There's the
one there and then the one that was killed there.
LAURA: Right and then, one hyena set.
KHARY: I appreciate you all counting ears, but can
we deal with the kid for a minute?
SAM: He needs some help!
LAURA: Do you see what I'm doing?
SAM: Who are you?! Ah! Who are you?
KHARY: I like your smile.
(laughter)
KHARY: Who am I? My name is Shakste. Nice to meet
you.
SAM: (swooning) He said Shakste.
KHARY: You can thank my bird for knowing what you
look like, actually.
LAURA: Oh, I saw your bird!
KHARY: That's not just some bird. That's the Grand
Duchess Anastasia Nikolaevna. They call her Stacy,
but that's not her name.
LAURA: (whispering) The Grand Duchess.
KHARY: The Grand Duchess. She's a sweetheart, but
she's angry.
LIAM: It is very dark in here, what kind of bird
is that you have?
KHARY: Oh, that would be an abrahum. That's a
dark, midnight hummingbird.
MARISHA: Hey, you're a badass, what's your deal?
KHARY: Well, right now my deal it to deal with
this little person over here.
LIAM: Yes, handle this child, but then we're very
curious to ask a couple-- I'll shut up.
LAURA: Can you heal? Do you have healing? Because
I'm stabilizing him don't worry, but--
SAM: He doesn't look good.
KHARY: I think I can maybe do something about
that.
MATT: Perhaps. The child is wounded, but the
child's wounds have been tended to. He's
unconscious, but is no longer in immediate danger
of dying. He'll eventually need rest.
LAURA: And some doughnuts.
MATT: Perhaps some doughnuts.
LAURA: I take one and push it onto his face.
TRAVIS: No, no! Fresh doughnuts! You know do no harm,
all that shit?
SAM: Can you do anything to help this guy?
KHARY: Well he seemed to be stabilized. I think
the best thing we could do is to get him to
safety.
TRAVIS: I agree. What were you doing down here? We
ourselves were comin' down trying to rescue folks.
KHARY: I tend to look over the people who happen
to be around here. I come by every once in a
while. I used to live and grew up in this place,
or in the valley not too far from here. Probably
just like you, I heard a commotion. I've taken a
few of these people to safety. I've been trying to
do it less overtly than some of you.
TRAVIS: We do make a bit of a clatter.
LAURA: We're working on it.
SAM: Insight check!
[laughter]
11 plus, what am I adding? 13.
MATT: 13. He's generally pretty forthright in
speech, charismatic figure, you don't get any
sense of any immediate lying or conflict to the
words he's saying. You're also not getting a full
read, either.
SAM: How handsome is he?
MATT: Quite handsome. If you'd like to describe
how handsome you are.
LIAM: Yeah, what do you look like?
KHARY: I would say I'm an old--
LAURA: On a scale from one to ten.
KHARY: On a scale from one to ten, I would call
him striking.
SAM: Bachelorette finalist?
[laughter]
KHARY: You know what? I think he's old enough that
he's gotten past all the bachelor-ing and the
bachelorette-ing.
LIAM: Are you a gray fox, is that what you are?
KHARY: I would call him more of a shock of white.
I mean, he's a striking character. He's got three
dimples, one you can't see. Two are pretty deep in
his face and can be menacing, unless he's
smiling.
LAURA: What are you wearing?
KHARY: He's covered in leather straps that are a
tangle of brown and red and green that pretty much
cover him from his neck to his calf where his
boots start to take over. There's a hood that he's
wearing, deep green. It goes down to his legs and
a big enough hood that's able to cover his ample
locks.
LIAM: Meanwhile everyone is talking to this
stranger, I'm going to edge up to this hole in the
ground and hold onto rocks because I'm scared to
death. Look over and send my globules of light
down there to see if it's a deep hole, if it goes
a long way, what am I looking at?
MATT: As your lights begin to slowly drift down
into the hole, they get about 50 or 60 feet down
before you begin to see the bottom of the shaft. It
looks to have been an intentionally created
well-like hole that has since seen disuse.
Currently ends into rocks and rubble.
LAURA: It's a poop hole!
MATT: You see the broken body of a gnoll and the
broken body of a hyena down at the bottom of it.
LIAM: We have to get this gnoll out of the bottom
of this hole because that's gold.
LAURA: He's probably covered in really old poop.
LIAM: It's still good for the monetary value that
was laid out for us, so maybe on the way out we
could send-- We have a rope we could lower you
down and you could slice it off.
SAM: Yeah, I could down there.
LIAM: Not right now, save it for a rainy day.
TRAVIS: Shakste, my name is Fjord. We are, like I
said, on a rescue mission. Are you familiar with
these tunnels, at all? Have you been down here
before?
KHARY: Have I been down here before?
MATT: The most you've been down was the opposite
side of this tunnel here. There was a group up
here where you had been working with previously,
but only recently decided to delve deeper once you
had made sure that those few were safe.
KHARY: Right, right. Well, I've done a pretty good
job of taking care of the other tentacle of this
cavern, I guess you'd say.
LAURA: Shaft.
KHARY: Yes, the shaft. That's a good way of
putting it. That boom you may have heard happened
to come from me, so we've got a little bit less to
have to deal with. This, I really don't know
what's going on.
LAURA: Oh, speaking of, I stand up and I
walk to the door where the little kid was pulled from.
LIAM: Wait, Nott, do you want to let her take a look
at it? In case it could blow up on you.
SAM: I've seen their traps. I know their methods!
LAURA: Are there any ropes across the door?
SAM: Let me look! Are there?
MATT: Make an investigation check.
SAM: Five. Plus five is ten.
MATT: Best you can tell, it doesn't appear to be
trapped. It does have a simple latch that is only
accessible from the outer side, but it is not
locked.
LAURA: I knock on the door. Housekeeping! Is
anybody locked in here?
MATT: A moment passes. There's no response, but
you hear the faint sniffing and whimpering of
somebody on the other side.
LAURA: I think it's the mom.
SAM: Let's open the door.
LAURA: Okay. (turning noise)
MATT: You lift the small latch and pull the door
open. First it hits you, a strong smell of decay.
You see the back of this room is filled with piles
of bodies or parts of bodies. It looks to be maybe
four people in total that have been placed here.
Then there's one living woman, in her mid-thirties
or so, who is wearing a dirtied apron. She's
covered in dirt. A spatter of blood, you don't
know if it's from her or not. Her hair is ratted.
She looks to be human. She's currently huddled
with her knees to her chest and there's tear
streaks down her face.
SAM: Is the, is the-- Oh, sorry, go on.
KHARY: Can I walk to her?
MATT: Yeah. As you open the door you watch as
Shakste begins to approach and take the space.
KHARY: I look her in the eye. I put my hand on her
chin, so that she looks me in the eye, and I tell
her, shh. What does that make her feel?
MATT: You watch as there's a brief moment of
confusion, and then an expression of
acknowledgement comes across her face. She reaches
up and takes your hand. She goes, "Thank you.
Thank you."
KHARY: We need to get her out of here.
LAURA: Yes. Definitely.
MARISHA: Holy shit, this guy's good.
TRAVIS: He is. Smooth operator.
SAM: Can I ask the woman, is this your child?
MATT: She turns around, and she goes, "Oh my god!"
She runs over to him and immediately picks him up
into her arms and begins to hold him.
LAURA: He's alive, don't worry.
MATT: (crying) "Thank you. Thank you." She's
rocking the child in her arms, quietly rubbing his
face and wiping a bit of blood off of his cheeks.
LAURA: Are there any other people that are alive
that you know of?
MATT: "There are a few. I haven't seen, but I've
heard voices across the way, and they took a
number deeper in, before they locked me in."
LAURA: Oh. Can we run over to the other door?
TALIESIN: I was saying, if I'm not near the other
door I'm going to start looking and unlatching it.
Nonchalantly.
MATT: You unlatch it. You watch as the mother,
who's currently running her fingers over the hair
of the boy, says, "Jules, it's okay. It's okay,
Jules." She pulls him in. The other door, as you
open it, a familiar sight. It looks like there's
three bodies in here. These bodies seem to be
placed in here for some sort of storage, for the
time being. There is one figure you can see, a man
in his older years. Half-elven in appearance, his
features are a little sharper, a little more
elven, but not fully. His hair is dark-brown,
black to gray, and salt and pepper on the sides.
He looks as disheveled as the woman you just
uncovered.
LAURA: But he's alive?
MATT: He's alive.
TALIESIN: This is a personal question. Is there
anyone alive in here right now?
MATT: "I'm the only one."
TALIESIN: Oh! Well, we'll take it. I'm swinging
the door open and coming in.
MATT: You get up, and you can see now, there's a
large claw gash across his midsection that might
be infected.
TALIESIN: If you wait a second, it's only getting
better.
MATT: "Who are you?"
TALIESIN: Oh, that is a question. We're here to
help. Come on out.
LAURA: We're the rescue party.
MARISHA: Is there anyone else that you were with
that's no longer with us in there?
MATT: "I mean--" He points back and says, "I don't
know most of these folks, I was just passing
through. We were bringing some of our armor-wares
up to Zadash when we were waylaid on the road.
MARISHA: You didn't get taken from Alfield?
MATT: "Oh, we were taken on the way to Alfield. We
were almost there. They hit us right as they were
reaching the city. We had no chance."
TALIESIN: You got hit on the way to the city, not
in the raid on the city?
MATT: "We were just arriving in Alfield when it
hit."
LAURA: Bad timing.
MATT: "You're telling me."
TALIESIN: Let's get you out here, for a second.
MATT: The woman has come up once again to--
KHARY: I have a place for these people to go. It's
up on the surface.
LAURA: They're safe there?
KHARY: They will be safe there.
LAURA: Do you have a cart to get them back to
Alfield?
KHARY: Well, a cart was just the thing I was
needing. What say we hang out?
LAURA: All of us together, like a big party?
KHARY: I've got nothing else to do.
LAURA: I like it.
TALIESIN: So many new friends lately.
TRAVIS: I am concerned that there are more further
on in these tunnels, but I think you're right, we
won't be of any use to these people if we don't
get them to safety first.
KHARY: Exactly.
MARISHA: How far was that tunnel to the surface?
We cleared out this side.
KHARY: Have we lost our way from- or at least the
way that I--
MATT: That tunnel's not operational.
KHARY: That tunnel's not operational. We've got
two ways out here, I see.
MATT: You have this way, which appears to go
deeper into the mine.
TRAVIS: Yeah, not that way, nope.
MATT: This way, which backtracks where you guys
come from.
TRAVIS: That's the one.
TALIESIN: Do we need to escort them or can we send
them up to the surface?
LIAM: You know what we could do? If we want to
check this cave for more people, is that we could
bring them up to the cart and I could do that one
spell that I have that would let me know down here
if anything is happening up there--
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: Yeah. If the little bell goes off in my head
then I know that either that something's coming out--
LAURA: The good bell, not the bad bell.
LIAM: The good kind, ja. We would know, more or less,
not 100 percent perfect, but pretty close. Then we
could come back down here quickly, and see if
there's anyone else who needs help.
MARISHA: How long is it going to take to hike back
the way we came?
MATT: Not too long, maybe 20 or so minutes back to
the surface.
MARISHA: Let's do it.
KHARY: That's not bad.
SAM: Are we going to leave some folks down here
to--
LAURA: No.
SAM: What if they repopulate all of these rooms
that we've already cleared?
TRAVIS: We should move together. There's no point
in leaving just a few--
TALIESIN: If you leave your alarm up here--
LIAM: Well, I was thinking about getting them to
safety outside. If anything leaves the mine, we'll
know it was them.
TALIESIN: That's fair then, yeah. That's a good
plan.
LAURA: Let's do it.
SAM: I don't like this plan at all. What if
someone-- What if one of the gnolls wanders into
this room and sees five of his dead brothers?
LAURA: Let's throw them down the hole!
TALIESIN: We start kicking them right up to the
edge, kicking them right in the hole.
MATT: One after another, you take the remainders
of the previous battle and roll them into the hole
in the center.
KHARY: Good call.
LAURA: Now they all look like they just left and
had some--
SAM: There's a whole other room with dead bodies
in it that we also caused, and also ball bearings.
TALIESIN: Oh, people die all the time.
LAURA: You know, sometimes accidents happen.
TRAVIS: We'll be coming right back down. We just
need to get them to safety.
LIAM: You know, people don't bare balls all the
time, but I think it's a reasonable risk at this
point in time.
TRAVIS: Plus, we could take a short rest up top
while we're getting them folks to safety.
SAM: All right.
TALIESIN: I like this plan.
SAM: Are there any other boxes or things to search
down here before we get out?
MATT: You can search if you want to.
LAURA: Yeah, let's search around.
MARISHA: Oh my God. I crack boxes like fucking
Zelda.
TRAVIS: Quietly, maybe?
MARISHA: Quiet, sorry.
LAURA: How many dead bodies do you think I could
carry?
MATT: You could drag two.
TALIESIN: I'll take a couple as well.
MATT: Because you're pretty strong, you could drag
two bodies.
LAURA: I'm going to try to drag some of the dead
out--
MATT: Everybody else can take one each, I think,
based on your strengths. You can take none.
KHARY: Yeah, my dragging days are over.
TALIESIN: We're going to look around, see if
there's anything of interest.
MATT: All right, so two of you can make
investigation checks on this one.
LIAM: I will help you look because I have an
eye--
LAURA: You need glasses though.
LIAM: No, I have very-- trust me, I mean I could
roll for shit but--
MARISHA: He's nearsighted.
LAURA: Oh nearsighted, I understand.
LIAM: That's okay.
MARISHA: But you have advantage.
LIAM: Do I have advantage?
MARISHA: Because he's assisting you.
MATT: If he's assisting you, yeah.
LIAM: That's a little better. Oh, yeah, it's good.
That's 15. You know, for level three. Fnfzehn.
TRAVIS: (chanting) Level three. Level three.
MATT: In a quick glance through, a lot of it
appears to be pickaxes, shovels. Most in here
seems to be tools and anything of worth has been
ravaged or taken. You find a few bits of rotted
meat of indeterminate origin, that you immediately
shrink away from.
LIAM: No, actually, I'm going to scoop up some of
those pieces of rotted meat and put them in my
pockets.
MATT: Okay. There you go.
LIAM: You can't smell it.
SAM: No, it smells good to me!
TRAVIS: Could be good bait later.
LIAM: That's why I'm taking it.
SAM: Any baubles or little doodads?
MATT: Nothing in this chamber, unfortunately. This
one has either been picked clean or didn't contain
anything of immediate worth in the process.
SAM: Oh, I don't care about worth.
MATT: I mean, there are plenty of bodies you could
rummage through if you wanted to, but.
LAURA: As we're walking them, Nott's going through
the pockets.
KHARY: Anything explosive?
MATT: You can make an investigation check, if
you'd like.
KHARY: All right. How would I do that?
MATT: Roll a d20 and add your investigation skill
bonus.
LIAM: It's there by-- good
roll.
KHARY: Plus one.
LIAM: Yeah, 15 for him.
MATT: 15 as well. All right, so. Not in this
chamber in particular, but as you guys are going
through the other tunnel, you glance over in one
of the overturned boxes and you find another
familiar object, one of which you had used
previously. Another singular stick with a long
explosive wick on the end. You have another piece
with you.
KHARY: Gingerly, I take it up.
SAM: Gently! You should be careful with that.
Those can make big booms.
KHARY: This ain't my first rodeo, baby. Thank
you.
SAM: (flustered noise)
MATT: As he says that and turns, you watch as the
small black hummingbird perches on his shoulder as
he continues to walk.
SAM: He's got a Frumpkin too!
LAURA: I'm dragging the bodies going, Duchess!
Duchess Stacy, please come over to me! Duchess
Stacy!
KHARY: Grand Duchess.
LAURA: Grand Duchess Stacy!
TRAVIS: We make our way back up to the top.
MATT: I'll have you all-- You can't make stealth
checks. You're dragging bodies. Who's carrying;
how many bodies are you bringing back?
TALIESIN, TRAVIS, LIAM, MARISHA, and MATT: One.
LAURA: Two.
MATT: That's four, five, six, seven.
SAM: I will go ahead of the party to run point.
MATT: Make a perception check for me.
SAM: 11.
MATT: Okay. You guys carefully make your way back
up through, trying not to drag the bodies over
heavy bumps or rocks, eventually making your way
out of the main entrance way. You notice a trap
that you had deftly avoided multiple times getting
people in and out, of a large tree trunk that had
been suspended in the roof to swing down when
triggered, had been triggered and is now hanging
there. Apparently somebody made an unfortunate
mistake making their way through. You all
eventually find your way out into the daylight
once more. The woman, who's now introduced herself
as Herma, and the older half-elf man, Petrov, all
step out into the light, blinking, bleary in the
sudden influx of light. As soon as you make it
into the open sky, you can see this breath of
relief wash over both of them, and the young boy
is now starting to come to consciousness again.
Goes, "Mom?" She goes, "Shh! It's okay; it's
okay." She looks up over towards Shakste, and has
more tears in her eyes, and goes, "Thank you."
SAM: I helped too!
LAURA: I stabilized him. I stabilized him real
good.
MATT: "Thank you all so much." You lead them over
through the hills here, that cluster around where
this mine once was, around the corner there
appears to be a shed that's been long abandoned
and locked up. As you approach, you have been here
previously.
KHARY: I take my reed stick and rap on the door.
MATT: "Is that you?"
KHARY: Shh.
MATT: The door opens and there you can see
emerging four survivors, also from Alfield that,
with bright eyes, welcome the arrival of this
strange traveler, as well as the three other
survivors you've brought in. As some of them begin
to reunite with people that are familiar to them,
people who live in Alfield and know each other,
they begin to hold each other and take a moment to
relish in this renewed moment of life. Then they
begin to pour over the bodies that have been
recovered, and they begin to identify them to each
other, and then sadness takes over. Then once
those waves have passed, individuals begin to go
up and thank you, and take your hand, and a few of
them are like, "Anything I can give you, please,
just let me know. Thank you so much." It's a lot,
to have at once, and for many of you an experience
that is different and new. Take it as you will,
however you wish to, but you also know time is of
the essence, and not too much time can be spent on
this.
LIAM: I would say that I did not partake in any of
that. As soon as we exited efficiently, I pulled
out the silver thread and I'm already doing my
thing while they do that.
KHARY: I would say, to the people inside: Stay
safe, stay here. I look at everyone else and say:
this isn't over.
MARISHA and KHARY: Let's go.
LIAM and MARISHA: Let's go.
TRAVIS: That's a badass motherfucker, I'm just
saying.
MARISHA: Yeah. I'm so about it. He's so cool.
TRAVIS: I know. Number one fan club.
LIAM: I guess we do not need a perception check.
MATT: All the bodies are placed in a small pile
and a large heavy piece of canvas material is
placed over them to hide them. The shed is closed
and locked, and they all seem to feel, at least
for the moment, comfort and safety in this space,
as you all begin to delve once more into the mines
beneath the hills. I would like you all to make a
stealth check, please, as you progress further in.
LIAM: Oh good. That's my specialty.
LAURA: Ooh, I could give someone a blessing, who's
shitty at this? Blessing!
LIAM: Thank you. Ugh.
TRAVIS: Ugh.
KHARY: What am I doing?
TRAVIS: 15.
SAM and LAURA: Roll a 20.
KHARY: Roll the 20.
MARISHA: 25.
LIAM: Eight.
LAURA: With advantage?!
LIAM: Ja.
LAURA: Fuck.
LIAM: You brought me from a four to a seven.
LAURA: Oh, Jesus.
KHARY: 17.
SAM: 13.
LAURA and TALIESIN: 18.
MATT: Universally, you guys are all confident in
your ability to delve without being seen, even
making up for those who maybe not have been a less
bumbling experience making their way in.
LIAM: I stubbed my toe!
MARISHA: Shh!
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Learn how to see in the bloody dark!
KHARY: You've got light, boy, you'll be fine.
MATT: You make your way back through the familiar
tunnel, and you can now see that the right tunnel,
the one that you had previously seen the pitfall
and decided to not head down into, is now a large
cluster of rock and rubble.
LAURA: Oh, that's where you came from?
KHARY: Mm.
MATT: You progress down through the ritual area,
carefully avoiding a scattering of metallic ball
bearings across the floor. You see an altar with
candles on it that have all burned down entirely,
except for a few tiny flickers. Is there any light
source you guys are bringing down here with you?
LIAM: (spell effect)
MATT: All right, the balls of light now float as
you progress, giving everyone who needs it sight.
You head down into the familiar chamber where this
last fray occurred, carefully avoiding the large
hole in the ground. This is the only other exit
from this chamber. You continue forward. Who's
taking point, and what is the marching order,
please?
LAURA: Keep checking for traps, okay?
SAM: All right, that's a good idea.
KHARY: Can I send the Grand Duchess?
MATT: You may.
TALIESIN: I'm not getting over that.
LAURA: Oh, the Grand Duchess and Frumpkin will be
best of friends.
MARISHA: Do they like each other?
LIAM: Frumpkin was obliterated.
KHARY: --stay away from my bird.
LIAM: You know, it's funny, because only about 30
minutes ago I also had a bird, but he was
obliterated.
MARISHA: Oh, that's right.
LIAM: It was very sad. I'll bring him back
tomorrow.
KHARY: Thanks for that.
(laughter)
LIAM: He and I, we are like that.
TRAVIS: It's going on, it's going.
SAM: He's very charming.
LAURA: I feel like we're seeing more of Caleb's
social awkwardness, seeing him from the outside,
it's so good.
TALIESIN: It's everything I could've wanted.
MATT: As you take a moment to continue focusing,
as you do, through the vision of your bird,
(hovering hum) coasts down through the tunnel
before you to keep an eye out.
Make a perception check for your bird, please.
Roll a d20, and add two to it.
KHARY: 17.
MATT: 17, nice. The bird's perception, not his.
MATT: That's great. The tunnel descends at a
moderate grade for about 80 to 100 feet before it
levels off once more. Ahead, you see a set of
rough stairs that rise for about five or six feet,
leading to the remainder of the tunnel, and then
curving to the left suddenly out of sight,
slightly along this elevation. Right there, you
have your bird (hovering hum), and right as the
stairs ascend and turn immediately, there is the
outer corner of a gnoll stands there
waiting, keeping watch. (gnoll murmurs) Do you
want to send your bird in further to check out the
rest of the room or pull it back?
KHARY: She's quick.
MATT: She's pretty quick.
KHARY: I say move on.
MATT: All right. (hovering hum) Okay.
LAURA: It's really smart that he made a
hummingbird. That's really fast.
TALIESIN: It's really clever.
LAURA: It's a pretty smart move, don't you think?
LIAM: It's not a cat.
SAM: One that can see in the dark.
LAURA: Yeah. I mean, it's really smart.
MATT: As the Duchess moves further and up to the
platform, the Duchess can see another portion of
the floor that is collapsed inward into another
falling pit that rests against the wall on the
opposite side of where these stairs ascend. The
tunnel curves to the left immediately, where this
hole is on the top, and where it continues down
there appears to be a large archway where there
was once a set of double doors. The doors have
been broken off the hinges and are not visible at
current sight, but to each side of the frame, you
can see two skeletal gnolls with bits of flesh and
skin hanging off their bones and rib cage and
snout, sitting there like silent undead sentinels
looking around.
KHARY: Thank you so much. Come back to me, dear.
MATT: (hovering hum) Charging back to the tunnel,
back to your shoulder.
KHARY: We have a friend about a hundred feet away.
He's by himself, but yeah, there's just the one.
Beyond him, there is more to deal with. I think we
quietly take care of this gentleman first, and
then we move on.
LAURA: Did you see any survivors?
KHARY: Not yet, but there are two sentinels and
they are guarding something. I'm hoping that's
someone.
TRAVIS: Perhaps we can create a little bit of a
lure to bring back that single fellow closer to us
and we dispatch him quietly.
KHARY: It's not a bad idea.
MARISHA: I reached into the ball bearings that I
have left since I have about half. I take one and
go-- (ball bearing bouncing)
MATT: Down along to the grade? (ball bearing
bouncing) Eventually, you can no longer hear any
noise the ball bearing makes as it continues out
of your earshot.
LIAM: I'm also going with the Dancing Lights.
They're not leading the way. The closest one is
actually ten feet behind us like a choo-choo train
back behind the group so that it's dim light 20 to
30 feet ahead of us.
MATT: Okay. A minute passes. Two minutes.
You don't see any indication that anything noticed
or heard.
MARISHA: Ah, shit! He's stupid!
LAURA: Maybe he's sleeping.
TRAVIS: Who's real good at dispatching them quiet?
MARISHA: Nott, do you want to?
SAM: Don't make me do this again.
TRAVIS: I tell you what, if you summon some
courage, I'll come with you.
SAM: All right.
KHARY: Could I give her some guidance?
MATT: You may if you are going to try to stealth
it.
SAM: Sure, what does that mean?
LIAM: Just give you a little bit of boost, you
know.
KHARY: I got a really good feeling about what
you're about to do.
SAM: Uh-huh.
KHARY: Like a really good feeling. Like the kind
of feeling that will put a big smile on your face,
you know, take you back home, make you feel like
there's a big--
SAM: I'm not interested in a relationship right
now.
KHARY: Well, this isn't working at all.
LAURA: Offer her shiny things.
KHARY: Ah, you know what? You know the way this is
turning out, I feel like you can get all kinds of
gold and silver.
SAM: Oh, yes! Pretty things. Sure, yes!
KHARY: Exactly.
SAM: Yes, absolutely. Give me something.
KHARY: Oh well, it's waiting for you just down the
hall. All you got to do is take care of a creature
quietly and quickly.
SAM: I feel inspired.
MATT: All right, so make your stealth check and
add a d4 to whatever you roll.
LAURA: Then I give you a Blessing of the Trickster
for your stealth.
TRAVIS: What does that do?
LAURA: You get advantage, Fjord.
TRAVIS: That's good.
TRAVIS: Oh god.
MARISHA: Did you roll the same thing?
TRAVIS: No, but not much better. Eight.
LIAM: Oh, low rolls at both?
TRAVIS: No.
TALIESIN: Plus a d4.
SAM: 18.
MATT: Plus the d4?
SAM: Oh no, d4. Sorry, not a four, but d4.
MATT: Not good.
SAM: 17.
MATT: 17. Okay. It's just Nott? You're going as
well?
SAM: He's going too.
MATT: The two of you begin to make your way down
the hall carefully, ever so carefully, about 60 or
70 feet towards the bottom where you can both see
the grade begin to turn up. Fjord, you discover
why you stopped hearing the ball bearing, as
suddenly you take a step and your foot slides up
from under you.
MARISHA: Oh, shit.
MATT: You try and catch yourself and you manage to
do so, but you dislodge a rock that begins making
more noise than the ball bearing did. At which
point you hear (growls and howl)
SAM: Does it see us?
MATT: It's down below the grade and out of sight.
It's just the rock that began to make its way down.
TRAVIS: I screwed the pooch. I think y'all need to
fucking join us.
MARISHA: Come back.
LAURA: We can't hear you, you're fucking 60 feet
ahead of us.
TRAVIS: It was a really loud stage whisper.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: (echoing) -sper, -sper, -sper.
SAM: I will tell them, all right? I'll point back
to them and I will bring out my little piece of
fabric. Wait. No, it's a piece of wire and whisper
into it and send a Message to Caleb that: We've
been made. Start making your way down here.
(laughter)
LIAM: Oh, verdammt. It didn't work, we're in
trouble, they are coming. I think they're coming.
LAURA: Should we go down the tunnel?
LIAM: Come back to us please.
LAURA: Or should we go to them?
LIAM: I already sent the message.
MATT: Okay. So!
SAM: Are we sticking?
TRAVIS: What did he say?
SAM: He said "Come back to us." I feel like we're
already here, we should just-- oh gods. What do we
do?
TRAVIS: I'm with you.
SAM: What does that mean?
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Let's take them on. I feel like I've never
felt. You and me, let's take them.
SAM: Why are you big men making these weird
speeches to me?!
(laughter)
SAM: All right, sure, I feel inspired again. I'll
take a swig.
MATT: You do take a heavy swig off of your flask,
thank you. Both wait carefully holding your action
until underneath you can see what emerges below
the lowest part of the curving tunnel roof, a
gnoll snout begins to protrude past. You can see
the arrow already nocked in the longbow as it
turns down and turns and glances up the tunnel to
meet your guys' vision.
TRAVIS: As soon as he fires, I will as well.
SAM: I will fire, my hand-- how far?
MATT: Right now he's about 30 feet below you.
SAM: Yeah. I can make that shot. (ping!)
(laughter)
MATT: Go ahead and roll an attack.
TALIESIN: Oh dear.
SAM: Ten.
TRAVIS: Oh, me?
MATT: Yep.
TRAVIS: 15.
MATT: Just hits. Misses.
MARISHA: 15 is the magic number.
TRAVIS: Can I say my bonus I move my Hex over to
him?
MATT: At this point, your Hex has faded.
TRAVIS: Fair enough.
MATT: Since you guys hadn't left before.
TRAVIS: I tried it. 20 up, 20 down that side.
MATT: Yeah, had you guys taken a short rest when
you were up there or not?
MARISHA: I was hoping so.
TRAVIS: Oh, we did say we were going to.
LAURA: Then it would add another hour up there,
wouldn't it?
MATT: It would. It's up to you guys. It may or may
not affect things.
LAURA: I don't really get anything back on short
rest.
TRAVIS: I do.
MARISHA: I would get my ki point back.
LIAM: I would get a spell back, yeah.
TRAVIS: I think we should. We rescued the
survivors, we gave them a little moment to
grieve.
LAURA: I mean there might be more survivors.
TRAVIS: I know but--
LAURA: We rescued some survivors.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LIAM: We say ja?
TRAVIS: Yes.
LIAM: Ja.
LAURA: We took a rest.
MATT: All right, so before we jump into this,
we'll say you took the short rest, which is an
hour, so you guys can use your hit dice. You
hadn't taken any damage, Shakste, so you don't
have to worry about it.
KHARY: No but I was just thinking about-- because
I did use the Thunderwave.
MATT: That does not come back on a short rest.
KHARY: That does not come back, okay.
MATT: Yeah, it's a long rest for you.
(background music)
MARISHA: Jesus, shitty rolls.
SAM: Is there a way to track the hit dice in
(singing) D&D Beyond?
MATT: Yes, under hit points.
TRAVIS: Yeah. You hit short rest and it will pop
up the number of hit dice you have.
MATT: It's under the short rest.
LAURA: Yeah, under short rest, not hit--
SAM: Yeah, okay.
MATT: All righty, so, with that the case, you've
taken a short rest. Now back to the current
moment. You both fired. You missed, you succeeded
to hit, go ahead and roll your damage on that.
TRAVIS: Thank you. 1d10 plus four. That is a ten
plus four, 14.
MATT: 14 points of damage, all righty. As it looks
up and gets hit in the snout and it looks back up
and you can see the black, charred exterior of its
head, one of its eyes is now ruined and he
(growls). Its tongue is dangling out. You can see
blood and slobber across the front of its chest as
it looks up and gets ready to release its bow
strike at you since you made the hit. That's going
to be a 23 to hit.
TRAVIS: Oh that definitely hits.
MATT: Natural 18. That's an eight on the die, that
is ten points of piercing damage to you.
TRAVIS: Damn.
MARISHA, TRAVIS and LIAM: (singing) Damn, damn,
damn.
TALIESIN: I was watching this, I was going to head
down this direction anyway.
MATT: Right, at this point you guys have now
begun to head down, yeah.
MATT: You guys head down, it's going to take the
better part of the turn to get to where they are,
unfortunately, because you guys were waiting at
the very top. As soon as you see the lights go off
suddenly and the impact of the spell from him and
hear the snarling in the distance, you guys begin
to make a full beeline and it takes you the full
dash and movement to even get beside your allies.
You guys get another round as well as the gnoll,
so go ahead and make your attacks.
SAM: All right.
LAURA: You can do it.
SAM: I can do it.
TRAVIS: Here we go.
SAM: Sure, 18 to hit.
MATT: 18 hits.
TRAVIS: 21.
MATT: Hits. Roll damage. No sneak attack,
unfortunately.
SAM: Five.
MATT: All right. Damage on you.
TRAVIS: On my bonus action, I'll cast Hex as well.
That's five points of necrotic.
KHARY: Is my Guidance still helping at all?
MATT: The Guidance only helps for the next six
seconds, so it helped him with the stealth check
originally. You can do it whenever you want to as
an action.
TRAVIS: Eight points of damage, five necrotic for
13 total.
MATT: As the gnoll pulling back its arrows, about
to give out a large bellowing cry, makes a large
inhale as it pulls back a second arrow and then
both of you slam into it and watch as it falls to
the ground, dropping its weapons that clatter
against the stonework. It's not longer moving as
you guys catch up.
LAURA: I go running past them right as they do it
and cut its ears off.
TALIESIN: I'm opening up the jar. There you are.
LAURA: Thank you.
TRAVIS: Pull it back into the tunnel!
LAURA: Oh okay. I do that.
MATT: Okay. You drag it back in, while you're down
you make perception checks, please.
TALIESIN: Both of us?
SAM: Her forearms are amazing.
MATT: If you're helping yeah, both of you.
MARISHA: They're bats, just baseball bats with
arms.
LAURA: 15.
TALIESIN: 13.
MATT: As you rush down and grab the body, you
glance up and whereas previously he described
there was the singular gnoll and the two other
skeletal ones in the opposite side, it appears
that since it was given some indication of nearby
sounds and it made that brief call before it began
to approach, there are a few more gnolls that have
appeared at the top of the platform above where
the stairs crest.
LAURA: Do they see us?
MATT: No, they do not at the moment, but only
because they're not looking at your direction. As
soon as you see it you immediately drag the body
out of the way. I would like you both make a
stealth check to try to quietly drag the body
back.
LAURA: 16.
TALIESIN: 20.
MATT: You both don't drag it, you both grab an arm
and a leg and very painfully lift it up without
making any sound and pull it out of range up the
grade out of view as you watch one of the gnolls
turns its face in your direction barely passing
seeing you guys yank it out of sight.
LAURA: (whispering) There's a lot more guys out
there.
MARISHA: (whispering) How many?
MATT: You saw three visually appear.
LAURA: I saw three visually.
TRAVIS: Fucking Beau and her ball bearings.
SAM: Why did you drop a ball bearing down there?
MATT: To give you perspective on this, because it
looks like we're going on that direction.
(cheering)
LAURA: Oh god this means that--
MARISHA: It's like a motion simulator ride. Whoa!
TALIESIN: Fun fact, Matt's house is actually made
of Dwarven Forge.
MARISHA: It's true.
TALIESIN: Every wall, the kitchen.
LAURA: That would be amazing.
TALIESIN: It's just Dwarven Forge all the way
through.
MARISHA: No, I don't know.
LIAM: You haven't lived until you've slept on
Dwarven Forge.
MATT: You now see.
MARISHA: Or our bed's not on braziers, no.
LAURA and LIAM: Critical Role, Critical Role.
LIAM: Oh god, we've got to stop.
TALIESIN: I know, this has to end.
MATT: This leads into the grade that head up in an
angle here where you guys originally shot the
gnoll and dragged him out of the way.
LIAM: We are down that way?
MATT: You guys are over--
LIAM: Over this way?
MATT: You're up in the tunnel here. It angles down
there and this is where--
LAURA: Oh no. They're coming. (whispering) They
were about to look in this direction, but they
weren't quite looking in that direction when we
dragged the body out.
MARISHA: (whispering) Okay.
KHARY: They're not exactly--
MATT: They haven't noticed anything yet. You guys
are up in this way, and this is the layout here.
LAURA: Fjord, what do we do?
SAM: Don't do anything yet. We have to figure out
what we're doing.
KHARY: Well, I'm meaning simply as a strategy.
Should we use something to distract them? Since
they're already not looking our way, so that we
could get a few shots at their back.
LAURA: Can you send the Grand Duchess in?
KHARY: I absolutely will. Can we start there?
MATT: You may. Yeah.
KHARY: Let's do that. Find a safe perch, my dear.
MATT: The Grand Duchess makes her way down to the
tunnel up. Let's see if they see her.
SAM: Is she really royalty?
KHARY: That's what she told me.
LAURA: Did she used to be a person and you shrunk
her down?
KHARY: No, she is who she is, baby. Just like
you.
MATT: She passes them over. There is one perch up
on the side of the wall right above where this
large pit is on the opposite end. She perches
right over the side as two of the gnolls are still
(growls). One of them begins to look over the
table and underneath for any possible source of
the noise earlier. One of them glances over his
shoulder as the Duchess enters, begins to pull an
arrow out of the quiver.
KHARY: Come back here, baby.
MATT: (bird noise). (growl).
KHARY: Thaumaturgy.
SAM: Oh no! It's on!
MARISHA: Do it.
KHARY: Thaumaturgy. I'm sorry.
TALIESIN: I'm going to use my bonus action just
before this happens and I'm going to activate the
second sword.
MATT: Okay, you reduce your max hit points.
TRAVIS: I roll to maintain concentration because
he hit me after I cast Hex.
MATT: Yes, please. Constitution saving throw.
TRAVIS: Oh no. Yeah, that's a six.
MATT: Six, no, that's a failure. You lose Hex,
sorry buddy.
LAURA: Oh no.
TRAVIS: Got to be honest with him.
KHARY: Thaumaturgy. Can I brighten the room? How
dark is it in here?
MATT: It's pitch black aside from the globes of
light that he has. There's nothing to make
brighter in there.
LIAM: It's bright behind us, not in front of us so
much.
KHARY: Let's see, then, if it's--
LAURA: You can shake the ground, though.
KHARY: Yes, let's shake the ground so however well
he thinks he can aim takes him off kilter.
MATT: For that instance, make a standard wisdom
check for me. Roll a d20 and add your wisdom
modifier which I think is--
LIAM: Oh, that's a 19 natural roll.
MATT: As you feel the Duchess return to you and
just past the vision as the Duchess passes over
you hear the sound of the fingers gliding across
the bowstring. You hear the creak of the wood as
it's pulled back. You know exactly what that sound
means as you see through the Duchess's eyes. You
focus on the ground below and cause it to quake
somewhat. Rolled a natural five plus four, with
that shaking it causes the-- it's very localized
in the area, the gnoll (yip) as it does, it
releases the arrow and it whips past and shatters
across the rock. The Duchess returns to your shoulder.
KHARY: Well, now I'm pissed.
SAM: Do they know we're here now?
LAURA: He saw the bird come back this way so
maybe--
LIAM and SAM: It's just a bird.
LIAM: He might have even thought it was a bat.
SAM: Should we all turn into birds and confuse
him?
LAURA: Do you know how to do that?
SAM and LAURA: I could try.
KHARY: Let's try later. Why don't we do things
we've done before?
(laughter)
MATT: What are you guys doing?
MARISHA: Are we doing this?
LAURA: Let's fucking go.
SAM: We're going to go in or-- this doesn't seem
very smart! I don't know.
LAURA: I rub her head and give her a little
blessing. Don't you worry. You keep hiding
whenever you need it.
SAM: What is this blessing?
LAURA: It gives you advantage on stealth checks.
SAM: Oh, okay. Thank you.
MATT: If this is the case, what are you guys
doing?
MARISHA: Do we get a surprise round?
SAM: No, they know we're here.
KHARY: No, they don't know we're here.
MARISHA: Or an earthquake. We're in a shaft!
Things shake a lot.
MATT: They're aware of something in the vicinity.
The first gnoll announced there was something
fishy. They don't know what it is or where you
are, but they're on guard.
LIAM: Surprised is like a condition. Like poison,
but they know something is--
LAURA: Not surprised.
KHARY: If I used Sacred Flame on one-- because if
it's dark in there and one of them burst into
flames wouldn't they all look in that direction?
MATT: It's possible.
KHARY: Let's try that.
LAURA: I could Sacred Flame him in the exact same
time.
TRAVIS: While we're waiting, can I cast Armor of
Agathys on myself?
MATT: You may.
KHARY: I like this.
TRAVIS: (hissing sound) I pull the moisture
out of the air and it forms frost all over me.
MARISHA: It's got a little moss on it from the
cave?
MATT: As you have this conversation you turn back
and you watch as Fjord, the rather handsome
looking half-orc, finishes muttering something
under his breath and the shadows coalesce into
this dark, cold, icy armor that shatter into bits
of shards around the exterior of his leather
armor. You watch as this mist rises off of it.
TRAVIS: Everybody chill.
LIAM: No, you ruined it! It was so good!
MARISHA: It wasn't cool when Arnold said it.
TRAVIS: Wait, everybody. Be cool.
(laughter)
SAM: Stay frosty? Stay frosty.
LAURA: I pull my sickle out so I'm prepared for
actual up-front combat.
TALIESIN: I've got both of those sticks going. I'm
ready for this.
MATT: This guy's moved forward to here. This guy's
moved forward to there. They're in the process of
searching the area, looking down the tunnel.
LAURA: Which one do you want to hit? The orange
one, the gray one, or the black one?
KHARY: Did we see those other ones over there?
MATT: You saw them, the skeletal ones there.
KHARY: That's what I thought. I thought my baby
saw them. I say, I think we need to get those
fellows to turn back and look at those fellows.
LAURA: We can't see those guys to Sacred Flame
them.
KHARY: I can't see them anymore?
MATT: You guys are up in this tower right now, so
you'd have to send Duchess back in to see.
KHARY: Isn't that always the way?
LAURA: We could get the one in the back, and then
the other two might look at him.
KHARY: I think that's a great idea, darling.
LAURA: Let's do it.
LIAM: Can I say, I change my mind every five
minutes about whether this group was a good idea
or a terrible idea, and I'm listening to these
chuckleheads talk to each other, and I'm waiting
to cast Blur on myself when it looks like
everybody's going to do something, but I'm waiting
until the last minute.
LAURA: I knew it was Blur!
LIAM: Good for you. You get a doughnut.
KHARY: Sacred Flame, on the gentleman in blue.
LAURA: At the same time I see his little reed
flick, I'm going to swirl my sickle around and
cast Toll the Dead.
MATT: All right, on this guy there?
LAURA and KHARY: Yeah.
MATT: As you guys slowly bring your way to the
base-- which in order to get you in the space
where you can see them, that would put both of you
rushing right down to the base in that area. If I
can get a marching order to where the rest of you
are, by the way.
LIAM: Hey, I'll be in the back.
MARISHA: I'll take the front.
TALIESIN: Let's take a line of the three of us, at
least.
TRAVIS: Yep. I'm good with that.
MATT: You guys rush forward to take the line as
they--
TRAVIS and MARISHA: Linemen.
SAM: I'll be back with Caleb.
MARISHA: Yeah. I knew what that meant.
TRAVIS: You going to be a guard or a tackle?
MARISHA: Oh. Tackle. I'm probably a guard.
MATT: As you all rush in below, you both release
Sacred Flame and Toll the Dead on the guy in the
blue. That's a wisdom saving throw for Sacred
Flame, I believe it is?
LAURA: It's a dex save for Sacred Flame and a
wisdom save for Toll the Dead.
MATT: That's right. A wisdom save for you, that's
a 13?
LAURA: 13.
MATT: Yeah, it succeeds. Sorry. For you, it's 13
as well for your DC. That is a five.
LAURA: You couldn't have them roll that for me?
MATT: Sorry.
(laughter)
SAM: It's Crystal Pepsi.
LAURA: I really love Crystal Pepsi.
TALIESIN: Original run.
MATT: Roll damage for the Sacred Flame, which
should be-- What's the damage on the spell?
KHARY: The damage on the Sacred Flame is-- The
spell's damage increases by 1d8 when you--
MATT: Yeah, so it's 1d8. Go ahead and roll 1d8
radiant damage.
KHARY: 1d8 is this thing?
KHARY: One.
LAURA: Ugh. That's okay. It was for visual
anyway.
KHARY: It was. That's true. I would have wanted
the--
MATT: You watch the light burst in.
LIAM: I've pulled the ripcord on Blur if they're
doing that.
MATT: You cast Blur. That all happens in a quick
instant as they rushed forward and you guys caught
up. Now we're rolling initiative.
MARISHA: Fuck yeah.
TRAVIS: Let's get this one right.
MARISHA: Son of a fuck!
LIAM: There is a vision of me before me and also
behind me, flickering in and out of view.
MATT: 25 to 20. 25 to 20 anybody?
KHARY: 20.
TALIESIN: A real initiative roll. That's
something.
MATT: All right. 20 to 15?
SAM: Nobody got 20 to 15?
TRAVIS: Can I call you Shaq?
MATT: 15 to ten?
KHARY: No.
TALIESIN: 13.
LAURA: Ten.
SAM: 11.
TRAVIS: Molly, Nott, and Jester?
MATT: Jester, you got ten?
LAURA: I got ten.
SAM: Ten to 15. Ooh, boy.
TALIESIN: Wow, really?
MATT: Ten to five?
LIAM: Siebzehn.
MARISHA: Eight.
TRAVIS: Caleb's before Beau?
MARISHA: What's zip-- seven?
LIAM: Siebzehn is seven.
MARISHA: No, I am.
MATT: Beau, what did you get?
MARISHA: I rolled a nine.
MARISHA: Five plus four. Nein.
TRAVIS: I rolled a three.
LAURA: Oh, Fjord.
MATT: As the gnolls are all clumping together,
preparing for your onslaught right at the edge of
the hole with the furniture on the opposite side
there, the two skeletal gnolls who are getting
ready to rush into the fray. Top of the round is
Shakste.
KHARY: Let's see. Frostbite.
MATT: Okay. Against which one?
KHARY: Let's see. Oh, wait, first of all, they
burst into flames, this gentleman burst into
flames, and when that happened, what did these
gentlemen-- how did these gentlemen react?
MATT: The two other gnolls glance over at the
side, and then look towards the tunnel where you
guys were. It didn't seem like it was much of a
distraction for them, unfortunately, in the moment.
LAURA: Right as we all ran in at the same time.
MATT: Unfortunately, it wasn't a sourceless
cluster as you guys all made your way to the base.
KHARY: All right then, I say the one closest to
us, I will hit with Frostbite.
MATT: All right. Would that be that one there?
KHARY: That would be that fellow.
MATT: All right, go for it. Frostbite he has to
roll against your DC, so I roll it for you. That
is a natural one, so go ahead and roll damage on
that.
KHARY: All right. That is the diamond?
MATT: It should be, is that a d8 for that one as
well?
KHARY: Yeah. Wait, by 1d6.
MATT: Okay, so it would be d6. I'm pretty sure
it's a d6 for the cantrip.
KHARY: 1d6? Is that this one?
LIAM: That is that one, yeah. The cube is a six.
Hey, a three.
MATT: Three points of cold damage to him, and he
has disadvantage on his next attack roll.
Suddenly, a similar cold to what you saw coalesced
around the armor of Fjord, this time it's
attacking and freezing inward, and you watch as
the gnoll (gnoll pain sounds). It's shaking
briefly, you watch as its muscles are beginning to
slow down and become sluggish. Do you want to
move, or do you want to stay where you're put?
KHARY: Let's see. Actually, I feel pretty good
right behind these fellows.
MATT: All right, so you stay there. That ends your
turn. The gnolls will now go. The three of them
are going to begin to back away, and they're all
going to take strikes with their bow.
SAM: Ranged attackers.
MATT: They all pull out their arrows, and each are
going to make a strike. The one you frostbit is
going to attack you, it has disadvantage.
SAM: Guys, let's all cluster up at the bottom of
the stairs.
MARISHA: Sounds great. Yeah.
MATT: It was a three and a two, with disadvantage,
so no, it misses you entirely. It actually gets
partially caught in the 'fro, and makes its way to
the back.
KHARY: Oh man, I've got beads in that thing, baby.
Got to be careful.
MATT: Missed them all, thankfully. The next attack
in the front is going to be against Beau, and then
one's going to be against Molly, since you guys
are the most visually impressive of the front row
color-wise. You blend into the surroundings a
little bit comparatively, so against Molly-- Man,
they cannot roll, that is a six.
TALIESIN: I slice it, catch it in the spin.
MATT: (grinding sound) Just grinding toothpicks.
The one versus you, Beau, that is a 14.
MARISHA: Miss.
MATT: Dodge out of the way.
SAM: Devil sticks?
KHARY: I think that's what they-- yeah. I seem to
remember them being--
MATT: All right, Molly, you're up.
TALIESIN: Goddamn it. I'm going to hop up and move
to the left. I'm not even going to use the real
stairs, I'm going to get to the side up on that
barrel over there.
MATT: There?
TALIESIN: Yeah, and use Vicious Mockery on the one
closest to us.
MATT: That's a 15 on the saving throw.
TALIESIN: So he's fine.
MATT: So he's fine, unfortunately.
TALIESIN: (devilish voice) Ack! Fuck! Can't finish
it!
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Talk tough.
MATT: You can keep using your movement if you want
or you can stay put.
TALIESIN: I'm going to get to the-- No, I'm going
to stay back because I'm a little-- yeah, I'm
going to let other people come up first.
MATT: Okay. Ending your turn Molly, it's Nott,
you're up.
SAM: Oh. Excuse me, pardon me, pardon me, excuse
me. I'm going to cut through the front and go as
far up the stairs as I can go.
MATT: (counting) 30.
LIAM: Careful.
SAM: Take one shot, at the one who looks frosty.
MATT: That's that guy there?
SAM: Yeah. (crossbow sound)
MATT: Make the attack.
SAM: Oh, boy, 12.
MATT: 12, it does hit, and then splinters off the
armor. Off the ice in particular.
SAM: (groans) I will, bonus action, go right back to
where I was.
MATT: (goblin yell) You rush back down. That
finishes your turn Nott, Jester, you're up.
SAM: Pardon me, excuse me, excuse me, pardon me.
LAURA: I'm going to move forward, up to the other
side. Yeah, can I see them?
MATT: You can see them.
LAURA: You know what? Fuck it. Should I do this?
MARISHA and TALIESIN: Always.
LAURA: Fuck it. I'm going to climb up the stairs.
SAM: (imitating Laura) Climb up the stairs. Hello,
gentleman.
LAURA: Then I'm going to Invoke Duplicity!
SAM: Shaka-pow.
MATT: Where's it going to appear?
LAURA: It's going to appear next to the-- yeah,
right there.
MATT: Right there?
LAURA: She's going to be like--
MATT: The one gnoll goes (growls). All right.
Seems immediately confused by the appearance of
two Jesters in proximity.
MATT: That's your action. That's your go?
LAURA: Yeah, and then can I use my movement to
crouch behind this table?
MATT: Nah, that's as far as you can get with your
movement, unfortunately.
LAURA: Okie dokie.
MATT: Ending Jester's turn. These two
guys come into play. This one rushes up and swings
at the illusory Jester; passes through, no effect.
This one's going to-- five, six. It does not have
a ranged attack, so instead it's going to rush
forward and engage with you right there.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: It's now Beau's go.
MARISHA: Okay. Is it dark in here?
MATT: It is dark. You currently, there's a little
bit of light that you have--
LIAM: The closest globule is ten feet behind us.
MATT: Yeah, you're seeing action happen up ahead,
and you're like (groan). You don't have a good
bead. You can still do things, but you're considered
blind, so you have disadvantage on any
attacks that you make.
MARISHA: Can I run up to the guy that just came up
to Jester and wait until that light comes up from Caleb?
MATT: Yeah, you can hold your action if you want.
MARISHA: Hold the attack?
MATT: Okay. All right, you're holding your action.
You rush up and you can see the outer glimmers of
bits of bone and its body moving as it rushes in
to harry Jester.
MARISHA: When I hold my action, can I also hold my
bonus action with that?
MATT: No. Only your action, unfortunately.
MARISHA: Can I use my bonus action to spend a ki
point and do patient defense?
MATT: You can.
MARISHA: Let's do that.
MATT: You go into a defensive potion there, all
right.
MARISHA: I can still attack when it comes, right?
MATT: Correct.
MARISHA: Okay. Thank you.
MATT: That ends your turn. Caleb, you're up.
LIAM: My choo-choo train of globules of light go
(whirring) and float over all our heads--
MATT: Lighting up the vicinity here.
LIAM: Yeah. I'm already falling into a routine
with my other human friend here, because I know
that she's a badass, but not without light. The
globules pass her and curve to the left a little
bit, and one floats above her head. The last one.
MATT: Okay. Perfect.
MARISHA: As soon as it comes around me, I'm going
to use the staff with the light as it comes and
crack it down over top of his head.
MATT: Go for it.
MARISHA: Natural 20! I rolled an eight on my die!
(sings) Max all the way around. That's 16 plus
four! I'm not going to touch you right now. I'm
sick.
There we go. I'll hit the elbow. 20!
MATT: All right, so as the light emerges above,
you leap into the air, swing the staff, bring it
straight down, as it does--
MARISHA: Can I have the light following behind me
as I run up?
MATT: Yeah. It splinters the skeleton into pieces
all around its entire body, crushes and collapses
to the ground. Scattered across.
MARISHA: Fuck yeah.
KHARY: Anastasia, did you just see that?
(laughter)
MATT: Caleb, rest of your turn?
LIAM: That was it. No, I'm staying where the hell
I am.
MATT: Stay where you are, all right. That finishes
your go. The light is in the room. The end of
Caleb's turn, that is now Fjord.
LIAM: Ah! I'll move up 15 feet. Sorry, I
apologize, Entschuldigung.
MATT: 15. There you go.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'll come up the stairs so I can get
a line of sight on any of those motherfucks.
MATT: There, 30?
TRAVIS: Actually, I'll be behind Beau.
MATT: Okay. Behind Beau right there.
MARISHA: I hug the wall, let Fjord do his thing.
MATT: I'll put you right there. We'll just lean
you.
TRAVIS: Coming through!
MATT: There. Oh, excuse me!
TRAVIS: Eldritch Blast.
MATT: Which one are you shooting at?
TRAVIS: The closest one.
MATT: That's the one that's been frosted. Go for
it.
TRAVIS: Only 14.
MATT: 14, for against him, does not hit.
TRAVIS: Yep.
MATT: Unfortunately. It manages to strike some
sort of shield on the side that shatters. It's
bolted to its forearm. It pulls it up just in time
to deflect the Eldritch Blast. It cracks the
shield and does damage to its exterior, but no
wound to the actual gnoll.
TRAVIS: Fair enough. That's my turn.
MATT: That finishes Fjord. Top of the round, you
hear this (hyena barking and growling).
MARISHA and LAURA: Oh shit.
MATT: (heavy footfalls)
LAURA: Oh no, it's the general!
MATT: Watch as an armored gnoll--
ALL: Here comes the general!
MATT: In the back of the chamber.
LIAM: Gnoll Washington!
(laughter)
LAURA: We are outgunned.
ALL: What!
LAURA an KHARY: Outmanned!
MATT: Outnumbered, and crossbow. As the pack lord
approaches, cackling at the sight of you, you see
a look of recognition on its eyes as it pulls back
its longbow and is going to go ahead and fire
immediately at-- Well, first I'm going to see-- It
does see through the illusion, so it does not fire
for the fake Jester; however, it does fire for
you, the actual Jester.
TALIESIN: I'm going to use Blood Maledict.
MATT: You currently do not have visual.
TALIESIN: I do not have visual?
MATT: Not in your current position, nope.
TALIESIN: Damn it. Fine.
MATT: So that's an attack on you with a longbow.
That is going to be a 15.
LAURA: Doesn't hit me!
MATT: Doesn't hit you.
LAURA: 17! I put my shield up.
MATT: It splinters across the shield, no impact.
That's going to end its go. We're now at the top
of the round. It's your turn, Shakste.
SAM and MARISHA: (whisper) Shakste.
KHARY: Aid.
MARISHA: A rakshasa.
KHARY: I don't know, this big guy's got me
worried. This may take a little time. Nobody seems
to be able to hit shit right now.
TALIESIN: Welcome to the game!
KHARY: Yeah, so I say myself and my two brave
warriors who are so far frontal, Mrs. and Mrs.?
MARISHA: Yeah.
KHARY: Let's all take Aid. I will, and so will
they.
MATT: All righty.
LAURA: What is Aid?
MATT: Aid, is that 2nd-level?
KHARY: Aid is 2nd-level, yeah.
MATT: I believe you both get five additional hit
points to your max, and five hit points.
LAURA: Me?
MATT: Yeah, so the three of you, your max hit
points go up by five.
LIAM: Oh, nice.
MATT: You gain five hit points on top of that.
TRAVIS: Damn.
MARISHA: I turn to Shakste and I say: Are you a
motivational speaker or something?
KHARY: I pack them in on the Menagerie Coast,
baby.
TRAVIS: He knew the location!
MARISHA: He totally did.
TRAVIS: He fucking studied up!
LAURA: There, it's already at 30, so 31?? Sweet.
MATT: All right, as you feel this sudden burst of
physical hardiness surge within, this warm glow in
your belly that helps stir you up to the future of
physical impact and damage. That's your action; do
you want to move at all on your turn?
KHARY: Sure. You know what? I think I'll move up a
few feet, and I'll also take Anastasia and put her
a little further forward, but at a safe distance
from these people.
MATT: All right. Like this direction, or this
direction?
KHARY: Actually, yeah, closer to me. Yeah, there
we go.
MATT: We'll put Anastasia perching on the wall
there, looking that way.
KHARY: I like it.
MATT: Okay. That ends your turn. It's now the
gnolls' go. This one is going to rush forward
towards you. This skeletal one is going to rush
forward towards Jester. This one's going to stay
back and continue to fire at Beau. It's going to
take a step back there. This one's going to stay
where it is and take a shot at Beau as well. We
have one gnoll that's attacking you with a spear.
That's a 12.
LAURA: Yeah!
MATT: You deflect it with your sickle, which
you've unhooked from earlier. Just grab it and
(shing) off to the side, parrying it. The skeletal
witherling rushes up and is going to attempt to
strike at you with a bite actually. It's going to
lash out with its horrible bony maw. That is
going to be a ten.
LAURA: Ha.
MATT: You pull the shield up a little higher.
Teeth shatter and break and fly off around the
exterior of the shield.
LAURA: I look over at Beau and I'm like: I'm doing
you!
MARISHA: Good job!
MATT: As you're doing that, "Good job!", you look
back just as two arrows go flying towards you from
the two other gnolls. They both have disadvantage,
I believe, right? Because you took your defensive stance.
MARISHA: Yep.
MATT: All right, which is good because that
would've been a 20, and an 11.
MARISHA: Miss, miss.
MATT: Well, that's the first attack. I rolled a 20
and 11. You dodge out of the way. The second one
is going to be a 21 and a 22.
MATT: That hits.
MARISHA: See if I can catch another arrow.
MATT: You take six points of piercing damage.
MARISHA: I'm going to do my Deflect Missile.
MATT: Reaction, right.
MARISHA: I'm going to try and do like a frisbee
catch in the air.
MATT: Okay. Go ahead and roll your die.
MARISHA: It's a d10, right, d10? What was it, six
damage?
MATT: Six piercing damage.
MARISHA: Five plus my seven, so yes.
MATT: All right, so the first arrow you dodge out
of the way, and the second one you see it coming
out of the way. There's a brief moment where time
seems to (whirring) and you catch it right in the
middle of your hand. It pulls you back a little
bit and looking down you can see the arrow is
there, right in the middle of your grip.
MARISHA: (stuttering) We're so cool right now!
Yeah!
KHARY: You're welcome.
(laughter)
MATT: That's going to end the gnolls' go. Molly,
you're up.
TALIESIN: All right, I'm going to try and run up
the stairs toward the undead guy.
MATT: There you go.
TALIESIN: I'm going to take a swing at him. That's
14 to hit?
MATT: 14 hits him.
TALIESIN: Okay.
MATT: Only a 12 armor class.
TALIESIN: Wow. Let's see what we do. That's
(counting) 11 points of damage?
MATT: 11 points of damage is just what you needed.
With your first strike, infused with the rite, you
streak down with your first blow and your scimitar
carves through the upper part of its shoulder
blade into its ribcage. As you do, you watch as
whatever necrotic energy's holding its body
together suddenly dissipates and all the bones
clatter to the ground in a pile.
TALIESIN: I'm going to keep running and to get to
the other side of that other gnoll.
MATT: This one here?
TALIESIN: Yeah. Actually, if there's any way, can
I get all the way around him?
MATT: (counting) Yes, there is.
TALIESIN: Yeah! I don't know if this is helpful,
but I'm going to take my second swing. That's 18
to hit.
MATT: That hits. Roll damage.
MATT: You don't get the bonus to your wisdom, but
you still have the rite on that one.
TALIESIN: That's ten points of damage.
MATT: Ten points of damage on the other.
LIAM: Regular gnoll.
MATT: Using the momentum of that first strike, you
continue running and with a backwards swipe carve
through the back of the other gnoll. It arches its
back with pain as you carve this giant wound
across the back of its shoulder to about where the
base of its spine is, and you see blood beginning
to flow from its wound where the bits of the armor
are separated, and the fur poking out from within
the haphazard hide. I believe that ends your
turn?
TALIESIN: That ends my turn.
MATT: All righty. End of Molly's turn. Nott,
you're up.
SAM: (whimpers) That's my turn.
(laughter)
SAM: No, I will run up behind Shakste and I'll
peek around and fire at the frosty one right in
front of Jester.
MATT: Okay. Go for it.
LAURA: (whispers) Frosty.
SAM: Yeah, 24.
MATT: 24 hits, and you do get sneak attack because
it is currently--
SAM: Yeah!
LAURA: Engaged!
TALIESIN: So engaged.
LIAM: (Picard voice) Engage.
SAM: 12.
MATT: 12 points of damage. It's already taken 11
from the rest of you, so that finishes it off.
(cheering)
MATT: You wait for the moment where Jester moves
out of the way. As it's pulling back and beginning
to try and strike again with its spear, and take
the shot and watch as it hits right in the sternum
and pulls back its spear and with its final thrust
of momentum, falls to the ground into a pile and
is now bleeding out of its mouth as it's
unconscious and dying on the ground.
LAURA: I'm a really good fighter you guys!
SAM: Bonus action, I will cast Mage Hand and pull
back the cloak around Shakste's cloak, to see
what's in his back pocket.
MATT: Can you cast it as a bonus action?
SAM: You can use it as a bonus action.
MATT: Meaning you cast it as an action. You can't
do that yet.
SAM: Then I will do this with my hand.
MATT: Make a sleight of hand check. I need you to
go ahead and make a perception check.
KHARY: Ah, yes.
SAM: 22.
MATT: Roll a d20. Add your perception skill
modifier.
TRAVIS: Come on, 20.
LIAM and KHARY: No.
MATT: Yeah, you don't notice it.
What does he see hanging off the back of
your belt?
SAM: Anything off the belt, in the back pocket?
KHARY: Oh, gosh, what do I have back there?
TRAVIS: What don't you have back there?
KHARY: Yeah, what don't I have back there?
SAM: It's assless chaps!
(laughter)
KHARY: He sees a pouch that's relatively full, I
would say.
MATT: Okay. Just hanging right there on the back
of the belt.
SAM: Okay. Good to know. That's my action; that's
my bonus action.
MATT: That's your action. That finishes your turn,
Nott. Jester, you're up.
LAURA: Okay. That went really well, so I'm going
to run-- Oh, god, there's three of them right there.
TRAVIS: They're going to spread pretty soon.
LAURA: I know, but--
TRAVIS: Right after you.
LAURA: What am I going to do? I'm going to run
into-- Oh, no, that's really dumb. I'm going to
use my duplicate and she's going to Toll the
Dead.
MATT: To which one?
LAURA: To the orange one.
TRAVIS and LAURA: Come on, Toll the Dead!
TRAVIS: One time!
LAURA: It's a wisdom saving throw!
LIAM: Toll house.
TRAVIS and LAURA: Roll low!
MATT: It did! It rolled a seven.
(cheering)
LAURA: This is a really loud gong. He takes four
damage.
MATT: Four points of damage. All right. That was
to which one of these two?
LAURA: The orange one.
MATT: The orange one, okay. Both of them have been
damaged now, a little bit. You watch as it shakes
its head for a second, and it's beginning to
string another arrow. That finishes your turn?
LAURA: Oh, had he not been damaged yet?
MATT: He had not been damaged before.
LAURA: I shouldn't have rolled a 12. I should have
rolled an eight.
MATT: Then roll that eight.
LAURA: Six damage.
MATT: Weirdly, more damage.
TRAVIS: Yeah!
MATT: Well, there you go. Now he's damaged. Good
catch on that. That end your turn or do you want
to move? Well you moved your-- oh, that was a
bonus action.
LAURA: As a bonus action I did that, so I'm going
hop up on the table that I'm next to.
MATT: All righty.
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: That's your turn. That brings us to-- all,
no, both of the skeletons have been destroyed.
That'll bring us to Beau's turn.
MARISHA: All right. I'm going to vault past
everybody. Well, never mind they all moved. I'm
going to run up right into fray.
MATT: Five, ten, 15, which one?
MARISHA: Right in between the orange guy and the
gray guy.
MATT: There you go.
MARISHA: Hit, and then I'll probably do my Flurry
of Blows.
MATT: Go for it.
MARISHA: I'm going to run up, I'm going to go for
a rib shot with the bo. It's not a good roll. It's
not great. 12.
MATT: 12 does not hit. As you rush forward to
swing with your first strike, the one that'd been
firing at you from the previous round notices your
approach, throws the longbow over the arm and
brings up the shield in the same motion and
deflects the quick thrust of your staff.
MARISHA: Uh-huh. Okay.
MATT: If you're doing Flurry of Blows you have two
more attacks on it.
MARISHA: Yeah, wonder if that's a good idea. Maybe
I should-- I'm going to Patient Defense this
again. Do I have a bonus attack?
MATT: No, you do that instead of your bonus
attack. You hit once, it gets deflected, and you
spend your bonus action to do Patient Defense.
MARISHA: That didn't go as well as I thought.
MATT: That's all right.
TALIESIN: That's okay. You've engaged them, which
means they're less likely to use their bows.
MARISHA: That's true.
MATT: That ends your turn. Caleb, you're up.
LIAM: I don't really have a clear view of what's
going on so I would, on this wall here, I would
inch five or ten feet up the cave to see what's
going on.
MATT: You get just about there.
LIAM: I see a gigantic gnoll and-- okay.
MATT: The one that you saw earlier in Alfield and
that you--
LIAM: The big one.
I'm going to do what I did to him before and
I'm going to bring my hand once around, twice
around, three times around and cast Scorching Ray
on that one only. First is a 17.
MARISHA: Come on, Caleb!
MATT: 17 hits.
LAURA and MARISHA: (cheering)
LIAM: Second one hits as well, and the third one
also hits.
(cheering)
TALIESIN: Take that.
SAM: Those are the only hits he's had all
campaign.
MARISHA: Guys, I think Shakste makes us better
people.
LAURA: Shakste, stay forever.
MARISHA: He makes us better.
LIAM: 18. That is a total of 20 of fire damage.
MATT: 20 points of fire damage.
(cheering)
MATT: That's awesome. As he turns the corner, the
two gnolls back out of the way and you see it
standing there. It has its large two-handed glaive
in its hand, its shield slung over one shoulder,
the bow over the other, and seeing this for the
first time, you see this larger, muscular, more
dark-furred gnoll that looks like the leader of
this cluster, this pack. The armor it has is
chunks of chainmail and hide armor that are
patched together where a number of long, thin
spines, like heavy, bone-like spikes have been
woven into it like a decoration to make it look
extremely intimidating. Right as it grins and gets
its glaive ready, it gets blasted with three beams
of burning arcane energy as they hit and impact
you watch as the flames curl up and it has to pat
it out with its giant hand. (snarling) It took the
hit like a champ, and it seems like it's hurt, but
it's still doing pretty well.
LIAM: I wipe my arm down and say: Oh boy.
MATT: Is that your turn?
LIAM: Yeah, that's done.
MATT: That was a good round. That finishes Caleb's
turn. Fjord, you're up.
TRAVIS: I pick myself up out of my prone position
there on the--
MATT: Well technically you're not prone, sorry.
TRAVIS: I know, I was commenting on the way I was
laying. Can I come up to the top of the stairs,
right there? Keeping some of my movement left, and
can I cast Eldritch Blast, at the gnoll that's
standing in front of the big bad baby?
MATT: Right there? You may. Go ahead and roll the
attack.
TRAVIS: 17.
MATT: That hits, roll damage.
TRAVIS: Nice. That plus six, that's eight points.
MATT: Eight points of damage. That one, as it's
notching another arrow into its bow it takes the
impact off of its shoulder. It grazed it.
TRAVIS: With my bonus action, can I cast
Hexblade's Curse on the big motherfucker and say:
Come on, you sack of shit, come get me.
MATT: You may. We'll mark him with the Hexblade
Curse with this big old angry black circle to mark
him as the target there.
TRAVIS: Can I use the rest of my movement to go
back down the stairs?
MATT: You may.
LAURA: Come get me, you coward!
MATT: That ends Fjord's turn. Back of the combat
round, it's now the pack lord's turn. The pack
lord returns to this way--
TALIESIN: Attack of opportunity-- oh, no.
MATT: No, it steps through the one and is going to
turn this way, and rear back for a giant kick.
It's going to make a shove attack against you.
TRAVIS: That's not a pit, is it?
MATT: Yeah, that's a big ol' pit.
TRAVIS: I thought they were stairs!
MARISHA: But we couldn't see that!
SAM: It's another poo hole.
LIAM: I had no idea that was there!
TALIESIN: Blood Maledict to all fuck.
MATT: He already has disadvantage because of
Patient Defense.
LIAM: We can imagine that, Matt. We needed the
fear of god.
TALIESIN: Oh, look at that.
MARISHA: (groaning) Well. I'm suddenly having
regrets.
MATT: One and 17. What's your armor class?
MARISHA: 17.
MATT: Oh, shit! All right, so, hold on.
SAM: Does that hit or not?
MATT: It hits. We'll see with the shove.
TRAVIS: I think it's five feet unless it's
stronger. Could be ten.
MATT: I'm seeing if there's a contested check, we
haven't done the shove in a while here.
LIAM: Yeah, that back wall perfectly blocks that
whole thing.
MATT: I'm so sorry, guys. That's my bad.
MARISHA: Totally probably wouldn't have even have
run up.
MATT: That's my bad.
LAURA: It's fine. You're just going to die.
MARISHA: It'll be great.
SAM: You've got a staff. You can jam it into a
thing on the way down.
MARISHA: Yeah! In more level I get Feather Fall.
That would've been nice.
LIAM: Your eldritch knight is going to be great.
MARISHA: Thank you!
MATT: Oh, actually it doesn't have a roll of
attack against you, technically, so that wouldn't
have mattered. It's a contested athletics versus
your--
MARISHA: Versus my strength, right?
MATT: Versus your athletics or acrobatics, your
choice.
MARISHA: I'll take the acrobatics.
LIAM: Come on, ninja!
TALIESIN: Oh man!
MATT: I'll check real fast to see if your Patient
Defense affects that at all, not sure if it does.
TRAVIS: Give her your energy, guys. What the fuck
are you doing?
TALIESIN: You don't want my energy,
it's been bad.
TRAVIS and LIAM: (chanting, rhythmic breathing)
MARISHA: Are you looking for patient defense
shit?
MATT: Yeah, it doesn't affect this roll,
unfortunately. It's just a straight roll.
MARISHA: Oh, it doesn't?
MATT: Nope. It's a contested roll.
TRAVIS: You got this.
LIAM: (chanting) Monk monk monk.
LAURA: (glumly) I know what he rolled.
MATT: It's a natural 20.
(yelling)
MATT: You can come look at The Snitch right now.
MARISHA: You did this! If I die it's on your
head!
TALIESIN: You can make this go away at any time.
MATT: Make your acrobatics check. It's not an
automatic success.
SAM: Just roll a natural 20.
MARISHA: Oh my god. Pick the dice that I use.
LIAM: A natural 20?
MATT: It's a 23 total. It only has a plus three
strength bonus, so.
LIAM: This is clearly a case of the husband
favoring the wife.
MARISHA: I don't want to die. (yelling) Ugh!
Goddamn it! That happened before!
MATT: It was almost an 18 and it went to a four.
So! He shoves you, not actually with the shield.
He pulls back and Sparta kicks you. Right as you
turn to try and defend, whack! It hits you right
in the sternum and you get pushed back five feet,
which puts you right on the edge. I need you to go
ahead and make a dexterity check to try and catch
yourself.
MARISHA: Make a what?
MATT: Dexterity saving throw.
MARISHA: Saving throw? (Panicked breathing) I'm
good at this.
LAURA: Don't say those things, Marisha.
TALIESIN: Yeah, we're not good at anything. Let's
stop pretending that we're good at anything.
TRAVIS: Yeah, because you did have patient dodge
going, right?
MARISHA: I had Patient Defense, but--
MATT: It's against attack rolls, but I feel like I
just saw something. For dodge action, "and you
make dexterity saving throws with advantage."
MARISHA: I do?
MATT: You do, so roll with advantage.
MATT: It's a high DC, you have to beat I think
with this and the impact that hit you, you have to
beat an 18, so go for it. You have advantage!
LAURA: You can do it.
LIAM: Advantage and have a good bonus.
MARISHA: I have to roll at least a 12.
LIAM: You've already fallen off one cliff, you're
not going to do it again.
MARISHA: That's an 11.
LAURA: Oh god!
MARISHA: Please be better.
LIAM: It's the exact same thing.
TRAVIS: Two 11s! Two! 11s!
MATT: You watch as Beau slips, can't get a grip,
and then falls and tumbles into the pit below.
MARISHA: (fading scream)
TRAVIS: Oh. Shit.
LIAM: Blind justice.
SAM: The pit is six feet deep.
KHARY: There's a grate on that-- can you grab it?
MARISHA: Busting fingernails.
MATT: That's what she was trying to grab as you
fell back. That was the dexterity saving throw,
because it was a grate. You suffer 11 points of
bludgeoning damage, which-- it's not bad. You fell
40 feet and landed on your back onto hard rocks
and stones.
TALIESIN: Could have been worse, although you are
our tank.
MARISHA: (wheezing) It knocks the air out of me,
so going to be sick, I guess. Hit real good.
(normally) 11 points?
KHARY: Did the aid I give help at all with that?
MATT: Oh yeah!
MARISHA: Oh, right. Hang on.
MATT: You have five more hit points than you had
before the battle started.
TALIESIN: Yeah, it halved the fall damage. That's
so mean.
MATT: That ends his go. Shakste, you're up. You
watched Beau fall into this pit behind--
LIAM: What a turn around.
KHARY: God.
MARISHA: (wheezing) I'm good. I'm okay.
SAM: There's an old man down in the bottom of the
pit.
KHARY: Good to know. Let's see, I'm running out of
spells. Let's see. I can't do this anymore because
LIAM: Well, you can do this a million times.
KHARY: I can do this a million times?
MATT: You have four 1st-level spells per day you
can cast and two second. You've used one
2nd-level, so have one of those, and you've cast
Thunderwave before, so you still have three
1st-level spells.
KHARY: I still have three 1st-level spells.
MATT: Correct. You can cast with any of those.
KHARY: Let's see. Would it be best-- could I
Command the big guy?
MATT: You could try.
MARISHA and MATT: You can certainly try.
MATT: What do you want to Command him to do?
TRAVIS: Or one of the smaller ones if you want a
higher rate of success, maybe.
LIAM: Maybe get a little bit closer.
KHARY: Right, maybe, yeah get a little bit closer
in order to--
LIAM: Not all the way.
KHARY: No, I can see him just fine.
MATT: Yeah, you can see him, the big guy.
LIAM: 60 feet of range on that.
KHARY: Yeah, how close am I to him?
MATT: He's within range. He's about 30 feet from
you.
KHARY: Let's see, if I asked him to drop or asked
him to fall-- could I ask him to fall on his fellows?
MATT: You can't ask him to fall on somebody else's
weapon. You can ask him to drop prone if you want to.
LIAM: Yeah, what are they, like "lie down" or
"drop your weapons" or it's a single word, so
"drop." Drop everything in his hands, or you could
say "lay."
SAM: Turn, jump.
LAURA: Drop his weapon, no don't listen to me, do
what you want.
LIAM: You could say "dance" and he would just
start dancing.
KHARY: The target doesn't move and takes no
action. How about-- oh, you know what? Drop,
TRAVIS: Keep going.
LAURA: Yeah, that's pretty good.
KHARY: I say: Halt. I say we tell the big guy to
halt. Not to mention, "halt" is good, because he's
actually standing in front of his dudes as well,
that'd give them-- that would make it harder for
them to move.
MATT: So what do you say as he finishes kicking
Beau into the pit and turns (snarling).
KHARY: Halt. Is what I say. Halt!
MATT: It looks back towards you, and I see the
spell DC is 13 for you. That is a two, it does not
succeed. You watch as it puts its weapons down for
a second and looks right at you, eyes wide,
confused as it turns its head (inquisitive
sound).
SAM: Does that last a round?
LAURA: He keeps his weapons in his hand, though?
KHARY: Yeah.
MATT: Yeah, it takes no actions for its next
turn.
KHARY: Yeah, he doesn't do anything.
MATT: Do you want to move or stay where you are?
KHARY: Let's see, I actually feel pretty good
about where I am.
MATT: It's the gnoll's turn.
KHARY: I can still see everything, right?
MATT: Yep. These guys are going to back up a
little bit, and they're both going to take shots,
one at Molly and one at Jester. At Molly, that is
a 16. What's your armor class?
TALIESIN: It hits.
MATT: It hits? You take four points of piercing
damage. Attacking against you, Jester. A natural
20, I'm sorry.
LAURA: Could they tell it was my illusion right
there?
MATT: They noticed earlier, unfortunately.
LAURA: Damn it.
MATT: That's okay, it's not too bad. That's eight
points of piercing damage.
LAURA: Oh. Oh! I'm going to take it.
MATT: Okay. That ends their turn, Molly, you're up
first.
TALIESIN: I'm going to rush around to the left of
the big guy. His left, I'm sorry. Right over here.
Right in there. I'm going to take two shots and
see what happens.
MATT: Go for it.
TALIESIN: Do I have advantage or anything because
he's not moving, or--?
MATT: No, he just doesn't make action on his
turn.
LAURA: Can he not react either?
MATT: He can react, but he doesn't-- He can't take
any actions or move on this turn.
TALIESIN: All right. That hits, that's a 23.
MATT: That hits, roll damage.
TALIESIN: I'll roll damage on that. He doesn't get
the bonus, does he? None of that special power
against him?
MATT: No, you don't.
TALIESIN: Ooh, that's nice! 13 points of damage.
MATT: 13 points of damage from that first strike.
You carve through the body. Its eyes still locked
on-- (chuckles) Its eyes are still locked on
Shakste, not looking away, going (grunts).
TALIESIN: Shot number two is 21 to hit.
MATT: That hits. Roll damage again for that one.
TALIESIN: That's seven points of damage. I'm going
to try and see what happens if I disengage.
MATT: All right. So as you back away.
TALIESIN: I'm going to back away towards me.
MATT: That way. It sees you walk away and makes a
strike towards you.
TALIESIN: Does he try and make his strike?
MATT: He does.
TALIESIN: I was just curious. I was going to hit
him if he's going to try and hit me. I'm going to
hit him right back with Blood Maledict.
MATT: Okay. That'll give him disadvantage.
TALIESIN: I'm going to use the full Blood Maledict
so I'm going to take a little damage. Yep. Oh, I
take my three points of damage. I start bleeding
again from the neck.
MATT: As his eyes go black and you watch him begin
to bleed from the corners of its eyes.
MATT: The second roll for that attack was a three
plus five. So yeah, it misses you; it's an eight.
TALIESIN: I'm going to back up a little further to
get--
MATT: Like over here?
MATT: Ending Molly's turn, Nott, you're up.
TALIESIN: Right up here, if that's okay.
SAM: No one's in sneaky range. I'm going to caress
the little pouch, little bit. Looking up to Caleb
to see if he's looking at me at all.
LIAM: I'm not, by the way.
MATT: Yes.
SAM: Trying to make good choices. I will leave the
pouch and draw the hand crossbow and run up a few
stairs and then I will crouch down on my knee and
hold my attack until someone is within sneak
attack range.
MATT: Okay. So you're holding that there. Ending
your turn Nott, Jester, you're up.
LAURA: Okay. I'm going to run forward and attack
him because he's not moving at all.
MATT: All right.
TALIESIN: He doesn't have a reaction, so you can
back away now.
TRAVIS: Dude, Command is clutch.
MATT: So both of you guys make your attack. Or
whatever you're doing, Jester.
LAURA: Yeah.
SAM: 23.
LAURA: 16.
MATT: 16 also hits. Both of you guys roll damage.
TRAVIS: 16 hits?
SAM: 15.
MATT: 15 points of damage.
LAURA: Four points of damage.
MATT: How do you guys want to do this?
(cheering)
MATT: Currently held.
LAURA and SAM: (yelling)
SAM: Jester! We've solved the mystery!
(laughter)
SAM: It was him! He did it!
LAURA: It was you!
LAURA and SAM: (yelling)
MATT: As you collide with the gnoll pack lord as
you release a bolt that strikes it in the throat.
LIAM: We've got four jokes this campaign.
MATT: The bolt sinks through one of the eyes as
the sickle hits the other and it (choking) and it
tries to make one final thrust before the halt
magic prevents it from doing so and it (falls).
MATT: And falls to the ground.
TRAVIS: Dude, thank you for that. Because of that,
I regain hit points equal to my warlock level plus
my charisma modifier.
MARISHA: Oh because your Hex thing?
TRAVIS: Really appreciate that.
MARISHA: That's awesome.
LAURA: Yeah, we do. Wait, what kind of weapon was
that guy holding?
MATT: That was a glaive. It was a large two-handed
polearm with an axe head at the end of it.
LAURA: That's really big.
MATT: It's pretty big.
TRAVIS: Seven points I heal. That's fucking
sweet.
KHARY: Which means to bluff.
TRAVIS: To blathe!
MATT: That ends Jester's turn. That brings us to
Beau.
MARISHA: (groaning)
MATT: You're like (groaning). You get up from
prone, so it's half your movement.
MARISHA: Fuck, that's half of my damn movement?
MARISHA: All right. Can I do some cool monk shit
and do like a (wall jumping) to get out?
MATT: It is a small enough space, I'll let you
make an athletics check or acrobatics check
instead of athletics.
MARISHA: Is it small enough to where I can do the
wedge myself--
MATT: It is not small enough for that,
unfortunately. It's about a ten foot gap, but you
can leap from side to side or you can climb with
athletics. It's your choice.
MARISHA: Is leap from side to side also
athletics?
MATT: That's acrobatics to do that.
MARISHA: Yeah, that one. Let's do that one.
MATT: It's monkish. Go for it.
MARISHA: Monkish? Okay. 19.
MATT: You leap, leap, leap, leap. You get about 20
feet up your movement before you have to grab onto
the wall to stop yourself.
MARISHA: 18. Sorry.
MATT: That's fine. Still enough. And if you wanted
to use an action to dash, you could make it the
rest of the way up.
MARISHA: Yes.
MATT: Pole vaulting off, parkouring up the wall
until eventually you leap and get back up to the top.
TRAVIS: Hey!
MARISHA: Did you guys know there's a hole?
TALIESIN: I did not know that. Did not know that.
TRAVIS: We did not.
MARISHA: Now I climbed out of the hole to two
gnolls. Hole to gnoll?
MATT: Yep.
MARISHA: Cool.
MATT: Ending Beau's turn, Caleb, you're up.
LIAM: Caleb, who was just going into his bag to
pull out a ro-- oh, she does not need the rope,
okay. So instead I pull out the diamond and I
start spinning it around and it turns to thunder
and I sent that flying into the tannish colored--
Chromatic Orb to that one, yeah.
MATT: Right there? All right, roll for the
attack.
MARISHA and TRAVIS: Thunder.
LIAM: That hits. That is a 20 to hit.
MATT: 20 hits. Roll damage.
LIAM: Yeah. This is thunder damage is a total
of... oh, just eight, you know. Just eight points
of thunder damage.
MATT: Eight points of damage. It impacts and it
looks like really hurt now and it's like (heavy
breathing). It's getting ready to run. It looks
like it's in the process of deciding to flee.
LIAM: Okay. This looks good. I'm going to back
down the stairs and stand by Shakste, I think.
Diplomatic immunity!
(laughter)
MATT: Finishing Caleb's turn, Fjord, you're up.
TRAVIS: Can I use my full movement to come back up
the stairs as far as I can? 30 feet.
MATT: There you go.
TRAVIS: Eldritch Blast into the darker gnoll.
Yes.
MATT: Go for it. Roll to attack.
TRAVIS: Plus six. That is 21.
MATT: That hits. Roll damage.
TRAVIS: All right. That is (counting) 15 points of
Eldritch Blast damage.
MATT: That one, seeing the other one about to
flee, tries to turn to meet gait right before your
Eldritch Blast slams it in the back and core
through its abdomen, leaving this burning hole in
the center before it falls to the ground and
collapses dead. Its friend going (whimpering).
It's now looking scared and ready to bolt. That
ends Fjord's turn.
TRAVIS: Yes.
MATT: Pack lord's gone. Shakste, you're up. There
is this one who's very wounded and about to flee.
KHARY: Yes. I will run a few steps up and hit it
with Sacred Flame.
MATT: All righty. That is a natural four. It does
not succeed so roll damage on that one. d8 radiant
damage.
LAURA: You got up!
MARISHA: I did! It took everything.
LIAM: All good! Sechs!Sechs-y.
KHARY: Six.
MATT: Six points of damage. That's-- aw man,
almost! As it bursts into flame, its body is now
singed by the radiant energy that's burned around
its torso. It's breathing heavy and limping and
it's going to go ahead and-- is that the end of
your turn?
KHARY: Is that the end of my turn? That's a
great question.
MATT: That's your movement, your action so.
KHARY: I moved and I action so bonus action? Is
there some?
MATT: If you have anything that could use a bonus
action.
KHARY: I know that there's something here that has
a bonus action.
MATT: You have a spell that does it, but I don't
think it's going to be helpful right now.
LIAM: Spiritual Weapon.
KHARY and LIAM: Nah.
MATT: Yeah, hold off on that. Okay, so that ends
your turn. It's going to turn and bolt. It was
right up against you, so you do get an attack of
opportunity on it.
MARISHA: Oh, yes! Fuck you!
LIAM: It's got one hit point.
MARISHA and LIAM: Yes!
MATT: Roll damage.
MARISHA: Okay, okay, okay. One! Plus four, so five
damage.
(cheering)
MATT: As it spins to run away, you're like "No you
don't!" (whack) and slam it on the head. It falls.
(grunt) "Again!" You just slowly bash it to the
ground until its head's a mashed-in pulp.
(cheering)
LAURA: Wait! Not the pulp, we need the ears!
MARISHA: Oh shit. Oh no. Is there still an ear
left?
MATT: Yeah, you can pull the ears out. There a
little wet, but they're functional.
LAURA: That's three gnoll sets and I'm going to
mark one as super special because it's big.
TALIESIN: We're also going to go through the
pockets of the big one, obviously.
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: All right. we'll come back and begin that
right after we take a quick break. So we're going
to take a quick break. I'm going to sit back down
here. We'll continue the story here in just a
moment, but before we do that, real fast, we have
a couple things. One, we have a gift here from
Wyrmwood for our resident monk over there.
MARISHA: What, really?
LIAM: With a letter.
SAM: I didn't get a letter!
MATT: Apparently, she's got fans at Wyrmwood.
LIAM: Patrick Rothfuss again?
MARISHA: Oh wait, this is to all-- wait. Oh. It
was probably addressed to me because of Geek &
Sundry.
MATT: That's probably it.
MARISHA: But this is to all of us. "To the cast of
Critical Role, while--" Hang on, let me make
sure.
SAM: It's mostly cursing.
TRAVIS: What is that word down there?
MATT: Open it! While she's reading it. Wyrmwood is
giving away two Adventurer's Arsenals, which we've
shown previously on weeks here, that are zebra
wood. If you guys haven't seen it, Wyrmwood's last
Kickstarter. It's a packaged dice box and then on
the inside, holds your dice, holds your pencil or
pen, eraser or mini. All magnetized in there.
We're giving away two of these at the break to
anybody who wants to enter.
MARISHA: It's mine.
LIAM: It's yours.
MARISHA: Yeah. It is a gift for me.
MATT: There you go.
MARISHA: It's so great.
LAURA: Thanks, Wyrmwood. Thanks for Marisha.
MATT: Oh, they give us plenty. Anyway, two of you
will win this. When you're prompted in the chat
and only in Twitch chat, to use the keyword
'hush'. H-U-ace-H-S. H-U-S-H. There we go, I can
spell. Brain not working, too much math. Hush in
the chat, when you're prompted. Only enter once or
you'll be disqualified, but we'll come back with
two winners after the break. We'll see you guys
here in a few minutes.
TRAVIS: I've gotta pee!
TALIESIN: Nice.
[break]
MATT: Hello and welcome back everybody. So, before
we jump in here, we have our two winners in the
chat of the Wyrmwood giveaway. They are
Grugswald.
LIAM: Yeah.
MATT: Grugswald and onegirlx10. Congratulations to
you guys, Grugswold and onegirlx10, Danoba will
contact you and get your information and get those
sent to you in the chat. Congratulations and we'll
have more of these in future episodes. They're
awesome. They're pretty rad.
MARISHA: They came fully stocked. Look at that.
Look at how jealous Laura is. Look at that. It
fuels me. I love it.
MATT: I would be careful.
TALIESIN: I'm here more than you these days. You
better hide that thing.
TRAVIS: Other people's dice.
LIAM: All those dice that you could check before
the game. You could roll them.
MATT: Bringing it back in, guys.
LIAM: We're all real good friends.
MATT: I know.
(laughter)
LAURA: No. Congratulations, Marisha.
TALIESIN: So happy for you.
MATT: You guys, finishing this fray, you gather
the gnoll ears as well as--
LAURA: Rummage through their bodies.
MATT: Make an investigation check. The two of you
who are investigating their bodies.
TALIESIN: I'll give advantage.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: Advantage.
LAURA: I did. I know. I'm doing that.
TALIESIN: Yeah. That's not good.
LAURA: (yelling) Did you see that?
TALIESIN: That's cocked. Well.
LAURA: That is not cocked. I rolled a one and a
two.
MATT: Aw.
LAURA: So yeah. A three for investigation.
MATT: Okay. Well, there's the glaive. It's hard to
miss that. It's pretty well-made; it's sturdy, it
has some of the spines that are part of the armor
as well affixed to it along the top.
LAURA: I'm going to take it. How heavy is it?
MATT: It's like-- Let me look at how much a glaive
weighs according to the book. The glaive is about
six pounds. It's not too bad. Well, this one's
probably closer to ten. It's a pretty top-heavy.
It's designed for a gnoll. Or at least designed
for something big that wants to hurt something
badly. You do manage through a collection of
shinies in the pack leader's pockets and manage to
find roughly 13 gold pieces, three silver and no
copper. It only wants things that are shiny.
Copper aren't as shiny to them.
LAURA: Who wants this gold? Anybody?
TALIESIN: Never say no to gold.
KHARY: I could use it.
LAURA: Yeah?
KHARY: Sure.
LAURA: Here is three gold for you.
KHARY: You are the best thing.
LIAM: How much was in there?
LAURA: There's seven gold left. Here's three gold
for you.
SAM: Where does Shakste?
MATT: Mm-hmm. Shakste.
SAM: Where does Shakste put the gold?
MATT: Where does Shakste put the gold?
KHARY: I put it in my--
MATT: You can do it discreetly if you want to.
KHARY: Well, I suppose a blind man does put his
gold in his back pocket pretty discreetly,
actually. He doesn't have to look at it.
MATT: Make a stealth check. Or a sleight of hand
check.
LAURA: Three gold for you. I've got one gold
left.
MARISHA: Yeah, I'll take it.
KHARY: It's a nine.
MATT: Plus what's your sleight of hand skill?
KHARY: Sleight of hand is plus five.
MATT: So 14. Make a perception check.
SAM: Seven.
MATT: Yeah, so you have no idea. He receives the
gold and the hand disappears beneath the cloak
which is now covering most of his torso and you
have no idea where it got put.
LAURA: How much silver did you say there was?
MATT: Two silver.
KHARY: Do I notice her looking at me? I mean, does
Anastasia notice her looking at me?
MATT: I mean, no more than anybody looks at
anybody.
KHARY: All right.
MATT: The little goblin girl isn't leering at you.
I mean, has been leering at you since you arrived
but nothing in a way that catches your attention.
KHARY: Nothing out of the ordinary. Very good.
Nice to know.
MATT: Make an insight check. Roll a d20 and add
your insight skill.
KHARY: Insight. Nine. Nine plus insight is plus
three so, eh.
MATT: It's a 12. I'd say, yeah. No more than
usual.
KHARY: Right. She's got awfully big eyes.
MATT: As you guys get closer to the exit where
this broken, hinged archway was, this double door
archway about eight to ten feet wide, a new smell
rushes into your nose. Whereas previously it had
been just decaying earth and dust there's now this
musky smell that resembles the faint mixture of
urine and citrus. It's hard to place, but it's new
and it's different than the rest of the mines
you've been through.
LIAM: It's a step up for me.
SAM: We got all the ears?
LAURA: We got all the ears. Should we search for
more survivors and then burn it to the ground?
LIAM: Like the mine?
LAURA: Yeah.
LIAM: Burn the mine to the ground? Under the
ground?
LAURA: Well, we can explode it.
TALIESIN: You can.
KHARY: I appreciate your excitability. Why don't I
let the bird do the talking?
LAURA: You mean search for people?
KHARY: That's what I meant, baby. Thank you.
MATT: (humming) You watch at the Duchess makes her
way further down the tunnel.
SAM: As the Duchess flies away, I push on
Shakste's body a little bit and see if I get any
reaction.
MATT: You feel this tiny goblin hand push on you.
There does not seem to be a reaction.
SAM: I'm going to pick the pocket of Shakste.
MATT: As you're focused currently to the vision of
your-- you do not sense--
KHARY: I do not sense a thing?
MATT: You do not because currently all of your
senses are through your familiar. So unfortunately no.
KHARY: That's fine by me.
TALIESIN: Do any of us notice this?
SAM: I will use sleight of hand to conceal this
from the group.
MATT: You will have to, so make a sleight of hand
check.
SAM: Okay. Yeah, okay, that's not great.
LIAM: Our guests are like farm animals that we
mine for loot.
SAM: 14.
MATT: 14. Nobody has a passive perception higher
than a 13, I think.
MARISHA and LAURA: Mine's 13.
TRAVIS: Negative.
TALIESIN: Yep. 13.
MATT: All right.
TRAVIS: Horrible bastard.
MATT: Go ahead and mark nine gold pieces off of
your total and you take nine gold.
SAM: I'm going for that pouch.
MATT: The whole pouch?
KHARY: You're going for the whole-- Wait, I
wouldn't feel the entire pouch being pulled off of my--
MATT: You don't, unfortunately, because your
senses. Well wait, no, it's sight and hearing,
isn't it?
LIAM: It's sight and hearing for Find Familiar.
MATT: That's right! I take it back. He didn't
react to you being touched earlier, but I need you
to go ahead and make a perception check.
LIAM: Nah, it's pretty good.
KHARY: 13.
MATT: Plus what is your perception skill?
KHARY: Plus insight or--?
LIAM: There it is, 16.
KHARY: Perception? 16.
MATT: After the initial pat, you were focused, it
didn't bother much. You feel your belt tug a bit
and you feel suddenly the back of your armor begin
to get a little lighter as your pouch is
noticeably being removed from your person.
SAM: He doesn't know by whom!
MATT: No.
SAM: Just knows that it's happening?
MATT: It's happening.
SAM: And can't react?
MATT: I mean, he can if he chooses too.
SAM: Oh god.
MATT: Shakste, do you want to do anything?
MARISHA: You have a height that's very
identifiable. It's a very recognizable level
you're on.
KHARY: No, I don't want to do anything.
MATT: You undo the pouch and now have it in your
possession. As you're focusing through the
Duchess's vision, beyond the broken doorway the
tunnel grows rougher as you sense that the deeper
shafts of the mines are coming to an end fairly
soon. The scent the Duchess is picking up is
strong, that weird musky smell. After about 100
feet of it snaking a little bit forward, through
ten, 15 foot wide tunnels, suddenly the tunnel
opens, into a large, rocky alcove formation,
stalactites from the ceiling, and some elements of
broken digging equipment around the corners of
this chamber. The uneven ceilings stand about 15
to 20 feet tall within in places, and are scarred
with pick marks from various attempts to meet the
end of the mine, which apparently were not enough
to keep the mine in business. A rough slope
descends from the immediate entrance to this
tunnel, hits the wall before it, rises a few feet
past that to a smaller platform that meets the
opposite side of the wall, about 70 or 80 feet to
the other side. The chamber's about 80-foot from
where you enter to the opposite end. Near the base
of the raised rock you see two humanoid figures,
sitting against each other, bound tightly in ropes
and above the platform on top, you see a figure
you haven't seen yet. Human-like, but seems to
have large chunks of gnoll flesh strapped to their
body, like they used a disembodied gnoll arm as a
glove, a gnoll head with the jaw removed and
hollowed out used as a hood. There is this
individual carrying baubles and chains of some
symbols across their neck and they're spattered
with blood. They're standing at the top, currently
holding a third humanoid figure who is bound in
ropes, and dragging them up the stairs to this
platform on the opposite end. Next to this
gnoll-wearing priestly-like figure, you see the
figure in their arm is a guard, one of the
Crownsguard of Alfield. You don't recognize him at
a glance, but you can see they are currently still
living, bloodied and are being dragged up to the
top of this platform. You can see right at the top
of this raised section a monstrous mound of broken
wood, rope, burlap and scrap from nearby within
the mine that has been amassed into this large
pile. At that moment a majority of the mound
begins to move and shift, as two large, brown red,
leathery wings unfurl from the mound. Where a
fur-covered body steps out. Is the Duchess going
to stay and continue to watch?
KHARY: I can explain what is happening as she
sees.
MATT: You can. You are describing this verbally to
everybody?
KHARY: Yes, absolutely.
LAURA: What should we do? What should we do?
KHARY: We should wait and see what else unfurls in
this thing.
MATT: This creature stands up from within this
pile, you can now see this large, lion-like body
and torso the size of a rhinoceros, massive and
muscled, with giant clawed paws. Around the neck
you see this thick, red, fiery mane of hair and a
humanoid female face, dark and tanned, with this
large, curled grin. The mouth that opens and hangs
with rows of sharp teeth, but weirdly humanoid in
appearance. It turns its head towards this
priestly figure, who thrusts the guard to the
front and says "Come, gifted mother. Feed and may
you grow strong. Your strength is a boon from
Yeenoghu, and one that will bring us much more
meat in the time to come," and kicks the guard
forward. This large beast turns, and inspects the
frightened, shaking, and sobbing guard. "Your god
meats hold me to nothing, but your offer pleases
me and my child." As the beast stands up further
in this pile of rough, found pieces of wood and
twine, a small infant of its same species seems to
be wound up and begins to mewl in its place. It's
pawing at the air, its eyes not even freshly
opened. This creature steps forward and bites into
the Crownsguard and lifts it up as he begins to
scream. The rest of you hear the echoing screaming
in the distance of the Crownsguard.
LAURA: I think that means he ate him!
MATT: As it begins to bite and crunch, pulling its
jaw open, it tears it into two halves and begins
to chew on the upper torso. The screaming has
stopped.
SAM: Get your medical kit ready.
LAURA: Don't think it's going to help.
KHARY: There are two people left?
MATT: There are two people left in the room and
you can look around the vicinity. It looks like
there were more people in here that have probably
been fed over the past hour.
KHARY: This sacrifice will not end. First, Duchess
come back to me.
LAURA: Should we go in?
KHARY: We should talk. This is going to take a
minute.
MATT: Thankfully, nobody seems to notice Duchess's
presence as Duchess retracts back into your chamber.
TALIESIN: How flammable is that nest?
LAURA: I meant it's--
KHARY: How far is the nest away?
MATT: It's past 100 feet of tunnel before it opens
up into the chamber, which is another 80 feet from
the entrance.
SAM: How big was the chamber?
LIAM: 80 feet.
SAM: Oh my god.
MATT: To give you a visual.
SAM: A visual? Matt, there's too many maps!
TALIESIN: (Singing) Too many maps! Too many maps!
KHARY: Oh look at this thing!
MATT: So you can prepare.
SAM: That-- What?!
SAM: That is upper level shit!
LAURA: What are we doing? We're level three! What
are we doing? We got to go in, we got to throw
some dynamite, get the people out, and run!
KHARY: We got one stick.
LAURA: We got two sticks!
TRAVIS: I don't see any support columns. I'm just
going to say it.
TALIESIN: No, we hit the nest. Set the nest on
fire and it'll run.
TRAVIS: Yeah. You got to get pretty danger close
to do that, though. I've got to stand up and look,
make sure there's no damn holes.
TALIESIN: Oh yeah, good point. Yep!
MATT: No holes in the chamber from what you can
see.
TRAVIS: That's the baby, the little thing.
MATT: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Okay, no load bearing support columns that
we can see right?
MATT: Not that you can see, no. There are various
portions in the ceiling that are stalactites. It
looks like it's the deepest part of the mine,
which is the roughest, which means it does not
have a lot of support structure built into it for
the miners. This like it's as deep as they got
before they abandoned it from the veins dried up.
TRAVIS: Before shit started going wrong?
MATT: This mine has been long abandoned. The
recent occupants seem to have discovered it, and
taken it their own.
KHARY: Well, personally I'm a fan of freedom of
religion, but that's got its limits.
TALIESIN: It's fair to draw a line at human
sacrifice.
KHARY: I think so.
TALIESIN: Yeah. Let's--
SAM: We can't possibly kill whatever that beast
is.
LIAM: I don't know, maybe not on our own, two at a
time. I'm pretty tapped, but there's a lot of us
here and only a few of them there, according to
our new friend.
SAM: But there's only two survivors in there,
right?
TRAVIS: Two survivors and two enemies, right?
MARISHA: Yeah, but what happens if they get
sacrificed?
SAM: No, I mean, what if we just get the survivors
out and leave?
MARISHA: I think that's smart.
KHARY: I tend to agree with my little friend.
LAURA: And we steal the baby.
LIAM: We could also try and seal the cave behind
us as we go?
TALIESIN: Sealing the cave would be one thing, I
think stealing the baby is going to be a bit of a--
TRAVIS: I love your enthusiasm, but I tend to
agree with Molly here. Maybe the baby just stays put?
MARISHA: If we can get the baby, I bet it would
fetch a high price.
SAM: A baby should be with its mother.
LAURA: Yeah. We might kill the mom though, or bury
it.
TRAVIS: I think I'm okay with that.
SAM: As long as they are close to each other.
TRAVIS: It just ate a Crownsguard in half.
LAURA: Let's get it out, and then collapse the
tunnel leading to it. Then they can get stuck in
this room.
MARISHA: All right.
LIAM: Could we do a quick inventory check of how
much of these boom sticks that we have, the TNT?
LAURA: We have one and one.
KHARY: I have one.
LIAM: We have more than one? You have one?
LIAM: We have one amongst. Okay.
LAURA: We should make our way towards this,
though. They're going to get to the next hostage
by the time we get to this room, cause we're 100
feet away from it still.
TALIESIN: We make our way.
LAURA: Start walking.
TALIESIN: Stealthy walk.
LAURA: Stealthily.
MATT: You guys all making an approach?
SAM: Stealthily.
MATT: Roll stealth, please.
LAURA: Who needs a blessing? Caleb, you need a
blessing!
LIAM: It would help.
LAURA: You're shitty at stealth right?
LIAM: I'm pretty shitty at stealth.
LAURA: I bless you.
TALIESIN: I'm pretty iffy.
KHARY: 19!
LIAM: Plus?
KHARY: Plus five.
LIAM: Thank you, Jester, for saving my ass because
the first roll was a four. The second one was a
15.
TRAVIS: Are there steps?
MATT: Yes, right there.
LAURA: Oh, they're real close to them.
MATT: All right so, marching order please.
LIAM and LAURA: I'm in the back!
SAM: Wait, what's our plan?
TALIESIN: We're going to make a bunch of noise,
we're going to throw some dynamite, we're going to
get the kids to run and we're going to keep them
distracted by threatening the baby.
SAM: That's not a plan.
TALIESIN: Yes, it is a plan!
SAM: No, to kill or to capture the--
LAURA: We get the guards out, we get the people
out.
SAM: Get the guards out and run? So who are we
leaving back with the sticks?
LAURA: Oh, we're all going to be in there.
MATT: What is the marching order?
TALIESIN: We will throw the sticks.
MARISHA: I'll go up front with Fjord.
SAM: No! We should use the sticks to blow up
narrow passage way so they can't get out!
TALIESIN: Well, we have two sticks.
SAM: We should use them both!
TALIESIN: If we run, then we'll drop the sticks.
MATT: Nott, where are you?
SAM: I'm in the middle.
MATT: I'll put you in front of Caleb. Molly, are
you next to Beau?
TALIESIN: Yeah, anywhere that-- I don't want to be
in the front front, but I'll be in the middle.
TRAVIS: Who are our two strongest? Jester?
LIAM: Jester and Beau.
MARISHA: Well, I'm dexy.
LIAM: Yeah, you've got dex.
MARISHA: But I'm not strong. But I'm dextrous. It
depends on what we're talking about. Are we doing
anything with strength checks? Oh! Dragging people
away? Is that what we're talking about?
SAM: Are the good guys unconscious?
MATT: They're conscious, they're just tied up to
each other.
SAM: Oh. Shit, so two people need to be on drag
duty.
KHARY: We could cut them free?
TRAVIS: We're going to have to keep them busy.
LAURA: You need to sneak in and you need to try to
unhook the ropes, okay?
SAM: I could try to untie them.
LAURA: You stealth around. They won't even know
that you're there while we're attacking. Untie the
guards and then we all run.
KHARY: Could we distract them with maybe a
Thaumaturgy or Spiritual Weapon?
LAURA: Spiritual Weapon is really good if you have
that, that's very badass.
MATT: You can certainly try, it's up to you guys.
KHARY: I think Spiritual Weapon could make a lot
of noise and call a lot of attention, and then
maybe you could sneak through.
TALIESIN: You could do two Spiritual Weapons if
you're feeling it.
LAURA: I know, but then I have no spells left. I
got a first level, y'all!
KHARY: I think, because I used Aid, I think I've
got--
MATT: You have one 2nd-level spell and you have
three 1st-level, I believe.
KHARY: Yes. No, I've got two 1st-levels, because I
used Thunderwave and Command.
MATT: That's correct. You have two 1st-levels, you
have three spells left.
KHARY: Why don't we use-- okay, here's the thing.
If we start with Spiritual Weapon, we lure their
gaze to this side of the area and then if this
beautiful young lady could find her way around
the other side to free the two--
SAM: I can sneak in down to those stalagmites.
KHARY: Yes.
LAURA: She should sneak in before you do Spiritual
Weapon, otherwise it's going to make them aware
that something's going on. The Spiritual Weapon will
definitely alert them to our presence.
KHARY: The Spiritual Weapon goes off, giving the
people a chance to run out of the place.
LAURA: Yeah. You make that Spiritual Weapon appear
right next to them. You can hit them immediately.
KHARY: Right.
LAURA: You do it right when we do the surprise
attack. You sneak in.
SAM: Yes.
MARISHA: The rest of us can be on distraction
duty, yeah? Until we go.
LAURA: Yeah.
MARISHA: Nott?
LAURA: Are you good to sneak? I'm going to bless
you.
SAM: Okay.
LAURA: Before you go sneaking around the side.
SAM: Can I have a ball bearing, please?
MARISHA: Sure. You can have a few. I hand him a
handful.
SAM: Thank you.
MARISHA: Did you just want that because it's
shiny?
SAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: Oh, Nott.
(laughter)
SAM: I will cast Mage Hand and hold one ball
bearing. I'm getting ready to move stealthily.
MATT: If I can have all of you who are approaching
to make a stealth check, please.
LIAM: Also, DM--
SAM: In addition to the one we just made?
MATT: Sorry, the one you just made. Sorry, so what
was were those scores?
SAM: 23.
MATT: 23.
LAURA: You get advantage, when you go into the
room, just in case of a natural 20.
LIAM: I will also say, and I'll do this a lot,
Dancing Lights is in effect behind us. 20 feet
behind us, waiting.
MATT: All right. Interesting point of order, this
human that you see, this priest. Pitch black, sees fine.
LIAM: Sees-- (groans) Okay.
MATT: Does have a set of, as they've walked into
this chamber-- although you would have seen this.
LIAM: I did not see that.
MATT: Actually, yeah. You're the only one who
would notice something. You don't see anything,
never mind. All right, so--
KHARY: Say that again.
MATT: You didn't notice anything in particular,
other than just seeing this scene. Nothing at all.
You know nothing! So stealth is 23.
LAURA: 13.
TALIESIN: Nine.
TRAVIS: 18.
MARISHA: 19.
MATT: All right.
LIAM: Did you know that you can't see?
KHARY: I'm blind.
LAURA: Caleb, what's your stealth roll?
LIAM: Oh. It was really good. It was a 16 total.
MATT: 16. What did you roll for stealth check?
SAM: How do you see things?
LIAM: The bird.
KHARY: The bird, baby, the bird.
LIAM: That's hot.
MATT: Shakste, what's your stealth check please?
KHARY: My stealth check. Oh, my stealth check was
19.
MATT: 19, okay.
TALIESIN: I'm the only problem.
MATT: Yeah, which is good because that means the
rest of the group picked up for you.
KHARY: That's right, it's 24.
MATT: As you guys approach, those of you who can
see in the dark, you can't quite see your quarry.
You'd have to get closer in because I believe it's
a 60 foot darkvision radius for most of you guys.
Which means you can see to about there.
LAURA: Okay.
MARISHA: We suck.
SAM: I can see the stalagmites?
KHARY: I believe Anastasia could fly in and hide
behind the stalagmite.
MATT: You can. Make a stealth check for your
hummingbird.
LIAM: Come on birdy. Ooh! Good.
KHARY: All right, 15 plus-- No, I'm sorry.
LIAM: It's 15.
KHARY: It's 15 plus five.
MATT: Natural one and a four on their perception.
Nobody sees your bird's arrival.
LAURA: Come on, Nott, go.
SAM: (scampering feet)
MATT: All right Nott, so you rush in?
SAM: Yeah. I'm going to-- Mage Hand's already
cast.
MATT: Yeah, and what's the range on that one?
SAM: 30 feet.
MATT: 30 feet, so you can keep it out as far as
that. Yeah, it's fine. All right, so you come in
there. Where are you holding the ball bearing?
SAM: I'm going to drop the ball bearing right at
the edge of that stair so it (tings).
MATT: As that happens, you watch as both the
priest and the large beast at this time-- which
now that we're getting closer and we're seeing the
form, I probably should've asked this of you
earlier: go ahead and make a general nature
check.
SAM: Who me?
MATT: Both of you guys.
LIAM: It's alphabetical right on the list. Ooh.
KHARY: 19.
LIAM: Plus?
KHARY: Nature? Plus one.
SAM: 15.
KHARY: 20.
MATT: You notice it, but you, after getting a
closer view of its form as your hummingbird gets
in close, you can, "I know what this is." This is a
manticore. The wings are scary, the teeth are
scary, the spines on its tail are scarier.
KHARY: It has spines in its tail.
MATT: You've heard rumors of such things being
flung as a weapon and regrown quickly and begin to
suddenly remember the spines that were affixed to
the armor of the gnoll leader and the glaive. You
rush in and have this moment of remembrance as you
begin to curl forward, stealthing around the side
as the ball bearing (ting ting ting). Both the
priest and the manticore whip over in that
direction. The priest pulls a glove on its hand
that's a dull red color that begins to sparkle
and glow at the tips of the fingers, and tightens
it on its hand and begins to step down the stairs
a bit in the direction of that.
SAM: I'm going behind those stalagmites over
there.
MATT: Over here?
SAM: No, like--
SAM: Yeah.
LAURA: All the way around.
MATT: Okay. Whereas the female manticore,
(flapping). The wind picks up and dust begins
to spiral and briefly obfuscates the area. The
manticore flies; with an impact, lands on the
opposite side, right where the ball bearing is and
(sniffs). "Company." All right, what are you guys doing?
SAM: I'm going straight for the Mage Hand to untie
them.
MATT: Make a sleight of hand check from a
distance. Well, this would be a straight dexterity
check. Roll dexterity, not sleight of hand.
SAM: Dexterity check.
MATT: Add your dexterity modifier.
SAM: 18.
MATT: 18. With a quick, rapid movement of your
Mage Hand, you watch as the ropes on one come
free. One of them (breathing heavily) looks at
their hands and doesn't know exactly what happened
but is apparently now free of the ropes.
LIAM: Are we in a weird in-between combat and
non-combat?
MATT: Yes. We're not in combat yet, so what are
you guys doing?
LIAM: I would like to hug the wall and slide along
it. I would like to think I can hear my
friends breathing-- and stop, yeah that's good--
and hold my action, and if anything comes this way that
is not my friends to cast Burning Hands as a
tripwire. I'm the tripwire.
MATT: Within range you mean?
LIAM: Yeah, of course within range.
MATT: All righty, anybody else? What are you
preparing for?
LAURA: Got nothing.
MARISHA: Waiting to beat face.
MATT: You're all staying right there?
TRAVIS: I mean, no.
MARISHA: Should we creep forward a little? What
should we do?
TRAVIS: Yeah. We're going to have to fan.
MARISHA: I guess Fjord and I will take a good ten
feet or so up.
LAURA: They might see you.
SAM: Yeah, you're going closer?
LAURA: You're getting really close to the
manticore.
SAM: Jesus.
LIAM: Yeah, maybe the other side of the tunnel so
they don't see you.
TALIESIN: He's got a distance weapon anyway,
there's really no such thing as a bad--
LIAM: You can see me doing this.
MARISHA: Will you put Fjord towards me?
MATT: Oh, this way?
LIAM: Yeah, pull him to the other side. They're
seeing me do arcane bullshit on the side while
sweating.
MATT: Anybody else preparing?
LAURA: I'll stand next to Caleb on the inside.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: I'm really, at this point, only useful
for a couple things. I'm going to keep in the back there.
MATT: Okay. Shakste, anything?
TALIESIN: I got my Vicious Mockery rolling.
KHARY: I would like for Anastasia to fly to the
other side of the room.
MATT: Whereabout?
KHARY: No those stalagmites over-- yeah, there you
go. Hide in those crags over there by the-- that's
it. Keep a good eye. Good girl.
MATT: (humming drone) All righty. The manticore
begins to clomp up the steps.
TRAVIS: Airborne?
MATT: No, on foot at the moment like (impact
sounds).
MARISHA: We'll just wait for Nott. Go Nott go.
KHARY: When do I go?
MATT: Well, right now as the manticore crests the
top of the stairs, the large, joker-like, toothy
grin of the female manticore glances up right
towards all of you and goes (growls).
LIAM: I attack her.
MATT: It's not within range of you yet.
LIAM: Not within range? Then I don't do it yet.
MATT: You're holding it and it's not close enough.
I need you all to roll initiative now.
LIAM: Wow. My initiative is such dick. All night
long. All campaign long, let's be honest.
TALIESIN: I did okay.
LIAM: Oh my gosh. At the end as always.
MATT: We have 25 to 20 anybody?
TALIESIN: 22.
TRAVIS 20.
MATT: Nice. We have Molly.
TALIESIN: Are we going to redo the initiative
flags?
MATT: And Fjord. 20 to 15?
LAURA: 18.
SAM: 17.
MATT: Nice. Jester and Nott. You have Molly,
Fjord, Jester, Nott, and the manticore. Then
15 to ten?
KHARY: Pass me Shakste.
MATT: Ten to five?
LIAM: Acht.
MATT: All righty. We have--
LIAM: There's people after my eight?
MATT: Well, simultaneously with the priest.
KHARY: I am a five.
MATT: Five (groans).
MARISHA: I'm a nine.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: Sorry.
MATT: It's okay, I got you. At this point, top of
the round: Molly, you're up.
TRAVIS: I have no idea what the order was.
TALIESIN: Vicious Mockery.
MATT: It's Molly, Fjord, Jester, Nott, the
manticore, Beau, then Caleb and the priest
together, then Shakste.
TALIESIN: Vicious Mockery on the manticore.
MATT: All righty, 12.
TALIESIN: I don't actually know what it's rolling
against. What is it against?
MATT: It's eight plus two, which is your
proficiency bonus, which is ten. Plus your wisdom
modifier. What is your wisdom modifier?
TALIESIN: My wisdom modifier, I believe it's
three.
MATT: It would be 13, so it hits, yeah.
TALIESIN: All right! That's one point of psychic damage
and it has disadvantage on the next attack.
(rasping) You should leave and protect the child.
Trying to--
MATT: All right, the female face grins even wider,
the eyes narrow (growls).
TALIESIN: I'm going to back up.
MATT: It seems like it shakes its head a bit. It
seems strangely wounded briefly, but then grins at
the prospect of a new meal.
TALIESIN: I'm backing up a little bit. I'm going
to step back ten feet.
MATT: You move back ten feet to there.
TALIESIN: Yeah, backing up.
MATT: That brings us to Fjord's turn.
TRAVIS: Can I move forward and end up right over
there?
MATT: Right there?
TRAVIS: Yeah and end up on his flank melee,
please.
MATT: Put you right there.
TRAVIS: I will unleash the full fury of my
falchion into his side.
MATT: With the blade drawn--
TRAVIS: Two-handed.
MATT: Right. Shakste, as you watch, the half-orc,
Fjord, suddenly emerges from his hand out of
nowhere, this flash of greenish-blue energy and a
splash of water spatters across the ground as a
slightly curved at the tip falchion appears that
has a cluster of barnacles along the base of it
and slowly curling up the blade and sea water
dripping off of it at all times leaving a trail of liquid.
TRAVIS: 23.
MATT: That hits.
TALIESIN: Yeah!
MATT: This thing is pretty big, it's not too hard
to hit comparatively.
TRAVIS: 13 points of damage. Slashing damage.
LIAM: What did you roll to hit?
TRAVIS: The ten, two-handed. That is it.
MATT: All righty, that ends your turn. It's now
Jester's turn.
LAURA: I'm going to run around to the other side
of it. This is so dumb.
MATT: (counting) 30. Are you getting within melee
of it?
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: There you go.
SAM: Oh my god, are you going to hit it with your
sickle or whatever?
LAURA: I'm going to hit it with my sickle or
whatever!
MATT: Roll for attack.
MARISHA: Do it girl!
LIAM: Those arrows are long gone.
LAURA: Natural one!
MATT: As you rush around the corner, out of the
corner of its eye it sees you. As it spins its
giant, spined tail which you can see now which
looks like a porcupine filled with javelins.
Rushes past and slams into your shoulder. As you
do, your sickle flies out of your hand and
clatters across the ground and hits the floor at
the bottom of the stairs. That is where your
sickle currently is.
LAURA: Oh no.
MATT: End of your turn, Jester?
TALIESIN: Bonus action, anything?
TRAVIS: Bonus action to run your ass.
LAURA: I'm going to just dance in place.
MATT: All righty. Nott, your turn.
SAM: Bonus action, use the Mage Hand to untie the
other one.
MATT: All right, make another dexterity check.
SAM: 19 plus four.
MATT: With that the other person's rope falls free
and they're both out of their ropes. They're both
looking at the only exit that is currently blocked
by this giant manticore creature. They look
scared and have no idea what's happening. They
haven't seen you. For some reason their ropes have
dropped and they're scared shitless. They aren't
guards. These two look like civilians and they're
having a really rough time.
SAM: (sighs) Should I waste my action on this
shit? I'm still hidden, yeah?
MATT: As far as you know.
TALIESIN: There's also another dude.
SAM: Another dude? Oh, you mean the bad guy.
MATT: There's the priest.
SAM: Yeah. Not another good guy.
SAM: Ah fuck. I'm going to use Message and point
to one of the guards that I just untied.
MATT: They're not guards, they're civilians.
SAM: Or whatever, the civilians and say to him:
The second after the priest casts a spell, grab
your friend and run.
MATT: Make a persuasion check.
SAM: Nine.
MATT: Okay, you deliver the message. That's as far
as you know.
SAM: Then for my movement I'm going to tuck in
even tighter.
MATT: Okay. All right that finishes your turn. It
is now the manticore's go. It is going to make
three attacks, a bite and two claw attacks. It's
going to make two claw attacks. Actually, it's
going to make one sweeping claw attack at Jester
from behind and then a bite and a claw attack at
you, since you're right in front of it and already
struck it with your falchion.
TALIESIN: First one's disadvantage.
MATT: First one's at disadvantage, which would be
against Jester as you rush past. That is a 17,
and a 19.
LAURA: Hits me.
MATT: Yeah, it hits you, that's without bonuses,
unfortunately. You take from the first strike nine
points of slashing damage, as it (woosh). It
rolled high, a nine again. Then two strikes
against you.
LAURA: I'm going to cast Hellish Rebuke at it as
soon as it does it.
MATT: Okay, what's the save? It was a natural 20
on you Fjord, unfortunately. The other claw attack.
TRAVIS: Oh player, I've got the Armor of Agathys
on.
MARISHA: Oh, that's right!
LAURA: It doesn't say on my thing. It's a dex
save.
MATT: A dex save, all right. That is a 12.
LAURA: Oh!
MATT: So that hits? All right, go ahead and
roll damage.
LAURA: 3d10! I'm going to say in Infernal--
SAM: 3d10?
LAURA: I'm going to say--
LIAM: All tens, come on.
MATT: 2d10.
LAURA: No, 3d10 because it's cast at 2nd-level
when you're doing Hellish Rebuke.
MATT: Oh, right, yeah.
LAURA: Okay, 13.
MATT: 13 points of damage. Of cold damage.
LAURA: Yeah, in Infernal I say, Oh, you're such a
cute kitty!
MATT: With an awkward flick of her wrist, you
watch as this wave of ice spike energy flies
outward and pierces the side of the manticore's
body as it rotates and breaks the ice off of its
torso. In doing so, it spins around with its other
claw and strikes right into Fjord with a natural
20. It rolled a one on the fucking damage die, so
you're fucking lucky on that, that's twice in this
game. It's kind of disappointing on my end, but
it's fine. So that's five points of slashing damage.
TRAVIS: And he'll take ten points of cold damage.
MATT: That's right.
MARISHA: So. Sick.
TALIESIN: We're at our best when we're losing.
MATT: As it strikes with its second claw attack
against you and the ice cracks, and it looks at
you and the mouth opens wide and you can see where
three separate rows of teeth like this horrible
shark maw. As it reaches forward to bite towards
you, the head itself about maybe this wide, the
jaw can almost clamp down onto your waist,
Jurassic Park style. That's going to be a 16 to hit.
TRAVIS: 16 hits.
LAURA: Oh no!
LIAM: Where's your AC?
TRAVIS: 14.
LIAM: You're Grog!
TRAVIS: Nope.
MATT: That's ten points of piercing damage from
the bite to you.
TRAVIS: Great, he takes another ten points of cold
damage, as my Armor of--
MATT: She.
TRAVIS: She, thank you. As my Armor of Agathys.
MATT: Interesting, in this quick series of hits,
she's doing fine, but this is an unexpected burst
of damage and you can see harrying's starting to
show. A powerful creature can do some powerful
damage, but is showing a little bit of wear and
tear. With that, the manticore is going to take to
the sky.
TALIESIN: (singing) Take to the sky!
MATT: It's going to fly up.
LAURA: Do we get an attack of opportunity?
MATT: You both do, yes.
LAURA: Ah, I'm going to kick it.
MATT: You can punch it, make an attack.
LAURA: No, I don't hit it!
MATT: What did you roll?
LAURA: I rolled a three!
TRAVIS: Do I get an attack?
MATT: You do, yes.
TRAVIS: I don't think that's going to hit either,
that's an eight.
MATT: Nope, you both, (whoosh). The giant gust of
wind from the wings flapping push you away and you
have to block your vision to keep the dust out of
the way. Finishing the manticore's turn, it is now
Beau's go.
MARISHA: Okay, well it took off flying, so that
sucks.
LIAM: You can't even see it.
MARISHA: I feel kind of like Grog. what can I do
with that?
TRAVIS: Welcome to my fucking three years.
MARISHA: Yeah, that's lame. I don't know what to
do. I'll move forward and hold my action for light.
MATT: How far are you going to move forward? 20
feet?
MARISHA: Oh, where's the priest? But I can't see
the priest, it's dark in here.
MATT: You're seeing faint flashes of light.
Actually, you don't see any light, because no
one's cast any spells, it's all been combat, so
it's just darkness and you hear roars and slams
and impacts. You're like, (worried noise).
MARISHA: I'm going to move behind Jester, and I'll
just dodge as my action, there's not a lot I can do.
MATT: Okay, that finishes your turn, Caleb and the
priest are going simultaneously. What are you doing?
LIAM: So this has happened like six times now,
where I go right after Beau, so Dancing Lights,
excuse me.
MATT: Well first off, the spell you prepared,
never went off, so the spell is gone, it's used.
LIAM: Of course.
MATT: So the spell's gone, so you lose one of
those.
LIAM: So instead, Dancing Light. I'm going to do
the same line of light that I always do because
Beauregard needs to be able to kill things and
see. One goes far as here, and here, and here probably.
MATT: You have enough to generally light most of
the chamber.
LIAM: It's always a line spread out.
MATT: Perfect. That's your action?
LIAM: No, I'm also going to back up about 15 feet
as well. Then I'm going to crouch because I'm frightened.
MATT: Okay. That comes to the priest's turn. The
priest is going to step forward angrily, and is
going to attempt to cast Hold Person on you.
SAM: Joke's on him, that's not a person. It's a
half-orc.
MATT: Half-orcs are people too, Sam. Make a wisdom
saving throw.
TRAVIS: Wisdom saving throw. Big modifier of
nothing. Six.
MATT: With that, you feel your muscles lock up,
your entire body freezes in place as you feel your
entire physical self lock up, unable to move.
LIAM: He done been bifurcated.
LAURA: He done been paralyzed.
MATT: All right. The priest is going to go ahead
and take two steps back after casting that, and
hide behind--
LAURA: (singing) Two steps forward--
ALL: (singing) Two steps back.
MATT: Caleb, that finishes your turn as well.
Shakste, you're up.
KHARY: Let's see, we don't need light anymore.
LIAM: Save us.
KHARY: I think we need a bigger mode of damage. I
think rather than Spiritual Weapon, we need to go
with the Thunderwave again.
LAURA: Oh, the spell.
LIAM: That's a very short range, though.
MATT: Yeah, it's a 15-foot square.
LIAM: You can't get close enough to anybody on
that map to use it.
MATT: Yeah, the manticore is about 15 feet up in
the air right now, so it's just out of the range.
KHARY: Ah, so I can't get to it.
LAURA: Spiritual Weapon stays on the field. Once
you cast it, it's out there in every single turn,
for a bonus action you can attack.
MATT: I will say, Spiritual Weapon, as far as I
know-- let me see here real fast. It's pretty
great.
LIAM: Do you have a level one left?
KHARY: I do have a level one.
MATT: It says a floating spectral creature, it
doesn't specify if that it can or cannot move up
and down, so I would imagine you could create it
in the air if you want.
LIAM: I think these are your best options: either
a floating weapon that can go anywhere, or a big
fog cloud, if you run up and put it on the priest,
or up there. I think probably Spiritual Weapon.
KHARY: I think Spiritual Weapon because the thing
is, is that I can move it from one to the other.
LIAM: You can adjust.
KHARY: Spiritual Weapon.
MATT: Do you move forward to cast it?
KHARY: Yes, let's see, I will stay in the
hallway.
MATT: How far, there?
KHARY: Yeah, right about there.
MATT: You're creating it at the base of the
manticore, or further in the chamber, or where?
KHARY: Oh, I would love to drum the underside of
her.
MATT: Easily enough to do. What kind of weapon do
you create?
LIAM: Decide what it is. A lollipop, a salmon, a
sword?
LAURA: Don't give-- Let him decide.
MATT: What magical, mystical weapon would you like
to create that represents your attack on this
creature?
LIAM: Nunchucks.
KHARY: I would--
LIAM: Have fun.
KHARY: (laughs) The first thing that I was
thinking, for some reason, was I would like to
materialize the awe-inspiring sass of Estelle
Getty, and pummel the stomach--
TALIESIN: Oh man.
TRAVIS: What the fuck.
KHARY: That's all right. That might be a little
bit too out there, so--
TRAVIS: It's not.
MATT: What do you want to do?
LIAM: It could be a cudgel carved to look like
Estelle Getty if you wanted it to be.
KHARY: You know what? The sassiest of the Golden
Girls-- I think because my lovely daughter,
literally-- It was 120 days into the school year,
and she dressed like a 120-year-old woman today,
my six-year-old daughter. I think that the bust of
a tiny curly-headed 120-year-old woman needs to
slam its way into the torso of that manticore.
LIAM: Like a Beethoven bust, but Estelle Getty!
MATT: Estelle Getty begins to bludgeon itself into
this creature. I love it.
KHARY: Into that thing right there. That's right.
Mya, you should be in bed, but this is for you,
baby.
MATT: Go ahead and roll a melee spell attack. Roll
that and add five to it.
KHARY: 13. 18.
MATT: That hits. Roll the damage on that one. It
is 1d8 plus three.
LIAM: That's the d8, yeah.
MATT: Roll that and add three.
KHARY: Ah! One.
MATT: Still, four points of damage. Nothing to
scoff at, and it's still out there without concentration.
LIAM: That's true.
MATT: Do you want to move anywhere, or you going
to stay put?
KHARY: Let's see. I am going to remain where I
am.
MATT: Good to know. Finishing that, top of the
round. Molly, you're up.
TALIESIN: Again, there's not much I can do-- I'm
going to step in front of Caleb, in an attempt to
be another target, and I'm going to try again with
Vicious Mockery.
MATT: All righty.
LIAM: Thank you for being a friend.
MATT: A two. It does not succeed.
TALIESIN: Yeah. (rasping) You are going to be
buried here! I hit him again. Four points of
psychic damage.
MATT: All right, four points of psychic damage,
and first attack has disadvantage.
TALIESIN: First attack has disadvantage. I'm going
to be in front of Caleb.
MATT: Cool, sounds good. That's the end of your
turn, Molly. Fjord, you're up.
TRAVIS: Oh, I'm up? I'm a Hold Person!
MATT: Yep, so roll a wisdom saving throw to see if
you can resist it.
TRAVIS: Nope!
MATT: Nope, you're still locked in place.
TRAVIS: Fuck that die.
LAURA: Can you do anything while you're
paralyzed?
MATT: Nope. Nothing. That ends Fjord's turn.
Jester, you're up.
LAURA: Okay. I'm going to Sacred Flame the priest.
MATT: Okay. Is it a wisdom saving throw?
LAURA: Sacred Flame is a dexterity saving throw.
MATT: Dexterity save. That is a ten.
LAURA: Yeah!
MATT: 12, sorry.
LAURA: Doesn't matter! Still hit! Six damage of
radiant.
MATT: Six damage of radiant. As it's right
behind-- it's trying to block around the pillar,
but you still have a clear visual as you
concentrate on the symbol of the Traveler hidden
beneath your outfit. You focus and there's a burst
of energy that burns around its body--
LAURA: Pink energy.
MATT: Pink energy that sparkles around him as he
looks over towards you and he continues to try and
crouch behind the stalagmite.
LAURA: Is Hold Person concentration?
MATT: It is, so he has to make a concentration
check. Which he fails? That's an 11? No, it's a
ten. No, it succeeds. Just barely succeeds. The DC
is ten. Sorry! He rolled a nine, but he has a plus
one constitution. Sorry.
TALIESIN: That's ten.
MATT: Yeah, he succeeded. He has to meet the DC or
higher. But good try.
TALIESIN: You still have movement, too.
LAURA: Oh, I can move.
MATT: Yes, you can.
TALIESIN: You could go get your sickle.
LAURA: Oh yeah, that's right! I could run down and
grab my sickle, why not?
SAM: Wait, so the boys didn't get up and run as
soon as the priest made his move?
MATT: No, not yet, unfortunately.
SAM: They're just lying there?
MATT: Well, they're coming around for their turn.
LAURA: Oh, that's right. They can't just move.
MARISHA: Save yourself!
TALIESIN: This is why you don't plan, Sam! This is
why we don't plan! Because plans go wrong.
MATT: You have your sickle, you still have more
movement if you wanted to move. You have ten more
feet. Or 15 more feet.
LAURA: I'm going to run up and engage the priest.
MATT: All right. You're right up in his face. That
ends your turn. Nott, you're up.
SAM: What to do?
MATT: Gnollish priest. Regular gnoll, regular
gnoll.
SAM: I will run right past those two guards. As I
go by, I say: Get the fuck out of here!
(laughter)
MATT: They watch as a tiny goblin with jagged
teeth yells at them as they run by. However, there
are more scary things in the current vicinity. You
rush past, and they're two civilians, not guards,
but continue.
SAM: Oh, sorry. No, I'm going to keep calling them
guards.
MATT: I'm okay with that. They're guards from your
perspective. All right, so you run past.
SAM: Bonus action dash up the steps.
TALIESIN: Are you going to go for it?
LAURA: Get the baby.
MARISHA: Oh my god, are you going for it?
SAM: I'm going to turn around and yell at the
manticore--
MARISHA and TALIESIN: Oh no!
MARISHA: Nott the Brave!
SAM: You want to save this thing? I will slice
down with my short sword on the baby.
MATT: Make an attack roll.
SAM: Ooh. I mean, 14?
MATT: It hits it. It's a baby. Roll damage.
LIAM: Nott's going to die!
SAM: Eight.
MATT: It's helpless, it's sneak attack.
MATT: It can't do anything. It can't defend
itself. Its eyes aren't open!
SAM: It's 16. 2d6. No sorry, 17 damage.
MATT: As you plunge your short sword down into the
mewling, eye-covered cub, it goes still, as the
mother manticore flying up in the air turns around
to watch this, and gives a (roar)!
SAM: (screaming) Get the fuck out of here!
ALL: Oh my god!
TALIESIN: I take it back! Plan!
MATT: Nott, that ends your turn? It's the
manticore's turn. The manticore, which was about
to unleash a triple round of attacks against a
paralyzed Fjord, who, while paralyzed, would have
all been criticals, strangely saved him and is
instead going to dart--
LAURA: Does the Spiritual Weapon get a--
MATT: It does not, no. At a 50-foot fly speed,
land right next to you, Nott, and take a full
round of strikes against you. Too angry to worry
about tail spines at this point, it's going all
in, physical assault to whatever just murdered its
baby.
TALIESIN: Disadvantage!
MATT: Disadvantage on the first strike. 17 and a
natural one.
SAM: Miss!
MATT: Which, I'll say, causes it to strike down
towards you in fury, and instead its claw gets
jammed into the ground, so it gets disadvantage on
its second attack. I'm trying to play with natural
ones a little more in this campaign. This is the
second claw attack against you. A natural 20 and a
17. It hits but it avoids the critical, which is
good.
LAURA: Oh my god.
MATT: That is nine points of slashing damage with
the claw.
TALIESIN: Are you all right?
SAM: So far.
MATT: Then the bite attack is going to come
towards you. I'm going to give this advantage
because you just killed its baby.
TRAVIS: Because you killed its baby!
MATT: Yeah, that's going to be a 21.
SAM: Sure, that hits.
MATT: All righty. There we go, there's the actual
damage die roll. That's 11 points of piercing damage.
LAURA: (gasp)
LIAM: Are you up?
SAM: (whispers) One point.
MATT: Oh shit!
(laughter and gasping)
TRAVIS and TALIESIN: Oh, fuck.
MATT: That ends the manticore's turn. The
civilians get up--
SAM: Yeah, leave, motherfuckers! Leave!
MATT: And begin to run. (counting) They get that
far with the movement and dash. They're (gasping)
tripping and falling, managing to make their way
there. They're both frightened, covered in all
sorts of dirt and gore, and running in your
direction, trying to get away from whatever's
happening back there. The roar set a further fire
in them. All right. Beau, you're up.
MARISHA: (moans)
SAM: She's got to grab Fjord!
LAURA: Grab Fjord and get out of here.
LIAM: Fjord? Nott! Nott's in danger!
LAURA: I know, I'm going to cast-- I'm going to
cure you.
MARISHA: Okay. How far away is Nott from me?
MATT: Nott is 40 feet from you.
TRAVIS: Or hit the fucking manticore. You got to
unfreeze me, too.
MARISHA: Okay. I'm going to yell at Nott, I'm
going to be like: Nott, the fuck?! Then I'm going
to take off in a full sprint towards Nott.
MATT: (counting) You can get right up to the top
of the steps.
MARISHA: I'm going to go: the fuck?! I grab you
again, and I scoop up Nott, and like a football
drill, I dart, and then I'm going to dart all the
way back with Nott. Carrying Nott like a football.
SAM: You're going to get the hit. With me, too.
MATT: Okay. You scoop up Nott. That means, because
you're carrying another creature, your movement is
halved when you run. Are you using-- it's your
action to grab and pick him up.
MARISHA: Okay. I want to use my Step of the Wind.
Ki point.
MATT: Ki point, Step of the Wind to run. That
moves you and Nott 20 feet. You get Nott to there.
The manticore is going to take an attack of
opportunity against Nott.
MARISHA: Ah, damn it! I was hoping it would be on
me!
MATT: Of course! The creature doesn't give a shit
about anybody but that little goblin that stabbed
its baby.
KHARY: You are like holding her and covering her,
aren't you?
MATT: That is 19 to hit.
SAM: Yeah, that hits.
MATT: A bite strike again, that is ten points of
piercing damage.
SAM: (scream)
LAURA: Unconscious.
MATT: As you pull Nott away, there's a sudden tug,
and you pull hard and you look back and you watch
as you drag Nott out of the teeth of it, grinding
across the body, dragging wounds like daggers
across Nott's face and chest. You see blood pour
out of each of these scars.
MARISHA: The fuck?! I still run.
MATT: All right, so you are unconscious and
bleeding out.
MARISHA: I don't have a bonus or anything, right?
That was everything?
MATT: Nope, that's your whole turn. You used
everything for that. End of Beau's turn. Caleb and
the priest are up.
LIAM: I saw that, and I walk as far forward as I
can with my movement and start stirring the pot on
Chromatic Orb. I have one left. I will use ice
damage and I will send it out and I knock it off
my hand towards the manticore. Come on, please.
SAM: The sticks! The dynamite sticks!
LIAM: That's a 25.
MATT: 25 hits. Roll damage.
LIAM: That is 3d8 cold damage. That is-- ooh! 15
total.
MATT: 15 points of cold damage. Nice.
LIAM: I would have gone as far forward as I can.
MATT: You moved up there. It strikes the
manticore, a burst of ice that freezes part of the
side of the mane and the fur on its body before
the fur cracks and the flesh that it impacted
cracks. There's a little bit of muscle exposed
beneath the wound left behind from the frost
freeze you left on the side of its torso.
LIAM: Caleb is breathing very heavily and not
looking at the manticore. He's looking at Nott in
Beauregard's arms.
MATT: That ends your turn. The priest, who is
currently working on that, going to maintain Hold
Person, is going to step up. No, it's going to--
yeah, because you're right there in front, it's
going to Inflict Wounds on you.
LIAM and MARISHA: Ooh!
SAM: No problem.
MATT: A melee spell attack. Not great. Actually,
not bad! That's a 17.
LAURA: 17.
MATT: That is your armor class. 17 hits. You take
3d10 points of necrotic damage.
LIAM: Oh! Necrotic! Necrotic just follows Laura
Bailey.
MATT: I know.
SAM: It will be like a 12.
MATT: That is 14 points of necrotic damage to
you.
TALIESIN: Oh my god.
SAM: Or the exact amount.
LAURA: Exact amount.
MATT: Oh no!
TALIESIN: Fuck fuck fuck.
LIAM: Cleric's down. One of our clerics is down.
MATT: You watch as the priest reaches out and
grabs onto the armor of Jester, and with a burst
of black energy, the veins under Jester's blue
skin begin to pulse with black energy, and she
screams out as her eyes loll back and close, and
she hits the ground unconscious.
MARISHA: She's next to me, right?
TRAVIS: Technically, there are three of us out,
because I ain't moving.
MARISHA: I'm next to two unconscious people going
(screaming).
MATT: Yeah. That ends the priest's turn. Your
turn, Shakste.
LAURA: You have one of the healing potions.
LIAM: It's your call. I will help you with
decisions you make. You can get to the front of
those stairs.
KHARY: Yeah, let's see, I should move forward.
MATT: You have 30 feet to move forward.
TRAVIS: If you could put a beat down on the
priest, do it.
SAM: That will release the Hold Person.
TRAVIS: I have a healing potion in my
possessions.
LIAM: Do you have any spells slots left?
KHARY: I think I--
SAM: He's got the Spiritual Weapon.
MATT: The Spiritual Weapon can only move 20 feet,
though, which will only get it about there, unfortunately.
SAM: Damn.
LAURA: No, Spiritual Weapon can move 30 feet.
MATT: I thought it was 20 on a bonus action.
LAURA: Oh, maybe I'm wrong.
LIAM and KHARY: The range is 60 feet.
MATT: Well, the range of the spell is 60 feet, but
then the bonus action to move it is 20 feet and
repeat the attack. Sorry, guys.
LIAM: No, that's great.
MATT: You can move forward if you want to. Did you
want to move forward the rest of your--?
KHARY: Yeah, if I move is anything going to get
close enough? I could do Sacred Flame.
LIAM: That's all you can do is try to take down
the enemies, and we can help. That's all you can do.
KHARY: All I can do is move forward and Sacred
Flame the priest.
MATT: Okay. That's a wisdom save, right?
KHARY: Yeah, that's a wisdom save.
MATT: That is going to be an 11. Which, your DC is
13, that hits. Go ahead and roll damage.
KHARY: All right, going to roll damage. Come on.
LAURA: Man, hit the fucking priest!
KHARY: Three plus--
MATT: That's just three points of damage. Three
points of radiant damage. It bursts and he's still
trying to concentrate on the spell. He does make a
constitution saving throw. That's an eight. That's
a failure. The DC is ten. With that, your
paralysis ends.
TALIESIN: Oh, thank god!
MATT: Yeah, it's either half the damage or ten,
whichever is higher. With that, you blast it, and
he loses the spell, and all of a sudden your body
comes back into control of you, Fjord. You have
the bonus action. You can still move the weapon if
you want to.
LIAM: I'd get it into the business.
KHARY: Oh, absolutely.
MATT: It was up ten feet, technically. It can move
down and then move over here, and it would be down
on the ground right there.
LIAM: It's on its way for the next round.
KHARY: Sure. Okay.
MATT: If you wanted. You could move it anywhere
else you want to.
TRAVIS: Who do I pour that potion into, you or
you?
SAM: The healer.
KHARY: Stay right there, Estelle. She doesn't move
quickly, but she moves effectively.
MATT: The bust (humming) and rests floating in the
air. That brings us to the top; Molly, you're up.
TALIESIN: Fuck, there is so little I can do. I'm
going to move forward a bit, I'm going to move
close enough that I can-- I'm just going to keep
trying to-- Put me next to Caleb.
MATT: There you go.
TALIESIN: Shite. I'm just going to keep trying to
give disadvantage to the first attack on the
manticore.
MATT: What's the range on Vicious Mockery?
TALIESIN: 60 feet.
MATT: Yeah, you can do that here. Wisdom save for
the manticore. 19.
TALIESIN: Yeah, it saves.
MATT: Sorry.
TALIESIN: Fuck. Fuck fuck fuck. Not even In
infernal. Fuck fuck fuck.
MATT: (laughing) Fjord, you're up.
TRAVIS: What is it, an action or a bonus action to
pour a health potion into somebody's mouth?
MATT: It's an action.
TRAVIS: I'll run down and pour a health potion
into Jester's mouth.
LAURA: That's good, because that gets me up and I
can heal you.
LIAM: Yeah, in time for your turn.
MATT: You reach down, pull out the healing potion.
It's a regular healing potion, right?
TRAVIS: It was a regular.
MATT: Yeah, so that would be 2d4 plus two you
heal.
SAM: You roll? You roll? Who rolls?
TALIESIN: Doesn't matter.
LAURA: Six plus two. Eight!
MATT: So you heal eight.
TRAVIS: Can I use the rest of my movement to start
running up the stairs?
MATT: You may.
TRAVIS: I don't know how much I have left.
MATT: From there it was (counting) six, that's as
far as you get.
TRAVIS: Okay, fair enough. Okay.
MATT: As you move out of range, the priest is
going to make a strike at you with his dagger.
TRAVIS: Was I in melee of the priest?
MATT: Yeah, to get to her you would have.
TRAVIS: I'll stay in there, then. I couldn't see
where I was. Yeah, I'll stay close.
MATT: Yeah, because you would have moved-- Oh,
god.
SAM: Oh god, everyone's dead.
LAURA: It's all going to shit!
MATT: That's okay. You stay there. That end's
Fjord's turn, Jester, you're up. You are on the
ground, prone, but are now conscious and
breathing, as you feel the glass vial pulled away
from your lips, and Fjord looks down at you with a
nod, like "Go!"
LAURA: Thank you! I stand up. I'll reach out and
cast Cure Wounds on Nott.
SAM: (gasping)
MATT: Go ahead and roll that. That's a d8 plus
your wisdom modifier?
LAURA: Yes, it is. Sorry.
SAM: I just say to Beau: The fuck?!
(laughter)
LAURA: Eight points to heal.
MATT: So you heal eight points.
TRAVIS: The fuck.
LAURA: Then I guess we should start running, yes?
I use the remainder of my--
MATT: Movement to run? You can move 15 feet.
LAURA: Can I use my bonus action to dash?
MATT: You do not have that ability, unfortunately.
That's a rogue and monk ability to use a point.
Clerics do not get that. Sorry. Let's put you
there.
LAURA: My bonus action to whimper a little bit.
MATT: Okay. The priest does get attack of
opportunity on you as you run past, as you were
engaged in melee.
LAURA: I'm hoping the priest is lame.
MARISHA: Yeah, a weakling.
MATT: Well, he rolled a three. The dagger hits
your armor and scrapes off the metal. No effect.
That ends your turn, Jester. Nott, you're up.
SAM: Oh, this is crazy.
MATT: You're prone, technically, in Beau's arms
right now.
SAM: Sure. I will look up at the manticore, I'll
take out my last shitty tart that you gave me, and
crumple it onto the ground, and point up to the
manticore and say: What did the incontinent druid
say on his surprise birthday party? I'm so
excited, I wet my plants!
(groaning)
TRAVIS: Wow.
TALIESIN: Never mind, leave him behind.
KHARY: How much damage did that give?
TRAVIS: Yeah, to all of us? TPK up in this
business.
MATT: This is, I assume Hideous Laughter?
SAM: Yes, Hideous Laughter.
MATT: All right, we'll see if this works. Wisdom
saving throw. That is a 12. What is your DC?
SAM: 13.
(cheering)
MATT: There's been a lot of just under this game.
TALIESIN: Oh, god.
KHARY: The dad joke works!
MATT: Weirdly, as angry as this manticore is at
you-- You know what? I'm going to give it
advantage in the saving throw because you killed
its baby.
LAURA: Oh, that's just mean!
MATT: You killed its baby.
MARISHA: Hindsight advantage.
MATT: I'm allowing it, because I'm the fucking DM.
It doesn't help, I rolled a two. Shit. I felt it
was fair for the mother of the baby that you just
murdered.
SAM: You would have given it to us.
MATT: I would have, and from a narrative
standpoint it made sense. Still takes effect. The
manticore, turning around, eyes filled with fury
and anger, goes (growling). She all of a sudden
begins to chuckle. As the mouth opens from the
laughter, you see the jagged teeth, filled with
your own blood, and the tongue lashing around from
the laughter as it falls on the ground, prone and cackling.
TRAVIS: Is goblin blood red or green? Red?
SAM: I think it's like a black. I don't know.
Matt, what is it?
MATT: It's dark enough where, in this lighting, it
looks black.
LAURA: Hideous Laughter. Does that mean we all get
advantage on hits now?
MATT: It is prone, which means melee attacks do
get advantage against it.
SAM: Or we could leave.
TALIESIN: Run!
LAURA: But you guys! We've got a whole other
round!
SAM: Of what?
LAURA and LIAM: Attacks to wail on her.
SAM: Or to leave.
MATT: It's up to you. The manticore's pretty hurt.
The priest has taken a little damage, but the
priest also doesn't look very hardy. But it's up
to you. You can flee or you can finish it. There
are advantages and disadvantages. There are
advantages to both.
MATT and MARISHA: There are advantages to both!
KHARY: Are there ears on all of that crap that
this priest has on him? Are there any ears on him?
MATT: No ears. There is actually on the head. The
gnoll head has ears.
KHARY: They have ears on that thing. And if we
drag that fucking carcass back to the surface, I
bet that'll--
TRAVIS: Be worth a pretty penny?
MATT: You're probably not wrong.
KHARY: You know what? Forget that. I want that
fucking thing on my wall.
MATT: All righty. Well, that's up to you guys to
make your choices.
TALIESIN: How long does Hideous Laughter last?
LAURA: For at least a whole round.
MATT: Each time it takes damage.
MARISHA: Okay, we could unload and then run!
LAURA: And each time he takes damage?
MATT: It gets to make a save again.
SAM: On the end of his turn, he gets to make a
save.
MARISHA: If you hit him, he gets to make a save?
MATT: Yeah. And on the end of its turn it gets to
save.
TRAVIS: It's not like a tee off and then we go.
LAURA: Oh, I thought it was like a paralyzation
sort of thing.
SAM: So he might save right now.
MARISHA: We should go.
TRAVIS: We should stick to the plan.
MATT: Well, regardless--
LIAM: What about the dynamite?
KHARY: That's what I'm saying! I want to stick one
in its mouth!
MATT: That's up to you.
SAM: You might not get that chance! It's the
manticore's turn, and she might save right now!
MATT: Yeah, that's true. Because it is the
manticore-- you still have movement, if you want to.
MARISHA: Do you want me to put you down?
MATT: You have 15 feet of movement if you want
Beau to put you down.
SAM: Yeah. I will jump down and run.
MATT: Ten, 15.
TALIESIN: Can you also take your bonus action to
run too?
SAM: Sure, if I still have a bonus action.
MATT: You do, yeah.
SAM: Bonus action dash. Well, you know what? I'm
going to stay within 30 feet of the priest.
MATT: Okay. Good to know. All righty. Finishing
Nott's turn, the manticore's turn. The manticore's
chuckling, laughing on the ground, howling. It's
echoing throughout the chamber in this very
dark--
SAM: 35 feet of the priest.
MATT: I'll put you about, roughly, we'll say
there. The manticore's going to attempt to make
its wisdom saving throw.
TRAVIS: No! Fail!
MATT: That is a 12, again! I rolled two elevens in
a row!
LAURA: Laugh it up, Fuzzball!
MATT: The civilians continue to run and they are
just up the tunnel. You hear their heavy breathing
fade as they disappear into the darkness. Beau,
you're up.
MARISHA: What do we do? Are we running or are we
fighting?
TRAVIS: Whatever you want to do.
MATT: Beau, it's your choice. What are you doing?
MARISHA: Okay, I'm going to, because I can, fuck
the priest.
MATT: Okay. You move in to the priest. Go for it.
MARISHA: Okay. Big ol' two-handed staff swing.
That's not bad. 16!
MATT: 16 hits! He's only wearing leather armor.
MARISHA: Nine points of damage.
MATT: Nine points of damage. Whack! Right across
the face. You knock part of the gnoll head off.
It's off-kilter to the side and he spits blood and
looks back at you, "Do not worry. He will come for
you too."
MARISHA: Ugh! Okay, in response to that, I'm going
to be like: Don't patronize me! Then I'm going to
fucking Flurry of Blows. Elbow strike him to an
uppercut.
MATT: Go for it.
MARISHA: First attack. Yeah, that hits, with a
12?
MATT: That hits!
MARISHA: Natural 12. And then, not so good. 12
again. Total.
MATT: 12 does not hit, unfortunately. But the next
one does.
MARISHA: Six plus four. Another ten points of
damage.
MATT: Ten points of damage, nice. With the staff
hit, he laughs at you, the blood spilling out on
the side of his chin. You smack him with the
elbow, miss with the upper cut, but as the elbow
cracks and hits you feel like the jaw kind of
dislodge a bit. As he looks back, he reaches up
and he's trying to put it back into place. He's
looking not too great.
MARISHA: Hang on, I messed up that. Three plus
four. I messed up.
MATT: You said ten? Yeah, you shouldn't have
done-- actually, it would've been seven.
MARISHA: Seven damage. I'm sorry. I was adding the
wrong modifier. I was looking at the wrong guy.
MATT: It's all good. No worries, so seven damage
on that one? That ends your turn?
MARISHA: Yes! No! I can still move? Right?
MATT: You can, yeah.
MARISHA: I'm going to now move past Fjord and
start heading away.
MATT: Okay. It already got an attack of
opportunity against--. So you move up (counting) 40.
MARISHA: I'll stay-- that's good.
MATT: All right. Caleb and the priest. Your turn
simultaneously.
LIAM: Ja, I cannot see too well, so I'm going to
take a step forward between Mollymauk and Nott.
Just a little bit there. Now I can see that blond
hair, and I am tapped out, so I'm just going to
let my hand blacken and say a few arcane words and
then send a--
MATT: He does have three-quarters cover behind
that from your current position.
LIAM: Well then I will, if I can't see too well,
keep going down the steps until I can see him.
MATT: You can move there to get a view without
hitting--
LIAM: That's fine. That's not fine, but that's
fine. Fire Bolt and here it comes to you,
shithead. That is a 25 to hit.
ALL: It hits!
LIAM: But I could roll a one. I rolled a ten.
(cheering)
MATT: How do you want to do this?
LIAM: I'm going to extend my hand forward. I have
five fingers out and then I pull in four. I send
the flame down my hand because these people have
hurt my little friend. I want his hair to burn off
his head and die.
MATT: Okay. As you release the bolt, the anger in
your eyes, the fury coursing through the veins in
your hand. The Fire Bolt slams into the priest's
head, and he falls back on the ground, screaming.
As you watch, Ghost Rider-style, his head just
bursts into flame and burn away, until he falls
back to his knees. You can just see the darkened
expression of a black skull into the fire as he
falls. I need you to make a wisdom saving throw.
LAURA: What?! What's this mean?!
LIAM: That's a seven.
MATT: A wave of memories come flooding to you, and
you feel your motions grow slow.
LIAM: I was going to do this on my own.
MATT: You guys watch as Caleb stares at this, and
continues to stare at the guy burning in flames.
That ends your turn!
SAM and LAURA: What?
MATT: Shakste, it's your turn.
LAURA and TRAVIS: (whispering) Backstory.
(laughter)
MATT: Shakste, your turn.
KHARY: Yes. Well, I do believe I still have a
Spiritual Weapon.
MATT: You do.
LAURA: That's right!
KHARY: The Spiritual Weapon goes wandering over,
just as sassy as she wants to be. I do believe
that the underbelly of the manticore is still
waiting there for Estelle to tell him all kinds of
horrible things about what it's like to live in
South Florida.
MATT: Oh, that's particularly awful.
KHARY: Absolutely. First of all, exactly. You know
what? There's way too much gambling at the track.
Everybody's constantly upset about the humidity.
This is what your problem is. Maybe next time,
you'll eat something less human-like, baby. What
do I need to roll?
MATT: Roll a d20 plus five, with advantage because
it is prone. So roll a d20 twice and take the
higher of the two.
KHARY: Roll the 20 twice?
MATT: Correct.
KHARY: Nine. Three.
LAURA: Nine plus five?
MATT: Nine plus five is 14. That is just its armor
class. That hits. It has an armor class of 14. So
roll damage on that. d8 plus three.
KHARY: d8 plus three. That's this one. All right,
four. Four plus three is seven!
MATT: Seven points of damage! As the bust slams
into the manticore after your musings pierced its
soul, it's going to attempt to make a saving
throw, with advantage.
LAURA: With advantage? Why with advantage?
MATT: It's a two. Because whenever it takes an
impact from an attack, it gets an advantage on the
saving throw to break it. A two and a five,
however!
(cheering)
MARISHA: Aw, baby.
MATT: It's okay, it happens. It's good, it's
cinematic. It's fun. That's your bonus action. You
still have an action.
KHARY: I still have an action?
MATT: Yes you do.
KHARY: Well then. Let's see. Where am I?
LIAM: Did you use all your slots?
LAURA: You got healing in there?
SAM: Was that a bonus action to use the weapon?
MATT: Yeah. So you still have an action if you
want to cast another spell or do something else as
an action.
KHARY: Let's see. How is everybody feeling right
now?
TALIESIN: Not too good.
KHARY: Not too good?
MATT: The priest is already dead. The manticore's
pretty hurt. Some of them are pretty beat up and
low. Some of them seem to have avoided the fray.
KHARY: Yeah. Am I close enough to the point where
I-- I'm still pretty far from the manticore,
aren't I?
MATT: You're about 60 feet from it.
KHARY: I'm about 60 feet, but I would need to be
at about a 15-foot cube to do my Thunderwave.
MATT: Thunderwave, yeah.
LAURA: You could do a cantrip as an action.
Because you got enough distance.
KHARY: Yeah, I think the cantrip will-- let's hit
him again with Sacred Flame.
MATT: Sacred Flame? All right. That will be an
eight plus one for the wisdom modifier. That does
not succeed! So roll, that's d8 radiant damage.
SAM: So that worked?
LAURA: Yeah. 1d8 radiant.
SAM: Oh, so you roll!
KHARY: Oh, so I do roll!
MATT: You did damage, yeah.
KHARY: I did damage. Oh, you did wrong, so I did
right!
MATT: Exactly! That's how spells work a lot of the
time, man.
KHARY: Big money. Come on, baby. That's a six.
MATT: A six? As is tradition, it seems, for our
guests, how do you want to do this?
(cheering)
MATT: That's ridiculous, by the way! That's fucked
up! I'm counting and I'm like, if he gets the kill
this is going to-- this is ridiculous.
LIAM: That's hospitality.
MATT: That's hospitality. Jesus Christ!
MARISHA: Put. That. Shit. On. Your. Wall. Describe
it!
MATT: So how do you want to do this? As it's on
the ground, laughing and cackling and writhing.
KHARY: I drop the reed that's in my hand, and I
start to play with the flames that start to light
on the edges of my fingers. As I slowly bring them
together, there's a musical interlude that starts
to play and shoots towards the manticore. Diving
down her throat, and bursting through the chest of
her, and exploding her heart. You know what? I did
that out of love. For someone who just lost their child.
MATT: There you go. As Shakste smiles, the
merciful grin of a person who knows that the loss
of a child is hard, you release this torrent of
sound energy into the cackling mouth of the female
manticore. As the writhing stops, and she begins
to stand up, looking down, looks back at the
corpse of the child now laid still. Looks back at
you with a look of pity and acceptance before
(explosion). There is a burst of gore out of the
chest, and the creature just falls to the ground,
motionless. The wings flopping onto the ground,
still. And silence takes the chamber.
(silence)
TRAVIS: Well, time to light the TNT, let's go.
TALIESIN: I'm going to douse the flames. I'm going
to run down to the priest and douse the flames,
and then give Caleb a good slap on the face.
MATT: Okay. Caleb comes to.
LIAM: (slapping)
TALIESIN: Hey! Back in the game! Time for that
later. You all right?
LIAM: Yeah.
TALIESIN: All right. Big kiss on the forehead and
then walking away.
MARISHA and KHARY: I'm--
KHARY: No, please.
MARISHA: I was just going to say, I'm going to do
a quick scan. See if there's anything of interest.
MATT: Make a perception check.
MARISHA: Copy. Natural 19. 22.
MATT: Amongst the chunks of flesh and rather
horrible attire, there's a couple of interesting
adornments on the priest. The nest looks like it's
a mishmash of all kinds of things cobbled
together.
MARISHA: I'll definitely take the adornments from
the priest.
MATT: Okay. From that, there was a set of goggles
that were affixed over the priest's eyes, of a
dark lens.
MARISHA: Can I see? If I can see in the dark. I
need night vision goggles!
LIAM: You do.
MATT: There is also that reddish glove that was
affixed to his right hand.
LAURA: Don't touch it! I wonder if that makes
spells better. (gasps)
TRAVIS: I'll run up onto the nest and start
looking for stuff.
MATT: Make an investigation check for me, please.
TALIESIN: You all right there? You all right?
SAM: Never better!
TRAVIS: Natural 20.
LAURA: Yay! Find all the shit!
MATT: No shit! What's the total there for that?
TRAVIS: 24.
MATT: All right. As you tear through the rubble of
this nest, you find a few interesting things: a
skeletal hand that has been mostly chewed through,
though a single fleshy finger still holds a ring
of beautiful silver make and a blue gem that
catches your attention. What at first looks like
part of the wooden riff-raff that makes the nest,
you pull out a refined and well-carved stick that
doesn't match the rest of the rather rough wood.
TALIESIN: I know I'm so excited, our first loot.
LAURA: This is so exciting!
MATT: Also, tangled within the mass, you find
chains but larger than normal chains. These chains
are attached to a set of unlocked manacles, much
larger than any human manacles you've seen. There
are four identical loops, a little over one foot
in diameter, all attached via this chain to one
larger one about four feet in diameter.
SAM: That's huge.
MARISHA: Was it for the manticore?
MATT: It looks like it would have been the size
for a manticore. Since you rolled so high in
investigation, you also notice that these
manacles, which are open, have a single rune
pressed into where they meet and lock in place, as
there is no other visible locking mechanism. You
are unable to really, at the moment, ascertain the
nature of it. These manacles are fresh, they're
clean compared to all the other stuff in here.
They are there.
MARISHA: Are the runes recognizable in any way?
MATT: Make an arcana-- are you proficient in
arcana?
TRAVIS: I'll make an arcana check.
MATT: Are you proficient in arcana?
TRAVIS: I have a pretty high bonus, I don't think
I'm proficient in it.
LIAM: I would like to sit on my ass and look at
the ground.
TRAVIS: I am proficient in it.
MATT: Make an arcana check, please.
TRAVIS: Seven.
MATT: You're unable to really ascertain the nature
of the runes, unfortunately.
LAURA: I'm going to walk up and pet the
manticore's mantle.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: Aw, fuck that thing.
KHARY: I'd like to cast a spell.
MATT: What would you like to cast?
KHARY: Fog Cloud.
MATT: Okay. You watch as the central portion of
the chamber begins to fill with a thick mist,
somewhat obscuring your vision more than a few
feet in front of you.
LAURA: What was that?
TALIESIN: Is this supposed to happen?
SAM: What's going on?
LAURA: We should get out of here.
KHARY: I step behind Nott and whisper in her ear,
I say that: This was a bold move you made and we
wouldn't have made it, we wouldn't have succeeded
without you, so I say you earned that gold. But
make no mistake, be careful where you put your
fingers.
SAM: Yes, fog monster.
MATT: All right. What else would you like to do?
LAURA: Should we get out of here, I guess.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: Anything else in the chamber? Does it look
like there's any other little, interesting things
in there?
TRAVIS: Hey, Molly?
TALIESIN: Yeah?
MATT: Honestly, it looks like everything was
clustered in the nest or on the priest.
TRAVIS: You want to help me butcher that manticore
head?
TALIESIN: Let's do this.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
MATT: Easily enough. Within but a few moments,
between the triple-blades that the two of you
wield, you manage to carve a fresh and carryable
by two of you-- this is now the second beast head
you guys have acquired, carrying along with you--
a female manticore head.
SAM: We're not going to take those giant manacles
are we?
LAURA: Yeah.
KHARY: I'll take the tail.
TRAVIS: Yeah we'll be taking all of that.
SAM: It's huge, can we carry that?
MATT: All the manacles together probably weigh
about 25 pounds, so it's carryable.
TRAVIS: Just over the shoulder, just walk out.
MATT: You couldn't carry it.
SAM: I can't carry it, that's how much I weigh.
TRAVIS: Even I couldn't carry that.
TALIESIN: Caleb, come on.
MARISHA: Hey, you all right?
TALIESIN: Later.
LIAM: Yeah.
TALIESIN: There's time for that later.
TALIESIN: Come on. Let's go get some sunlight.
MARISHA: I grab Caleb, wrap an arm around him, and
try to walk him out.
TALIESIN: I'm going to grab the other side, we're
going to-- yep.
TALIESIN: You did good.
LAURA: Well I'm still here with this big, giant
manticore head so-- you guys got Caleb?
TRAVIS: I'm helping out.
KHARY: You're going through a change, my friend,
and that's not a bad thing.
(laughter)
MATT: All right. You guys manage to exit the
mines, it seems that the remainder of the gnoll
warband have either scattered or collapsed beneath
the earlier tunnel falling.
KHARY: Gnoll cowards.
MARISHA: Cowardly gnolls, cowardly gnolls.
LIAM: You just cured me.
MATT: You bring yourself back to the surface. The
light of the day is growing closer to sunset,
another hour, hour and a half or so before the sun
sets, but you return to the shack, which has been
untouched, unsullied since your leaving. The
remainder of the survivors greet you upon you
letting them know you've returned, and you watch
two more reunions occur as the two individuals you
had saved from the belly of the manticore find the
rest of their family within the survivors. You
gather the rest of the bodies, and whoever needs
the travel, and begin to load up the cart you
brought with you, as well as the manticore head,
unless you want to carry that back to town yourself.
LAURA: I think it might be easier to put it on the
cart.
MATT: You can rope it onto the cart without much
of an issue, though you still have a single horse
pulling a lot of people and a lot of manticore
head. That horse is not going to be traveling at
maximum speed, it's going to be a slow pace on that
thing.
LAURA: I mean, if it's all slow then it doesn't
matter I can walk alongside it and pull the
manticore head.
MATT: Eventually after night falls, you can make
camp or you continue to make your way to Alfield.
It's only a few miles off and you'll probably get
there maybe an hour or two after sunset.
TALIESIN: Sure.
LAURA: We should probably just get there.
TALIESIN: Let's make it all the way back.
MATT: All right. As you guys make your way under
the outskirts of town, back through the forest
that cradles the northeast side of the city, a
handful of crownsguard that are keeping watch for
any sort of incursion watch you approach and
immediately one of them puts up a hand, "Halt. Who
"goes there?"
TALIESIN: All hail, the conquering heroes!
LAURA: The saviors of Alfield have returned!
TALIESIN: Huzzah!
MATT: "Right the, um, yes-- come this way," he
seems to not be able to deal with the fact that
you've arrived with all of these survivors, and
the head of a manticore being pulled by this poor horse.
SAM: It's two horses.
TRAVIS: There are two horses.
SAM: W.C and Crapper.
MATT: Making your way into the town. Since you've
seen it last, a number of buildings still lay
in cinders, ash, and burned structures, but the
people are in the process of cleaning and
rebuilding their lives from the night before where
this first attack initially happened. Within a
short time, the crownsguard seemed to have brought
Bryce back for you. Bryce, which you have not met
yet, is currently the Watchmaster of the town. You
see a genderfluid half-elf with blonde
shoulder-length hair and armor. They seem to be
recovering from the wound they sustained the night
before and as you approach they immediately come
up to you with a bit of a jog and say, "My gods,
"you've certainly come through on my-- what is
that?"
LAURA: It's a manticore head.
TALIESIN: There was a lot.
MATT: "Apparently." They scratch their head, and
shake their head in wonderment, "Well, you've--
(laughs) "Thank you. What do we call you?"
MARISHA: Oh shit.
LAURA: Oh fuck.
SAM: We'll get back to you.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: We're still a--
TALIESIN: This is all very new.
TRAVIS: We're the TBDs.
MATT: "Very well." The woman by the way, who you
had helped earlier, she comes forward with two of
the members, and they come forward to the
Watchmaster and they say, "Bryce, Watchmaster, all
"of these people came and helped my baby. And--"
and turns and looks at you and is looking about to
introduce you, if you have a moment you wish to
halt or intercede.
KHARY: I stop. I hold my hand up. I put my finger
over my lips. Shh.
MATT: "Anyway, thank you all." Other folks are
starting to come out of their respective homes now
to see this spectacle. Children are gawking and
you hear gasps at the sight of the horrible beast
head, the tongue lolling out and dragging across
the ground.
Other people are gathering and having
reunions, other people are beginning to identify
the dead that have been brought in the cart and
while there is sadness and crying, there is also
closure. There are even some still that are
disappointed to not see those they had hoped to
see amongst those who had been recovered. Given
that still, a hero's night is to be prepared and
people begin to prepare food. For a brief moment
past the darkness, you can hear music begin to
build as people begin to bring chairs and
tables out to the center of the town square, the
intersection of where Alfield's simple backwoods
lifestyle seems to still understand what
celebration is in the face of victory. As what
better case is there to be but to celebrate those
who stood up to such evils? As you all think over
what you've done, this ragtag group of wandering
know-nothings that have managed to come together
and do a good thing. For some coin, maybe, but a
good thing nonetheless.
LAURA: I pull out the jar of ears.
(laughter)
LAURA: Before I hand them over, I open the lid and
I whisper in: Thadeus Candleglow says hello. I
shut it. I think I did what he asked.
SAM: He said to do that. He said to say that to
the people.
LAURA: They heard it.
LIAM: Also, Caleb has been very distant for the
last couple of hours, but absentmindedly scoops up
Nott's hand. Doesn't look at Nott, but holds
Nott's hand.
SAM: I stealthily take my bag of coin and slide it
into his back pocket, and I pat it and say: I got
you some book money.
KHARY: Shakste is standing at a distance.
Everyone else is walking towards the village. The
Duchess is perched on his shoulder, and he
scrawling something in the dirt with that long
reed. It's kind of an "H." And he fades into the
forest.
MARISHA: We don't get to say goodbye.
LAURA: He's the coolest
MARISHA: He's so cool.
MATT: On that note, we're going to end tonight's
game.
(groaning)
LIAM: Khary!
MATT: Khary! That was amazing, man!
MARISHA: Have you ever played before?
KHARY: With my kids.
LAURA: You're so epic.
MARISHA: You're so good.
MATT: Dude. Thank you, finally. We've been wanting
to have you on for so long, but schedules haven't
lined up. I'm so glad we could.
KHARY: Sometimes I can't believe my luck. I love
the things people ask me to do and I can't believe
I get to hang out with you guys and do this, this
has been so much fun, I don't know how to thank you.
MATT: Pleasure is ours, man, thank you so much,
seriously.
KHARY: Oh!
SAM: Are you inviting us on your show?
KHARY: I have a gift! Is it all right if I--?
MATT: Yeah, go for it.
LAURA: Do you have a present?
KHARY: I do have a present.
MATT: Kind of.
KHARY: Yeah, sort of, from your old friend. Let's
see I-- let's see.
LIAM: Uh oh. All right, I know how this works.
(laughter)
KHARY: I was given something from Will Friedle.
SAM: Is it a venereal disease?
KHARY: At first he was like, "Oh, I've got
something for you."
LIAM: Slipping you the digits.
KHARY: Yes, he brought me this 20-sided dice.
LAURA: It's so pretty.
KHARY: It is, it's lovely, isn't it?
LIAM: He's got gloves on him, don't touch it.
MARISHA: What's it mean?
LAURA: It was up Will's butt.
TRAVIS: He carried it in his ass.
LIAM: Crystallized rice.
MATT: Ass-20s, it's like ass pennies.
KHARY: My ass-- no. He played with this,
apparently, but at some point, it was touched by
Wil Wheaton.
ALL: Oh no!
KHARY: Exactly. At some point, I had a hammer--
MATT: You know what we should do, because we don't
want to do anything near the table, after this,
we're going to go ahead and record a video of you
dealing with that like the Ring in Mount Doom.
KHARY: Exactly.
MATT: We'll put it up on socials.
KHARY: He gave this to me as if I would use it
today. I was like, you know what, that's the last
thing I'm going to do.
MATT: He had it blessed and everything, you were
telling me.
KHARY: He said that two witches blessed this thing
and that it was okay. I watched him roll it, and
it seemed like it was okay, but there's no way
this thing can be okay.
MATT: It's safer for everyone.
KHARY: Rather than have any foolish soul wander
upon it, we're going do with this thing, like
you say, we're going to take this thing out.
MATT: We'll have that video for you guys in the
near future. Guys, great game. We'll take this up
next week.
LAURA: I can't believe we survived.
MARISHA: We're heroes.
TALIESIN: We lived.
LIAM: Just for one day.
KHARY: The plan was perfect.
MATT: The plan was perfect. A couple things didn't
work out to get out of there in time, I was hoping
that would.
KHARY: I was really disappointed in Nott for a
while, and then she ran up there and did what no
one else would.
MARISHA and LAURA: Nott the Brave.
SAM: Nott the Stupid.
MATT: Thank you guys so much. Khary, thank you
again. Shakste goes into the annals of Wildemount
history. Thank you guys so much for tuning in.
We'll be back here next Thursday to continue this
story. Until then, is it Thursday yet? Have a good
night.
[music]