MATT: Hello everyone, and welcome to tonight's
episode of Critical Role, where a bunch of us
nerdy-ass voice actors sit around and play
Dungeons & Dragons.
LAURA: Oh God!
TRAVIS: We're all a bunch of assholes!
LAURA: That might be the worst one!
TALIESIN: Oh man.
MATT: So welcome, Travis and all of you guys.
Before we jump into tonight's game, let's get
through some announcements real fast, so hang
tight with us for a moment. First and foremost
tonight, our fantastic returning sponsor for this
campaign beginning and the foreseeable future,
until they decide to vanish in a puff of smoke: It
is D&D Beyond!
(cheering)
MATT: Happy to have you guys! Sam, do you have a
few words one that?
SAM: D&D Beyond has a mobile app, guys, and it is
out on beta! You can download it now at the App
Store and the Google Play Store-- The Apple App
Store and the Google Play Store. And because
most-- well not most, but a lot of our audience is
located in the United Kingdom, I tailored
tonight's D&D Beyond pitch to the British
audience.
TALIESIN: I'm so sorry.
SAM: Oi, mates! Have a butcher's and be gobbed by
this brand new D&D Beyond mobile app for your dog
'n' bone!
LIAM: Sorry, Kit.
SAM: I know my onions on this and I ain't all
mouth and no trousers! It's a real corker of an
app, and you can nick yours on the Apple App Store
and blimey, the bloody Google Play Store, too! Are
you skint? Tosh! It's free, and that's the dog's
bollocks! You don't got to be minted to get
sorted. There's nothing bent as a nine bob note
about it. You get an ereader with the beta, and
character sheets will be added in the future
tickety-boo!
LAURA: Wow!
SAM: That's a real phrase that I looked up.
MATT: Of course it is.
SAM: So don't faff a dozy fortnight. You'll be
right gutted if you do! Oh, sweet fanny adams;
don't wag off! Search D&D Beyond at your app store
and you'll be jolly good chuffed about it! Oh now
I'm knackered and cream crackered so I'm off to
Bedfordshire! Pip pip!
TRAVIS: Yes!
MATT: Oh wow!
TRAVIS: I feel like that was Masterpiece Theatre
all at once.
LIAM: I refuse to applaud that. I refuse.
LAURA: I feel like that would be real hard to do
quickly, so I'm impressed!
MATT: Thank you, Sam, and we're sorry. Also, as a
quick note for you guys, they've begun posting
article content on DnDBeyond.com, which has been
awesome. We've done video content before. Now
they're doing article content as well, editorial,
which our very own James Haeck, who you may know
helped me with the Tal'Dorei campaign guide, a
fantastic writer and a good friend of the show, is
doing stuff there now. He's officially on board
with D&D Beyond, and he's doing the campaign two
summaries right now for the Critical Role
campaign. Those episode recaps will be posted
every Friday! Check them out! So awesome
congratulations to you, James, and if you haven't
checked it out, please do, because he's amazing.
That's DnDBeyond.com! DND not D&D. Next up,
reminder for you guys who have Amazon Prime with
Twitch Prime. You can subscribe to any channel on
Twitch for free each month. You get one which you
can grab for free. Just connect your Amazon Prime
and your Twitch account and it's a little button
press and there you go. That's awesome. Talks
Machina hosted by Brian W Foster, whom I'm tempted
to mess up his name every week because apparently
I really-- Anyways, he hosts our fantastic Talks
Machina wrap-up show about today's episode next
Tuesday at 7:00pm Pacific here on Twitch and
Alpha, so check it out there and check out
whatever cast members show up to dish the dirt and
shoot the shit and whatever else involves doing
something and something. You got it. Daylight
Savings Time hits the US on Sunday.
TALIESIN: That's not true, is it?
SAM: I didn't know that!
TALIESIN: Why would they do that?
MATT: Well, it's on the list if it's not. I don't
know anymore.
TRAVIS: We spring forward.
LAURA: So we lose an hour.
MARISHA: So we lose an hour of sleep.
MATT: So check out WhenIsCriticalRole.com for an
update on when Talks Machina and Critical Role
will be live in your timezone if you aren't lucky
enough to be living in the Dark Ages like America
is when it comes to keeping track of your time.
LIAM: Also, if you're watching this episode in
July of 2019, you're welcome.
MATT: The podcast episode of last week's episode
of Critical Role is available now for all your
fine downloadable podcast purposes. And there's no
giveaways tonight from Wyrmwood, but
congratulations to our friends at Wyrmwood on the
success of their Adventurer's Arsenal Kickstarter
and to all of the guys who supported it. It looks
really awesome and to all the critters who
supported it, thank you so much and we'll
hopefully be back to giving something next week.
We have a couple other cool announcements. One,
issue five of Vox Machina: Origins is out if you
haven't seen it yet.
MARISHA: Oh man!
TRAVIS: Beat to shit Vax on the front! It's
fucking awesome!
MATT: It's pretty great!
SAM: I still haven't read it! I need to!
MATT: Sam! It's really good. We've already gotten
back a good portion of the art for issue six, the
end of this arc, and it looks really good. If you
haven't had a chance, you can check it out. You
can download it on ComiXology, on the Dark Horse
Comics app, and many other places where fine comic
books are sold digitally.
LIAM: Laserdisc.
MATT: Yes, that too. Let's see.
LAURA: I have an announcement.
MATT: Yes, you do.
LAURA: Is it on the list?
MATT: I think it might be.
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: I will be leaving late tonight,
post-midnight, to fly out to Lexington, Kentucky.
TRAVIS: Oh, gross, really?
MATT: Yeah, but it'll be great. I'll be at the
Lexington Toy and Comic Convention to hang out
with a bunch of you guys out there in Kentucky! If
you haven't already decided to go, and you're in
the vicinity, please come! We'll have panels and
signings and be around. We can hang out, swap
stories, and be general nerds.
LAURA: Are you leaving from here to there?
MATT: I'm leaving from here to home, to pack, and
then leaving.
LAURA: You haven't packed!
MATT: I had to finish campaign prep.
LAURA: Oh no, Matthew.
MATT: It's a sprint every day! It'll be fine.
Laura, you had an announcement.
LAURA: Yes, I do! Oh my gosh, you guys,
merchandise! Number one, the tarot cards, which a
lot of people have been asking about, are back in
stock right now in the Geek & Sundry store. Number
two and three, check out these fabulous, fabulous
T-shirts!
SAM: These are new T-shirts!
LAURA: Look at this, our throwback shirt! And we
redid our logo shirt in new sophisticated--
TALIESIN: Darkest timeline Critical Role. Critical
Role darkest timeline.
LAURA: If you're looking for them, they're not in
the store now. We wanted to announce them--
SAM: Wait, they're not?
LAURA: I know. They're going to be available next
Thursday. We're announcing them right now so that
those of you that don't see this live--
MARISHA: People on YouTube always get mad at us.
TALIESIN: This is a little love to YouTube. Now
you've got four days to figure your stuff out.
TRAVIS: Think about the Europes and the other
places that are asleeps.
MARISHA: Those people you just addressed.
LAURA: They're going to be there on Thursday next
week.
MATT: Awesome. Thank you, Laura.
LAURA: Thanks, everybody, for talking over my
fucking announcement.
TRAVIS: Hey, it's okay, baby. It's okay.
MATT: You got this, Travis. This is all you.
TRAVIS: I know.
MARISHA: Pregnant rage.
LIAM: You son of a bitch!
TRAVIS: (pretend cries) You want some pickle
juice?
MATT: Last but not least, we have a cool
announcement for an upcoming event. For those of
you who are in, around, or planning to visit
Chicago in April for C2E2, I think pretty much the
whole cast, aside from Ashley who will be filming,
will all be there for Critical Role panels,
signing events, all that fun stuff. In Chicago,
April 7th on Saturday and April 8th on Sunday,
we'll be there to party in Chicago.
TRAVIS: Panels and autographs. We loved the
critters that came out to Seattle. Chicago, it's
time to represent.
SAM: I want to taste some bratwurst.
MATT: That can be done.
SAM: Some beers. I want some Chicago-style pizza.
MATT: Bring all those for Sam at the signing.
LAURA: By the way, this isn't an announcement, but
I think it's important, that I only chose from
dice that were given to me in Seattle for my dice
that I was rolling tonight.
TALIESIN: I may have picked from the remains,
carrion-like, as well.
LIAM: I would like to announce a small amount of
progress for Laura Bailey, who resisted the urge
to keep a super cool d20 for herself, which she
wanted to do. She gave it to me.
LAURA: I was ordered to, so yes.
LIAM: Hopefully it stays in my bag.
LAURA: Maybe.
MARISHA: I have one final announcement.
MATT: Okay.
MARISHA: Key Question just came out on Tuesday!
It's a show that Key and I created. We talk about
Deadpool-- Matt Key! Watch Alpha! For those who
want to watch it and don't want to pay for Alpha,
you can get a free 60 days with the promo code
"question." There were a ton of people who
responded to my tweet with the promo code in it
saying, "Yeah, but I don't want to have to pay for
Alpha." You need to read further down the tweet.
I'm telling you now! Promo code Alpha-- no. Promo
code for Alpha: Question. 60 days. Go watch shit.
TRAVIS: Roll a d20 real quick, just for that.
MARISHA: Not bad, I did okay.
MATT: The full schedule will be announced for us
at C2E2 early next week. You can buy tickets at
c2e2.com, and tomorrow is the deadline to order
badges to receive them by mail, so any badge
orders after that will have to be held at will
call. Just a heads up! I think that's the last of
our announcements. With that, let's jump in to
tonight's episode of Critical Role!
[click, TV static]
[groovy Critical Role theme]
MATT: Welcome back.
(laughing)
MATT: Welcome back. Last we left off, the newly
decided-upon title for this adventuring group was
announced to Bryce, and as such you are now
referred to as the Mighty Nein.
ALL: Nein!
MATT: The Mighty No, in Zemnian.
TRAVIS and TALIESIN: Big nope.
MATT: Upon finishing your business in Alfield, you
acquired your new cart, new horses, and found your
way on the Amber Road northward for a number of
days, making your way toward Zadash. Along the
way, you had some curious naps, you found some
cool little landmarks from a war long past, you
were nearly robbed and instead shooed them off
with cries of extreme syphilis, and then entered
the gates of Zadash yourselves. Upon which, you
briefly met a character named Ulysses, who
offered, at a bit of cost, to show you around town
for the remainder of the day. Unfortunately, the
sun set within the next couple of hours, but you
were led toward the Pentamarket, where you did a
little bit of shopping, offloaded some things
you'd acquired in your previous venture in the
mines where you battled the gnolls, encountered a
purveyor of various magical artifacts named
Enchanter Pumat Sol, acquired some baked goods
from the market, and then finished up by making
your way to The Leaky Tap, where you had just
begun to cross the threshold when we left off last
week. With that, coming in out of the now-cold
night air, mouths filled with various crumbs and
residue of sweets having been consumed on the
walk, you enter the darkened interior of The Leaky
Tap. Now, The Leaky Tap itself is a simple, but
very large tavern. You can see there's space here
for at least a dozen tables, and chairs and stools
crowded around. While it lacks decor, it seems to
have charm, with a rather ratty-looking band in
the corner that's playing mostly on-key. It
appears that a number of people who have found
their way-- this is the Eastern Outersteads, I
believe-- have wandered in to spend whatever
coppers they want to throw towards a drink to send
their cares away for the evening, and/or argue
with each other about how better to make the day
before them. Upon stepping into the chamber, you
can see there's already about 25 patrons scattered
amongst the tables, and the evening appears to be
slowly crawling to more of a roar. There's chatter
and whispers, there's laughter and the clanks of
metal and glass. You can see already there's one
long bar on the far end of the room that is broken
in the center for a number of entryway hatches,
and two busied bartenders rushing back and forth.
What do you guys want to do?
SAM: I, Sam Riegel, want to go back and see Pumat
Sol again. But that would not make narrative
sense.
MATT: There's always tomorrow.
MARISHA: Can I do a quick case of the room? See if
I see anybody suspicious?
TRAVIS: Give them the old evil eye?
MATT: Make a perception check.
TRAVIS: Come on, first roll of the night.
MARISHA: Perception check. Okay, that's not too
bad. 15.
MATT: 15, okay. Glancing about, most of the
patrons in here range from somewhat dusty,
destitute clothing that looks to be torn and
ragged at the edges. Some can be farm hands, but
most of the farm work you've seen is done on the
outskirts of the outer walls of Zadash, but you've
also walked through folks in the street that sit
on the side peddling handcrafted wares and
whatever they can muster to try and make ends meet
on the outskirts of the city proper. You notice
two fairly dressed individuals compared to the
rest that are in the process of doing a quick game
of cards. You can see a large group of people that
are just beginning to gather and keeping an eye
out towards the door if anybody else they
recognize is going to come in. Looks to be about
eight or so strong, with younger half-elf woman or
so who, as you guys enter, sees you, glances over,
then shakes her head and goes back to
conversation.
SAM: Bachelorette party.
MATT: Oh, straight up. You can see the whole
banner on the--
MARISHA: Penis necklaces.
TRAVIS: Dick whistle. Yeah.
LIAM: Except this is D&D so they're real penises.
MARISHA: Gnoll penises, yeah.
MATT: Cast Identify on that.
LIAM: Ten gold a head.
MATT: The attunement process is a little weird.
Anyway.
LIAM: I'm at a bar, that's the way it goes.
MATT: You do see one of the barkeeps leaves behind
and gives a finger off to the other one to pick up
the slack. The one leaving looks to be an elven
woman, what would look to be the equivalent of a
human 40s or so, so who knows how long her actual
elven age is. Looks graceful, looking a bit
disheveled, hair pulled back and tied into a small
haphazard bun, simple apron, washing up her hands
and toweling them off as she passes off the full
bar to a male dragonborn. White-scaled, plump
physique, he himself is wearing a similar apron
with a big smile on his face. He seems jolly,
rushing back and forth taking orders, filling
drinks, and looks like even though he's a bit
stressed at the moment, having to take the slack,
is handling it with a smile and is used to the
usual evening ruckus.
MARISHA: And so the two, the dragonborn and the
female elven lady seem to be running the joint.
MATT: They seem to be, yeah.
MARISHA: Copy that.
TRAVIS: I figure we want some drinks and food,
yeah?
LAURA: And also we should rent some rooms.
MARISHA: Hey, Jester, it looks like there's a game
of cards going on over there.
LAURA: Oh, okay, I will--
MARISHA: Just tossing it out there.
LAURA: I will do that.
MARISHA: You don't have to take my--
TRAVIS: Or you could eat first; we've been
traveling--
LAURA: I'm gone.
LIAM: I saw that you were eyeballing the room.
Alles gut?
MARISHA: What?
LIAM: Everything is good?
MARISHA: Yeah, it's fine. Yeah. Seems like a room.
People in it.
LIAM: That is accurate.
MARISHA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Sir, can I bother you for a second?
MATT: At that point, and hand comes up and he
goes, "Excuse me, just a moment." Fills up two
tankards on the side, slides them down a bit,
grabs a couple silver, pockets it, comes back.
TRAVIS: He's busy.
MATT: Turns back to you, and maybe a good solid
inch or two taller than you, a burly-looking
dragonborn--
TRAVIS: (whistles)
LAURA: He's not that tall. You're not Grog
anymore.
TRAVIS: Who's that?
MATT: With a dangerous-looking front of the snout,
that as soon as it spins to you and he looks at
you with this big, toothy grin, you can see scars
in areas where it's been split in the past. This
guy's seen some rough action in his past. But as
soon as the large dragon mouth curls up into this
smile, the golden yellow eyes peeking from behind
these stark white scales, themselves look a bit
dusty--
LIAM: White scales?
MATT: Yes. "Right, so what can I do for you?"
TRAVIS: Yeah, can we just grab any booth or table
that's available? We're looking for some food and
drink this evening.
MATT: "Oh food and drink, I can go ahead and get
started, at least get the order in the kitchen.
Pick a table, sit a spell, rack up. You paying up
front, or you like a tab?"
TRAVIS: I think a tab. Yeah?
TALIESIN: A tab with a conversation of possible
rooms for rent later.
MATT: "Oh. How many rooms you looking? (louder)
I'll be right with you, hold your shit! Yes?"
MARISHA: How many rooms you got?
MATT: Looks under the counter real fast. Pulls out
a small board.
TRAVIS: Three rooms.
MATT: "Oh, we got plenty, we've got like seven of
them open. Three rooms, and a tab under the
name--"
SAM and TALIESIN: Nein.
TALIESIN: Nein.
SAM: Just Nein.
TALIESIN: Nein will do.
MATT: "There's six of you."
TALIESIN: N-I-E-N, Nein.
MATT: "Oh, Zemnian. Fucking weird. All right."
LIAM: It is one of the languages of the country.
SAM: It's a lovely language.
MARISHA: What was your name?
MATT: "Me? I'm Wessek the Trim."
MARISHA: Wessek the Trim.
LIAM: Good name.
SAM: We have the same middle name!
MATT: "Purveyor of the bar here--"
TALIESIN: Is he, in fact, trim?
MATT: No, he is a plump dragonborn.
TALIESIN: Just checking if it was an ironic
nickname or not.
MATT: He has lived a happy midlife. "I'm purveyor
of drinks and keeper of food here at the Leaky
Tap. Happy to get your food orders in, get some
drinks to your table. Sit back, relax. There's
usually a show at some point in the night."
LAURA: I'm hopping over to the card game.
SAM: I'm going to tag along beside her. Hey, do I
see any other goblins in this bar?
MATT: Make a perception check.
SAM: Two.
MATT: No. In fact, from your height, just a lot of
bums.
LAURA: A lot of butts.
MATT: A whole lot of butts in there.
SAM: I'm going to assume that I'm okay then.
TRAVIS: Any other half-orcs in this bar?
MATT: You do not see any half-orcs in this bar. As
you go over to the table, the two gentlemen who
are playing cards, you sit down and glance. One of
them looks to be an older man in his 50s or so,
his pattern baldness curling back, but has this
curled mush of brown, now graying, hair on the
outskirts of it. He's wearing a billowing shirt of
a nicer silk. That's why it caught your eye. These
two seem, not extremely well-off by any means, but
at least better than a lot of the other riff-raff
that are finding their way in, including you
guys.
LAURA: My dress is nice, I don't know what you're
talking about.
MATT: Your dress is pretty nice, you're right.
That's true. The other one is in the process of
heavily concentrating on his hand. This one looks
a lot younger. He has this scraggly mustache. It
looks like he's probably been growing it since
childhood, and has let it go in its glory. He has
a button-up high collar bit and a cravat that has
loosened and fallen. Both of these gentlemen, upon
a closer look, look like they're dressing up
beyond their station, and at the end of the night
have come to alleviate their stresses with drink
and yelling at each other over cards.
LAURA: Hop, hop. I sit down.
MATT: "Yes?"
LAURA: What are we playing? Are we playing Go
Fish, or War, or--
MATT: They both stop mid-conversation and glance
over. "We're playing whatever suits us at the
moment. We're in the midst-- "
LAURA: What is suiting you right now?
MATT: "Well, we are in the moment finishing a
quick game of poker. If you would be so kind as to
leave us to our game in peace, that would be
appreciated."
LAURA: I will play with you! I'm not very good, so
you can take so much money from me.
MARISHA: Yes! Grift it, girl!
MATT: Make a deception check.
TALIESIN: I am watching this from the table. This
is the show.
LAURA: 17.
MATT: 17. The younger one, who was talking to you,
glances over to the older gentleman, who's in the
process of glancing back, and they take a moment
and they both look back to you together. "I
suppose, if you want to buy in, then that is your
choice."
LAURA: You can finish your game though, I'll just
watch.
MATT: They wordlessly continue the game. They
begin arguing over the process of rising prices
between irons coming down from the Druvenlode
city, which is one of the larger mining cities in
the empire. They begin to also discuss the quality
of alcohol, seems to be diminishing the more they
drink. Eventually, with one final hand, the
younger one slaps down his cards, and the older
one in frustration goes, "Fine! You win."
LAURA: I applaud the younger guy. What do you want
to play, Nott? Do you want to play?
SAM: I'll just watch for now. Do you want me go
get you a drink and bring it back, or are you
okay?
LAURA: No, unless you want to get some milk.
SAM: I'll just watch for now.
LAURA: Okay. What is the buy-in?
MATT: "What do you wish to play?"
LAURA: What do you wish to play?
MATT: For the sake of ease of the sudden card
game, he looks around at the other guy. "Do you
know the Crick-Queen's Call?"
LAURA: I do! I love it, this is the one I was
telling you about!
SAM: You were?
LAURA: Yeah, remember, with the three cards?
SAM: Oh, yes, I remember.
LAURA: Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
MATT: "Very well, then." He goes to shuffle the
cards rather rapidly before he begins dealing out
the early sets.
TALIESIN: Is it a clean shuffle?
MATT: You may make a perception check.
LAURA: I would watch that, too. Are you watching
this?
TALIESIN: Nope, I don't see shit.
LAURA: I would be watching this, too, because I'm
kind of a--
MATT: Make a perception check.
LIAM: A question. Is there any rafters, or any
high place in the room behind these gentlemen?
MATT: There are rafters, yeah. It's not a very
high peaked ceiling. The actual roofing element of
this, at least, begins about twelve feet up, and
there's a small space before the beams meet the
top.
LIAM: For the moment I scootch Frumpkin down to the
floor and send him off towards behind these
gentlemen to hang around under that spot, for the
moment.
MATT: All right.
LAURA: 22 perception.
MATT: It seems to be a clean shuffle, and a clean
deal.
LAURA: Do we put two gold in, or some silver?
MATT: Both the guys look at each other again,
their eyes a little wide. "Two gold would suffice,
yes. Of course."
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: He strokes his way-too-soft mustache.
TRAVIS: Not-all-there mustache.
LIAM: Nott, I think you're too young to be
watching this. You should come sit with me over
here.
SAM: It's very fascinating, though.
LIAM: No, it's a bad idea. You're too little for
gambling.
LAURA: You're not too little, Nott, you're not.
SAM: She doesn't think I am, but if Caleb says so,
then I should go with Caleb. Good luck!
LIAM: Use your skill.
LAURA: Okay!
MARISHA: I'm confused. Is she actually that young,
or is that part of the game?
LIAM: Come, let us go sit over here.
MARISHA: Is that part of the scam?
LIAM: I walked away from this one.
MATT: Two gold on the table from each of you, so
that's six gold in the full pot. Go ahead and make
your roll, 3d6.
SAM: Ooh. What do you do, take the best two? What
do you do?
LAURA: No, no, no.
MATT: Everyone rolls, and then you can raise your
ante.
LAURA: Wait. I'm going to try to use one of my own
cards and try to replace one of the cards.
MATT: Make a sleight of hand check.
LIAM: Frumpkin climbs up into the rafters with a
view of the gentleman's cards.
LAURA: 19.
MATT: 19? Okay.
TALIESIN: Can I try to perceive this too?
MATT: Sure, make a perception check.
TALIESIN: 18.
MATT: No, you do not. They all look at their
hands. The younger one with the mustache keeps
stroking the front of his face and goes, "I'll
raise four." You don't roll yet. You have to raise
first.
LAURA: I thought I was trying to cheat and replace
one of my things.
MATT: Oh, you were. Yes, you're right.
LAURA: Do I get to choose what it is, or do I roll
again?
MATT: You just roll again.
LAURA: Okay. I rolled it. It was shit. Okay.
MATT: He goes, "Raising an additional two gold
pieces."
LIAM: I would like to start looking at their cards
through Frumpkin's eyes.
LAURA: I'm definitely raising two. From your two,
I'm going to add in another three. So five extra
on the table.
LIAM: (quietly) Get ready to use your wire.
SAM: Okay. I'm pulling out my thin bit of wire and
I'm getting ready to cast Message.
TRAVIS: We just can't have a fucking peaceful
drink, can we? Just got to get right into shit.
Okay.
MATT: I know. All right. They meet your raise.
That's now 21 gold, I believe, on the table, so
you all get to draw another card. So reroll one more.
The older one--
SAM: Folds?
MATT: No, he stays.
LAURA: Okay. The younger one?
MATT: Perception check.
LIAM: Yeah. That's a 21.
MATT: 21. Yeah, you can see.
LAURA: I'll cover my ears so I don't know.
SAM: You're about to know when I whisper it to
you.
LAURA: Oh, okay. Never mind.
MATT: The younger one has a crap hand. He's trying
to bluff and he's already sweating a bit. The
older one is looking really good.
LIAM: Okay. Tell our friend that Mr. Mustache is
sitting pretty and the young boy has Scheiße.
MATT: Well, the mustache is the younger one. The
older one is--
LIAM: Reverse that order please. Also, I would
like the curly fries.
SAM: I point to her and whisper in my bit of
copper wire and do a little hand gesture, and say
all of that to her. The young one's bluffing! The
old one's got a sick hand! He's going to burn you!
Burn you good!
LAURA: Hmm. I'm going to sleight of hand and try
and replace one of my cards.
TRAVIS: Jesus! In one game?
MATT: All right, so go attempt it again. Go and
roll a deception-- or sorry sleight of hand.
LAURA: Oh god.
MATT: You guys are so honed in on this!
LAURA: Oh, 16?
TRAVIS: Oh no.
MATT: The young guy is sweating a bit and he gets
more nervous. He just continues to stroke his
little caterpillar mustache, quicker and smaller
bits. The older guy who seems to be playing rather
spacey the whole time suddenly zooms in on your
hands and goes, "I do say, I think we're being
had."
LAURA: What, by who?
MATT: He leans forward and pulls one of the cards
that you had slipped into your sleeve, out onto
the table.
LAURA: Oh, that's weird where did that come from?
I shouldn't wear such loose sleeves, you guys.
That was really obvious.
MATT: The old guy stands up and leans forward. You
can see he has this bloodshot corners, a little
bit where the white show for deep brown irises.
The smell of alcohol and dirt wafts off of him as
he leans forward. "I will not report you for
cheating, but we will taking the rest of the pot."
LAURA: Wait, cheating? What are you talking
about?
MATT: He just takes the coins and scoops them up.
LAURA: Wait, I thought that was part of the game.
Is it not?
MATT: They get up and leave.
LAURA: Motherfuckers, they took my money.
SAM: Did you win?
LAURA: Yes Nott, I won real good.
SAM: I knew you would.
LAURA: I only lost seven gold. That was a lot of
fun, you guys. That was a good trick with the
messages!
SAM: It didn't seem to help very much, though.
LAURA: No, but it would have if I had succeeded in
these-- gosh I really need to get tighter sleeves,
though.
LIAM: Yeah, but that one had potential.
LAURA: Molly, you have to teach me how to do that
better, okay?
TRAVIS: She wants to play again, right now.
LAURA: What?
TRAVIS: What? I said you want to play again, don't
you?
LAURA: (laughing) So bad.
TRAVIS: Yeah Laura's dying on the inside.
LAURA: (yells)
SAM: Should we follow them outside and kill them?
LAURA: Ooh. No, probably not.
TALIESIN: That doesn't seem very nice.
LIAM: Why don't instead we have something to drink
and eat.
TRAVIS: I agree with you 100%.
LAURA: You know what else we should do?
TALIESIN: Follow them outside and rob them?
TRAVIS: Molly, come on now.
TALIESIN: Sorry.
LAURA: Did we get rooms?
TALIESIN: We did get rooms.
LAURA: Yay. Are we roommates?
MARISHA: Roomies!
MATT: Dinner arrives, drinks have been provided.
You guys are able to use your meal and figure out
who you want to talk to, what you want to do, your
business.
LAURA: We should look for Claudia.
SAM: We were told that there was Claudia Sheet
here.
LAURA: Sheed.
SAM: Sheed. Sheedy. Ally Sheedy is here.
MARISHA: Oh I love her.
TRAVIS: Sheed or Sheen?
MATT: Sheed.
SAM: Charlie Sheen.
LIAM: Only I get to say Schiet, you have to say
Sheed.
SAM: She's probably the elven woman working at the
bar since we were told she works here, right?
TALIESIN: Claudia Sheed?
LAURA: Yeah.
TALIESIN: Claudia Sheed.
LAURA: Let's ask about--
TALIESIN: (yelling) Claudia Sheed!
TRAVIS: Yeah, go get her, Molly.
MATT: As you're shouting this out, some people
start looking over, curious as this very
ostentatiously dressed tiefling starts shouting
essentially the owner of the tavern out in the
center of the tavern. No one seems to make any
physical action towards it. However, Wessek points
over towards you. "Oh, she took some time off.
She's up in her office, sorry."
TALIESIN: Brilliant, thank you.
TRAVIS: That was very effective.
TALIESIN: I normally find shouting people's names
really loudly tends to bring them to your table.
TRAVIS: Right. I wonder where her office is.
LAURA: We could ask.
TALIESIN: We could look. Have we had food and
drink yet?
MATT: Yeah, you guys have eaten. And now you're in
the process-- you don't have to roleplay every meal.
(various eating noises)
TRAVIS: Nott has to roleplay every meal.
LIAM: What time of the evening do I know it to
be?
MATT: At this point, it's probably pushing close
to ten o'clock.
LIAM: Ja, okay.
MATT: The sun's been set for a couple hours.
LIAM: Yeah, that's late. It's not that late.
TRAVIS: Anybody feel like going up and giving ole
Claudia a door rap, at her office?
LIAM: I thought you were going somewhere else, for
a second.
TRAVIS: No.
TALIESIN: I'm interested either way. So I'm going
to stand up and start heading upstairs.
MARISHA: Yeah, I'm bored. Let's go.
TALIESIN: Come, Unpleasant One, let's go.
MARISHA: All right. Obnoxious One, I'm with you.
MATT: There's a brief spiral staircase towards the
far back that leads to a landing and then the
second floor. From the outside, you could see
there were three floors to it. So this probably
progresses-- there's another staircase further
down the hallway. From the landing up there,
there's a single doorway that is currently closed.
It has no name on it, but it stands alone from the
rest of it, and it seems to be in the direction as
to where Wessek was pointing.
TALIESIN: I'm going to look for what looks like an
office. For whatever door seems most inconvenient.
MATT: At a quick glance, the one on the landing.
TALIESIN: The one on the landing it is.
TALIESIN and MARISHA: (click and knock the same
pattern)
SAM: What the fuck was that?
TRAVIS: Wow, y'all.
MATT: We've been hanging out far too long. This is
a problem. There's a moment. "Yes, who is it?"
TALIESIN: Friends from out of town.
MATT: "More information, please."
TALIESIN: Bryce sent us.
MATT: "Bryce who?"
LAURA: Bryce from Alfield.
SAM: You're not there.
LAURA: Yes, I am. We went up there, I thought.
MARISHA: Crownsguard Bryce.
TALIESIN: From Alfield.
MATT: "All right, just a moment, please." About 30
or so seconds pass and the door opens, and the same
elven woman you saw leave from behind the bar
earlier. However, the disheveled appearance you saw
earlier is gone, is pristine, clean and the hair
is immaculately combed and pulled up into a high
bun, wearing a deep maroon, almost a silk robe
that is pulled over, arms across.
LAURA: I was desanitizing him.
MATT: Oh, fair enough. "So you are friends of
Bryce."
TALIESIN: We have come from very far to take a look--
MARISHA: Converse.
TALIESIN: Converse.
MARISHA: Right?
MATT: "Well, they are a very good friend. And if
you are friends of them, then you are friends of
"mine. I ask you to enter for the time being and
perhaps we can get to know each other, I suppose,
"if you have business. Enter, please." She turns and
whips around and heads back inside. This office is
a simple office. When you consider most of the
offices you've encountered have been in some level of
empire clerical work, and/or in various
institutions, this is mainly just a desk with a
chair, some books and ledger information, some
scattered papers, ink and quill, a few books on
the side. Other than that, it's pretty barren and
simple. There is a window in the back that has a
crossbeam bisecting it into four squares. It is just
pitch black outside 'cause the rest of it is just
an alley below. Anyway, she turns around and sits
in the chair and comes back, and crosses her hands
in front of her with her elbows on the edge of the
table. "All right, you have my attention. What can
"I do for you?"
TALIESIN: Well, to wrap it up a bit, we've just
recently got into town. We're looking for
employment, odd jobs. We were recommended to you
to be the person to talk to about what actually is
going on in this city. We're new to this city, we
don't necessarily have our thumb on the pulse of
what's going on.
MATT: "You are here looking for work? Well, for
one, if you are in need of paying work, I always
"have dishes to wash. But at a quick glance at how
you are presented as a little more capable
"individuals at first glance, I would say that
perhaps you have other skills. So I would--"
MARISHA: I do the dude at a bar thing and push up
my biceps.
TRAVIS: It works.
MATT: "If you are better with a blade or
information, then checking at the King's Hall Board
"might be a solid bet for you."
TALIESIN: We just figured we would make sure that
you were aware we were here. We don't want to
ruffle any feathers and we don't necessarily know
who are the right people, the wrong people to work for.
MATT: "Every person you meet is the right and the
wrong person, depending on where you are coming from."
TALIESIN: That's very fair.
MATT: "I guess I would ask what for you is the
wrong type of people?"
LAURA: Shitty people.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we'd like to avoid entanglements
with the law, being so new and all.
MATT: "Right, then perhaps do not punch any
crownsguard and I think you'll be okay."
TALIESIN: Sounds easy, except it's really not.
MARISHA: It does seem like crownsguard tend to be
assholes.
TALISIN: Deeply punchable.
MARISHA: Have you ever had any issues with the
Crownsguard? We've heard rumors.
MATT: "I mean, individuals, yes." There's a brief
moment where she looks wistfully into the
distance. "I've had my encounters, not so much
with Crownsguard, but with other figures."
MARISHA: Do we need to kick someone's ass for
you?
MATT: "Oh, I've already made sure their ass has
been thoroughly kicked."
TRAVIS: Maybe it might be wise to ask
any particular groups to avoid while we're here.
MATT: She crosses her arms for a second.
"Interesting point. Where are you from? Have you
"always lived in the empire?"
LAURA: No, I'm from-- you're from Port Damali.
I'm from Nicodranas.
MATT: "From the Menagerie Coast. You are in for a
treat of comparably colorful times. But a probably
"less jovial atmosphere in places. You know about
the religious control, correct?"
TRAVIS: We're slightly aware.
LAURA: Wait, what?
TRAVIS: Well, they frown--
TALIESIN: Grace of the Platinum Dragon.
MATT: "There are-- for well over a century now, the
worship of various deities in the empire has been
"controlled. There are shrines throughout the city.
Most cities contain a shrine of some kind to the
"approved worships. I just want to ensure that, if
you do not fall into this realm, you do not go
"flashing it about, because that will get you very
easily put into the Umber Dungeon and that is not
"a place you want to be."
LAURA: Where are these shrines that you are
talking about?
MATT: "They are scattered about. For instance,
there is the Allhammer. Their shrine is-- let me
"think for a second," as I consult my notes.
TRAVIS: Yeah, getting the good shit right now.
MARISHA: The Umber Dungeon?
MATT: The Umber Dungeon. "There is the Hearth of
the Allhammer that is existing in the Pentamarket."
LAURA: Ooh, we were just there!
MATT: "Look for the domed iron structure. It may
be a bit rusty, not in the best upkeep. It's hard
"to miss the interior with the very heavy,
beautiful anvil, for both craftwork of those that
"maintain a position. What else do you want
to know about it? There is the Raven's Den, which
is in the center of the graveyard."
LAURA: That sounds good, too.
MATT: "The Ossuary Gates is the multilayered
catacomb graveyard. The Raven's Den exists in the
"center area of that field."
LAURA: Do the shrines usually have a lot of people
in them?
MATT: "Midday, and depending on which places of
worship they are, yes. But there are Heralds that
"run each shrine; they work for the empire. They
hold all sermons. They give council to anybody who
"requires it. It's all pretty much within the
government structure, yes."
TRAVIS: Are there any particular groups of people
that are responsible for unsavory business in the
city? Any identifying clothing or memorabilia they
might have on them?
MATT: "Not visibly, no. There are many people that
work underneath the law here, but they are careful
"enough, if they wish to continue business, to not
show it. I mean, what, are you looking for that
"kind of work?'
TRAVIS: No, just perhaps to keep an eye out for in
case we sought employment from the wrong type.
MARISHA: You know, tourists. We have that tourist
look.
TALIESIN: Speaking of tourist looks, how much of a
problem would this be in general?
MATT: "You should be fine. It's-- you should be
fine."
TALIESIN: Excellent.
MATT: "For the most part, those of various unique
heritages have harder times at the farther
"eastern areas, around the garrisons. Those that
have to keep the creatures of Xhorhas at bay, and
"possibly historians that believe that this is the
Curse of Ghor Dranas, but you know. For the most
"part, most nobody studies history and just consider
you either unique-looking or will avoid you regardless."
MARISHA: Wait, no one studies history, really? Do
you not have a good public school system or
something? I was just curious.
MAT: "Well, if you want to go study history--" that
would be over here. "In the Interstead Sprawl, we
"do have the Apple Tree Tutor Village. That is
three long buildings owned and provided by the
"Soltryce Academy for basic learning to children
and adults of the less affluent lifestyle for a
"moderate price."
MARISHA: Like private school?
MATT: If you're looking for a comparison here, it
would be upper-end public school, if anything.
LIAM: Charter school?
MARISHA: Magnet programs?
MATT: Sure, we'll put it at a charter school.
LIAM: Lotteries are a bitch!
MATT: But controlled by the Soltryce Academy.
MARISHA: All controlled by the Soltryce.
MATT: Yes. "The head tutor there is an overworked
and relatively stressed-out individual."
TRAVIS: Head tutor, you said?
MATT: "Yes. Mikael Drom. Very nice fellow. Eager
to help, but the system has been difficult for him."
TALIESIN: Is there a shrine to the Dragon, as
well?
MATT: "There is. There is a Platinum House. That
would also be in the Interstead Sprawl. Look for
"the beautiful white building with deep blue
tapestries on the outside. They're reflective,
"mirror-like, during the day. It's almost a beacon
for having to shield your eyes. Meditation,
"worship, is all available within there. Sermon's
usually around noon."
MARISHA: You mentioned all the sanctioned shrines.
Are there any unsanctioned shrines?
MATT: "Anything that isn't the Platinum Dragon,
the Raven Queen, Allhammer, Dawnfather, Lawbearer,
"and the Knowing Mistress."
MARISHA: So six, that's it?
MATT: "There are six."
MARISHA: Six approved gods.
LAURA: All of those guys. Of course we knew about
those guys.
TRAVIS: Jester, now, that doesn't seem to cover
who you're looking for, though.
LAURA: Oh, well, you know--
MATT: "I don't judge. If you worship what you want,
you can, just be careful about it."
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: "Don't tell anyone."
TALIESIN: Ixnay on the angers-stray.
LAURA: Okay! I won't tell anyone.
MATT: "Very well."
SAM: She's going to tell everyone.
MATT: "That's going to help you. Anything else you
want to know? I've been living here most of my life."
TRAVIS: Job postings. Anywhere we might go to--
LAURA: Well, we have the King's Hall board, yo.
That's where the job postings are.
MATT: "King's Hall is a good resource. If you're
really hit up hard and you want to try the route
"that Bryce did, you can always sign up to become a
member of the military."
TALIESIN: Eh.
LAURA: Go fuck yourself! No!
MATT: "It works well for some people. It pays, you
are trained. The Righteous Brand is very helpful
"and helps keep the Empire safe from the terrors
that wander in and beyond the borders."
TALIESIN: We're also always big fans of
underbellies, especially if there's an underbelly
with a heart of gold.
LAURA: Especially one if it's furry and you can
pet it.
MATT: "There are plenty of underbellies, but they
are localized, scattered, and very protective.
"Keep your ears open, ask the right questions."
TALIESIN: Are there names that, if we hear, we
should trust?
MATT: "I don't trust anybody. That's how I'm still
alive and that's how I came to own this tavern."
MARISHA: Great corner office, by the way. You have
a window!
MATT: "Thank you."
MARISHA: That's great.
MATT: "I had to change it a bit. The man I took it
all from, I wanted him to leave nothing behind."
LAURA: Was he perchance named The Gentleman?
MATT: There's a quick glance in your direction.
Her expression darkens and she goes, "No, but I
"would be very careful how you use that name."
LAURA: Oh, shit.
MARISHA: Really, now?
LAURA: Do you know him?
MATT: "I do not know him, but I know of him. That
thing I said about trying not to get in trouble
"with the darker elements of the city that might be
in over your head? That is very specifically one
"who wallows in that mire."
LAURA: Okay.
MARISHA: He wallows in the underbelly shit? That's
what you said? That's me asking the DM.
MATT: Yes, basically, wallows in the mire of the
underbelly shit. Sounds like a fun lyric.
(singing) Wallows in the mire of the underbelly
shit!
LAURA: That's the second verse.
TRAVIS: Well, thank you for your time. I think
we'll find our way back down to the belly of this tavern.
MATT: "Very well. I will walk you down."
LIAM: Sorry.
MATT: "Yes."
LIAM: I want to touch on something happening--
I'm not there. We're not there.
MATT: Oh, right.
LIAM: So I want to touch on something that's
happening at the same time, but I will wait until
you think it's a good moment.
MATT: Sure. You can do it now while they're
exiting the office. While they've been in there--
LIAM: Yeah. Nott and Caleb didn't go up. They're
busy. Would you like to learn something interesting?
SAM: A magic trick?
LIAM: Sort of.
SAM: Yes!
LIAM: It's a little homework and a little bit
magic trick. This is where I keep my spells. This
is my book. And this is the piece of luck that you
helped me achieve in Trostenwald. Over the months
and years, I gather the amount of magic tricks that
I can do. So in this book, for instance, there is
a new spell that I do not even know how to use
myself where I can make an invisible helper. What
is going to happen now, I bought supplies for it--
I find a booth for us in the corner-- is I am
going to move it from here into here and I thought
you could help me. Would you like to do that?
SAM: Yes!
LIAM: Okay. So you can see--
SAM: Photocopying!
TRAVIS: Xerox!
LIAM: I don't know what that means, but this will
take a little while. Here, hold this. I hand a
quill to her. Hold that. You can see the markings
on this page. It's intricate, but you can do the
first few strokes. It needs to look like that, it
needs to go here. I guide her hand a little bit to
make sure that it doesn't smudge too much. It's
still workable. Good. Now I will fill in the
details. I spend the next-- they are probably gone
for 15 minutes-- putting down the glyphs and
the markings.
SAM: It's delightful!
LIAM: And begin the first 30 minutes of the two
hours I need to spend copying this.
SAM: Too much. I'll need to be plied with many
drinks.
LIAM: Oh, yeah. Sliding them over.
SAM: How's my penmanship?
MATT: So far, so good. We'll see how it
progresses. As you guys exit the office, at the
bottom of the stair, you can see that group that
was gathering earlier, with the young girl that was
looking out towards the entryway, is there waiting
at the base of the stair.
MARISHA: The bachelorette party?
MATT: Yeah, the bachelorette party, if
you will.
Though it was a mixed group. As soon as
you exit with Claudia, they notice her, notice
you, and all step back for a moment and wait. As
you step down the stairs, a young half-elf girl,
freckled, auburn hair, a smudged face of a hard
day's work, leans forward and goes, "Terribly
"sorry, Claudia. Are we good to use the cellar for
the meeting?" "Yes, of course. It is available to
"you right now. Not a problem." She goes, "All
right, thank you very much." She turns around and
begins gathering up the crew. You can see a few
people at the bar, she's slowly gathering the folk
until there's a cluster of about 20 or so. They
all begin making their way towards where the
kitchen is into a pantry area.
LAURA: Are they going to have an orgy?
MATT: You're going to have to follow to find out.
LAURA: I'm asking that of Claudia.
MATT: Oh.
SAM: Out loud.
MATT: She goes, "No, not so much. They are
passionate political debaters."
LAURA: Oh.
MARISHA: Are you helping run some underground
clubs?
TRAVIS: Just right out in the open, huh?
MARISHA: In your cellar?
MATT: "No, I am merely providing a space for
people that are wanting to work through some
"difficulties they have with their lifestyle. That
is all."
LAURA: I'm running to find Caleb.
LIAM: It's like latticework, you have to do the
smaller circle inside the larger.
SAM: You have to do this with every spell?
LIAM: Each one's a little bit different.
TALIESIN: (whispering) Caleb!
SAM: We're busy here!
LIAM: We're really right in the middle of
something.
TALIESIN: That's all right, we just need your
cat.
MARISHA: I trail with Fjord! I want to know.
TRAVIS: As we're heading down, I lean over to
Beau.
LIAM: Frumpkin climbs up Molly's back.
TALIESIN: I'm tossing Frumpkin in the direction of
that.
LIAM: What are you doing with my cat?
TALIESIN: In the basement!
LAURA: Oh, you have to look through his eyes.
SAM: You won't be able to see anything!
TRAVIS: The two of us are going.
LIAM: Go to the base-- look, the circle goes
inside the larger circle.
SAM: What is the "a e" that's one letter?
TRAVIS: I lean over to Beau and I say: I don't
know if you're aware of it, but when you
compliment people it sounds like a fucking insult.
Is that intentional?
MARISHA: What?
TRAVIS: It was just an observation. Like
commenting on the office window? You've gotta put
more smile--
MARISHA: Oh, but that was badass! She had a cool
fucking office, I guess.
TRAVIS: It didn't quite sound that way.
MARISHA: Oh, no?
TRAVIS: Yeah. Just something to put in your hat.
LIAM: You know, maybe we pick this up later.
MARISHA: Can I try it with you?
TRAVIS: Yeah, go for it.
SAM: I've just mastered the 'f' that looks like an
's'!
MARISHA: You're really attractive.
TRAVIS: Yeah, so let's start with maybe a little
smile on the face. That's always a good starting
point. Try again.
MARISHA: You're really attractive.
TRAVIS: Oh man, you look constipated.
MARISHA: Is that worse somehow?
TRAVIS: You ever winked at anybody?
MARISHA: You're really attractive.
TRAVIS: We'll keep workshopping it.
MARISHA: No? That still wasn't it? Fuck. Thank
you. At least thanks for telling me. Most people
would just be like, "You're a bitch," and then
would leave.
TRAVIS: I've been around you long enough that I
can tell you were actually trying to be nice.
MARISHA: Thanks, man. I think you're real nice,
too. Genuine! I was being genuine!
MATT: The two of you have wrapped up for the time
being.
LAURA: I just wanted to borrow some parchment. Do
you have any extra pieces of paper, though?
LIAM: How much do you need? For what?
LAURA: I don't know. Like 20 pieces.
SAM: Do you need to write a long letter?
LAURA: A really long one.
LIAM: I'll give you two.
LAURA: I can make do with that, yes. Thank you.
LIAM: I hand them over.
TALIESIN: I need to know what your cat's
seeing. What's the cat seeing?
LIAM: Hold on.
SAM: Okay. I've got you.
LAURA: I've got you, too.
MATT: The cat, who's been following Fjord and
Beauregard, you guys have been having this
conversation as you follow down to the cellar. As
you descend down the cellar stairs, you can hear
conversation and a few voices passing. They all
get quiet. As you step and descend past where the
ceiling of the basement reveals you, the group of
20 folks are all gathered around with a central
podium on an elevated step or a box. They're all
looking at you, quiet. The one who's standing on
the box is a human man probably in his early 60s
or so. Shorter hair, graying but a little unkempt
in the face. He's got smaller spectacles at the
edge of his nose and unshaved stubble against his
chin, but he's dressed in a nice, white shirt,
tucked in well, and looks thin and well-mannered.
He puts his hand up and goes, "Hey there. Can we
help you?"
LIAM: There's a bunch of people staring at Fjord
and Beauregard. Why are we doing this?
TALIESIN: Oh, for fuck's sake.
TRAVIS: Apologies. We don't mean to intrude. We're
new to this city. We just heard that some higher
thinkers were going to be meeting down here. We
hoped we might be able to join you.
MARISHA: Just looking for good conversation.
TALIESIN: They're making asses of themselves,
aren't they?
MATT: Everyone looks at each other. There's an
ornery dwarf fella who looks over to the guy in
the top and shakes his head. The half-elven girl
who was gathering the group gives a nudge toward
you with a smile and says, "We can at least ask."
He goes, "All right, well, step on up." The crowd
separates a little bit as you guys approach. "I'm
curious. Share with me briefly the joys the Empire
"has brought to your life."
LIAM: I think it's like Alcoholics Anonymous
or something.
MATT: "Be honest."
TRAVIS: I'm afraid my list is not that long,
unfortunately.
MARISHA: We're a bit skeptical. We're looking for
support, just like any other wayward souls in this
crazy town.
TRAVIS: We seek knowledge.
MARISHA: We want to be able to trust our Empire,
but maybe we need some reassurance in one way or another.
MATT: Make a persuasion check with advantage with
his help.
MARISHA: Persuasion with advantage? That's good! I
got a natural 18 with a plus one, so 19. Just
being real vague.
MATT: "You seem to be on the level. We are a group
called the Knights of Requital, and we are
"discussing methods of changing the current
political unhappiness in the city of Zadash and beyond."
MARISHA: See, we're not the only ones. We felt
like something's been missing.
TRAVIS: Tearing at our heart. It's an ache.
MATT: "Very well. I will continue with my talk, if
you don't mind."
TRAVIS and MARISHA: Please, yes.
TRAVIS: Preach on.
LIAM: Does that name mean anything to Caleb?
MATT: No. Looking around the room, most of the
folks in here look to be salt-of-the-earth folk of
the city. A few folks look to be a little more
wealthy, lower-to-middle class if you were to give
any sort of comparison there, and they all look
like they're a bit riled up. The dwarf, who had
eyed you up previously, his eyes have these heavy
bags under them, he's got this scraggly unkempt
brown beard, and very short, almost buzz-cut hair
on top. He's glaring at the two of you. He steps
away from the crowd and keeps a very close eye.
The gentleman at the top, "First off, to our new
"conversationalists, I am Dolan Thrym. As many of
you know her, I once ran a very successful physician
"practice here in the Interstead Sprawl, one that
my partner was the head physician. Well, he was
"unfortunately brought to an unearned level of
shame, and his practice ruined, as well as our
"industry, by the house of Sutan naught but a year ago.
We went from a comfortable living helping people
"to a life of squalor and shame. I know we're not
the only one, as now the son of the house of
"Sutan, Ren, sits at the top of that practice. Took
all of our clients and squeezes them for all of
"their worth. And I, for one, am sick of it".
Everybody else in the group goes (grunt).
MARISHA: (grunts)
MATT: "I'm sick of it and we can't sit back and
let nothing be done about it. Now, would you like
"to take the floor, Ulog?" The dwarf who was
watching you guys takes his-- doesn't leave you
for a moment before he steps over and the crowd
separates and he steps up onto the small block
which at his height puts him about head level with
most of the crowd. "As many of you know, I was a
woodworker for many years, carving wood, did good
carpentry. My wife, Illiana, is a good wife.
About six months ago, she was up late at night
picking up food for the night for the two of
us in the Pentamarket. She was in the wrong place
at the wrong time. There were some street bandits
outside the Tri-Spires. They stabbed someone who
had run in, ran clean into my wife, just as the
Crownsguard descended. She got looped in with
them, thrown in jail. I went and fought. There
wasn't even a bit of a trial. The High-Rictor sent
her straight to the Umber Dungeon, sentenced her
20 years for this business. It's been six months
now, I can't even see her. I'm sick of it, and I
think it's time we did something." Everyone in the
crowd goes (grunts).
TRAVIS and MARISHA: (grunt)
MATT: This continues one after another,
individuals start coming up and talking about
resharing stories for the newcomers. Things that
have come up recently that frustrate them. They
begin throwing things around like instability
within the Starosta's capable hands to maintain a
political structure in a city this large. They
begin to talk on anger and frustration with the
lack of proper education for the masses, keeping
them unable to climb status and eke out of living
and thus are forced into the military to die out
on the fields of Xhorhas. There have been
discussions about frustration dealing with the
ever creeping power scale of what's called the
Cerberus Assembly and influence that stretches
from Rexxentrum into the city itself. Eventually,
it begins to rise into many voices clamoring out
in frustration and once again, Dolan, the softer
gentleman at the beginning puts his hands up and
steps back and goes: "I know, I know. I know.
But we're going to find a way. I have friends that
I've made, people that we're talking to and we
have, hopefully, a new beginning soon, an
opportunity where I think we can have a voice in
the politics here. I hope to have more for you
soon, in the meantime, try and keep your chin up.
I know it's hard now, but I believe we'll have an
opportunity soon. Thank you. Thank you to Kara,
who has been helping set these meetings up."
Points over to the younger half-elf earlier and she nods
and a few hands clap. "And to our new members--
I'm sorry, I didn't get your names."
MARISHA: Beau.
TRAVIS: Fjord.
MATT: "Beau and Fjord, thank you for joining us
tonight. It goes without saying, please, if you
don't mind, we prefer to keep these conversations
personal. For obvious reasons."
MARISHA: Absolutely.
MATT: "If even the most misunderstood discontent
leads to unfortunate circumstances."
TRAVIS: We understand. Thank you for sharing with
us.
MARISHA: I know I, for one, have had my discontent
with the Empire, so it's good to hear we're not alone.
MATT: "Of course. That's requital. I appreciate
your time. Rest well, we'll meet soon. Dismissed!"
Everyone begins to scatter and make their way back
up to the tavern.
TRAVIS: We stay down.
MARISHA: Yeah. I'm going to wait behind. Wait to
talk to Dolan?
TRAVIS: Yeah. Really appreciate what you said.
MARISHA: Yeah, thank you. So much.
MATT: "Yeah, of course. I understand that you
aren't from around here, so don't feel that you
have to take too much of this to heart. Best we
can do to try and keep spirits up. I believe that
we can find a way to exact some change real
soon."
TRAVIS: It struck a chord. It mirrors a lot of
what we've seen since we've been here. Do you meet
very often? I'd love to come back.
MATT: "Well, we're scheduled to meet here in the
next two days or so. We're gearing up for a couple
of important events."
MARISHA: How often are the meetings that heated?
That seemed pretty intense.
TRAVIS: Yeah, personal. Emotional.
MATT: "It can vary. Anyway, I'm sorry. I really
should be going."
MARISHA: Where abouts in town do you live?
MATT: "Oh, I live outside of the Apple Tree
Tutors."
MARISHA: We'll probably be staying here the next
few days.
TRAVIS: Yeah. We'll check in with-- what was her
name?
MARISHA: It's Claudia.
TRAVIS: Yeah. We'll check in with Claudia if
there's any other meetings. Again, appreciate you
being so open.
MATT: "Appreciate you being respectful and close
to your chest. Anyway." He steps past the two of
you, puts the rest of his jacket on, and exits.
Now it's just the two of you there in the cellar below.
TRAVIS: What's in the cellar?
SAM: You going to rob the place there?
TRAVIS: I just want to know. Is it munitions? Is
it meat? Is it booze?
MARISHA: Wine? Is there good wine?
MATT: There are large casks, large wooden barrels
and casks. This is where major ale storage is set,
but none of them are tapped. It looks to be full
of crates that are still sealed; unopened.
MARISHA: Any good wines? That I would recognize?
MATT: None of the wines are kept in this cellar.
MARISHA: Okay.
MATT: By the size of the place, you get the sense
there's probably more than one storage place here.
LIAM: When you scroll your cursor over it, though,
the descriptions are all in red.
MARISHA: Sure. Can't access that.
TRAVIS: Talk about an underbelly. That was more
than I was expecting.
MARISHA: Yeah, and I totally called Claudia on it
too, and she didn't even come forward. I'm like,
you're running some shit! She's running some
shit.
TRAVIS: Right upfront.
MARISHA: Did you notice he said thanks for keeping
things close to your chest? Are we that transparent?
TRAVIS: No. I mean, I would say the same thing if
I was taking such a chance with people I didn't
know, right? I think he's just trying to invest in
us a little.
MARISHA: Right.
TRAVIS: Seemed nice.
LIAM: I tell Frumpkin to yowl between their legs.
MATT: (meowing)
MARISHA: (yells)
TRAVIS: (suppressing a sneeze)
MARISHA: I give Frumpkin the finger, hoping Caleb
will see.
LIAM: I don't see it. I'm not looking through it.
MARISHA: Now I'm just flicking off a cat.
TALIESIN: You gave us the basics, though?
LIAM: Yeah.
TRAVIS: Let's go back up. Fuck it.
LAURA: I was spending my time cutting the
parchment up into even, little rectangles so I
could make them into multiple pieces of paper.
MATT: Easy enough to do.
MARISHA: We go back.
MATT: As you guys head up into the tavern to meet
up with the rest of your troop, you see they're all
sitting around, handling their other business.
What are you guys up to?
TALIESIN: We were listening to the description of
this insanity.
LIAM: I bamfed out of that probably two minutes
before it finished, so I didn't get the tail end,
but I got the meat.
MATT: You got the meat of it. You watched the
people that were in the meeting leave in small
groups. They're pacing their exits.
TRAVIS: Jester, don't believe what you hear. It
was a huge orgy. Just naked parts everywhere.
LAURA: I figured it was and Caleb was lying to us
the whole time.
TRAVIS: I know. Maple syrup. They had little Tic
Tacs and all sorts of chocolate chips. Lollipops galore.
LAURA: Usually, in orgies like that, they don't
let you stay unless (tongue clicking). You're part of it.
LIAM: He's not sticky with maple syrup. He's
lying.
TRAVIS: Tongue bath.
LAURA: Eww. Nice.
SAM: I think what we should do is take the names
and descriptions of all of those people and turn
them in to the authorities for 50 gold a person.
We could make so much money and be heroes in this
town as well! Just like we were in the last!
LIAM: Maybe not that, but quite frankly, those
people are reckless, telling you what they told you.
TRAVIS: Yeah, it is. The only problem with that
would be we were in that meeting at well.
SAM: As spies!
TALIESIN: Except that they told them their real
names. And where they're staying.
LIAM: The authorities don't delineate between the
real McCoy and the passersby. Just like that man's
story. The dwarf.
TALIESIN: Groups of people are always idiots.
Never trust a group of people. I specifically used
to gather people into groups to make them into
idiots. It's just what you do. You don't--
LAURA: So you did that to us!
TALIESIN: That is exactly what I did! It's how I
met you. It's why I keep you around.
MARISHA: You also traveled with a group of
people.
TALIESIN: Yes, but we weren't a group of people.
We all hated each other.
TRAVIS: It's a smaller group.
LAURA: It's a pretty big group. There's nine of
us.
MARISHA: Do you notice how often his logic falls
apart?
TALIESIN: You just told them your real name!
MARISHA: No. I told them I'm Beau.
SAM: You left out the -regard part! And you
mispronounced your name "Ford" when we all know
it's Fjord!
TRAVIS: That's right. Yeah.
SAM: Clever!
MARISHA: Yeah. there's a lot of people named Beau.
Right?
LAURA: Are there? I've only met one other person named
Beau.
TALIESIN: I've literally only met one other person
named Beau.
TRAVIS: It's a good nickname. Beau. Beauregard.
LAURA: I think his name was not the same Beau as
your Beau.
TALIESIN: It was a different Beau.
LAURA: It was a different Beau. I'm going to start
folding my little pieces of paper into little trifolds.
MATT: All righty. What else are you guys doing?
TRAVIS: I think we're probably good to retire.
LIAM: I'm going to turn in. I have a little bit
more homework to do before the end of the night.
Good night. Thank you. Good night.
TALIESIN: I'm eventually falling asleep, but
before that, I'm going to go take a fucking bath.
There is a bathhouse. I'm going there. Anyone who
wants to come with me is welcome to do so.
LAURA: Aww, I want a bath so bad, but it's so
late, Molly!
TALIESIN: It's just a walk!
LAURA: Is it even going to be open at night?
TALIESIN: Is it going to be open at night?
MATT: You can go and try and find out.
TALIESIN: I'm going to go and try and find out.
I'm going to and try and find out!
LAURA: Okay. I have important work to do.
SAM: I'll accompany you, just to make sure you
don't get killed.
LAURA: I'll come with you too because I really
want a bath.
MARISHA: I guess I stay behind with Fjord. We talk
about the crazy shit we just heard.
TRAVIS: Yeah, because we're fucking spies!
MARISHA: Fuck yeah, man! We'll break the system!
Put it in the ground!
LAURA: It's folded like this.
TRAVIS and MARISHA: Fuck the man!
MATT: All righty.
TALIESIN: I'm just happy with my company.
MATT: Right. Now, the two of you make an
investigation check.
TALIESIN: Three.
MATT: That's right. She's coming as well.
LAURA: Oh, that's really bad. It's because I'm
folding paper.
SAM: 17. I'm specifically looking for stores.
TALIESIN: 15.
LAURA: Four!
MATT: You do manage to discover the location of
The Steam's Respite, but it is closed for the
night. It is too late for its functionality.
LAURA: Damn it!
SAM: On the way, do we pass Packwearer's
Provisions or any of the other fine establishments
you've told us about?
MATT: If you wander through the Pentamarket, which
you can go roundabout to do that.
TALIESIN: That's not on the way, then.
SAM: No. Just on the way.
MATT: On the way from where you are exiting there,
none of those, no. The Pentamarket is pretty much
this cluster at the center of--
SAM: Any shops at all, or is it just--?
MATT: You would've come across more small food
establishments like small dumpling establishments.
Nothing too crazy. It looks like most of the
stores that are on the outskirts would be simple
glassware, the occasional basic blacksmiths for
putting horseshoes on and the construction of
that, simple armor repairs for whoever needs it.
SAM: Nothing fun.
MATT: Nothing crazy. Most of the good stuff is in
the vicinity you've already been.
TALIESIN: You know, Nott, I notice. I notice the
way that you eye things, on occasion.
SAM: I'm not stealing anything right now!
TALIESIN: Not right now and that's fine. And I
would hate to get in the way of any of your
business. Your business is your business and I'm
perfectly fine with that. But it's good to
remember that there are people who need what they
have. There are people who need every bit of what
they have. And there are people who would be much
happier if they had a little less.
SAM: How do I know which is which?
TALIESIN: Well that's a skill worth developing.
That's a skill very much worth developing.
LAURA: If the people look like you and Caleb, they
probably need it.
TALIESIN: If they seem grumpy, or angry, and seem
overly concerned with an enormous amount of money
that they happen to have, or using it to just be
mean or cruel to somebody, that's probably a sign
that they'd just be much happier if they just knew
exactly who liked them and the only way you could
ever really know if someone likes you is if you
don't have anything over them. And the easiest way
to get to that honesty is if you don't have
anything.
SAM: So you're saying steal from grumpy people?
TALIESIN: Oh yes.
LAURA: Shitty people specifically.
TALIESIN: Unless they're grumpy because they don't
have enough. Because if you're hungry, you get
very angry.
LAURA: I do, I do get really mad.
TALIESIN: You get so angry when you're hungry!
LAURA: I know.
SAM: Which kind of grumpy is Beau?
TALIESIN: Beau has way too much. So you should
probably take some stuff from Beau. That's fair.
(laughter)
Beau really needs to know who likes her.
TRAVIS: Beau knows grumpy.
(laughter)
LAURA: Oh no! It makes sense when you're in that
shirt.
MATT: It makes sense when you're over 30.
(laughter)
TRAVIS: Passive sports marketing campaign: check!
MATT: All right. So you guys find your way back.
What about the rest of you guys, anything?
LIAM: I am just finishing up the spell Unseen
Servant before I go to bed so that I will know it
in the morning.
MATT: Easily enough. You have it copied over
without issue.
LIAM: Yes. Yes!
TALIESIN: I'm so excited about a long rest.
LAURA: Before I go to sleep, I'm going to use my
little folded papers and make little pamphlets to
the Traveler. So it's going to be like, "Have you
heard of our lord and savior, the Traveler?"
TALIESIN: You're going to get us killed!
LAURA: He sure is the coolest, everyone should
worship him, he's the best guy around.
TALIESIN: You're making Tijuana bibles. You're
making Tijuana bibles for your religion. Is there
going to be nudity and sex in these? Because then
it's basically a Tijuana bible. Don't Google
Tijuana bible.
LAURA: They're like this little, because I had to
make them out of only two sheets of--
MATT: How many did you make?
LAURA: Well, however many I could make out of two
sheets of parchment, so probably like eight or
maybe ten.
MATT: We'll say ten and a few that didn't quite--
you got halfway through and like (frustrated
noise) tore it up. Okay cool. So the rest of you
guys, are you all resting for the evening?
TRAVIS: Mm-hmm.
MATT: All right. Night rest comes without issue.
You awake in the morning to the sound of an
already muttering tavern floor below you. The
smell of food and whatever dried ale has been
spilled into the room that you're currently
sleeping in. But the day is yours, the morning has
arrived, you are welcome to do what you wish.
TRAVIS: Molly, do you need to pray over your
swords? I don't know how often--
TALIESIN: Oh, I did it before you woke up.
TRAVIS: Oh. Well next time, could you include me
in it? I don't know if maybe it would help me with
my skills.
TALIESIN: Sure. Happily.
TRAVIS: I appreciate that.
TALIESIN: That would be no problem.
MARISHA: Morning, Jester.
LAURA: Beau! You know what we need to do today?
MARISHA: What?
LAURA: We need to go to the pillow place and go
get some money from my mom!
MARISHA: Your-- okay, yeah.
LIAM: How do you get money from your mom?
LAURA: You're not with us in our room right now!
LIAM: Oh, you didn't come downstairs? Okay.
MARISHA: Are you--
TRAVIS: Peeping tom!
LAURA: How does he do that?
MARISHA: How do you know? How do you know that
it's going to be there?
LAURA: Because I asked her for it.
MARISHA: Okay, but asking isn't the same as
confirmation of receiving.
LAURA: Yes, but it's my mom and of course she's
going to send me money! You're crazy.
MARISHA: Yeah. Totally. Let's go. I'll go with
you.
LAURA: It's called the Pillow Trove. We need to go
there. But we need to look very pretty, so before
that, I'm going to see if Molly wants to go get a
bath.
MARISHA: Okay. We have to look pretty?
LAURA: Yes, we have to be fancy for that place.
MARISHA: Okay. Yeah.
LAURA: We also need to go to the blacksmith, you
guys! As I'm coming down the stairs. We have so
many things to sell.
MARISHA: We do.
TALIESIN: Blacksmith's is filthy; we'll go there
first.
LAURA: Good call.
SAM: All right.
MARISHA: We stumble downstairs.
MATT: You get your food, your breakfast set. Let's
see here. We'll say for the two meals and the
drinks, and the three rooms overnight. If you want
to keep track of the tab. Though you haven't paid
it yet, necessarily, if you're staying for a
while.
MARISHA: Under the Nein?
MATT: Put you at--
LAURA: Plus, we're good friends of Claudia's!
TRAVIS: He's the DM.
MATT: I'll put you at, at the three rooms, food
and drink, at about six gold so far.
TRAVIS: Okay, gotcha. Six gold.
MATT: This isn't the nicer part of town.
TRAVIS: So far. One gold each.
MATT: All right. So.
LIAM: Is Claudia down in this room at the moment?
MATT: At the moment, no. Looks like it is your
dragonborn friend and there's maybe six people in
the room.
TRAVIS: How did your homework go last night?
LIAM: Very well. I am a step ahead of where I was
yesterday.
TRAVIS: Hey, that's great! Nicely done.
LIAM: (lip smacking) I walk over to this
dragonborn. Good morning to you.
MATT: "Right, good morning."
LIAM: Sorry, I know you are busy preparing for the
day.
MATT: "That's all right."
LIAM: I hear there is a rather large library here
in this city. This is correct, ja?
MATT: "There's probably a few places with
libraries. There's the Archive--"
LIAM: That's the biggest one. The main one.
MATT: "Yeah. There's also the Hall of Erudition.
I'm pretty sure they got libraries as well."
LIAM: The Hall of Erudition?
MATT: "Yeah, it's where the Soltryce
Academy's...academy...is here."
LIAM: Oh good. Okay. The first place, though,
could you point me in the direction of it from here?
MATT: "Right, that would be, let's see, right
around-- Hmm." (singsong) Let me make sure I get
this correct for internal consistency. Ah, that
would be in the Interstead Sprawl. If you consider
the city's triangular shape, there's the pentagram
market off-center and a little bit to the west of
it, and then there's the East and West
Outersteads, which are the outside cusp and the
slums and the outside of the main wall; there's
the Tri-Spire, which is up north; then there's a
section, a quadrant over here, it's a military
section in this weird ring that surrounds and
bisects them all around the Pentamarket. That's
the Interstead Sprawl.
TRAVIS: That's the garrison area?
MATT: Yeah. Well, no, that's the more
middle-class, central connecting part that holds
the rest of the city together.
TRAVIS: Gotcha. Garrison's more east, you said.
LIAM: Library is there?
MATT: The library is there.
LIAM: And it's to the east, you were saying?
MATT: From where you are now, you guys are in the
Eastern Outersteads, it would be west. And he
goes, "Actually (ugh), hold on just a second, I'll
get to your meal. Follow me." He comes out from
behind the bar and slaps it up, and puts an arm
around your shoulder and leads you right
immediately outside to the front of the tavern,
pushing you along.
LIAM: Ja, okay, I shrink inward.
MATT: He goes, "You look over that rooftop there,
and you can see that-- " and you see this slowly
tapering tower that then curves off at the very
top to be a very dome-like pinnacle. The stonework
itself appears to be like a smooth concrete
looking texture just from this distance, and the
way the morning sun is hitting it, half of it is
just bright and reflective and really intricate
carving and various tiers along the towers. He
goes, "That there's the Archive. That's what
you're looking for. So just look at that tower and
keep going."
LIAM: Thank you.
MATT: "No worries."
LIAM: Also, asking the DM, not this dragonborn,
but you had mentioned the Chastity's Nook. Caleb
would remember if you said what area it's in?
MATT: Tri-Spires.
LIAM: Tri-Spires. Thank you. Got it.
MARISHA: Get that smut, boy, get that smut.
LIAM: Sure, sure.
TRAVIS: Did you say, "Get that smut?"
MARISHA: Mm-hmm.
LIAM: Was there any question?
TRAVIS: Just making sure.
LIAM: Okay. All right. Thank you very much. You're
very helpful.
MATT: "No worries." He runs back and quickly gets
beneath-- there are now two people waiting for him
to get back, and he gets back to pouring drinks
and getting food orders situated.
TRAVIS: So we're going to the blacksmith. Then
we're getting Molly a bath.
LAURA: And me and me and me.
TRAVIS: And you. And then are we looking for job
postings? Like, maybe some work?
TALIESIN: You're welcome to take a look at the job
postings if you don't want to take a bath, but I'd
highly recommend a bath. Baths are great.
LAURA: They really are.
TRAVIS: Is it like a fancy thing?
TALIESIN: Yes. Very fancy.
TRAVIS: Is it expensive?
TALIESIN: That entirely depends what you think
it's worth.
TRAVIS: Are you doing this?
MARISHA: Blacksmith first and we'll see, how about
that?
TRAVIS: Yeah, fair enough.
LAURA: Because we might make so much money from
the blacksmith.
TRAVIS: That is true.
LIAM: Nott! What do you want to do today?
SAM: I want to steal something. I have the itch.
It's back.
TRAVIS: The syphilis itch?
LIAM: All right.
SAM: Extreme syphilis!
MARISHA: We met an ex-physician. Just...never
mind. Never mind.
TRAVIS: Yeah, yeah, he could check you out. Give
your crotch the old once over.
SAM: A former doctor?! Sign me up!
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Wow.
LIAM: You know, I'm sure we can facilitate that.
Let's maybe manage our expectations, not go for
the plumpest plum on the bush.
SAM: Don't worry, I'm only going for grumpy people
today.
LIAM: Okay.
TRAVIS: Amazing!
TALIESIN: I'm so excited!
LIAM: This was an idea you had?
SAM: It was given to me by a wise weirdo.
LIAM: Right. I'm not going to question it.
TALIESIN: It's not the first time I've been
called-- actually, no, it's not the first time
I've been called that, that's fair. It's not
Molly, this is me.
LIAM: Okay, thank you, okay.
MATT: As you guys are making your way through the
East Outersteads towards the Pentamarket, you said
you're going to the blacksmith?
MARISHA: Yeah. To... the... Spark Hammer
Smithing!
(laughter)
MARISHA: That worked real well!
MATT: Yeah, it did.
LIAM: She is the grumpy one! Pencil in the DM's
neck!
MATT: As you're making your way there, one thing
that you do-- you hear a voice that's loudly
talking that crosses you guys as you're walking
down the street. You can see a younger man in his
early 20s or so; he has really thin, blondish
hair, and he's wearing a tabard that is the same
colors as the Crownsguard, but other than that,
normal clothing.
LAURA: What's a tabard?
MATT: A tabard is a piece of cloth that goes over
the front and back--
LAURA: Okay.
MARISHA: Like when you see like knights--
LIAM: It's like Medieval Times.
MARISHA: Yeah. "I'm going for the green knight!"
That.
MATT: He's shouting out-- you get very quick
instance: he's a town crier. As you come into
Zadash, you can see this is probably how a lot of
news is disseminated amongst the populace here.
MARISHA: Ooh, what's he saying?
MATT: What you hear approaching is, (shouting) "--
a crownsguard and the King's grace! Attack on
Alfield is ended! Terrible fiends responsible put
to the sword by a crownsguard and the King's grace!"
SAM: Hey! We did that! That was us!
MATT: "The attack on Alf--" He repeats it as he
continues down the street.
LAURA: Aw, man!
SAM: They stole our thunder!
TALIESIN: But not our gold.
SAM and LAURA: That's true.
TALIESIN: Thank you.
TRAVIS: Although, I mean, credit would help our,
you know, reputation.
LAURA: Yeah! We could be famous!
TALIESIN: Why would you want to be famous?
MARISHA: What do you expect from the Crownsguard,
though?
LAURA: Have you ever been famous?
TALIESIN: No, I have no interest in becoming it,
thank you very much.
LAURA: You have no idea the kind of stuff that
is given to you when you're famous.
TALIESIN: I have most everything I need already.
Why would I need more stuff?
TRAVIS: Jester, any interest in chasing down that
guy and seeing where the news is gathered? Maybe
they could print a retraction.
LAURA: Want me to go tell him he's got it wrong?
TRAVIS: Or where it comes from?
LAURA: Okay I chase after him.
TALIESIN: No!
MARISHA: He's going to think you're crazy!
LIAM: Also, I'm sorry, some of you wish to be in
the spotlight with the things that we do?
LAURA: I chased after him already.
MATT: Okay. He's moved onto-- it looks like he's
cycling through different pieces of news, and as
you approach, he's shouting, "Families missing in
Nogvurot! Crick kidnappers steal them away in the
night! Lock and seal your windows and doors while
you slumber! The attack on Alfield has ended!
Terrible--" and you approach him at that point.
LAURA: Excuse me, town crier man?
MATT: "Yeah?"
LAURA: Where does your news come from?
MATT: "From my boss."
LAURA: Where is your boss located?
MATT: "It's the King's Hall."
LAURA: Because your boss at the King's Hall has
some of his news-- his news is wrong. Did you
know that the attack on Alfield was defeated by a
group called the Mighty Nein? They're this really
amazing band of heroes--
MATT: "I was not aware. I did not know."
LAURA: Yes--
MATT: "That's really interesting."
LAURA: Yes, it is, it's really cool. Because we
were there and we saw it happen and it was really
cool and you should probably get your news
right--
MATT: "That sounds amazing. You should go tell
that to the Herald of the Hall. He's probably the
one who would care the most."
LAURA: Okay, because by the time, though, that we
get there, and then it gets back to you, you've
probably been around town so much, and then you'll
have to retract your article, and that would be
really weird.
MATT: (shouting) "The attack on Alfield--" and he
quickly gets away from you, repeating the process
over and over again.
LIAM: Also, Fjord walks right up behind Jester and
says: (deeper voice) Come on, we need to get back
with the others. Okay? This is not a good idea to
put yourself out in the open, let's go.
LAURA: Fjord?
LIAM: (deeper voice) Yes, it's me, I'm Fjord. Come
on.
LAURA: What is this? Is this a new accent you're
trying out?
LIAM: There was a cough drop stuck in the side of
my mouth.
MARISHA: Like Arnold Schwarzenegger.
LAURA: Fjord, you almost sound like Caleb.
LIAM: This is deep Texan, I don't know--
LAURA: Are you planning on sounding like Caleb
now?
LIAM: Listen, accents are not my strong suit.
Would you please just stop talking to the town
crier? Thank you. I'm trying to drag her back.
LAURA: What are you talking about? Accents are
your strong suit. You're really good at it, Fjord!
TRAVIS: You look like me?
MATT: You trying to drag her along?
LIAM: Yeah, back towards the group.
MATT: Do you let him drag you?
LAURA: Yeah. Wait, can I tell it's not actually
him?
LIAM: Probably.
LAURA: Can I tell it's not Fjord?
LIAM: It sounds about as good as I just did.
Caleb's not good at accents.
TRAVIS: But Fjord does accents.
LAURA: That's the thing. Can I tell from the
physicality? Because you do accents.
MATT: That's interesting.
LIAM: I am Fjord Tough, let's go.
LAURA: Fjord, you seem even weaker than you were
before, pulling me along. This is weird.
LIAM: But I don't smell bad. Now come on, let's go
to the rest of the group.
LAURA: (gasps) Caleb? Is it really you?
LIAM: I pull her by the earlobe. Can we please go
back to the rest?
LAURA: Okay, just let go of my ear now, okay.
LIAM: I'm sorry. Is this what we are going to be
about? Huge credit, and get ourselves to be part
of the news?
LAURA: Hey man, I was just doing what Fjord told
me to, okay? So don't you give me shit!
LIAM: I am not giving you shit, I am putting a
subject on the table for the group. I need to make
an informed decision about what Nott and I are
doing.
TALIESIN: I prefer to keep it on the down-low,
personally.
TRAVIS: Yeah, of course. Not to alarm you, I only
meant that if we are going to be paid for our
escapades, a reputation, anonymously, might help,
if we belong to that name.
MARISHA: You want an anonymous reputation?
LAURA: Oh my gosh! This is perfect! Because if
we're called the Mighty Nein, people will expect
it to be a different group of people.
SAM: Because we're just six?
LAURA: Yeah. That's actually brilliant.
SAM: We're disguised! We're hiding in plain
sight!
MATT: As you say that, across the way, you can see
there's one crotchety-looking dude with one eye
who's like--
TALIESIN: I'm going to look right back at him.
MATT: Averts his gaze and keeps on walking.
TALIESIN: Do I have something in my teeth?
MARISHA: Plus, what makes you assume we're about
anything right now? I don't think we've made any
decisions. I thought we were just having fun,
right? Making good money?
TALIESIN: I'm here for making money.
MARISHA: Are we about anything?
TRAVIS: No.
MARISHA. Yeah. Do you want to be about something?
LIAM: I don't want to be about making a stink
everywhere we go.
TALIESIN: This is what happens after you go to
meetings, is suddenly you want to be about
something. Be careful.
TRAVIS: That's not true. Caleb, I'm sorry.
MARISHA: I didn't say it, he did!
TRAVIS: If we put you at unease, that was not our
intention.
LIAM: It's not just me. You are vomiting salt
water, and you are getting into fistfights with
people, I don't know what you're doing. And you--
Look at you.
MARISHA: Wait, wait, wait.
TRAVIS: "Look at you" is always the worst. Look at
you!
TALIESIN: I'm well aware. This is entirely for the
sake of my mirror. I'm very well aware.
MARISHA: We're the ones that you don't know?
What's going on with-- You two take off every day!
The two of you! Maybe you would know what we're up
to if you went along with the group once!
LIAM: Go along with the group?
LAURA: He always knows what we're up to because he
has his cat follow us.
LIAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: Yeah, super personable.
LIAM: I have fought a giant toad creature with
you. I have fought a big lion thing with a woman's face.
TALIESIN: I propose a plan.
LAURA: You killed its baby!
SAM: I did. I feel very bad about that.
TALIESIN: I have a plan for this. I have a plan,
we're going to take our scrap and we're going to
sell it, so that we have some money. We're going
to take the good feelings from that money and
we're going to spend it on hot water and
inappropriate, friendly nudity.
LAURA: Yeah!
TALIESIN: And we're going to have a discussion
about what we're doing, with heat, steam, water
and a little bit of cash.
MARISHA: Okay, you're super insistent about this,
so I'm going to go with it.
TRAVIS: Yeah. I'm down for it, too.
MARISHA: Because now I feel like it's real
important to you.
TALIESIN: I just find it's easier to have this
conversation when everyone is sitting around naked
in hot water.
TRAVIS: Molly, I expect you to lead this escapade.
Please, lead on.
MARISHA: Sherpa us to our first bathhouse
experience.
TALIESIN: I take five steps and then I go, I don't
know where the blacksmith is.
LAURA: I'll lead the way!
TRAVIS: Five steps in a circle.
LIAM: As everybody walks, to Beau I say: Listen
it's just about logistics. I mean you are very--
TRAVIS: Do you still look like me?
LIAM: No, I dropped it. You are in peak physical
condition, your guns are amazing. I can't do
what you do. I can't run into it, of course. I'm
100 yards back, because I'm thin as a wet toilet paper.
MARISHA: Thanks man, thanks.
LAURA: Thin as a wet toilet paper?
MARISHA: I'm sorry, were you trying to tell me
about-- I'm sorry, what? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
LIAM: I've got to stop complimenting you, it does
not lead to good moments. I walk away.
MARISHA: Okay wait! Damn it! First time Liam's
walked away from me in the campaign!
MATT: Following Jester, you make your way back to
the Pentamarket, to the outside of the Spark
Hammer Smithing. What was previously closed the
night before, you can now see the open air smithy
is lively and banging. You can hear the slamming
of hammer on metal and the shower of sparks from
the exterior anvil setup. Currently out there is a
halfling man with deeply tanned, red skin, short,
black hair and very muscular arms, who currently
has leather gloves on, leather apron, and is in
the process of forging some kind of long metal
blade, hammering it out over a heavy anvil on the
outside. There is the trough for the quenching of
the blade and then in the interior you can see, a
few steps away, the orange glow of the rest of the
blacksmith interior. There looks to be somebody
else on the inside but you don't get a view of
them right now. You can just barely get rows and
rows and racks of various pieces of armor and
weapons that are currently hanging on display on
the inside. There is nobody in the process of
walking through at the moment, just in the process
of crafting, so you are the only individuals who
are holding the space at the moment. So the (metal
clanging), turn, (metal clanging).
LAURA: I take my pink bag and I put it down on the
table in front of him.
MATT: (Metal clanging "Hello?"
LAURA: Hi! We have things to buy and sell from
you.
MATT: "Well, I'm all certainly here for that. What
you got? What you looking to buy?"
LAURA: I pull out-- Well it depends, do you have a
hand axe that I could buy?
MATT: He sets the hammer into the water, the steam
rises up, quenches the blade, takes the gloves off
and wipes heavy sweat from the brow. "You're
looking for a--?"
LAURA: Hand axe! Something that is very sharp and
can kill people!
MATT: "That I can do." Turns around to the inside
of the building and comes back. He has two hand
axes, both look pretty well made, one looks a
little more intricate than the other, but both are
pretty solid. "So we got these two." Throws one
and catches it, throws the other and catches it.
LAURA: Okay, put those on the table and then we
will look at some other stuff first. Okay! I have
six short swords, and I put them down on the
table. I've got two daggers here! I've got two
hand crossbows! Two light crossbows and two heavy
crossbows!
MATT: You place them all down and looking at the
quality and the shininess and the smooth, fresh
weaponry that he's placed on the table and the
pockmarked, used, damaged, in some cases gnoll
mess covered weaponry, you immediately realize--
oh.
LAURA: Maybe scrap metal is a good thing for this.
MATT: "I say so, these have all seen some use. Not
all that great. Sorry."
LAURA: But also! Also, we have some other things!
MARISHA: There were then chains, the manacles.
Cart, we definitely drug here. Definitely around
Fjord's neck.
SAM: We're selling these things?
TRAVIS: Are they in the bag?
LAURA: I have them!
MARISHA: Oh, were they in the bag?
LAURA: We put everything in the bag, then it would
be good.
MATT: You couldn't fit the manacles in the bag.
The one that was around the neck of the manticore.
LAURA: Then we fucking had them around our necks.
MATT: Yeah, you had them in the cart. So you bring
them along with you.
LAURA: We knew we were going to the blacksmith.
MATT: "Well these here, these are some nice
metal."
LAURA: And they were magic!
MATT: "They were magic."
MARISHA: I show him the rune.
LAURA: They had to be real good metal to be magic!
MATT: "Let me have a look at that." He takes them,
pulls on the chains, drags for a minute and he
inspects them over. "This some real nice
craftsmanship, you don't see something this well
made. So where did you get this?"
LAURA: This giant lion thing with a woman's head
had them around it and then we killed the lion
thing.
SAM: We found it.
MATT: Did you guys bring the cart with you?
TALIESIN: Well, if we got there then yeah,
probably.
MATT: He glances past you. Well, the manticore
head is still affixed to the cart, by the way. The
halfling looks past and he goes, "I'll take it you
mean that thing. It's quite scary, well done. Ah,
looking at all the weapons. The wood's mostly
rotted, unfortunately. Some of the metal can be
melted down and reused, have to hammer out all of
the imperfections, smelt it all. The manacles look
very nice. Tell you what. Give me the lot and the
manacles, I'll give you both these axes and be in
excess of about 20 gold pieces."
LAURA: Do we want both of the axes or just the
one?
SAM: Why do we need any axes?
LAURA: I need another weapon. Just one of the axes
is all I need. I don't need both.
MATT: "Put that at about 25 gold then, and the one
axe."
LAURA: Sound good for you guys?
TALIESIN: Works for me.
TRAVIS: Yeah.
LAURA: I like it. I think that is a very good
deal. What's your name, sir?
MATT: "Sorry about that. Yannick. Yannick Dumel.
LAURA: Yannick. I'm Jester. It's nice to meet you.
MATT: "Nice to meet you as well, Jester. Inside
there is Jan. She helps run the place. Fantastic.
I'll go get your gold for you."
SAM: Do you sell flasks?
MATT: "I do not work in smaller bits of metal,
unfortunately. More the hefty kind. My apologies.
If you're looking for flasks--" Takes a moment and
thinks of something. "There's Wares & Ends.
They've probably got something there for you.
There's Packwearer's Provisions, they probably got
flasks around there. Well, they probably have some
at the Lodge of the Eclipse, that's possible."
TRAVIS: Lodge of the Eclipse?
MATT: "Right, right. That's the more hoity-toity
night time tavern here in the Pentamarket."
TALIESIN: Why is it called Lodge of the Eclipse?
MATT: "Because at nighttime they has the great
shows on stage."
MARISHA: You know anyone that might want a scary
lion head thing to decorate their walls?
LAURA: Specifically one that's melting.
TALIESIN: Is there is a taxidermist, is what I
think she's asking.
MATT: "I don't know about a taxidermist,
unfortunately. I'm pretty sure if you ask around
you can find someone willing to pay for that. I
probably ask the Hall of Erudition, they deal in
weird things and strange beasties. Sorry about
that."
MARISHA: What did you say the fancy tavern was?
MATT: "Lodge of the Eclipse."
MARISHA: Lodge of the Eclipse.
LIAM: We might be able to take it to a school or a
medical facility to sell. Studies.
LAURA: Yeah.
TRAVIS: I'm good.
SAM: Let's go.
MATT: All right. You guys head on towards where
now?
LAURA: The bath!
LIAM: We're in the pentagram, penta--
MATT: Pentamarket.
LIAM: So we're close to the library? I thought it
was in that area.
MATT: No, the library is-- the Archive you're
talking about. It's in the western side of the Pentamarket.
LIAM: Okay, so we're closer now then we were. I
don't see the entrance from where we are, or do we?
MATT: No, it's not one of the tallest towers in
the city. In fact, the Tri-Spires, as it's called,
has three massive towers of all different designs
that lord over the rest of the city. They're the
first things you saw when you crested the hill on
the way into the city the night before. This one
is still visible from your perspective, though.
It's a little more squat and maybe four or five
stories tall.
LIAM: The whole kit and caboodle is visible from
here?
MATT: Well, you can see where the Archive is but
it's maybe another ten minute walk to get there.
LIAM: Okay. Does anyone mind if we swing by and
just take a look at the Archive? Not go in, you
know, we have other things we're going to do, but
just to take a look.
TRAVIS: At the outside?
MARISHA: It's a bit of a tourist trap, but sure.
LIAM: You have seen it before?
MARISHA: Yeah, I lived here for like a short time,
passed through.
LIAM: Okay, how long did you do that?
MARISHA: A few months.
LIAM: Okay. Well, I am a tourist.
MARISHA: Yeah, it's pretty.
TRAVIS: If it's on the way sure.
LIAM: Okay.
TALIESIN: Is the board between here and there? The
job board.
TRAVIS: Oh, the postings, yeah. What was it?
SAM: The King's Hall.
TRAVIS: The King's Hall. Where the Herald of the
Hall is. Where we can get that retraction.
MATT: The King's Hall is actually not that far
from the Archive. It would be a brief detour to
get there.
TALIESIN: We can do a couple to the Archive,
couple to the King's Hall. Just pick it up.
TRAVIS: Yeah, that's cool.
LIAM: Would you like to show me the Archive? Not the
inside, the outside.
MARISHA: I think it's this direction, if I
remember.
LIAM: Never mind, I don't want to put you out.
Anyone want to go see the Archive?
TRAVIS: Enthusiasm, Beau, enthusiasm.
MARISHA: Aww, fuck.
TRAVIS: Come on, work on what we did, come on.
MARISHA: I don't think Caleb likes me.
TRAVIS: Just try, give it a whirl.
MARISHA: All right.
SAM: It would be great if you could both take
me!
MARISHA: All right. Hey, Caleb!
LIAM: Yeah?
MARISHA: Right this way!
LAURA: She's really scary.
TRAVIS: (whispering) Yeah!
MARISHA: Is that-- fuck. Was that all right?
Fuck.
LIAM: It's just a volume thing sometimes. Okay
let's go look--
MARISHA: (louder) He said enthusiasm!
LIAM: Oh jeez!
MARISHA: Was that not...? Let's go this way.
TRAVIS: Baby steps.
MATT: All right, so where are you heading first?
LIAM: The Archive.
MATT: The Archive, okay. On the way another town
crier crosses by; another individual, same garb, a
middle aged woman, hair pulled back into a very
tight bun with the tufts of curled hair around the
edges. Same tabard in the front and she's shouting
out, "Riot in Rexxentrum squashed for peace!
Radical groups brought to justice under the
crown!"
MARISHA: Ooh!
TRAVIS: Oh shit.
MARISHA: Ooh, that's some dirty fucking shit.
LAURA: I follow behind her and yell: Town crier
has toilet paper stuck to her shoe!
(laughter)
MATT: In the middle of her next line, "Two weeks
to--"
LIAM: So you do know what toilet paper is.
MATT: "Two weeks' time to the Harvest Close
Festival! Victory Pit in the Pentamarket, entry
begins in four days!"
LAURA: Wait, what did she just say?
MARISHA: Harvest Festival?
MATT: Harvest Close Festival.
MARISHA: Harvest Close.
MATT: Harvest Close. It's the end of the harvest.
MARISHA: It's in two weeks?
MATT: In two weeks.
MARISHA: In a fortnight.
MATT: In the Victory Pit in the Pentamarket. Entry
begins in four days.
MARISHA: Victory Pit!
LAURA: We need to get a really big piece of
vegetable.
MARISHA: Yeah, yeah! Big pumpkins.
MATT: You eventually find your way to the outside
of the Archive. Where you had seen was the
tapering tower that had the dome, with the
polished sun reflection on one side, the rest of
it you can see with the intricate carvings that
happen with each bit of the spiral as it continues
downward. You can see three specific smaller
spires that from this perspective make it look
like, I would say, almost like a TIE fighter on
its side. It has a series of smaller three spires
at the base and a central spire that is the
mainstay of the library. You can see there's a
double door at the base and a number of
individuals dressed in deep grey robes with blue
sashes, very gray and blue color scheme. As you
approach, the outside of it you can see folks
entering in and out but as they enter and exit the
facility they usually enter and exit under the
watch and being escorted by one of these
individuals that seem to be members of the Archive.
LIAM: Okay.
TRAVIS: Sure is pretty.
LIAM: I would just like to look around. It's in a
square, you say?
MATT: It's built off of one of the main roads that
leads in the direction of where the King's Hall
is. So it's not in a major square area, but it's
off a large road.
LIAM: Yeah? Well I am no super spy, but I would
like to just look at the area and see what I see
in the nature of security, other than these
obvious robed figures.
MATT: All the windows that exist are at least
eight feet off the floor and look to be a very
thick stained glass. The only entrances you see
are currently guarded by at least two members of
the Archive and the dress of them actually is very
close to the individual that helped in the trial
that you had in Trostenwald who introduced himself
as Zeenoth, the one who helped provide information
that eventually got you off the hook for that
trial. You can now see similarities in the color
scheme of their attire and the way that it's worn.
It's ceremonial. It looks like it comes with a
ceremonial robe. They're all uniform to a certain
extent with some being more intricate and longer
with more jewelry and they seem to have a little
more station.
LIAM: And you said everyone going in and out was
being escorted by one of these individuals?
MATT: Escorted by one of these, yes.
LIAM: If I see one or two people going in or out
what do they look like?
MATT: One of them you see appears to be a woman,
very well dressed, looks to be a high collar, a
buttoned up blouse of some kind, a dress that just
barely cuts off right where her ankles hit the
ground with very nice shoes. Looks to be a very
well off humanoid woman, a human.
SAM: Does she look grumpy?
MATT: She looks stoic. Leaves with a very--
(laughs)
SAM: Is she leaving or coming?
MATT: Leaving.
SAM: I will follow her.
MATT: Okay. The other one looks to be a man
probably in his late 30s or so, also human. He has
a cluster of small pieces of parchment that are
folded and wadded into his arm and he's leaving
like he just was either taking something out or
just retrieving something.
LIAM: Same fancy type?
MATT: Less fancy than her, but still more well off
than most of the other individuals that have
passed through.
LIAM: Fancier than me?
MATT: Oh yeah.
LIAM: Yeah. Okay. That's a beautiful building.
They're all wearing the same thing.
MARISHA: Mm-hmm.
LIAM: You've lived here for a few months. What do
you know about this place?
MARISHA: There's a lot of books in it and fancy
people are super interested in it.
LIAM: Obviously I am very interested in learning.
Is it easy to gain admittance? Do you know that
sort of thing?
MARISHA: I'm not entirely sure.
LIAM: Oh.
MARISHA: I know that they're super into their
knowledge.
LIAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: They're like "Eh, knowledge, means you're
like powerful or something."
LIAM: Yeah, that's what it means.
MARISHA: Yeah.
LIAM: Yeah.
MARISHA: Knowing's better, yeah, books.
LIAM: Well, you've really sold me on it, let's go
find the others.
MARISHA: Yep.
MATT: While that's happening, you are following
this woman down.
SAM: I'll try to stay 25 feet behind her.
MATT: Make a stealth check.
SAM and LAURA: Ooh.
SAM: 13? Oh! 15.
MATT: Okay. No one immediately seems to pay mind
and she's currently eyes on the prize, heading in
some direction with earnest intent. The escort, of
course, that had helped her out of the Archive
stays behind and reenters the building, and she
continues on her own, but stays mainly on the main
streets; doesn't go and duck into any alleyways
very much for her own personal safety during the
day and staying out in the open.
SAM: Does she have any bag, purse, visible
necklace, pockets, anything pickable?
MATT: There do appear to be two small pockets in
the front waist part of the blouse and a small
satchel that's hanging off the right, over the
left shoulder, off the right side of the body.
LIAM: Do I have any chance in hell knowing where
she went? Because I start looking around immediately.
MATT: Make a perception check.
LIAM: Okay, no. That's a one.
MATT: You have no idea. You come back and Nott's
gone.
LIAM: (panicked mumbling)
MARISHA: She's an adult goblin woman girl, she's
fine.
LIAM: You're not helping me. Like at all.
MARISHA: Okay, I look around. Do I see Nott? Kind
of haphazardly.
MATT: No. Not at this point.
LIAM: We are going to look around now is what
we're doing.
MATT: While the rest of you are regathering
yourselves together to continue onto the next
length of your journey, Nott--
SAM: I'm going to cast Mage Hand and try to pick--
well, let's see, can I unbuckle the satchel thing
or would it be easier to just get in a pocket?
MATT: It's up to you.
SAM: I'll go in a pocket, I guess.
MATT: The front pocket?
SAM: You said she had two side pockets, I think?
MATT: Yeah, the front of the blouse.
LAURA: Front of the blouse.
SAM: Front of the blouse or a satchel on her side?
MATT: Yeah.
SAM: I'll do the side satchel.
MATT: Go ahead and roll sleight of hand, please.
SAM: Okay.
TRAVIS: (laughing) What is it?
SAM: 11.
MATT: Okay.
TALIESIN: Higher than ten.
TRAVIS: Is she still with one of the--?
LAURA: No, she's alone.
MATT: As you're walking and you're concentrating,
you watch as the satchel itself lifts and tugs and
just tugs. Her head spins around and looks behind
her, looks back.
SAM: I press up against the wall.
MATT: Glances around confused, eyes one of the
small pauper children that's off to the side,
begging on the side of the road--
ALL: Oh no.
SAM: It was that one.
MATT: Scoffs and holds her chin up and then
continues walking with a brisker pace.
SAM: I follow at a brisker pace.
MATT: Make another stealth check, please.
SAM: Stealth? 22.
LAURA: Ooh, that's good.
TRAVIS: Yeah, killed the baby and false
imprisonment for the kids.
LIAM: That's how the empire works.
MATT: Okay, brisker pace, but does not seemed to
take notice of your tracking.
SAM: I'll get a little closer this time and try
for one of the pockets this time.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: Oh my god.
SAM: Ooh. 12.
LIAM: That's better.
MATT: There's a brief moment where you've watched
the flap of the blouse open up and expand a bit as
the Mage Hand begins to reach in for what is
within and then with a slight tug you watch as two
of the blouse buttons bounce off and just a bit of
the brassiere shows and she closes her shirt real
fast and looks about again and turns and what you
can see is a man there who's selling apples on a
small cart on the side, is maybe two feet from her
and goes "Miss?" With the apple and she smacks him
right in the face and he, "What was-- what?!" "How
dare you."
TRAVIS: Oh shit.
MATT: Then holding her shirt closed and bundles up
her satchel up in her arms and is now beelining it
deeper into the city.
TRAVIS: Don't let her get away with that.
SAM: I run up to where that happened and pick up
the two buttons.
(laughter)
MATT: They're nice buttons.
SAM: I come back. I did it! I got these two
things. They're very nice and round and shiny.
LIAM: They're very nice. Where did they come from?
SAM: A very grumpy person. She was awful. She
scowled at children and slapped an innocent man
for no reason. She was evil!
LIAM: Insight check. That is a 20.
MATT: If you want to insight check her, you've got
to make a deception check.
LIAM: Well, maybe she believes it, I don't know.
SAM: I believe it! She was a horrible person.
LIAM: Yeah, okay well.
SAM: My itch has been scratched.
TALIESIN: I feel good about everything that just
happened.
LAURA: In the time that Nott was gone could I spot
the Allhammer temple? Just so I know where it is?
MATT: Make a perception check.
TALIESIN: Or the Platinum House.
LAURA: 12.
MATT: Unfortunately no, the Platinum House nor the
Hearth of the Allhammer were noticed. The Hearth
of the Allhammer is in the Pentamarket on the
northern side and you guys had cut through to get
directly to the vicinity of the bathhouse. In the
area you are now in the city, you don't have any
sort of visual on the Platinum House. As you guys
have gathered yourselves together and you make
your way towards The Steam's Respite, we're going
to take a break! Because it is nine o'clock.
LAURA and MARISHA: Nein.
MATT: We'll be back here in a few minutes, we'll
make this as quick of a break as we can so we can
jump back in. In the meantime, guys, sit tight,
we'll see you again in a few minutes.
ALL: Yeah!
[break]
MATT: Welcome back, everyone. Welcome back. Thank
you for your patience. Once again, you didn't miss
anything. Sorry, we didn't have a giveaway this
week. We hope to have one up and going real soon
from our folks at Wyrmwood. In the meantime, hang
tight, you didn't miss anything.
MARISHA: You have shit all over your arm!
LIAM: Oh, I pooped on myself.
MARISHA: Ew, you really are Caleb. What is that?
LIAM: That's not poop, that's where I've had this
circle.
MARISHA: No, that is--
LIAM: That's Pocky chocolate.
MARISHA: I'm going to dad thumb you.
MARISHA: That's gross.
LIAM: It's just fecal matter, it's not like
it's--
MATT: Anyway, welcome back, guys. Great to have
you. You guys coast alongside the road leading
towards the Steam's Respite. You catch a glance at
the King's Hall. You see a massive structure of
bronze and cobalt that is, essentially, the
central courthouse of the city. You can see its
this massive, tall, single story that stands at
least 20 feet high, with long thin windows about
every 15 or so feet. The crownsguard presence is
pretty thick. You see probably, at first glance,
at least ten or so that are watching the front as
general sentries. There it is. You do also, at a
quick glance, see a ten-foot by five-foot large,
heavy piece of wooden board that is standing on
its own about four feet from the main entrance to
the right. It has a number of pieces of parchment
stuck to it. Are you guys continuing on? Head to
the bath house? What are you doing?
MARISHA: Take a gander?
TALIESIN: We've got Mr. Memory Board here to scan
the thing.
LIAM: Yeah, I just take a quick look at it.
LAURA: Are there people watching the board right
now?
MATT: Looks like there's one person scanning past
in the process of reading and looking at things as
they go. Looks to be a person in basic leather
armors. Probably a sellsword of some kind.
LAURA: As soon as he walks away, is there anybody,
any guards looking at the board?
MATT: Not directly reading it, but there are,
right now, four that are within a 15-foot
proximity of it.
MARISHA: That's a lot of guards.
LAURA: That's a lot of guards at this one board.
MATT: Well, the board's right at the front what is
essentially the courthouse center of the entire city.
TRAVIS: Are we all hanging back? I'll walk up with
Caleb.
TALIESIN: Works for me.
SAM: Is there a place I can duck away for a
second, or is there a--
MATT: There is away from the building, but there's
nothing--
SAM: I walk away from the building, cast Disguise
Self on myself and make myself look exactly like Fjord.
MATT: Just a shorter version.
MARISHA: But tiny? Oh my god.
SAM: I've never done this before. I've only seen
people do that, so that's what I'm going to do.
MATT: The height difference you can create with
Disguise Self, I believe, is it a foot?
SAM: Uh-huh.
MATT: Yeah, so you have--
SAM: I'm four-foot tall.
MATT: You're a four-foot tall Fjord.
TRAVIS: Fjord Junior.
MATT: A perfect replica of Fjord on a smaller
scale emerges from the shadows and sidles up
alongside you, Fjord.
MARISHA: It's a very focused Fjord.
TRAVIS: Oh wow. Like a tiny little Fiesta.
SAM: Howdy.
LIAM: Are you doing a variation of Mother's Love
right now?
SAM: Well, I've never used this spell before, so I
just did what you did.
LIAM: That's good. Mistakes that I have made,
learn from them. Keep quiet.
TRAVIS: Yeah, I was going to say the same.
SAM: (softer) Howdy.
MATT: As you approach the board, which you can see
has atop of it pressed into the wood the lettering
that say Task Board. The heavy, wooden board looks
like in immediate view of it, there are maybe
eight pieces of paper that are currently stapled
to it with various rusted nails that have been
reused, and they have been placed onto it, or have
been stuck in and then replaced into it. There's
probably close to 45 or 50 other rusted nails that
are stuck there and have been left that have
currently holding nothing to it. You do see
through a first glance, both of you, as you look
past them, a lot of them are looking for general
work helping construction, some are looking for
people that want to help reinforce buildings that
are crumbling, there are some that are looking for
folks that can help shoo away parts of the
Outersteads that are encroaching upon the
farmlands on the outside of the wall. You do see
one that says, "Seeking and paying for any
information on Myriad activity in the city."
TRAVIS: Oh shit. Cops.
SAM: I don't know what that is. Okay.
MATT: There is one that says, "Reward for
information on rebel gatherings and anti-Crown rhetoric."
MARISHA: Ooh.
MATT: There's one that says--
SAM: Let's do it!
MATT: There's another that says, "Proof of others'
worship of heretical gods paid in gold." One that
says, "Looking for work for the glory of our King
Bertrand. Good pay and adventurous living as a
soldier of the Righteous Brand. Seek Leopold
Wanstiker at the Marrow Keep."
SAM: What?
MATT: Wanstiker. Wanstiker.
LAURA: Can I try sleight of hand and just try to
make that into Wangstacker?
MATT: Yeah, go for it.
TALIESIN: I believe in you.
LIAM: So we're all up there now?
MATT: Apparently.
LAURA: It was a 12.
MATT: No one seems to notice as you quickly
scribble out and alter the visual to where it says
"Wangstacker at the Marrow Keep in the Signet
Wall," and then, "Roving beast in need of
extermination. Must be trained sellsword with
experience."
MARISHA: That's right up our alley!
Extermination!
LIAM: Control action.
MATT: There looks to be one piece of engraved
brass or bronze material on the side that says,
"All job inquiries to be taken to Herald of the
Hall Voloshin within."
MARISHA: The fucking Herald.
LIAM: Would you repeat that last phrase please,
DM?
MATT: Oh, "All job inquiries are to be taken to
Herald of the Hall--"
LIAM: Herald of the Hall.
MATT: Voloshin.
LIAM: Voloshin?
MATT: Yeah. V-O-L-O-S-H-I-N.
MARISHA: It's the guy the town crier said.
SAM: Personally, I think that we should turn in
those devious schemers and get all the gold we can.
TRAVIS: No, look, come on. They confided in us.
The last thing we should do is turn on that just
for a simple coin.
MARISHA: Besides, did you see how many posts on
that board were all revolved around ratting people out?
LIAM: Yeah, I also don't want to stick my neck
out, but anything that is a thumb in the eye of
the Empire, I'm all for.
TALIESIN: Stitches get-- eh snitches get
stitches. Stitches are just--
SAM AND TALIESIN: Stitches.
TALIESIN: Snitches get stitches-- wait--
MARISHA: Stitches are just stitches?
SAM: In the original Zimean--
LAURA: It makes more sense.
TALIESIN: One of the few.
TRAVIS: I personally enjoyed the last beast that
we slayed, but I think that we have plenty to
discuss in that warm bath you're talking about.
TALIESIN: It's time for a bath.
MARISHA: As we walk there I talk to Caleb. You
mentioned being like "Bah! Empire!"
LIAM: Just now or do you mean just a moment ago?
MARISHA: Yeah.
LAURA: Don't say it in the open, you guys, wait
until we're in the bath.
SAM: Yeah, let's just mosey onto the bath, nice,
slow, and steady.
TRAVIS: Can you put your thumbs in your pocket and
give a little waddle?
SAM: (pathetically) Hyuck, hyuck.
(laughing)
TRAVIS: You look right on, right there.
LIAM: He's a little tiny mosey--
MARISHA: It's so cute!
LAURA: It's tiny little Fjord!
TALIESIN: This is a dark mirror, man. A dark, dark
mirror.
TRAVIS: Give a little spit, so people know you're
coming.
SAM: (spitting)
TRAVIS: (tinging)
SAM: (western flute trill)
MATT: Which is strange because the spit actually
emerges from your sternum.
(laughing)
MATT: As you progress, you eventually find
yourself to the outside of The Steam's Respite.
Fairly simple looking building, of deeply
dark-stained wood slats that are all vertical
against heavy load-bearing columns at each major
corner, but it's fairly sizeable for its simple exterior.
TALIESIN: I've learned one thing in my travels:
always hit the bathhouse first. Every major town.
TRAVIS: Good to know.
LIAM: Finally, a bath.
MATT: You guys walk your way into the main
chamber. There's a couple benches to the right and
left of you. There's some small planters that have
low-light plants being kept in the area to give a
fresher scent. There is a small chair and a desk
set up with a clerk, an older female half-orc,
hunched but smiling with her hair gray, thick hair
braided up on the sides and pinned in the back
with a long spike of some kind with a lower jaw
that extends with two visible tusks, but a warm
smile amongst the rest of the nice flower dress
that she wears. As you approach, she looks up from
the desk. "Hello! You've come to the Respite. I am
Miss Rima. Are all of you here for a bath?"
LAURA: Yes, Miss Rima!
MATT: "Would you like individual rooms?"
LAURA: Oh, I think we plan on doing a lot of
stuff, so probably all together.
MATT: "Right, so the Common Room. It is less
expensive, but less private. For the six of you,
for the Common Chamber, that'll run about three
silver apiece."
MARISHA: Oh, yeah.
TRAVIS: Quite reasonable.
LAURA: Rima, is there someone who can take
clothing and clean it up as well while we are
bathing?"
MATT: "That can be provided at an additional cost,
my dear. That'll be an additional one silver each
for the washing and cleaning fee."
TALIESIN: Oh, happily.
MARISHA: I'll take it.
LIAM: I'll pass on it.
LAURA: You probably shouldn't, though.
TRAVIS: He's all clean right now. Pumat Sol
cleaned him up.
LAURA: They can stitch up the holes and stuff.
LIAM: The clothes are still pretty shit, though.
LAURA: No, you were Prestidigitation-ed.
LIAM: My hair is killer right now. The clothes are
old and shitty.
MATT: The clothes are cleaner, they're just
tattered and patched.
LIAM: Some stink don't come off.
LAURA: Ew! Like the poop splatter!
LIAM: I meant blood, but sure.
LIAM: The poop is right there.
TALIESIN: Early 90s River Phoenix hair going
everywhere of its own volition.
TRAVIS: I'd like to have my clothes cleaned, yes.
LAURA: Four silver.
MATT: "Four, eight, 12, 16, 23 silver for the lot.
Thank you so much." Takes the change, leads you
into a back chamber where you get undressed. There
is a doorway that leads open into a central common
hot spring bath that is dug out of the ground
here. It has a rock perimeter to it, and the steam
immediately hits you. It smells of herbs and
soaps. The water itself is somewhat cloudy, and it
looks like there's maybe only four other people in
there, obscured by the steam at the edges of the
pool. As Miss Rima leaves your presence, you guys
can finish disrobing and leaving your clothing
behind and enter the bathhouse.
MARISHA: I go in, and I'm like that drunk person
at the hot tub at the hotel. Hi, how are you guys
doing? Excuse me! Scoot over! I got more friends
coming.
LAURA: I run by her and say cannonball! And jump
in.
MATT: (water splashing)
MARISHA: Told you.
MATT: As the explosion of water hits, there's this
older couple in their 70s or so that, as you
muscle in, they slowly scoot away. There's this
splash and they both (upset squealing) and avoid
the space.
TRAVIS: (elderly voice) My anniversary!
MATT: As you come up out of the water, Jester, and
(breathes), you hair flaps back on the back of
your neck.
LAURA: Hair like the Little Mermaid.
MATT: Your eyes focus, and you see a familiar face
in the water across from you. Leaning, arms
akimbo, against the rock, with a thick hilt of a
sword just resting, apparently--
TRAVIS: In the hot tub?!
MATT: In the hot tub. You see a familiar
pale-looking, muscular woman, with darker hair
that fades to light, as there is Yasha, staring at
you with a curious look.
(cheering)
MARISHA: Fresh off the east coast!
TRAVIS: Beast mode!
MATT: Scoot in a bit.
ASHLEY: Oh, hi!
ALL: Oh, hi!
ASHLEY: I'm here! A little sleepy, but I'm here!
Oh! Well, if it isn't my old friends.
MARISHA: The fuck?
LAURA: Oh my god, Yasha!
ASHLEY: You know, I've been tracking you guys for
quite some time, and I knew you were here, but I
just figured I might want to get a bath first and
get a rub down. Treat myself.
TRAVIS: Oh man. You come to these places a lot?
I've never been.
ASHLEY: I enjoy sometimes the finer things of
life.
MARISHA: She rolled with Molly.
TALIESIN: I walk out of the changing room and walk
by, don't even-- just give a kiss on the head.
Took you bloody long enough to find us.
ASHLEY: I know, I'm sorry. I had some things to
do.
TALIESIN: I'm, for the record, tattooed a lot.
MATT: Explain the tattoos.
TALIESIN: Okay. I apologize that there's no art
yet. I'll get around to that. There's a snake
tattoo that curls all the way up the arm. That
goes all the way up into the peacock-- people have
seen the top of the peacock, but the peacock is
actually roving into a big floral piece that goes down
into a snake that is swallowing the hand. There is
an eye in a pyramid piece with another eye
illuminated above it. It seems to almost go into
the hairline, all the way up the back. There's a
moon and sun connected to the shoulder piece that
all interconnects. The whole thing's very complicated.
LAURA: Is it all upper body?
TALIESIN: It is all upper body, yeah.
LAURA: What about the Prince Albert?
TALIESIN: Except for-- do you actually know what
that is?
LAURA: I do.
TALIESIN: Yeah, no, I don't.
TRAVIS: She knows a lot about dicks, remember?
SAM: Poor Ashley. Wherever she goes, it's body
tattoos.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: I found him in the woods. In a Bag of
Holding.
TALIESIN: Each tattoo has 15 meanings.
LIAM: Have you been hot on our heels this whole
time to keep pace with us?
ASHLEY: You guys are not very discreet. You're
pretty easy to follow.
LAURA: Did you see what happened in Alfield?
ASHLEY: Uh, yeah.
LAURA: That was us. We killed them all.
ASHLEY: Okay. I came for the aftermath of it, but
I didn't see. Or I would have jumped in and
helped, of course.
SAM: Why are you following us? And by the way,
even though I am totally naked, I still look like--
MATT: A fully clothed, tiny Fjord. Yeah. Even when
you remove your clothing, they just shed off your
body and they still visually appear on you. It's a
very strange visual.
SAM: It's me, the goblin, by the way.
ASHLEY: Oh. I do remember you quite well.
SAM: Why were you following us?
ASHLEY: I said I was going to meet you here in
Zadash.
LAURA: We told her where we were going to go.
SAM: Oh. But don't you have mysterious big person
things to do?
ASHLEY: I did. I have things that I occasionally
tend to, and I did.
SAM: Did you do them?
ASHLEY: Ish.
SAM: (whispering) So mysterious.
ASHLEY: It's not that mysterious. I just have
things that I have to do sometimes.
TRAVIS: We're looking to get in some--
ASHLEY: Trouble?
TRAVIS: Yeah.
TALIESIN: They paid us 60 gold for three days.
ASHLEY: You made 60 gold in three days?
LAURA: We killed things for money!
TALIESIN: I've never made money like this.
TRAVIS: We've got the head of a manticore out on
our cart. Melting in the sun.
SAM: I stole two buttons!
ASHLEY: Oh. How nice! What do they look like,
these buttons?
SAM: They're in my existing clothes.
ASHLEY: Your other clothing?
SAM: They're in the other room. They're very nice,
though.
ASHLEY; You're among friends. You don't have to
wear any clothes if you don't want.
SAM: No, I'm okay.
LAURA: Oh, are you free of bandages and everything
too and we just can't see it?
SAM: Yeah, I handed all of those bandages to be
washed.
(laughter)
ASHLEY: I did hear that you've been calling
yourselves something? I hear a name floating
around, that you're calling yourselves the Mighty
Nein?
LAURA: Mm-hmm.
MARISHA: We are getting a reputation!
TALIESIN: Word of mouth. You don't need a big,
public thing.
TRAVIS: Not too much, Caleb. It's all right. Not
too much.
LIAM: How many people have you heard that from?
ASHLEY: Three and a half.
TRAVIS: That's less than a handful.
TALIESIN: Three and one dead.
TRAVIS: Not even worth mentioning at all.
LIAM: In a handful of days.
ASHLEY: In a handful of days.
SAM: And is our reputation intimidating?
Threatening?
ASHLEY: It's neither here nor there, but just for
clarification, is it Nine, as the number nine--
SAM: Yes. It's the number nine.
TRAVIS: Actually, that's not correct.
LAURA: So we still need a few people left.
ASHLEY: Okay.
TALIESIN: It's going to be very hard to search for
us if they don't know if it's Nine or Nein.
SAM: No, it's Nine, the number nine.
MARISHA: It's deliberately con-- are they looking
for nine people?
SAM: That's right.
ASHLEY: You look different.
TRAVIS: I thought it was "no."
LIAM: Yes. I have been in this bath for a few
minutes. No, you were here when I got here. That's
true. We visited an arcane shop and the
gentle...men? I'm not sure, really. The
proprietors of the shop did a little dippity doo
to me and it just took everything away.
LAURA: Did you know there's a spell that can do
that?
ASHLEY: No. I actually don't know much about
spells and things.
LIAM: Yeah, he gave me the carwash. Took it all
away.
ASHLEY: Nice.
MARISHA: That's something different from where I
come from.
LIAM: Yeah, I don't like this. I start sinking
into the bath, enveloping everything, and sitting
on the bottom and holding my breath for a little
while.
TRAVIS: Well, we've lost Caleb. Should we discuss
the potential job offers that we've collected?
TALIESIN: Also, if we're going to get him back, we
going to have to have an agreement about the fact
that, while there's going to be a certain amount
of advertising necessary for this kind of venture,
there are many of us-- and I think it's fair to
say-- that want to keep things quiet. As quiet as possible.
TRAVIS: I agree. I am also not looking to attract
any attention.
MATT: (clapping) You hear this four series of
quick snapping claps, and you hear, "Heat it up!"
You hear the voice of Miss Rima from within, and
you watch as two side doors open. These small
troops of women and men come through with these
pots of heated water, and then dump them into the
bath to refresh the heat, and then exit again and
then close the doors behind them.
TALIESIN: Bless you!
LIAM: Oh, it's hot down there on the ears!
MARISHA: Yeah. I wasn't going to tell you.
SAM: I'm not in the water.
LAURA: You're not getting in the water?
SAM: Nope.
LAURA: You're just standing off to the side,
Nott?
SAM: Yep.
LAURA: But you're naked.
SAM: Possibly, yes.
LAURA: You're ready to come in. Come into the--
ASHLEY: Have you been in the water at all?
SAM: No, I'd prefer not to.
ASHLEY: Do you not like going into the water?
SAM: No, thank you.
LAURA: What is it about it?
SAM: It's creepy. It's dangerous in there. It can
drown a person.
MARISHA: So wait. You're creeped out by water and
you're creeped out by fire? Man, covering the
spectrums. Yeah.
LAURA: Yeah.
ASHLEY: Nott, do you know how to swim?
SAM: I don't know. I haven't tried in a while.
TRAVIS: Well, we can certainly teach you.
ASHLEY: We could hold you.
TRAVIS: Yeah. It's very shallow here. Very little
risk.
TALIESIN: My father just threw me right in. That's
how I learned.
MARISHA: You know, that's actually--
TRAVIS: We're not going to do that.
TALIESIN: No, that's a terrible idea.
SAM: No, that sounds terrifying and horrible!
TALIESIN: It was awful, but here we are.
LIAM: I could hold you and you could do the dog
paddle. Have you ever seen the dog paddle before?
SAM: I mean, it seems dangerous, though. How do
you breathe in there?
MARISHA: Well, you keep your head above water.
LIAM: Well, you know.
MARISHA: Here, I take Nott and I say, hold my
hands. Just hold my hands. Okay, ready? And I pull
Nott into the water and I go: Now kick kick kick!
There you go! Kick kick kick! Keep kicking! Keep
kicking! Good job! And I put her back on the
edge.
SAM: (coughing) It got in my nose!
TALIESIN: Wow, that brought it back.
TRAVIS: She vomits up a popsicle into the pool.
MARISHA: It's okay. See?
LAURA: See? How did it feel?
SAM: It wasn't terrible.
LIAM: Does the little Fjord look wet or dry?
MATT: Looks dry. But leaving a trail of water
behind.
LIAM: I love magic so much.
SAM: It's not bad.
LAURA: Are the old couple looking at us like we're
weird?
MATT: Yes. They're both off, holding each other,
just going.
LIAM: Hey, they're all about to start having sex.
You might want to get out of here.
MATT: They immediately get up and start leaving
into the changing room, exiting the chamber.
LAURA: Is there anyone else in this pool with us?
MATT: At the moment, no.
TRAVIS: Yeah!
LAURA: Yeah! It's all ours! It's a party room
now!
TALIESIN: I don't think they understood that was
an invitation.
TRAVIS: So here's what we got. We got "gold from
'My-riad' activity?"
LAURA: Myriad.
TRAVIS: Myriad activity. Whatever that is.
TALIESIN: That's exciting.
TRAVIS: We got "reward for rebel gatherings."
Which we are not going to do. We've got "tracking
down heretical god worship." I don't think we're
feeling that one, right?
LIAM: With this one?
LAURA: Probably a bad thing to do!
SAM: Do you have a god that you worship? Because
we've just been told that's it's bad juju around here.
TRAVIS: Yeah. Apparently there are only six
deities they allow to be worshipped publicly here.
ASHLEY: What are the six deities?
TRAVIS: The Allhammer, the Raven Queen, the--
LAURA: Platinum Dragon.
SAM: The Dawnfather, the Annoying Mistress?
MATT: The Knowing Mis--
(laughter)
MATT: That's a different pantheon all together.
MARISHA: What was it? The Dawnfather, the Raven
Queen, the Knowing Mistress, the Allhammer--
MATT: The Lawbearer.
MARISHA: The Lawbearer!
LIAM: Do you have any sort of religion or
tradition of heavy metal or something?
ASHLEY: Yes, I do.
SAM: Are you in the clear?
ASHLEY: Not here.
LAURA: (gasps) Do you worship the Traveler too?
ASHLEY: I do not.
LAURA: Oh, okay. I thought I would have known you
if you did.
ASHLEY: Probably.
LAURA: We have really small group meetings. It's
usually just me.
ASHLEY: Oh. He sounds like a great-- so many
adventures. With traveling and with him.
LAURA: What about you?
ASHLEY: Well, I don't feel like I'm comfortable to
say here--
SAM: We can see your vagina.
LAURA: Yeah, you don't have anything to hide from
us.
ASHLEY: I mean, it's underwater, but--
SAM: So we're all comfortable.
TALIESIN: One assumes there's a mist that's just
covering everything--
MATT: It obscures it to the point where, yeah.
ASHLEY: You stand up and it's still like--
TALIESIN: I mean, nudity's going great and all,
but this is more about comfortability.
LIAM: As a victim of Campaign One: yes, there has
to be.
LAURA: Everything is a milk bath.
TALIESIN: Thank you!
LIAM: That's not milk!
TRAVIS: We also got, apparently, Winestacker. Wang
stacker? Yeah, he had something, at the Morrow Keep?
LAURA: He wanted people to join the military, so
no.
TRAVIS: Yeah, we're not going to do that. But
there is a roving beast, which feel like falls
into our wheelhouse.
LAURA: I like killing roving beasts.
TALIESIN: I don't know what a wheelhouse is, but I
feel pretty positive about the metaphor in general.
LAURA: Nott, do you want me to wash your hair for
you? No one will see. Because you look like Fjord.
SAM: All right, that'll be nice!
TRAVIS: If you're not planning on bouncing tout
suite, might be a fair way to find our way in the town.
ASHLEY: Sometimes I have to go, but I like killing
things, so sign me up.
TALIESIN: My god, the money.
ASHLEY: And my god, the money.
TALIESIN: I've never seen anything like it.
LAURA: We made so much money off of ears!
TRAVIS: Yep, we really did.
ASHLEY: Just ears alone?
TALIESIN: Three months' worth of shows, like
that!
ASHLEY: Wow.
MARISHA: The Crownsguard have so much money.
TALIESIN: And they're so lazy!
LAURA: And we're going to make a whole lot of
gold over at the Pillow Trove.
ASHLEY: What is the Pillow Trove?
LAURA: It's a fancy hotel place.
TRAVIS: Apparently Jester's mother's going to hook
it up, right?
LAURA: Mm-hmm!
ASHLEY: Who's your mother?
LAURA: She's the Ruby of the Sea.
ASHLEY: I feel like I've heard of the Ruby of the
Sea.
ASHLEY and TALIESIN: [whisper inaudibly]
ASHLEY: Okay, I have heard of the Ruby of the Sea.
That's pretty spectacular that that's your mother.
LAURA: I know!
MARISHA: She has her own jingle.
SAM: How does that go again? (singing) Everybody
knows the Ruby of the Sea!
TRAVIS and MARISHA: (singing) The best lay
around!
LAURA: You guys have really bad memories because
it was not like this at all.
TRAVIS: Hey, Nott, now the next step is to get
your head underwater. Okay, we're going to take a
big breath.
LAURA: I've been sudsing up your hair. You have to
do it to dunk your hair.
SAM: To wash my hair?
TRAVIS: Beau and I will hold you, and on the count
of three, we're going to go under.
TRAVIS and MARISHA: One, and a two, and a three!
TRAVIS: We all go underwater with Nott.
TRAVIS, MARISHA, and SAM: (bubbling)
TRAVIS: And we bring him back up.
SAM: (gasping) I'll kill you all! I'll kill every
motherfucking one!
TRAVIS: (shushing)
LIAM: He's done, you are with friends.
TRAVIS: Hey, you did great! You did great. You're
going to get a sticker.
MARISHA: A sucker, at the end of this. From
Jester, not from me, but you'll get a sucker.
TRAVIS: It didn't burn, right? You lived. Great
job.
SAM: Thank you.
ASHLEY: How do you feel now? Are you still
scared?
SAM: I'm less scared, but it's still
uncomfortable, and I'd prefer to do it at my own
speed, thank you very much.
ASHLEY: Do you want to stand at the side then, and
hold the side?
SAM: Hold the side, like this? Yes.
LIAM: Yasha, there's a heavier presence of the
Empire here than there was in Trostenwald. How
does that sit with you?
ASHLEY: Well, I know I have to be careful about
some certain things. I think I'll be fine.
TRAVIS: Nobody's chasing after you or giving you
any heat, are they?
ASHLEY: No.
LIAM: Insight check.
TRAVIS: Which one? I am lying!
MATT: Generally you can say, "Do I believe her?"
and then I'll tell you to make an insight check.
LIAM: Okay. Do I believe her? I do! Okay.
ASHLEY: I'm not in trouble for anything. I think,
if anything, it would be because of the god I've
chosen to follow.
LAURA: Which is whom?
TRAVIS: Jester!
ASHLEY: It's the Stormlord. I don't know if you
know of him.
SAM: Do any of us know what the Stormlord is?
MATT: Yeah. For basic religion, you would, because
you've been outside the Empire. Those of you who
grew up in the Empire, you would vaguely have an
idea.
LIAM: What about a big reader?
MATT: You would, maybe. Make a religion check.
LIAM: Natural 20.
MATT: You are very aware of the Stormlord. You
knew the Stormlord well. Since the Menagerie Coast
largely relies on port trade, it is one of the
most-worshipped gods in the Menagerie Coast for
people who travel in and out of the ports there.
Overseas, safe passage amongst bodies of water,
contests of strength, proving worth through
action. Lot of very interesting elements that the
two of you would know of that following.
TRAVIS: I understand the Stormlord is to be feared
and respected.
ASHLEY: Yes, he's pulled me out of what literally
felt like the depths of hell, so I owe him my
life. I will continue to serve him and do as he
asks, whenever he asks.
LAURA: Are you from the Menagerie Coast as well?
ASHLEY: No.
LAURA: Are you from the empire?
SAM: Where are you from?!
(laughter)
LAURA: Sorry, Yasha. This is a lot. If you don't
want to answer, I understand.
LIAM: Yeah, you just joined back up with us. She
doesn't need to tell us her life story.
MARISHA: When you say "pulled you from hell,"
though--
TRAVIS: Wow, Beau. Really?
MARISHA: What? She brought it up.
LIAM: You are literally undercutting the very
thing I just said.
TRAVIS: We are very glad that you're back.
TALIESIN: I vouch for her, for what it's worth.
TRAVIS: Which means a lot, Molly.
TALIESIN: It means what it means.
LAURA: I trust her fully.
TRAVIS: Molly, what else do you do around a hot
bath-spa-place?
TALIESIN: You run into your friends who are also
heading in odd directions.
LAURA: You stand uncomfortably close to people you
know and make them feel awkward. And I walk really
close to you, Fjord.
TALIESIN: I tend to find it's easier to look into
somebody's eyes and figure out if they're lying to
you if they're naked and boiling.
TRAVIS: Uh-huh. Jester-- I forgot what I was going
to say.
MARISHA: Yasha, it's interesting to see you
without your cloak. You were super adamant about
that one.
ASHLEY: I was cold.
MARISHA: Sure. Hot tub, you know.
ASHLEY: I recall when you asked for it, it was a
very cold day.
MARISHA: Uh-huh. Do you need a towel? Do you need
me to get the hard-to-reach places in your back or
anything for you, while we're here?
ASHLEY: I got it.
TALIESIN: I like to think you're scratching--
You've got a sword in your hand, for god's sake.
TRAVIS: This is normal, right?
ASHLEY: You pay extra to keep your weapons.
SAM: You've been in the water before, haven't
you?
TRAVIS: No, I know, it just seems to be happening
faster than before. It's all fragrant and stuff.
LAURA: Oh no, Fjord! Are you melting?!
SAM: He's turning into a fish!
LAURA: Oh no, you're turning into water!
TRAVIS: Oh no, oh no. Jester, help. (fake drowning
noises)
LIAM: Five or six days in, I think, and I'm really
questioning this decision.
SAM: Should we take the mission to go kill the big
beast?
TRAVIS: I think so.
TALIESIN: I say we take the beast. Again, keep it
on the down-low. We'll figure out a way of getting
credit and keeping our reputation, but keeping it
quiet.
MARISHA and LAURA: Okay.
TRAVIS: We take it to the Herald of the Hall.
LAURA: Yes.
TALIESIN: God, I hope his name is Harold.
MARISHA: You guys know how Shakäste was all like
(shushing) and secret, you know?
LAURA: Is that what he was like?
MARISHA: Yeah, he was all like, "I'm mysterious."
TRAVIS: We met a guy named Shakäste, he was super
cool. White afro, really awesome.
MARISHA: Have you heard of him?
LIAM: Totally blind.
MARISHA: Everywhere he went, he was like,
(shushing). He was super badass.
TRAVIS: He said "baby" a lot.
LAURA: He called us "baby."
ASHLEY: He called you a baby a lot?
TRAVIS: But in a charming way.
MARISHA: I was into it, I didn't feel demeaned by
it. It makes me feel good, makes me feel safe.
TALIESIN: I felt demeaned, but in a good way.
MARISHA: I'm just saying, maybe we can--
MARISHA and LAURA: Be like that.
LAURA: I get out and I start drying my hair and
try to get pretty.
TALIESIN: Yeah, we're up.
MATT: You guys start making your way out of the
bath, gathering your clothing once more, as you
head back.
TRAVIS: I gather my clothing away from Jester.
LIAM: Is this one still in disguise? Nott, are you
still in disguise?
SAM: How long has it been?
LIAM: It's an hour, that it takes.
MATT: You've been in here, catching up and soaking
for about a half an hour, 40 minutes, so you're
getting pretty close to losing.
SAM: I wrap a towel around myself, and then I'll
drop form.
TRAVIS: Come on, "son."
MATT: You now see the towel-covered, goblinoid
form of Nott, her hair wet and tattered down
across the face. It's long in the front, the
yellow eyes peeking through.
LIAM: Are our clothes in here, or somewhere else?
LAURA: They probably folded them up for us.
LIAM: But I didn't send mine off to be cleaned.
TALIESIN: Then yours was in a locker.
LIAM: I'm going to pull the spool of silver thread
and I'll take a length of it out, and I'm going to
pull Nott's hair back and do a little ponytail.
Simple.
ASHLEY: I'm going to wait until everyone gets
out.
MARISHA: Damn it. I was going to say, I wait and
watch all my friends get out.
TRAVIS: You all just sit on opposite sides.
SAM: You guys coming?
MARISHA: Yeah, yeah.
ASHLEY: Yeah, I just want to make sure that I get
my full time's worth.
MARISHA: Yeah, we paid a lot for this.
TRAVIS: Should we catch you outside, then?
MARISHA: No, it's good.
TALIESIN: It's a really hot hot tub.
LIAM: I think the moment's passed for the rest of
us. I think we should go.
SAM: We'll just go.
TRAVIS: Maybe they need more hot water, we'll send
some in on our way out.
LIAM: Have fun storming the castle.
MATT: The clean clothing is presented. You guys
get dressed and your outfits are waiting for you
in the dressing room.
TALIESIN: I'm ready for Monster Hunter.
LAURA: Who gives up first?
TRAVIS: I'm real down for that showdown.
MARISHA: We're in hot tub chicken right now.
ASHLEY: I mean, I don't care to show anything.
MARISHA: No?
ASHLEY: I feel like this is a pool of honesty. I
just wanted to see everybody else naked first.
MARISHA: Yeah, it's honestly kind of my thing.
ASHLEY: Okay, I'm getting out.
LIAM: And the water drops a foot and a half.
(laughter)
MATT: It's fun to watch her make her way out using
the large greatsword essentially as a walking
stick as she emerges from the tub.
MARISHA: Do I get a nice view?
MATT and ASHLEY: Yes.
SAM: Roll for perv.
TRAVIS: Perving on Yasha.
MARISHA: And now I get out, yeah.
TALIESIN: Backflip.
MARISHA: Three-point landing.
MATT: You guys have regathered your materials.
You've reconvened outside the Steam's Respite.
It's about midday now, about noon-ish. The rest of
the day is still yours. What do you wish to do?
TALIESIN: Let's find a herald. The maudlin
herald.
LAURA: While you guys do that, I need to go to The
Pillow Trove, okay?
LIAM: Where are you going?
LAURA: I need to go to The Pillow Trove, which is
the nice tavern in the place.
LIAM: Would you mind, I don't want to go in, but
would you mind if I tagged along with you?
LAURA: No, that's fine.
TRAVIS: Will you be gone for a while, or is it a
quick errand?
LAURA: It's a quick errand. I just need to pop in
and pop out, you know how you do.
TRAVIS: We'll see you back over here, then? Okay.
LIAM: Nott, did you want to stick with the others?
I'm going to run an errand with Jester.
SAM: Do you need me?
LIAM: Not for this. I should just be gone a couple
of hours.
SAM: Do you need health potions, because you might
die?
LIAM: I think chances are very low.
SAM: Do you have one?
LIAM: Yeah, I have the one you secured for me,
yeah.
SAM: Okay, good.
TALIESIN: Come on, Nott, it'll be fine. We'll see
if we can meet anybody else who you could make
feel better about who they are.
LIAM: Go have fun. Maybe you get another button or
two from a grumpy person.
SAM: Excellent.
LAURA: Before we leave, I run up and give Yasha a
hug, and say: I'm glad you're back.
ASHLEY: Oh, thank you, Jester. I get
uncomfortable. I don't hug her back, but I gently
give her one pat.
LIAM: Caleb sees this, and just goes--
TRAVIS: Hug around the arms that are down, and
you're like--
MATT: Perfect.
ASHLEY: I'm trying. I'm very uncomfortable with
human touch.
LIAM: I feel like I know you better now.
TRAVIS: We'll see you back at the King's Hall.
LAURA: Okie-dokie.
MATT: Those of you heading to the King's Hall, you
make your way back to the familiar outside, this
large center for law, order, and judgement within
the city of Zadash. As you approach the doorways,
the guards pass, but keep an eye very closely as
you enter. On the interior, you can see there are
two round tables with curved benches that meet the
sides of it, and there you can see some of the
crownsguard in the process of talking to various
civilians and taking notes. There's conversation
about-- pardon me. So?
TRAVIS: Is there a desk, or a clerk?
MATT: You don't see a desk or a clerk, but you do
see the crownsguard that are currently at the
tables, talking to these individuals, and you see
two other individual crownsguards that are
standing and guarding two hallway entrances that
lead further into the King's Hall.
MARISHA: As we walk up, I'm going to take my robe,
and for the first time any time this party has
seen, cross it over and tie it more
traditionally.
TRAVIS: I'll walk up to one of the king's guard,
ask him. We're here to inquire about one of the
postings. There's a roving beast that needs taking
care of.
MATT: "Oh, let me go and get the Herald for you,
hold on just a second." He scoots out of the next
hallway. A few moments later, you watch as this
really stressed-looking male dwarf with these
thick mutton chops and salt-and-pepper hair,
well-groomed, combed really heavily to one side,
the thick hair is being tamed to the point where,
in a very Gene Wilder way, it's combed and then
(poof), out one side. As he walks in, he's wearing
long robes of gold and white and silver, and
carries the holy symbol of the Lawbearer. You can
see an axe that hangs on a chain with a scale
embedded in the center of it. He walks in. "Right.
So you're inquiring about the job board?"
TRAVIS: That's right. We're a few members of the
group known as the Mighty Nein. We would like to
take one of those listings off your hand, if we
could.
MATT: "All right. Which one in the task board you
looking for?"
TRAVIS: The one mentioning that roving beast.
Seems about our speed.
MATT: He gives a quick glance over all of you.
"All right. Let me go ahead and pull this out." He
pulls a small side bag that has a bunch of pieces
of paper in it. He unfurls one section, sets it
down. "And your names?"
MARISHA: Can't we all go under The Mighty Nein?
MATT: "I'm sorry, but for the purposes of
maintaining organization within the paperwork here
we need to know the names of those who are to
claim any rewards or benefits of completing a job."
TRAVIS: Yeah, I'm Philbin.
MATT: "Philbin, all right. And you are?"
LIAM: Regis.
MARISHA: Damn it, I can't say it now.
TRAVIS: Yeah, fucker.
MARISHA: Lawrence.
MATT: "Lawrence."
SAM: Kylre.
MATT: "Kylre."
TALIESIN: Esma.
MATT: "Esma, all right."
ASHLEY: Um. Barry.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: Short for Barrymore.
ASHLEY: It's short for Barrymore, but I just go by
Barry.
MATT: Make a deception check.
TRAVIS: The head-shake afterward is the best
ASHLEY: Oh! D&D Beyond! Am I remembering how to do
this?
SAM: What screen are you on?
ASHLEY: I'm still new.
SAM: Refreshing! What did you roll?
ASHLEY: Refreshing, it's loading.
MARISHA: Ashley, that's DocuSign, you're in the
wrong app completely!
TALIESIN: Really, oh wow, that's a number.
ASHLEY: Okay, 13.
MATT: Okay.
TRAVIS: Is it a minus?
TALIESIN: It's a minus two.
MATT: "All right, Barry. Okay (clears throat).
This here is a writ of Lawmaster intent. This will
"give you entrance to the location of where the job
is supposed to take place. This supposed creature
"has holed up in a sewer nexus right on where the
Interstead Sprawl meets with the outer wall of the
"Tri-Spires. We need you to travel down there, and,
well, let's say there's a whole region on the
"inside where we've been hearing about this backing
up of various liquid and strange noises from
"cleaners who were making their way through, so we
sent a few crownsguards down and came across a
"mass of congealed sewage slime and webbing, so the
fucking cowards ran back and we need to dig
"deeper. So here we are: find a way of whatever is
creating this disturbance, kill it, take it back
"with proof of the kill, whatever built that little
nest, and the Crown is willing to drop you about
"700 gold pieces."
TALIESIN: 700 gold pieces?
MATT: "That's correct."
TALIESIN: Just for the entrance, they are aware
that there are several of us, we are just
representatives of a slightly larger group.
MATT: "Well, you have to divide it evenly from the
700 you get."
TALIESIN: Of course, but we can all get entrance
from this writ?
MATT: "All the ones that are named on here."
TALIESIN: You need all the names of everybody
involved?
MATT: "There's more involved?"
TALIESIN: Well, we're called the Mighty "Nine,"
aren't we?
MATT: (groans) Takes the writ. "And who are the
other companions?"
TALIESIN: Well, let's just send seven of us down
for now.
TRAVIS: Yeah, that's fair.
SAM: Seven of nine?
TALIESIN: Oh, really? I've never felt such hatred
than this moment. Wow, god damn it.
TRAVIS: What are those other two called? I
forget.
ASHLEY: We've got Karen--
TRAVIS: (laughing) Karen.
SAM: And Rothschild.
MATT: "Karen and Rothschild."
ASHLEY: Yeah. Wouldn't that mean we would get 900
gold? 100 per person-- per, you know?
MATT: "No, that would be 700 gold, split between
the lot of you."
TRAVIS: Just to be clear, there's no clearage of
sewage? We're just here to take care of whatever's
causing that webbing you mentioned.
MATT: "Whatever's causing the blockage, and the
webbing, whatever else they found down there. Yes,
"take care of that, bring back proof of the
death."
TRAVIS: Proof of-- okay.
MARISHA: But you don't know what did it?
SAM: Do you know what kind of monster it is?
MATT: "No fucking clue, that's why you're being
paid 700 gold for it!"
SAM: Okay. Have people been killed?
MATT: "People have gone missing. You think you're
the first to try and take the job? No, it's
"dangerous! That's why we're paying so much. If you
don't want it, go away. If you want it, here's the
"writ, good luck."
MARISHA: Thank you.
TRAVIS: Mighty obliged, we'll take care of this
most expediently.
MARISHA: Bye.
ASHLEY: Wait! Has anyone gone and come back?
MATT: "There have been three times that it's been
taken up and one's come back declining it and two
"that have not."
TRAVIS: Declining it? For any specific reason or
did they just change their mind?
MATT: "Think they changed their mind a bit."
ASHLEY: We'll take care of it.
MATT: "I'm sure you will."
ASHLEY: I sense a little sarcasm in you, sir.
MATT: "It's a dwarven thing. We've got resting
bitch voice."
(laughter)
ASHLEY: Fair enough.
TRAVIS: Good day to you. We'll take care of this.
MATT: "Great. Well, shove off!"
SAM: Okay!
TRAVIS: And we leave.
TALIESIN: We walk away.
MATT: All right.
MARISHA: Theoretically.
TRAVIS: Yeah?
MARISHA: Not that I want to be a-- what's the
word-- "shysta"?
LIAM: Shyster.
SAM and TRAVIS: Shakäste.
MARISHA: If they don't know what the monster is,
and we have a perfectly good manticore head--
TALIESIN: Then they're going to send people down
there.
TRAVIS: That's not really our problem.
TALIESIN: But then they'll know.
MARISHA: If we get the gold first.
ASHLEY: Maybe it came back to life?
TALIESIN: As someone who actually has towns that
they can't re-enter again for reasons, that we
will go into later, over booze-- it's best to keep
a clear reputation.
TRAVIS: Beau does have a good point, though. I
mean, if we get down there and it's some
world-ending monster--
TALIESIN: We can just run back up.
MARISHA: We found a manticore, who knows, they
make nests.
TALIESIN: There's a blacksmith who knows.
MARISHA: Do you think the blacksmith cares what
the Empire is doing? The blacksmith is just trying
to survive.
TALIESIN: I think the blacksmith will get ten gold
for telling them if they find out there was a
manticore down there that--
MARISHA: If the blacksmith knows.
SAM: It's a good plan B.
TALIESIN: It's an emergency plan. It's a good plan
B, I'll grant you that.
TRAVIS: I head to the outside and wait out by the
posting where we last saw Caleb and Jester.
SAM: Karen and Rothschild.
TRAVIS and MARISHA: Karen and Rothschild.
TALIESIN: I'm going to juggle.
MATT: After asking some questions and making your
way around you eventually find the Tri-Spires,
which is not too difficult to see once you know
what you're looking for. You see these three very
unique-looking towers that ascend past a round
wall that encases the interior of this elite
portion of the city. As you approach the wall--
the outer walls you see are basic stonework and
masonry, thick as they may be and used as from a
defensive position-- these walls are made of solid
marble, and look more decorative than designed to
be a military buttress of any kind. As you
approach, you can see there are two entrances to
it-- or at least you've been told there are two.
The one that's nearest to you opens in the
direction of the Pentamarket, and while the
portcullis is lifted you see there are two
crownsguard there, currently standing with spears
and shields at the ready. A horse-drawn carriage
clomps by you and makes its way inside. You guys
approach and one of the guards steps forward. "Can
I help you, please?"
LAURA: Yes, we have business at the Pillow Trove.
MATT: "I don't think you do. Please, shove off."
LAURA: Oh, well, I have business at the Pillow
Trove.
MATT: "What's your business with the Pillow
Trove?"
LAURA: I have a package that's being delivered
there. What business do you have at the Pillow Trove?
MATT: "Look, your friend here looks like he just
wandered out of the Evening Nip if anything, so it
would be best--"
LAURA: Oh, yes, I hired him to protect me because
you know I'm very fragile and delicate, but if he
doesn't look well enough to be my guard, you're
welcome to walk me instead.
MATT: They look at each other. Make a persuasion
check.
TRAVIS and MARISHA: Come on!
(exclamation of surprise)
LAURA: 22!
TALIESIN: That was impressive.
MATT: Look at each other, look back at you. "All
right, I'll walk you in. Briefly. Then I'll get
back to my post. You, stay the fuck out of this."
LAURA: (whispering) Sorry, Caleb. I'll let you know
what it's like, okay?
MARISHA: Rejected!
LAURA: (whispering) Frumpkin, kitty, kitty.
MATT: "All right, to the Pillow Trove. This way,
follow me." The other guard steps past him and
blocks you from the other two. As the guard guides
you in he makes a big whistle sound, does a finger
loop, and you watch as another guard gets relieved
and comes down to help him at the front doorway.
LAURA: You guys are really on top of your shit in
here.
MATT: "Thank you. I appreciate that." Now,
stepping into the Tri-Spires--
LIAM: Does that happen lickety-split, the second
guard comes down?
MATT: There's maybe a 20 second period where he's
making his way down. You get the sense from the
look of this, and glancing through the interior,
you see elements of beautiful courtyard parks with
trees and bushes. You can see statuesque
structures that decorate what normally was just
dirt road with occasional bits of stonework, as
beautifully laid cobblestone from the interior,
you can see homesteads of different styles of
construction from all across this continent and
beyond. This is where the money in the city goes.
This is the district where the elite live, where
the elite work, and where folk of very specific
visual presentation and purpose are allowed entry.
LIAM: Right, and as she goes and does her thing, I
just want you to know that Frumpkin does follow
her, and I leave and walk around the block, and
duck into an alley, or any private place, and cast
Disguise Self on myself to make myself look very
resplendent.
MATT: Roll a stealth check for Frumpkin.
LIAM: For Frumpkin? It's not very good. That is
only a four.
MATT: As Frumpkin begins to (meowing) run on its
way, and one of the guards goes, "Piss off," and
kicks Frumpkin about ten feet off, and stumbles
and skids, and then gets back up.
MARISHA: No! Not okay!
LIAM: Does that take any damage?
MATT: I'd say take one point of damage.
LIAM: Gone.
LAURA: No, you said one point?
LIAM: I rolled hit points for him when I made him,
and it was one, so he's gone.
TRAVIS: (explosion)
MARISHA: You kicked his cat into oblivion!
TRAVIS: You kicked his cat until it burst!
MATT: I didn't.
TRAVIS: He kicked his cat so hard!
TRAVIS and LAURA: He kicked the highlights out of
his hair!
LIAM: Who's laughing now, Billy? Who's laughing
now?
MATT: Stray cats can't just wander into--
LIAM: Caleb curses to himself and wanders around,
and does what he says, suddenly looking very
noble. I'll let that go and then I'll follow up.
TRAVIS: You guys, I kicked this cat today, and it
fucking evaporated.
(laughter)
TALIESIN: If that isn't a beer-worthy story, I
don't know what is.
TRAVIS: Somebody punch me. (punching sound)
LIAM: Caleb is pissed.
MATT: The guard looks a bit confused. As you
wander back, he's pointing at the tip of his boot,
and he's like, "I don't know, it was fucking
crazy." So what do you look like?
LIAM: I am wearing the deepest black robes, and I
have a black goatee. Very Evil David Hasselhoff.
TALIESIN: The Master from Doctor Who.
LIAM: Sure, that.
LAURA: He looks very embroidered and everything.
LIAM: It's all black velvet. The way the audience
thinks Vax looks, that's what I look like right now.
SAM: Kneel before Zod.
LIAM: I have a meeting in 20 minutes at the Pillow
Inn. I don't know what it's called, but Caleb
does. I don't remember shit, but Caleb says
whatever the name of it is, because of my feat.
TALIESIN: This is the smartest feat you've ever
taken.
LIAM: Of course it is, it was chosen very
specifically. I say whatever it's called--
MATT: The Pillow Trove.
LIAM: I don't remember, he does. I have a meeting
in 20 minutes at the Pillow Grove-- I know that's
wrong-- Right now, 20 minutes, I need to get in.
MATT: They both blink their eyes at you. As you
glance down to look at your hand, it's your
regular sleeve.
LIAM: The spell didn't work here?
MATT: It worked, but then as you approached, you
looked down and it's no longer there.
(gasping)
MARISHA: Oh, magic shit.
MATT: You have a sense now, you think back to the
air of magical longevity the spell would maintain,
it's gone.
LIAM: Oh, wow.
SAM: Oh no.
TRAVIS: Disguise Self?
LIAM: Yeah, he used Disguise Self.
LAURA: So they dispelled it?
LIAM: We don't know.
MATT: At some point, as you approached and then
walked up to the gate, your Disguise Self just
dissipated. The one guard that was there before is
like--
LIAM: Okay, I just walk away.
MATT: As you walk away, he just goes, "Yeah,
that's what I thought."
LIAM: Cat kicker.
MATT: "Quick meeting, right? Quick fucking
meeting."
SAM: Kill that guy.
LAURA: What a dick.
MARISHA: You just made some guard's night.
TALIESIN: We got to kill that guard.
TRAVIS: Yeah, he's gone.
MATT: You are escorted to the exterior of the
Pillow Trove, which would be over here in the Tri-Spires.
MARISHA: I wonder how much of the Tri-Spires is
like this?
TRAVIS: It's got to be locked up--
MARISHA: Right?
LIAM: Yeah, it's fancy pants.
MATT: You're led down the beautiful cobblestone
street. Around the bend of this beautiful
courtyard where you can see a family that is
currently sitting down and having an open-air
picnic here amongst the grass. Butterflies in the
air, it's picturesque to the point where you
question how engineered it is to a certain degree.
With a couple of quick spins, you see one that
catches your eye, which is really interesting,
this massive one of the Tri-Spire towers that's
closest to the vicinity of The Pillow Trove, looks
like it was this old temple that's been completely
hollowed out and re-purposed to look like a glitzy
casino. There are banners that are pulled across
in brightly-colored silks that mingle and braid
into each other. You can see on each different
floor there's a different tone to the stone that's
been slightly altered, and you can see signs
showing different forms of entertainment. It's
simultaneously historically awe-inspiring and
gaudy combination that is intriguing.
LAURA: Like Caesar's Palace?
MATT: Kind of, yeah. It's a little Vegas-y,
compared to the rest of this area. You can see a
lot of the--
MARISHA: There's clouds painted on the ceiling for
no reason.
MATT: At the corners of these roads, you can see
these tall lanterns that contain a very faintly
ever-burning flame. Between each of them, there's
a long, white, silken banner that hangs as part of
decoration along each road. The roads themselves
feel like they're always in some loose parade-type
celebration, that's just part of the decor of the
vicinity. The stark contrast between the
Outersteads, to even the moderately average
Innersteads, to the Tri-Spires is astronomical.
LAURA: Can I ask the guard: What is that
building?
MATT: "Have you not been here before?"
LAURA: No. I'm new to town, actually.
MATT: "Interesting. You're in the Silken Terrace.
What you're looking at right there is called the
Triumph Chime. It's got all sorts of bars,
gambling halls, inn rooms, brothel, everything you
need up here."
LAURA: Oh, wow. I didn't think you had things like
this in the Empire.
MATT: "We've got them in places. What, you think
we're uncivilized folk? Where are you from?"
LAURA: I'm from the Menagerie Coast, actually.
Nicodranas.
MATT: "Huh. Well, you'll feel right at home,
yeah."
LAURA: Quite.
MATT: "Well, here you are. Pillow Trove." As he
motions over to the side, you see this luxurious
inn that has this cylindrical appearance to the
front and then turns into a blocky building
behind. It has this gold and deep purple
coloration to the pillars that hold up the various
walls to each intersection, and as soon as you
walk inside, the scents of scented candles and
various lavender-type smells hit your nose. The
element of it reminds you of home. As you walk
inside, there's a beautiful semi-circle desk, and
a human woman, probably in her mid-20s or so, jet
black hair that's straight and dangles past her
shoulders, watches you approach, as the guard
says, "I'll wait here and escort you out when
you're done."
LAURA: Thank you very much, kind sir! I walk
grandiosely up to the woman. Hello. I have a
package that's being delivered to here.
MATT: "Very well. What is the name receiving?"
LAURA: Jester.
MATT: "I shall inquire. I'll be back here in just
a moment."
LAURA: Thank you very much.
MATT: As she leaves from the front desk, you can
see there are two crownsguard that are assigned to
the sides that are keeping a close watch on you,
but they're lackadaisy through their day. You
get the sense they probably don't have to work too
hard this side of the city. About five minutes pass.
LAURA: Is anybody watching me?
MATT: They're both watching you, but not intently
like hawks, more just making sure you're not doing
anything silly. You watch as a rather bounding
obese merchant in his late 40s or so comes
barreling down the stairway, sniffling hard and
rubbing his nose. He's dressed really well-- maybe
a size too small, trying to reclaim a presentation
maybe of a younger self and he hasn't quite come
to terms with the fact that he's hitting that age.
As he walks past, he goes, "Ah. Good day."
LAURA: Good day.
MATT: He exits the building. Another five minutes
pass, and eventually the woman comes back and she
goes, "I'm sorry, we don't have a package for that
name here. Is there any other it might be under?"
LAURA: Maybe under Lavorre?
MATT: "I'll check."
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: She leaves again for another few minutes.
Comes back after that, "I'm sorry, there's nothing
under that name."
LAURA: Anything from The Ruby of the Sea, maybe?
MATT: "I'll check one more time."
LAURA: Okay, thank you.
MATT: She leaves.
LAURA: I smile back at the guard, like (pained
laugh) this is crazy, isn't it?
MATT: She comes back out. "I'm terribly sorry, we
do not have a package for or under any of those names.
LAURA: Well, that's really weird. Okay. Well, tell
you what, how about, because it's probably going
to be coming, you know, I'm here really early for
it, you know-- so if it comes for me-- when it
does-- could you leave word with the guard outside
the Tri-Spire?
MATT: "Which one?"
LAURA: The guard house, you know.
MATT: "Oh. All right, okay."
LAURA: Then I can come and ask if it's been
delivered and then I can come, because I don't
want to have to walk all the way here, you know,
if it's not here for me yet.
MATT: "Very well. I'll make a note of it."
LAURA: Okay. Unless I should maybe stay here,
waiting for it?
MATT: "If you like, we could set you up with a
room."
LAURA: Oh! Yes, how much would that be?
MATT: "Well, depends on the size. We have our
general suites, we have the lordly suites, and
then we have the diplomatic invitational suites.
Pricing begins at ten gold per room for the basic
suites, 20 for the next tier up, and for the
diplomatic ones, those run about 50 gold a night."
LAURA: Well, I normally stay in the diplomatic
rooms, but I guess the smallest room because, you
know, I'm small.
MATT: "Of course. Ten gold per night, how long do
you plan to stay?"
LAURA: Probably just tonight, because it'll
probably be here in the morning.
MATT: "All right. That was Jester, right?"
LAURA: Yes.
MATT: "Very well, all right."
LAURA: Oh yes, here you go, thank you.
MATT: "Thank you, and here is the key to your
room."
LAURA: Oh, thank you!
MATT: "Second floor, third door on the left, it
should be number 12."
LAURA: 12, that's my favorite number!
MATT: "So sorry I couldn't be of help with you."
LAURA: Okay. I go upstairs.
MATT: Okay.
LAURA: I sit down.
MATT: You get into your room. The door opens, it's
a beautiful small room, but well decorated and a
nice queen-size canopy bed and a dresser with a
mirror, a chair, a little--
SAM: Mini-fridge.
TALIESIN: Wet bar.
LAURA: Right? Hmm. Traveler? Are you here? Shit.
Okay. I don't know where I'm staying tonight,
Traveler, I might be here, I might be with my
friends, but-- Okay, I'll see you soon, okay! And
I run back out of the room.
MATT: You turn and in the hallway to where you
entered, you see a familiar cloak of deep green, hooded.
LAURA: (gasps) Hi!
MATT: The cloak nods down towards you and the
voice slowly cascades out from underneath, "I'm so
sorry she's not aware that you're here now, but
you're with friends."
LAURA: Okay. Do you think you could help me,
though?
MATT: "Child, I think I help you quite a bit
already."
LAURA: I know. You do.
MATT: "What do you need?"
LAURA: I don't know how to let her know-- I don't
know what to do.
MATT: He leans forward and the hand reaches out
and takes your chin a little bit and holds it
there. There in the dark space of the hood, you
can see the familiar verdant irises looking back
and the warmth fills you once more, the comfort
that kept you comfortable so many years alone in
that room. "I think the more deeds you do, the
more lives you change, the more confident brats
you break-- She'll find you."
LAURA: Okay. I pull out the pamphlet. Look what I
made for you!
MATT: The hand pulls back and takes the pamphlet.
"Hmm. Adorable."
LAURA: People are going to worship you like
crazy.
MATT: "You know what to do, then?"
LAURA: Yes! Okay. I missed you.
MATT: "I'm never far."
LAURA: (high-pitched) All right, I'm going to
walk, if you want to follow me, I'm going to go
over here then.
MATT: As you look down at the pamphlet and look up
to say that, he's gone. You hear this faint little
(chuckles).
LAURA: I skip away.
TRAVIS: Skip away?
LAURA: I go back to the guard. Okay, I have a room
here. I don't know if you need to escort me
anymore because I'm staying here at The Pillow
Trove, but I'm going to go, okay?
MATT: "Um, all right."
LAURA: Okay.
MATT: "You're welcome."
LAURA: Hey, guard, what's your name?
MATT: "Reeve."
LAURA: Reeve, it's so nice to meet you, I'm
Jester.
MATT: He had his hand out, looks like he's
expecting some sort of a tip--
LAURA: And I shake it.
MATT: "Oh, okay."
LAURA: Hey, so that guy that I hired to guard me,
I gave him some money. What am I supposed to do,
am I allowed to get him in here so he can actually
do his job?
MATT: "He's not an interior guard. Based on his
markings, it looks like he's supposed to be at the perimeter."
LAURA: The guy that was all in his tattered coat
and stuff?
MATT: "Oh! I misunderstood."
LAURA: Yeah.
MATT: "He's not coming in."
LAURA: But I hired him to guard me, though.
MATT: "I'm sorry, we have to maintain a certain
kind of presentation here."
LAURA: All right. Okay.
LIAM: Quickly, could I have asked around and found
my way to the other entrance to this area by now?
TRAVIS: Or to a Banana Republic, maybe?
(laughter)
LIAM: No, I have this. Super quick: a single
question at the gate.
MATT: Yeah, in this time you could have made your
way around.
LIAM: Ask around, find my way there. All right, so
I walk up straight, looking like me.
MATT: Yeah.
LIAM: Excuse me, may I have a word of your time--
may I have a moment of your time?
MATT: "Piss off."
LIAM: Listen to me, there is a store in here
called Chastity's Nook that sells dirty books. I
have heard of it for months, and I am going to
shop at this store, and if you want to make three
gold-- and if this one wants to make three gold--
you will let me in there to shop for smut at the store.
MATT: You watch as his face-- His eyes go wide for
a second and he goes, "You're a fan of the
Chastity Nook?"
LIAM: I want to be.
MATT: "You hear that?"
LIAM: One, two, three. One, two, three, each of
you.
MARISHA: The guard's a critter!
MATT: "No!"
ALL: Aww!
MARISHA: Damn it!
LAURA: You know, for six gold, you could buy
yourself some real fancy clothes.
MATT: "I appreciate what you're trying to do, pay
off a Crownsguard of the city of Zadash to let
you, a lowlife from the skids of the town, in the
most expensive and most well-guarded region of the
city. I like my job, I like my head."
LIAM: Okay, enjoy working for the man. I walk
off.
TRAVIS: Yeah! Anarchy!
TALIESIN: Boom!
LIAM: Done.
MATT: Jester?
LAURA: I guess I go back to Caleb.
MATT: Okay. You guys meet up on the outside of the
district.
LIAM: How was it?
LAURA: It was really pretty in there. People are
kind of stupid, but I did talk to the Traveler, so
everything's cool. Also, I don't have any money.
LIAM: That's okay, I have a little bit of money,
do you need some?
LAURA: No, I mean I have--
LIAM: I have about 50 gold, do you want me to give
you some?
LAURA: I mean, that's about as much as I have now.
It's so stupid, though!
LIAM: That's a lot of money!
LAURA: It's not, Caleb.
LIAM: It is!
LAURA: It's not!
LIAM: That's more money than my parents ever made
in their entire life.
LAURA: That's what I made, like, every day for my
allowance!
LIAM: In full view of Jester, I reach into my
pocket and take what's left of the mud and just--
Then I storm off towards our original shitty inn.
LAURA: Caleb! I didn't mean to make you put your
shit on your face again.
LIAM: I don't hear that.
MATT: As you guys jaunt off to catch up with the
rest of the troop, meeting probably-- because you
guys would probably be heading back to The Leaky
Tap. You manage to gather in the center of the
common area. You see a freshly-muddied Caleb enter
with a somewhat flustered, but smiling, Jester.
TRAVIS: Hey-- oh.
MARISHA: Yeah! Hi-- oh.
TALIESIN: We're clean, we're relaxed, we're ready
to go into a sewer.
TRAVIS: Fitting, absolutely fitting.
ASHLEY: How did-- didn't you just--?
SAM: This is his normal look-- I think it's very
nice, actually.
TALIESIN: I do, too.
ASHLEY: I thought we took a-- Hey, I am not a
person to judge. I know I don't look-- It's fine.
Where are we going again?
LIAM: I like you. Do you want to hang with us for
a while?
ASHLEY: I don't know.
LIAM: Oh, this day is great!
TRAVIS: We'll take it.
ASHLEY: Well, let's go kill something, yeah?
TRAVIS: We're going to the outer wall of the
Tri-Spire.
MARISHA: What time is it?
MATT: By now, I'd say it's probably closer to
three in the afternoon--
LIAM: It's beast killing time!
MARISHA: Oh, it's beast killing time, yeah!
TALIESIN: It's time to eat some roast beast.
TRAVIS: Maybe a late lunch, carb up, and then
let's fucking--
MARISHA: Yeah!
TALIESIN: Let's carb up.
ASHLEY: Pot roast beast?
LAURA: Guess what, Molly.
TALIESIN: Hm?
LAURA: I got a room at The Pillow Trove.
TALIESIN: Why would you get a room at The Pillow
Trove?
LAURA: Well, because my package didn't come, so I
thought that maybe if I got a room there, then I
can check in in the morning as well, maybe?
TALIESIN: Oh, that's very clever, actually. Well
done. Are you still expecting your package?
LAURA: Yeah, it's been not enough time, I don't
think.
TALIESIN: Sometimes I expect things to show up and
then they don't. It can be very disappointing, but
it's all right. I'm sure it'll show up.
LAURA: It'll show up, of course it will.
TALIESIN: Not that it matters if it doesn't.
ASHLEY: The trick is to not expect anything in
life.
TALIESIN: I didn't expect you to say that.
LIAM: That's good advice.
ASHLEY: Then you'll never be disappointed, you
know?
TALIESIN: That's very true.
MARISHA: Yeah, here's to abandoning expectations!
TRAVIS: Abandoning expectations!
SAM: Where did we get these drinks?
(laughter)
ASHLEY: On the way home from the airport!
MATT: Taking a little bit of liquid courage as you
muster your weaponry and gather your way to the
direction to the entry of the sewer where the
currently acquired mercenary contract had been taken.
MARISHA: Before we enter, Beau says: Wait, should
we have done research on what we're fighting?
SAM: Nah, we'll be fine.
MARISHA: All right, let's go!
(laughter)
MATT: And that's where we'll pick up next week.
(cheering)
TRAVIS: Yasha!
ALL: Yasha!
LIAM: Send all of your complaints for not knowing
what would happen in the porno shop to @matthewmercer.
MATT: Sorry, man!
LAURA: You just got to get some fancy clothes,
man!
TALIESIN: I was just waiting for the drop to look
at the shoes and you look back and yep, no, those
shoes don't get in here.
TRAVIS: We got to figure out how to get rid of the
Disguise Self blockage, that's a big-- What caused that?
SAM: We can go over the wall, around the wall,
under the wall--
TRAVIS: Plus, there are sewers.
LIAM: The place is crawling with--
MARISHA: If it's a vicinity thing--
SAM: We will get you porn, Liam. We will get you
porn.
TRAVIS: Smut you shall have!
MARISHA: I agree, I think you just need a nice
coat.
LIAM: Got to get to that shop, man.
MARISHA: A nice coat can get you porn.
MATT: Please continue to try! Not every means to
an end is the easiest and most straightforward, man.
TALIESIN: When I was young, we would stack three
up and put on a coat.
MATT: I want this to be an Ocean's Eleven-style,
like three episode mini-arc to get into the smut
shop, that's what I want.
(laughter)
LIAM: Got reasons.
MATT: Thank you guys so much for watching. Those
I'll see in Kentucky, I'll see you soon. Oh, boy.
MARISHA: Take care of my boy, home-state. Be good
to him.
MATT: Be back next week, with Ashley.
ALL: Yay!
MATT: Excited to have you home for a little
longer.
ASHLEY: Yeah! Just a little bit.
MATT: I missed you. There was something else I was
supposed to talk about.
SAM: Yes, you were supposed to say something about
giveaways or something.
MATT: No, I already commented on the giveaway.
What was it?
SAM: What were you supposed to say?
MATT: Where'd Lockey go? He was supposed to remind
me of something.
MATT: Anyway. I'll put it on Twitter if I remember
what it was. Anyway, love you guys, take care of
yourselves, we'll see you next week, and is it
Thursday yet? Good night.
LIAM: It still is!
MATT: We had a bathhouse episode!
[music]